<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-11-05T04:20:00.888Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-11-05T04:20:00.888Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wayland 1.20 Alpha Released With Upstreamed FreeBSD Support, Autotools Nuked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wayland-1.20-Alpha</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wayland-1.20-Alpha"/>
        <updated>2021-11-05T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the plans to release Wayland 1.20 before Christmas, Wayland 1.20 Alpha was released on Thursday to kick off the start of the release process...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switch Online Surpasses 32 Million Subs, Nintendo Says It Will Continue To "Improve And Expand" Expansion Pack Tier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123260</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/switch-online-surpasses-32-million-subs-nintendo-says-it-will-continue-to-improve-and-expand-expansion-pack-tier"/>
        <updated>2021-11-05T03:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subscriber count growing alongside hardware install base.
During Nintendo's latest Corporate Management Briefing, it was revealed its paid subscription service - Nintendo Switch Online - now has over 32 million members, as of September 2021.
The last significant figure was in September 2020 when the company said it had over 26 million users. According to the latest update, the subscriber count has increased again, thanks to the growing Switch hardware install base - which is now sitting at 92.87 million units.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Brilliant Diamond And Shining Pearl Get A Five-Minute Overview Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123259</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/pokemon-brilliant-diamond-and-shining-pearl-get-a-five-minute-overview-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-11-05T02:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Launching worldwide November 19th.
It's a rather exciting month for the Nintendo Switch, with a lot of huge releases on the way. We've just shared our review of Shin Megami Tensei V (it's excellent, by the way), but if you're looking for even more RPG action later this month, you might want to keep an eye out for Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl.
These remakes based on the classic Nintendo DS titles from 2006/07 are returning on November 19th, and ahead of the big release Nintendo and The Pokémon Company have been pumping out new hype trailers. In the latest upload on Nintendo's channel is a lengthy 5-minute overview of the anticipated release.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Is Opening A New Store In Japan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123258</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/nintendo-is-opening-a-new-store-in-japan"/>
        <updated>2021-11-05T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Expected to be up and running by the end of 2022.

Nintendo has announced it will be opening a new retail and merchandise store located in Osaka, Japan. It'll be located within the Daimaru Umeda building. It will be the second store to open in the company's homeland, following on from Tokyo in 2019.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zelda: Skyward Sword On Switch Has Already Matched Its Lifetime Wii Sales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123257</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/zelda-skyward-sword-on-switch-has-already-matched-its-lifetime-wii-sales"/>
        <updated>2021-11-05T01:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sky is the limit.
It seems Nintendo's decision to remaster and port its 2011 Wii release The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword HD to the Switch has well and truly paid off.
In the company's latest financial report, it's been revealed the Nintendo Switch version of the game has already sold 3.60 million units as of 30th September 2021. As highlighted by many other sources, means it has already matched the lifetime sales of the original Wii game (roughly 3.67 million, according to industry analyst Daniel Ahmad) in just 77 days.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freeze!]]></title>
        <id>1848001411</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/freeze-1848001411"/>
        <updated>2021-11-05T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[François Leroy, aka Friendly Robot, is a  concept artist, designer and creative director.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EA CEO says FIFA players want NFTs, which are "part of the future of our industry"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-ceo-says-fifa-players-want-nfts-which-are-part-of-the-future-of-our-industry</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-ceo-says-fifa-players-want-nfts-which-are-part-of-the-future-of-our-industry"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T23:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous generations worried that humanity would be hurried towards its demise by nuclear war. My fear is that our destruction will be brought about by FIFA players opening Ultimate Team packs to "earn" NFTs. 

Yes, EA CEO Andrew Wilson followed in Ubisoft's footsteps by saying that he thought NFTs and play-to-earn would be "an important part of the future of our industry." 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Nejdokonalejší grafen]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-nejdokonalejsi-grafen</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-nejdokonalejsi-grafen"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kolik bitů se vejde do vesmíru? Jak se programuje automobil. Algoritmy v naší hlavě a chůze městem. Heliové hvězdy, svlečené hvězdy a obří neutronové hvězdy. Svítící DNA.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unpacking: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847994273</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/unpacking-the-kotaku-review-1847994273"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I studied archaeology at university, and on our very first day of classes our professor walked in carrying all these bags of trash. He  dumped them on our tables and said “here, pick through all this then tell me everything about the person they belonged to”.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Co se chystá pro Linux 5.16, část první: spousta nových ARM SoC]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15749</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/co-se-chysta-pro-linux-5-16-cast-prvni-spousta-novych-arm-soc/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podpora Gen12 GPU v Intel Alder Lake-S či DisplayPort 2.0 a USB 4.0 u AMD, podpora pevných disků s Multi-Actuator, nově rozpoznávané snímače na mnoha základních deskách Asus a ASRock.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel + Microsoft Bring oneAPI L0 & OpenCL To WSL2 With Open-Source Stack + DXGKRNL]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-oneAPI-L0-WSL2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-oneAPI-L0-WSL2"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T22:21:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Intel Alder Lake is dominating today's news cycle, Intel and Microsoft also announced today that they have brought oneAPI Level Zero and Intel OpenCL support to Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL2) while employing Intel graphics hardware acceleration...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4's next DLC brings the outdoors indoors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-next-dlc-brings-the-outdoors-indoors</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-next-dlc-brings-the-outdoors-indoors"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T22:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like many people, I became a plant guy during the pandemic. I don't know the names of the plants, I don't know what they need except sporadic watering and moderate light, but they're green and I like them.

The Sims 4's Blooming Rooms kit feels designed for me. It's one of Maxis's new micro-DLCs, and it lets you pack rooms with flora without the need to keep the alive through knowledge or effort.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[League Of Legends, Valorant and every Riot games are now on the Epic Games Store]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/league-of-legends-valorant-and-every-riot-games-are-now-on-the-epic-games-store</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/league-of-legends-valorant-and-every-riot-games-are-now-on-the-epic-games-store"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T22:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[League of Legends, Teamfight Tactics, Legends of Runeterra, and Valorant are all now available via the Epic Games Store. That's all of Riot's games, in case you were wondering, which have previously been solely available on PC via their own launcher. At the same time, League Of Legends hero Jinx is hopping into Fortnite.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Katrina Joins Animal Crossing: New Horizons, Costs 100,000 Bells]]></title>
        <id>1848000190</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/katrina-joins-animal-crossing-new-horizons-costs-100-1848000190"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brewster isn’t the only fan-favorite making their triumphant return in Animal Crossing: New Horizons this week. In addition to the sea shanty-singing Kapp’n and others, fortune teller Katrina is also back as of the 2.0 update, ready to grant you all sorts of bonuses, for a price.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hit Puzzle Game Unpacking Features 14,000 (!) Audio Files Replicating Ordinary Sounds]]></title>
        <id>1848000220</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/hit-puzzle-game-unpacking-features-14-000-audio-fil-1848000220"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T21:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unpacking is more than meets the ears. The chillwave puzzle game, developed by Brisbane-based Witch Beam and out this week for Switch, PC, and Xbox (via Game Pass), apparently features a whopping 14,000 individual Foley sound effects. No, that’s not a typo.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rune Factory 4 will craft, marry, kill on PC this December 7th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rune-factory-4-will-craft-marry-kill-on-pc-this-december-7th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rune-factory-4-will-craft-marry-kill-on-pc-this-december-7th"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T21:03:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I write about a lot of games that I describe as being "like Rune Factory." Well. If you like games like Rune Factory, you'll love that Rune Factory 4 Special is headed to PC in a little over a month, on December 7th.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Truck Full Of Precious PC Graphics Cards Has Been Stolen]]></title>
        <id>1847999927</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/a-truck-full-of-precious-pc-graphics-cards-has-been-sto-1847999927"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to EVGA, one of NVidia’s primary manufacturers, a shipment of RTX 30-series graphics cards has been stolen from a truck in California. I do not care how badly you think you need more frames per second, you should not rob a truck to do it. The frames just aren’t worth it. I promise you that your eyes will…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual Studio Code a VSCodium 1.62]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/visual-studio-code-a-vscodium-1.62</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/visual-studio-code-a-vscodium-1.62"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T20:01:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 1.62 editoru zdrojových kódů Visual Studio Code (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek i s náhledy a animovanými gify v poznámkách k vydání. Ve verzi 1.62 výjde také VSCodium, tj. komunitní sestavení Visual Studia Code bez telemetrie a licenčních podmínek Microsoftu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallery: Check Out The Animal Crossing: New Horizons Museum In First-Person Mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123254</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/gallery-check-out-the-animal-crossing-new-horizons-museum-in-first-person-mode"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just like in real life!
Animal Crossing: New Horizons has a massive new update, and the new Pro Camera App is one of the latest additions.
The new camera app adds two important features: the Handheld Camera and the Tripod Camera (learn how to unlock and use them in our guide), so now you can take selfies and close-up first-person photos.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Linux Performance Benchmark Data For Alder Lake, Comparison Data Points]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=i9-12900K-i5-12600K-OB</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=i9-12900K-i5-12600K-OB"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the embargo lifted following this morning's Intel Core i5 12600K + Core i9 12900K Linux review, I've begun uploading more public test data to OpenBenchmarking.org and making my earlier test results public. With that and initial data flowing in from others in the community, here is some more data to poke through if interested in Alder Lake on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 162: the best literary adaptations in games special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-162-the-best-literary-adaptations-in-games-special-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-162-the-best-literary-adaptations-in-games-special-1"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T19:35:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey podcast fans. Mum’s away this week, which means the inmates have taken over the asylum once again. The temptation was to play another round of Sweeten The Deal, but instead Nate and I were good little podcast boys and delivered a surprisingly on point discussion of our favourite videogame adaptations of literary works. Well, I say ‘on point’; there’s a fair amount of discussion of new Dune, too, which is what got us thinking about successful book to screen journeys. Sadly, the House Atreides bagpipe band were not available for a rousing rendition of the podcast theme.
There’s also a micro Cavern of Lies in which things get biblical.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Unpacking's 14,000 Audio Files Make For One Hell Of A Polished Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123251</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-unpackings-14000-audio-files-make-for-one-hell-of-a-polished-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[*clunk* *schwif* *bang*.
Earlier this week, a zen game about unpacking, which is unsurprisingly called Unpacking, launched on Nintendo Switch. Since then, it's been getting a lot of attention, both for its players who don't know what GameCubes are, and for the stunning amount of detail within the isometric pixel art game.
The latest detail to go viral is one that doesn't usually get nearly enough recognition: the Foley work, done by BAFTA-award-winning composer and audio designer, Jeff van Dyck, who has credits on Total War, Hand of Fate, and a number of EA Sports games.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World's new patch targets gold sellers and item duping]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-new-patch-targets-gold-sellers-and-item-duping</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-new-patch-targets-gold-sellers-and-item-duping"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T19:06:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new update hit New World today, aimed partially at cracking down on gold sellers and exploits used to duplicate items and cash. Amazon say they've banned many players who were spamming chat advertising their illicit services. They also blasted a blog post talking about many of the issues concerning players, explaining things, detailing plans for fixes, and other welcome news.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: Switch Is A Juggernaut, But Nintendo Will Still Feel Investor Pressure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123235</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-switch-is-a-juggernaut-but-nintendo-will-still-feel-investor-pressure"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Production issues and no 'Pro' will remain topics.

Today brought the Q2 Nintendo financial results, which would be easy to miss with the understandable excitement of Animal Crossing: New Horizons version 2.0 arriving a day early. In some ways they're results with two sides, though within Nintendo's boardroom they may feel like they're somewhat stuck in the middle.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: There's A Street Fighter II Easter Egg Hiding Inside This (Checks Notes) 'Can Depalletizer']]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123239</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-theres-a-street-fighter-ii-easter-egg-hiding-inside-this-checks-notes-can-depalletizer"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That's quite the headline, right?
The wide impact of video games means that little references can appear anywhere. In movies. During TV shows. In books. Or, in the case of Capcom's Street Fighter II, as a hidden screen on a can depalletizer used in the brewing industry. Yes, you read that right.
Reddit poster RonnieBringIt has uploaded a video which shows him inputting a combination of commands into the Ska Fab Nimbus depallitizer's HMI (Human Machine Interface) and getting rewarded with a screenshot from Capcom's famous one-on-one fighter.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Call Of Duty: Vanguard guns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-best-guns</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-best-guns"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T17:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know which are the best guns in Call Of Duty: Vanguard? Recent Call Of Duty games have among the most complex weapon meta of any FPS games, thanks both to the sheer number of weapons and the absurd number of attachments you can use to customise each gun. Call Of Duty: Vanguard continues this trend in a big way, with 27 primary and 9 secondary weapons that you can unlock, customise, and experiment with.
We fully expect Call Of Duty: Vanguard's weapon meta to evolve quickly with future updates and balance patches, but at the moment there is definitely a top tier of guns which have risen above the rest in effectiveness. Below we'll walk you through the very best guns in the game and how to get the most power out of each one.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing's New Fisheye Lens Makes Everything Better]]></title>
        <id>1847997387</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossings-new-fisheye-lens-makes-everything-bett-1847997387"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve downloaded the new Animal Crossing update early, chances are good that you’ve already bought the new Pro Camera and are fiddling with its new features, like the fancy new first-person view. But that’s not all. The camera also comes with a few other new features and filters, which I am ignoring in their…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patricia Hernandez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Datamining Finds Thousands Of New Items In Animal Crossing: New Horizons Version 2.0]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123247</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/datamining-finds-thousands-of-new-items-in-animal-crossing-new-horizons-version-2-0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well the download did take a while...
Nintendo has been eager to emphasize that version 2.0 of Animal Crossing: New Horizons is the first and only 'major' update to the game. We had various small updates previously of course, adding new events, items and themes, but today's arrival was far more substantial. In addition to new characters, locations and features, it seems to have added a lot of items.
Datamining results shared on animalcrossingworld.com suggest the number of new items could be as high as 9000+. That's crazy, but the number is currently being reviewed and debated, as it also depends on whether you count clones and new colour variations of existing items. In terms of items that are fully brand new, it could be more in the region of 1000+.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing's New Update Is Full of Picture-Perfect Food Recipes]]></title>
        <id>1847997220</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossings-new-update-is-full-of-picture-perfect-1847997220"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A year ago, Animal Crossing: New Horizons offered us the tantalizing opportunity to emulate something we couldn’t do in real life: go outside. Now, the new 2.0 update similarly allows some of us a vicarious experience we can’t attain IRL. Namely, you can now craft Instagram-worthy meals, even if you’re actually a cook…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HBO's '8-Bit Christmas' Is Giving The NES Power Glove Another Shot At Movie Glory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123242</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/hbos-8-bit-christmas-is-giving-the-nes-power-glove-another-shot-at-movie-glory"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["How far would you go to score the ultimate gift?".
Remember the Power Glove? It was a mostly awkward means of interacting with games back during the NES era, and was immortalised in the 1989 Hollywood flick The Wizard. It's since become something of a cult object in the world of gaming, inspiring adoration with older gamers (as well as a feature-length documentary), but this much-maligned peripheral is getting another chance of movie fame thanks to HBO's upcoming festive flick, 8-Bit Christmas.
Set in the late '80s, the film tells the quest of one boy to get a Nintendo Entertainment System, the hottest item with any self-respecting child. But alas! The NES is sold-out everywhere, so ten-year-old Jake Doyle sets out on a mission to secure one.

Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5: PC performance and the best settings to use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-pc-performance-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-pc-performance-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:43:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ll admit I misjudged Forza Horizon 5 – not just the extent to which I’d enjoy it, but how much its searingly shiny visuals could justify the significantly heightened PC requirements. Well, lock me in one of this game’s hundreds of boots and take me away, because it’s both tonnes of fun and genuinely, magnificently gorgeous. Here’s how Forza Horizon 5 runs on PC, and which settings to tweak if you want a performance boost without cutting too deep into that top-notch fidelity.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm so glad Elden Ring sounds like a Souls game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-so-glad-elden-ring-sounds-like-a-souls-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-so-glad-elden-ring-sounds-like-a-souls-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:31:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Software and Bandai Namco have treated us to a new Elden Ring gameplay trailer, which showed off 15 glorious minutes of exploration. All I wanted was one laugh and I got it, from a rotund POT-BOY at that. Plus, it was narrated by a guy who sounded suspiciously like SoulsTuber VaatiVidya as the Tarnished trotted and fought and summoned and stealthed. Undoubtedly a showstopper of a trailer, but the higlight for me was how good the action sounded. And boy, it sounded good didn't it?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing's Got Hundreds Of Cool New Items, Like Fairy Lights And Castle Towers]]></title>
        <id>1847997121</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossings-got-hundreds-of-cool-new-items-like-f-1847997121"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since Nintendo announced Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ big 2.0 update players have been scrambling to build up their Nook Mile stashes knowing good things were in store. Now the update is live and they’ve been rewarded with lots of cool new stuff like better hairstyles, outdoor furniture, and fairy lights, which…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: Latest Pokémon Brilliant Diamond And Shining Pearl Ad Keeps The Hype Rolling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123240</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/video-latest-pokemon-brilliant-diamond-and-shining-pearl-ad-keeps-the-hype-rolling"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA['Rediscover the Sinnoh Region'.
Hot off the heels of this week's 'Become a Pokémon League Champion' trailer for Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl, Nintendo's back with another ad to keep the hype rolling ahead of this month's release.
This latest clip, called 'Rediscover the Sinnoh Region', offers up another quick look at the remakes' reimagined version of Sinnoh and reminds us of the three starter Pokémon we'll be choosing from – Turtwig, Chimchar, and Piplup.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bloodborne PS1-style demake coming to PC next year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloodborne-ps1-style-demake-coming-to-pc-next-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloodborne-ps1-style-demake-coming-to-pc-next-year"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:27:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're not too busy fawning over that new Elden Ring gameplay trailer (I don't blame you, it's very exciting), then I have some more exciting Soulsborne news for you - a PlayStation 1-esque demake of Bloodborne is coming out in January next year, and it looks excellent. Bloodborne PSX turns FromSoft's gothic action-RPG into a low-poly spookfest, complete with crackly old sound effects and 16-bit music. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 developers wanted to make a sequel that "didn't sabotage its older brother"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-developers-wanted-to-make-a-sequel-that-didnt-sabotage-its-older-brother</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-developers-wanted-to-make-a-sequel-that-didnt-sabotage-its-older-brother"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2, the sequel to Red Hook Studio's gothic roguelike, is a somewhat familiar affair. It's dark, it's tough, and a narrator likes to remind you of those things frequently. But this time around, we're leaving the Ancestor's squalid hamlet behind, and swapping it out for a stress-fueled stagecoach. Heroes are no longer cannon-fodder to send out on doomed expeditions, but vital team members who have stories to share and relationships to forge. 


I recently talked with creative director Chris Bourassa and design director Tyler Sigman about why they decided to take the game in this new direction, the difficulties of switching to a relationship-based affliction system, and why they're excited to be working in early access again. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Trade Skills: how to level up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-skill-leveling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-skill-leveling"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:05:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you level up Trade Skills in New World? Trade Skills are non-combat skills in New World — just about any activity your character takes part in that isn't tied to their weapons is linked to a Trade Skill. There are 17 of these skills in all, separated into three sub-categories: Gathering, Refining, and Crafting.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turris OS 5.3]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/turris-os-5.3</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/turris-os-5.3"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Turris OS, operační systém pro síťová zařízení Turris postavený na OpenWrt, byl vydán v nové verzi 5.3. Podrobný přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing: New Horizons' Endless Sea Bass Finally Have A Purpose]]></title>
        <id>1847996856</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-new-horizons-sea-bass-finally-have-a-p-1847996856"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sure, there are lots of positive things to say about Animal Crossing: New Horizons, but there was one argument that could tale it all down: the Sea bass. But not any more! In the New Horizons 2.0 update, those sneaky people at Nintendo have made the floppy blighters useful. You can cook them!

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lost Ark is a Diablo-like MMO that promises late-game thrills, if you can survive the early slow burn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lost-ark-is-a-diablo-like-mmo-that-promises-late-game-thrills-if-you-can-survive-the-early-slow-burn</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lost-ark-is-a-diablo-like-mmo-that-promises-late-game-thrills-if-you-can-survive-the-early-slow-burn"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lost Ark is a free-to-play action RPG-inspired MMO that came out to great acclaim in Korea back in 2018. Now, Amazon Games are bringing its flashy, Diablo-like combat to the west in the form of a closed beta later today, and we've had an early sneak peek at it. Of course, what with Amazon's own MMO New World now settling into its third month, not to mention Final Fantasy 14's Endwalker expansion looming on the horizon, Lost Ark arrives at a busy time for fervent EXP grinders. The big question, then, is whether Lost Ark’s Diablo-y formula can do enough to compete with the already well-established MMO juggernauts. Judging by my few hours of hands-on time, I’m thinking it might, but only if you’re able to embrace its slow burn.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 arrives February 17th, and on Game Pass]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-arrives-february-17th-and-on-game-pass</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-arrives-february-17th-and-on-game-pass"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:55:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After taking a deep breath, Sega have shouted a large amount of news about Total War: Warhammer 3's launch. For starters, the release date is February 17th, 2022. For main course, folks who buy it within a week of launch will get the Ogre Kingdoms DLC for free. And for dessert, it will be in Xbox Game Pass For PC. A fair meal, there. But here, come meet the Ogres in this new trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Animal Crossing: New Horizons Guide - Walkthrough, Tips And Hints]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-97909</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/animal-crossing-new-horizons-guide-walkthrough-tips-and-hints"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bugs! Fish! Tools! Bells! Blathers!
UPDATE: We're adding new guides for the free 2.0 update and the Happy Home Paradise DLC — find new and updated guides in bold in the relevant sections below!

Animal Crossing: New Horizons slowly but surely took over many of our lives – but if you're at a loss of what to do next in the game, then you should check out the tips and hints we've outlined below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix's Squid Game Is Accidentally Making One Twitch Streamer's Life Way Harder]]></title>
        <id>1847996695</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/netflixs-squid-game-is-accidentally-making-one-twitch-s-1847996695"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix’s Squid Game is a popular show, having been watched by some 142 million households worldwide since it hit the streaming service on September 17. Unfortunately for Twitch streamer Lydia ‘SquidGame’ Ellery, the username and brand she’s built for the past decade is in jeopardy due to a perceived association with…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PSA: Leif Can Now Weed Your Animal Crossing: New Horizons Island, But It's Pricey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123233</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/psa-leif-can-now-weed-your-animal-crossing-new-horizons-island-but-its-pricey"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Costs a lot of green.
The weeding process has been made a little easier in the new Animal Crossing: New Horizons update, thank Nookness! With the addition of Leif's permanent shop on Harv's Island, you can now buy flowers, bushes, crop seeds and saplings whenever you flippin' want.
But there's a secret feature that we didn't know about beforehand: Leif now has a weeding service! He'll clean up your entire island, including all the weeds that are inaccessible and hidden, even, all in one go.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Senior Couple Was Having Trouble With TLOU2. He Answered Their Craigslist Ad.]]></title>
        <id>1847996198</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/senior-couple-was-having-trouble-with-tlou2-he-answere-1847996198"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You never know what kind of ad you’ll find on Craigslist. While some listings may be unorthodox, one gig post back in late September was wholesome enough to sound like a fairy tale. And this one has a happy ending. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This ghostly indie puzzler looks absolutely gorgeous]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-ghostly-indie-puzzler-looks-absolutely-gorgeous</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-ghostly-indie-puzzler-looks-absolutely-gorgeous"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:03:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grief is a delicate subject to tackle, and games sometimes stumble in their approaches, either making things excessively mournful or veering into cringe territory with you know, like, emotions, man. But Arte's upcoming puzzling game, How To Say Goodbye, looks like a refreshingly playful take on loss. Not to mention that it’s a feast for the eyes. I mean, just LOOK at it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japanese Charts: Mario Party Superstars Goes Top In A Busy Week For New Releases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123228</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/japanese-charts-mario-party-superstars-goes-top-in-a-busy-week-for-new-releases"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mario's-a-numba-one!
Famitsu's Japanese chart figures are now in for the week ending 31st October, revealing that Mario Party Superstars has gone straight in at number one.
The game sold an estimated 163,256 physical copies in its opening week in Japan, managing to fend off several newcomers releasing this week. Among the other new titles was Super Robot Wars 30, which sold better on Switch than PS4, and Fatal Frame: Maiden of Black Water, which did the opposite.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Download: 4th November (Europe)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-85135</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/nintendo-download-4th-november-europe"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fast & Furious! Just Dance 2022! World War Z!
The latest Nintendo Download update for Europe has arrived, and it's bringing new games galore to the eShop in your region. As always, be sure to drop a vote in our poll and comment down below with your potential picks for the week. Enjoy!
Switch Retail eShop - New Releases
Cupid Parasite (Reef Entertainment, 5th Nov, £44.99 / €49.99) - What's love got to do with it? In this divine romantic comedy, play as , 's top bridal advisor and none other than 's Goddess of Love, ! Determined to prove that love is more than bows and arrows, she meets her biggest challenge yet - the infamous . But in finding love for the , will find love herself?
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Move Your Animal Crossing Island Onto Your New Switch, OLED Or Not]]></title>
        <id>1847894755</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/how-to-move-your-animal-crossing-island-onto-your-new-s-1847894755"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the liminal period between Animal Crossing: New Horizons offering nothing new to do and Animal Crossing: New Horizons offering arguably too much new stuff to do, Nintendo released a new Switch model complete with a bigger screen and a 0 percent increase to battery life. Perhaps you were lucky enough to snag one.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PSA: Animal Crossing: New Horizons' NookLink Smartphone App Has Also Been Updated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123230</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/psa-animal-crossing-new-horizons-nooklink-smartphone-app-has-also-been-updated"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don't forget the app!
With all of the Version 2.0.0 shenanigans taking place in Animal Crossing: New Horizons today – it was supposed to be tomorrow and we weren't prepared, Nintendo! – you'd be forgiven for forgetting all about the NookLink app available through the Nintendo Switch Online smartphone app. You might want to remember it for just a second, though, because it's also been updated alongside the game.
That's right, the NookLink app – which lets you view your passport, scan QR codes, use keyboards to chat with friends and more – has also been given a surprise update. When opening the app for the first time after updating, you'll be greeted with a message letting you know that there are some new additions.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Shin Megami Tensei V - The Best Entry Yet In This Dark, Engrossing RPG Series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122507</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/shin-megami-tensei-v"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A HEE-HOme run.
Shin Megami Tensei V has been a long time coming. The last mainline entry in the series was released over eight years ago for the 3DS, while the last home console entry was another ten years before that. Moreover, Shin Megami Tensei V was one of the first games ever revealed for the Switch, mere months after the console itself was first shown to the public. All those years of hype have thus generated some awfully high expectations. It was never in doubt that Atlus would give this release the attention it deserves, but the question has always been whether it would be good enough to get over the high bar set by its predecessors. Fortunately, any such concerns can be cast aside — Shin Megami Tensei V is the best entry in the series yet and stands as an impressive achievement for a beloved franchise.
Right from the off, it’s made abundantly clear that Shin Megami Tensei V is every bit as ‘heavy’ as its predecessors. Things start off seemingly normal as you follow your character through a typical day of school, but there’s an ominous tone to the announcement at the end of the day that advises students to travel home in pairs. People have been disappearing and there are rumors of violent attacks taking place around Tokyo, but nobody really seems to have a clear idea of what exactly is going on.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's 20 Minutes Of Elden Ring Gameplay]]></title>
        <id>1847995482</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/heres-15-minutes-of-elden-ring-gameplay-1847995482"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At this point—and you’re well within your rights to still have reservations—it’s becoming pretty difficult to refute that Elden Ring...is real? Today, during a digital showcase, publisher Bandai Namco shows off 15 minutes of the next action-adventure game from FromSoftware. (Update, 10:20 a.m. ET: It’s over, and it…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Download: 4th November (North America)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-117555</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/nintendo-download-4th-november-north-america"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing DLC! Airborne Kingdom! Just Dance 2022!
The latest Nintendo Download update for North America has arrived, and it's bringing new games galore to the eShop in your region. As always, be sure to drop a vote in our poll and comment down below with your potential picks for the week. Enjoy!
Switch eShop - Highlights
Animal Crossing: New Horizons – Happy Home Paradise - Join Lottie and the Paradise Planning team in this paid DLC* that expands your Animal Crossing: New Horizons experience. You’ll travel to a chain of charming islands in an archipelago, where you can design the dream vacation homes of your clients, decorate island facilities – like a school and a restaurant – and discover new ways to create and personalize. With dozens and dozens of clients eager to enjoy your design inspirations, including your main island residents, the chance to create dream vacation homes offers new experiences to discover! Animal Crossing: New Horizons – Happy Home Paradise will be available on Nov. 5.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh Snap, Animal Crossing Rocks Can Give You Star Fragments Now]]></title>
        <id>1847995379</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/oh-snap-animal-crossing-rocks-can-give-you-star-fragme-1847995379"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, this is a nice surprise. Folks have been exploring the big new Animal Crossing update since last night, as the patch went up early. Already, the community has struck gold. As it turns out, you can now visit a type of island that contains a special, never-before-seen type of rock.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patricia Hernandez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Adds Linux Support To Endpoint Manager]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MS-Endpoint-Manager-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MS-Endpoint-Manager-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's latest surprise is adding native Linux support to their Endpoint Manager software...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EA Boss Says NFTs Will Be An "Important Part" Of The Games Industry's Future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123227</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/ea-boss-says-nfts-will-be-an-important-part-of-the-games-industrys-future"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's still early to figure out how that's going to work".
Recently, Ubisoft stated that it wants to be one of the key players in the world of video game-related NFTs (non-fungible tokens), and now publishing rival Electronic Arts has noted that it too is looking at how to breaking into "play to earn" market.
During an earnings call this week, EA boss Andrew Wilson referred to NFTs and blockchain gaming as an "important part about the future of our industry", which echoes what Ubisoft CFO Frédérick Duguet said earlier this week. Duguet believes that the technology "will enable more play-to-earn that will enable more players to actually earn content, own content, and we think it's going to grow the industry quite a lot".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 explains how to create custom modes with Portal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-explains-how-to-create-custom-modes-with-portal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-explains-how-to-create-custom-modes-with-portal"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:28:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dice have detailed some of the options players will get to mess around with in Battlefield 2042's map customisation tool, Battlefield Portal, and there's just so much. It will present you with some of your fave maps from the likes of Bad Company 2 and the Battlefields of old, then let you tweak them as much as you please by adding various vehicles, rules and more. I'm personally hoping to see plenty of oldies with 2042's sweet new grappling hook thrown in. Every map could be improved by a grappling hook.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: This Is Not A Drill! Sea Bass Are Actually Useful Now In Animal Crossing: New Horizons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123226</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-this-is-not-a-drill-sea-bass-are-actually-useful-now-in-animal-crossing-new-horizons"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best thing in the update, tbh.
STOP THE PRESSES. This new Animal Crossing: New Horizons update brings a lot to the table — Kapp'n, Brewster, Reese, Cyrus, and so on — but what it really brings to the table is PIE.
With the new Cooking update, you can now unlock recipes just by catching fish and remembering that fish are edible, which means... you guessed it... THE PESKY SEA BASS IS NOW GOOD FOR SOMETHING AT LAST.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core i9-12900K review: Alder Lake at its most extreme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-core-i9-12900k-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-core-i9-12900k-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By now you’ve probably heard about how Intel’s 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs shake up the previously stagnant Core line. Led by this, the Intel Core i9-12900K, Alder Lake sees the adoption of a hybrid architecture that combines high-power Performance cores (P-cores) with Efficiency cores (E-cores) that can free up headroom by taking on background tasks. The Core i9-12900K takes this opportunity to bulk up, combining eight P-cores and E-cores apiece for a total of 16 cores and 24 threads.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core i5-12600K review: a gaming CPU worth waiting for]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-core-15-12600k-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-core-15-12600k-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Intel Core i5-12600K is, in some ways, the CPU that Intel should have made three or four years ago. Ever since AMD’s Ryzen chips appeared with an alluring balance of gaming speed, desktop multitasking performance, efficiency, and affordability, Intel seemed to sink into a comfort zone of simply raising clock speeds and maybe adding a few cores. 


This was often enough to earn some half-throated recommendations for gaming builds specifically, but this past year proved that something needed to change, with the AMD Ryzen 5 5600X claiming the best gaming CPU title and 11th Gen Rocket Lake Intel chips – like the 5600X’s rival Core i5-11600K – looking thoroughly skippable. For those who did decide to wait until the 12th Gen Alder Lake launch, consider yourselves vindicated, as the Core i5-12600K is a great all-rounder: both a Ryzen-beater in games and, thanks to a long-overdue architecture revamp, a drastically better general purpose processor.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core i5 12600K / Core i9 12900K "Alder Lake" Linux Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30653</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30653"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the Intel 12th Gen Core processors shipping today along with the new line-up of Z690 motherboards, the review embargo lifts for talking about these Intel "Alder Lake" processors. While by now you've likely heard a lot about Intel Alder Lake on Windows and various leaked benchmarks with Windows 11, how does these processors with the new hybrid architecture work and perform on Linux? Here are the initial benchmarks and support information for Intel's Core i5 12600K and Core i9 12900K processors under Ubuntu Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XWayland Lands Another Performance Fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-Another-Perf-Fix</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-Another-Perf-Fix"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T12:46:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat engineer Michel Dänzer has uncovered and addressed another performance shortcoming within X.Org's XWayland code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Čtvrtletní aktualizace instalačních obrazů pro openSUSE Leap]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ctvrtletni-aktualizace-instalacnich-obrazu-pro-opensuse-leap</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ctvrtletni-aktualizace-instalacnich-obrazu-pro-opensuse-leap"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T12:14:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[openSUSE release tým se rozhodl poskytovat  čtvrtletní aktualizace instalačních médií pro Leap na základě zpětné vazby ze strany komunity a nedávné žádosti od openSUSE Board. První QU (Quarterly Update) pro openSUSE Leap 15.3 byl publikován minulý pátek. Cílem je uživatelům poskytnout pravidelně aktualizované instalační média, které obsahují všechny vydané softwarové aktualizace k danému datu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>lkocman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Dance 2022 Launches On Switch Today, Here's The Full Song List]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123212</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/just-dance-2022-launches-on-switch-today-heres-the-full-song-list"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every song included in the new Just Dance game.
If you're thinking of picking up the latest entry in Ubisoft's Just Dance series but want to know which songs you'll actually get to dance to, you've come to the right place.
Just Dance 2022 will include 43 songs in total (not including the hundreds of bonus tracks you can play if you're subscribed to the Just Dance Unlimited service) and we've got the full list for you below. You can also catch a quick snippet of each song in the brand new trailer above.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch: Nintendo Life's Lovely Video Team Plays Animal Crossing: New Horizons Version 2.0]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123214</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/watch-nintendo-lifes-lovely-video-team-plays-animal-crossing-new-horizons-version-2-0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What's the date, Nintendo?
Update:
The live stream is finished but you can view the whole thing above, enjoy!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take-Two cancel unannounced superhero game from Mafia 3 devs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/take-two-cancels-unannounced-superhero-game-from-mafia-3-devs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/take-two-cancels-unannounced-superhero-game-from-mafia-3-devs"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:42:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last night, Take-Two Interactive's quarterly earnings report mentioned a $53 million (£39 million) "impairment charge", related to their decision to cease development on an unannounced project. According to a number of reports, that project was a third-person action game from Mafia 3 developers Hangar 13 that would've featured superheroes and online play.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy: should you pay the Nova Corps fine?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fine</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-fine"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:42:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know whether to pay the fine or not in Guardians Of The Galaxy? After talking to the Worldmind in chapter 9, you will have the option to pay the Nova Corps fine that you incurred after escaping the Quarantine Zone and running into the Hala’s Hope in Chapter 2. Some decisions can have large and unexpected consequences in Guardians Of The Galaxy, so a bit of foresight is worth having if you want the best outcome when deciding whether to pay the Nova Corps fine or not.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard release time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-release-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-release-time"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:38:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the Call Of Duty: Vanguard release times and download sizes? Yep, it's that time of the year again: a brand new Call Of Duty to sink our rotting zombie teeth into. And so there are two questions flooding Google's airwaves above all others: when can we start playing Vanguard, and how much storage space do we need in order to install it?
This quick guide will give you the answers to both these questions, with release times for various timezones, and download sizes across all platforms - including the optional high resolution assets pack for PC players.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch the Elden Ring gameplay trailer, complete with laughing NPC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-the-elden-ring-gameplay-stream-here-today-i-sure-hope-the-npcs-laugh</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-the-elden-ring-gameplay-stream-here-today-i-sure-hope-the-npcs-laugh"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:32:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope you've packed your marshmallows folks, as From Software and Bandai Namco have greenlit a 15-minute Elden Ring gameplay stream, due to go live at 2pm GMT/7am PDT. Personally, I feel alive, and a little woozy. What's going to be shown off? Swords, dragons, pots-that-are-boys, who knows. If you're as excited as I am, though, you best bookmark the stream below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Top Ten Best-Selling Games For Wii U, 3DS, Wii And DS (As Of September 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123157</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/the-top-ten-best-selling-games-for-wii-u-3ds-wii-and-ds-as-of-september-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many of these do you own?
We've already seen an updated list of the top ten best-selling Nintendo Switch games, but what about the good old Wii and Wii U, and even the DS and 3DS?
Naturally, sales for games on these older systems aren't what they used to be, but some copies continue to be picked up thanks to digital stores or the odd bit of stock still being available at retail. Most of the totals listed below are still the same as they were this time last year, but some games – most notably the 3DS' Pokémon titles – have increased by tens of thousands over that time frame.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook's BOLT Nearing Mainline LLVM For Optimizing Binaries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BOLT-Nearing-LLVM-Monorepo</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BOLT-Nearing-LLVM-Monorepo"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook's BOLT project for optimizing the performance out of compiled binaries is nearing the point of being added to LLVM's official source tree with its mono repository...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XCOM studio's Marvel superhero game Midnight Suns is delayed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/xcom-studios-marvel-superhero-game-midnight-suns-is-delayed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/xcom-studios-marvel-superhero-game-midnight-suns-is-delayed"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T10:32:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[XCOM studio Firaxis have announced a delay for Marvel's Midnight Suns, their turn-based tactics game in the BAM! BIF! POW! world of Marvel superheroes. Previously due in March 2022, it's now pushed back into the second half of 2022. I say "previously"; the game was only announced two months ago. Sounds like someone had a serious rethink about the state of the project. But if it needs the time, it's good that it's getting the time.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here Are The Nintendo Switch's Ten Best-Selling Games]]></title>
        <id>1847994673</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/here-are-the-nintendo-switchs-ten-best-selling-games-1847994673"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo has just updated its list of the Nintendo Switch’s all-time top selling games. Which is, let’s face it, a two-horse race between Mario Kart and Animal Crossing. But which one crosses the finish line first? Let’s find out. 
The list is for worldwide life-to-date numbers, as of September 30, 2021. These sales…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Today's Animal Crossing Update Adds Not One Froggy Chair, But Six Froggy Chairs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123207</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-todays-animal-crossing-update-adds-not-one-froggy-chair-but-six-froggy-chairs"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What a glorious day.
As you may have already seen, this week's major free update for Animal Crossing: New Horizons has dropped a day early. Why? Who knows... But thanks, Nintendo!
Anyway, while the addition of Brewster, Kapp'n, Gyroids, cooking and more are all very welcome indeed, there's one other important addition now available in-game: Froggy Chair. Yes, the internet meme sensation is back and as a nice surprise, there are multiple designs that you can dot around your home.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy: should you sell Groot or Rocket?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-sell-groot-rocket</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-sell-groot-rocket"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T10:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know whether to sell Groot or Rocket in Guardians Of The Galaxy? After a rather disappointing attempt to capture a monster from the Quarantine Zone, the Guardians Of The Galaxy will incur a large fine from the Nova Corps. In a dire attempt to scrape together some units, you must travel to Seknarf Nine to meet Lady Hellbender, the Monster Queen. When you arrive, you must choose whether to sell Rocket or Groot. The choice you make majorly impacts the next mission of your adventure, so we’ll walk you through the differences between the two.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Reconfirms Release Windows For Major Upcoming Switch Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123151</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/nintendo-reconfirms-release-windows-for-major-upcoming-switch-games"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Breath of the Wild 2 still on track.
As part of Nintendo's latest financial report, the company has published an updated look at its upcoming release schedule.
Below, you'll find a list of Nintendo's major releases planned for the end of 2021 and beyond. The updated info confirms that Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2 is still on track for a release in 2022, as well as other highly anticipated titles like Splatoon 3 and Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope, and that Metroid Prime 4 is still 'TBA'.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Just Updated Super Mario 3D All-Stars Adding N64 Controller Support]]></title>
        <id>1847994650</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-just-updated-super-mario-3d-all-stars-for-swit-1847994650"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo has released a new update for Super Mario 3D All-Stars, ver. 1.1.1, to add support for the Switch’s new Nintendo 64 Controller. This is the first update for the game since November of last year, when Nintendo GameCube controller support was added to Super Mario Sunshine. Not that you can currently buy either…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nginx zahodil podporu NPN, pro vyjednání přechodu na HTTP/2 používá ALPN]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42976</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nginx-zahodil-podporu-npn-pro-vyjednani-prechodu-na-http-2-pouziva-alpn/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T08:48:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili novou verzi webového serveru Nginx s označním 1.21.4. Od této verze je zrušena podpora protokolu NPN (Next Protocol Negotiation), který byl původně vyvinut pro vyjednání přechodu na protokol SPDY. Později jej však nahradil modernější protokol ALPN (Application-Layer Protocol Negotiation).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular 13.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/angular-13.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/angular-13.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T08:42:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 13.0.0 open source webového aplikačního frameworku Angular (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Arm SoC Changes Bring-Up The Snapdragon 690, Other Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Arm-SoC-Platform</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Arm-SoC-Platform"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T08:35:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All of the Arm SoC/platform changes were merged on Wednesday evening for the Linux 5.16 kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 9 Beta se zaměřuje na automatizaci]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42975</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/red-hat-enterprise-linux-rhel-9-beta-se-zameruje-na-automatizaci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T08:26:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Red Hat vydala betaverzi připravované distribuce Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 9. Nová verze staví na jádře 5.14 a je k dispozici pro architektury Intel/AMD64 (x86_64), ARM 64-bit (aarch64), IBM Power LE (ppc64le) a IBM Z (s390×).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3-rc4 Release Led By Many Zink Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-rc4-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-rc4-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T07:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3 as the final feature release for this collection of open-source OpenGL and Vulkan drivers isn't yet ready to go as some blocker bugs persist, but available now is the fourth weekly release candidate...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847989847</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/forza-horizon-5-the-kotaku-review-1847989847"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T07:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The implicit promise of Forza Horizon is in the name. You see something on the horizon, you can drive to it. Skyrim with cars. Far Cry with more cars and no guns. Forza Horizon 5, the latest game in the venerable Xbox racing series, is no more and no less than that promise—just bigger, brighter, and so, so much more…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brewster Is Finally In Animal Crossing: New Horizons, If You Know Where To Look]]></title>
        <id>1847994327</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/brewster-is-finally-in-animal-crossing-new-horizons-i-1847994327"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T05:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a long wait, Animal Crossing’s Brewster has finally arrived in New Horizons slightly ahead of schedule, at least if you know where to find him. Nintendo may have given players a head start on the game’s massive 2.0 update, but the coffee slinging pigeon isn’t hiding in plain sight. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16's Smorgasbord Of Power Management Changes Land]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Power-Management</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Power-Management"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sent in on Tuesday and since merged to the mainline Linux 5.16 code-base were the power management updates and accompanying ACPI and thermal changes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing's 2.0 Patch Adds First Person Camera That Makes The Entire Game Look New]]></title>
        <id>1847993932</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossings-first-person-camera-makes-the-entire-g-1847993932"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T03:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ October direct presentation did mention that the incoming massive update would introduce a new point of view, but if you forgot that was the case, I wouldn’t blame you. There was a lot in there, because this update—which is now live early—is massive. But even knowing it was coming didn’t…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patricia Hernandez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Massive Animal Crossing Update Releases Super Early]]></title>
        <id>1847993755</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/massive-animal-crossing-update-releases-super-early-1847993755"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T02:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been eagerly awaiting Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ impending v2.0 patch, you can breathe a sigh of relief: Nintendo has apparently pushed the massive update live way ahead of its November 5 release date. Most folks were expecting to download it tomorrow night but, nope, Christmas came early.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Hackers Laundered $10 Million On Twitch]]></title>
        <id>1847993263</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/report-hackers-laundered-10-million-on-twitch-1847993263"/>
        <updated>2021-11-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After an investigation into last month’s leaked data, it has been alleged that a group of hackers laundered almost $10 million in illegally-obtained funds by making a ton of tiny donations to Twitch streamers.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh Man, Look At These Death Stranding Dropkicks]]></title>
        <id>1847993301</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/oh-man-look-at-these-death-stranding-dropkicks-1847993301"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T23:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Death Stranding is an objectively beautiful game, though sometimes that beauty isn’t found in its lush environments or character interactions but how players use the tools at their disposal to pull off amazing feats.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amiga 600: setkání s nejmenším z rodiny po třiceti letech]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15720</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/amiga-600-setkani-s-nejmensim-z-rodiny-po-triceti-letech/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T23:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V nové sérii návratů k historické IT technice se podívám na blízkou příbuznou hrdinky série minulé, konkrétně na Amigu 600, mnohými vyzdvihovanou, mnohými zatracovanou. Jak působí dnes a co potřeba k plnému zprovoznění?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Tauchman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operace s daty uloženými v binárních souborech v knihovnách NumPy a Pandas (dokončení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15748</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/operace-s-daty-ulozenymi-v-binarnich-souborech-v-knihovnach-numpy-a-pandas-dokonceni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T23:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Už jsme si ukázali základy práce s daty uloženými v binárních souborech v knihovnách NumPy a Pandas. Jednou z největších předností binárních souborů jsou rychlé přesuny (seek) a namapování obsahu souboru do paměti (mmap).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Sound Ready To Play On AMD VanGogh + Yellow Carp, Continues USB Low-Latency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Sound-Improvements</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Sound-Improvements"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T22:29:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux sound subsystem is seeing some useful and significant additions with the Linux 5.16 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take-Two Cancels Unannounced $53 Million Dollar Game By Hangar 13]]></title>
        <id>1847992907</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/take-two-cancels-unannounced-53-million-dollar-game-by-1847992907"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T22:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take-Two revealed in its earnings call today with investors that it had cancelled a $53 million unannounced project. Sources tell Kotaku that game was intended to be a live service, third-person action game in the vein of Destiny, developed by Hangar 13 called  Volt. The decision to cancel it took some developers at…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Games To Try If You Like Destiny 2]]></title>
        <id>1847992175</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/13-games-to-try-if-you-like-destiny-2-1847992175"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T21:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you love playing Destiny 2, but also appreciate playing other games every once in a while, then welcome: You’re in the right place. And if you actually don’t like playing Destiny 2, but wish you had something similar to get lost in, then you’re in the right place, too.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's 'XCOM' Game Has Already Been Delayed]]></title>
        <id>1847992456</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/marvels-xcom-game-has-already-been-delayed-1847992456"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite having just been announced less than three months ago, Marvel’s Midnight Suns, a tactics role-playing game in the vein of XCOM, has been delayed, developer Firaxis Games announced today. It will now come out in the back half of 2022, pushed out of a previously vague March 2022 window.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibrePCB 0.1.6]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/librepcb-0.1.6</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/librepcb-0.1.6"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T21:22:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po více než roce vývoje od vydání verze 0.1.5 byla vydána nová verze 0.1.6 svobodného multiplatformního softwarového nástroje pro návrh desek plošných spojů (PCB) s názvem LibrePCB. Přehled vlastností a náhledy v aktualizované dokumentaci. Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitHubu pod licencí GPLv3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sioyek 1.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/sioyek-1.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/sioyek-1.0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T20:36:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sioyek je prohlížeč PDF dokumentů, zaměřený na četbu akademických publikací: umožňuje např. zvýrazňování, rychlou navigaci a zobrazování náhledů referencí. Nyní byla vydána verze 1.0.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Publishes October 2021 Update For Its Linux Distribution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Microsoft-CBL-Mariner-Oct-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Microsoft-CBL-Mariner-Oct-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T19:21:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft today released its monthly update to CBL-Mariner, its internal Linux distribution that is used for a variety of purposes at the Windows company...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Radeon Graphics Driver "AMDGPU" Ported To DragonFlyBSD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Ported-DragonFlyBSD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Ported-DragonFlyBSD"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T17:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The "AMDGPU" kernel graphics driver has been ported and pulled into the DragonFlyBSD operating system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SELinux/LSM/Smack Controls + Auditing For IO_uring Comes With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SELinux-IO_uring-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SELinux-IO_uring-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to IO_uring improvements in Linux 5.16 itself, the Security Enhanced Linux "SELinux" patches for this new kernel cycle bring controls and auditing around IO_uring...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4 Scenarios]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-scenarios</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-scenarios"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T15:32:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do Scenarios work in The Sims 4? There have been fan-made Sims challenges for as long as there have been Sims games, but now the makers of The Sims 4 have introduced Scenarios into official gameplay.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Enterprise Linux 9.0 Beta Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-RHEL9-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-RHEL9-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T15:31:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat today announced the first public beta of the upcoming Red Hat Enterprise Linux 9.0...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 dostane hotovou podporu Intel Alder Lake GPU včetně PXP]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42974</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-5-16-dostane-hotovou-podporu-intel-alder-lake-gpu-vcetne-pxp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T15:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podpora čerstvě uvedených procesorů Intel Alder Lake-S, tedy například Core i9–12900K, je pro Linux 5.16 hotova a prohlášena za stabilní. Vedle samotných CPU dostává příští verze jádra též podporu Protected Xe Path (PXP), což umožní běh video dat chráněnou cestou. Mizí potřeba používat parametr force_probe a podpora GPU tak bude v Linuxu 5.16 automaticky zapnutá. V rámci větve DRM-Next tak již proběhl veškerý potřebný vývoj.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Enterprise Linux 9 Beta]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/red-hat-enterprise-linux-9-beta</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/red-hat-enterprise-linux-9-beta"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T15:27:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána beta verze Red Hat Enterprise Linuxu 9. Přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu a v poznámkách k vydání.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy disabler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-disabler</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-disabler"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T15:25:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know whether you should buy the Disabler in Guardians Of The Galaxy? Whilst on Knowhere during Chapter 6, you can look around and partake in a bit of shopping. Whilst looking between the various stalls, you will find a merchant who offers to sell you a disabler that will supposedly remove the Nova Corps tracker from your ship. This would mean you don’t need to pay the Nova Corps fine that you incurred earlier in Chapter 2. However, Knowhere is a seedy place, and it’s hard to be certain whether you might get conned.
This guide will explain whether you should buy the disabler on Knowhere in Guardians Of The Galaxy, so that you can avoid any scams.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption is the first card game that actually makes me feel like I'm playing cards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-is-the-first-card-game-that-actually-makes-me-feel-like-im-playing-cards</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-is-the-first-card-game-that-actually-makes-me-feel-like-im-playing-cards"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption is good, very good. I mean, we've slapped a Bestest Best badge on it, like one of its in-game sigils. What effect does it have? Play the game and you'll quickly realise it does things games aren't supposed to do. Most notably, for me at least, Inscryption makes me feel like I'm actually playing a proper card game; that feeling of being present at a table, slapping cards down on its hard surface. I hadn't realised how crucial this was to my enjoyment of CCGs, until now.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you get 100% collectables? Psychonauts 2 just made that easier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/do-you-get-100-collectables-psychonauts-2-just-made-that-easier</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/do-you-get-100-collectables-psychonauts-2-just-made-that-easier"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T14:56:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reader dear, I have to ask: do you try to get 100% collectables in games? Someone must, because games still have them. But I certainly don't, and I don't think I've spoken about the subject with anyone who does. So, seeing as Psychonauts 2 has now released a patch with new features to help players collect every little doodad and tick off achievements, I want to ask: do you do this? Will you? Please tell me about it!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Thoma build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-thoma-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-thoma-build"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T14:21:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Thoma build in Genshin Impact? As the chief retainer of Inazuma’s Kamisato Clan, Mondstadt native Thoma is always down to lend a helping hand, even aiding the player in their arrival to Inazuma. It makes sense, then, that he’s a support and sub-DPS character similar to Zhongli.
This guide will show you how to create the best Thoma build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Thoma, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Sucrose build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-sucrose-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-sucrose-build"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T14:14:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Sucrose build in Genshin Impact? Anemo Catalyst user Sucrose is a bio-alchemist and the shy assistant of Albedo. Despite her timid personality, Anemo Catalyst user Sucrose is definitely not afraid to use her alchemical abilities in battle and serves as a 4-star substitute for 5-star Anemo characters like Venti and Kazuha — essentially, she’s a sub-DPS great at crowd control and applying the Swirl reaction.
This guide will show you how to create the best Sucrose build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Sucrose, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demon Turf review: new Beebz on the block]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/demon-turf-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/demon-turf-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You'd think being 1000 years old would earn you some respect, but in Demon Turf, that means you're still a child. Admittedly, it makes for an intriguing premise in this tale of conquest and demonic shakedowns, but don't be fooled. While its core systems take inspiration from 3D platformers of the N64 era, Demon Turf isn’t another Banjo Kazooie successor like publisher Playtonic's Yooka-Laylee. You’ll find those familiar cliches, sure, but there’s something great about Fabraz’s latest effort that goes beyond its unique visuals.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henry Stockdale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Continues Work On Flutter+Dart Written Firmware-Updater Utility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-Firmware-Updater-WIP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-Firmware-Updater-WIP"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with the work-in-progress new Ubuntu desktop installer, another GUI project being pursued by Canonical going into the Ubuntu 22.04 LTS cycle is the "firmware-updater" as a firmware updating GUI solution written in the Flutter toolkit and Dart...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Octave 6.4.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/gnu-octave-6.4.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/gnu-octave-6.4.0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T12:55:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová stabilní verze 6.4.0 svobodného softwaru a vysokoúrovňového programovacího jazyka pro numerické výpočty GNU Octave (Wikipedie). K dispozici bude také na Flathubu a Snapcraftu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreELEC (Matrix) 10.0.1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/libreelec-matrix-10.0.1</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/libreelec-matrix-10.0.1"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T12:37:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze 10.0.1, tj. první opravné vydání verze 10.0.0, minimalistické linuxové distribuce (JeOS, Just enough Operating System) pro Kodi (dříve XBMC) a multimediálního centra LibreELEC (Libre Embedded Linux Entertainment Center). Jedná se o fork linuxové distribuce OpenELEC (Open Embedded Linux Entertainment Center). LibreELEC 10.0.1 přichází s Kodi "Matrix" 19.3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 and Diablo 4 are both delayed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-and-diablo-4-are-both-delayed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-and-diablo-4-are-both-delayed"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T12:12:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard's monster-clicker Diablo IV and face-shooter Overwatch 2 have both been delayed, pushing their uncertain launches even further into the future. Blizzard had never stated a release date for either game anyway, we only had a vague hint that they didn't expect to launch them in 2021. Now, maybe 2023 at earliest? 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard co-lead Jen Oneal steps down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blizzard-co-lead-jen-oneal-steps-down</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blizzard-co-lead-jen-oneal-steps-down"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T12:02:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jen Oneal is stepping down as co-lead of Blizzard Entertainment, just three months after she took the position. Since J. Allen Brack left the company in August, Oneal had been in charge of the studio with Mike Ybarra, who'll now take the lead on his own. Oneal claims she's not leaving because she's "without hope for Blizzard", but wants to "do more to have games and diversity intersect, and hopefully make a broader industry impact that will benefit Blizzard (and other studios) as well."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy game collectibles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-collectibles</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-collectibles"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T11:45:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to get all of the Guardians Of The Galaxy game collectibles? On your journey to save the galaxy, you can find lots of trinkets and collectibles which are often hidden slightly off the main path. If you find these collectibles, you can take them back to the Milano and unlock new conversations with the other Guardians, which reveal details about their past, as well as other lore from across the Marvel universe.
This guide will cover how to find all Guardians Of The Galaxy game collectibles, so that you can stop worrying about missing something important on your playthrough.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy foggy cave]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-foggy-cave</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-foggy-cave"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T11:44:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to escape the foggy cave in Guardians Of The Galaxy? After trying to convince the Worldmind to fight Raker and proceeding into chapter 10, Mantis will join the team to help you save Drax, who has fallen victim to Grand Unifier Raker’s Promise. She will lead you into a mysterious cave that tries to trap any who enter. As you explore, you’ll discover two particular puzzles that require some out of the box thinking to proceed.
This guide will cover everything you need to know to escape the foggy cave in Guardians Of The Galaxy.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se používat Linux správně a bezpečně (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40574</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-pouzivat-linux-spravne-a-bezpecne-online-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T11:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxových systémů přibývá, každý den se spouštějí nové servery a někdo se o ně musí starat. To znamená spoustu různých dovedností specifických právě pro linuxové prostředí. Jak to zprovoznit, kudy bezpečně dovnitř, co tam najdeme, jak se o to postaráme a jak to nastavíme nebo rozšíříme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Graphics Drivers: Alder Lake S Is Stable, Initial DG2, AMD DP 2.0 + USB4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Graphics-Drivers</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Graphics-Drivers"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All of the DRM (Direct Rendering Manager) kernel graphics/display driver updates were submitted and already merged for the very exciting Linux 5.16 kernel cycle. There is a lot of good stuff this round especially when it comes to the open-source Intel and AMD Radeon drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice Of Cards: The Isle Dragon Roars review: a JRPG in card game cosplay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voice-of-cards-the-isle-dragon-roars-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voice-of-cards-the-isle-dragon-roars-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Card games are all the rage these days, so much so that even Yoko Taro of Nier: Automata fame is getting in on the action. Alas, if you’re expecting a similarly galaxy brain take on tabletop RPGs here, you’re going to be disappointed. Despite the creative minds behind it (Automata’s producer Yosuke Saito and composer Keiichi Okabe are also on board), Voice Of Cards: The Isle Dragon Roars is a decidedly simple role playing affair where its titular cards are nothing more than a fancy visual layer papering over a by-the-book tale of dungeons and, yes, a dragon. Inscryption this ain’t.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Beta Adds VA-API Acceleration For Remote Play]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Beta-VA-API-Remote-Play</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Beta-VA-API-Remote-Play"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T10:07:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those enjoying Steam Remote Play in-home streaming functionality, the latest Steam client beta now supports making use of the Video Acceleration API for encoding...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More ASRock & ASUS Motherboards Will Have Working Sensors With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-HWMON</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-HWMON"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T09:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hardware monitoring "HWMON" subsystem updates have landed in the Linux 5.16 kernel and with this comes sensor support for some additional ASRock and ASUS motherboards...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel DG2/Alchemist Soon To See Big Performance Boost With Mesa Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DG2-Pixel-Perf-Boost-Mesa</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DG2-Pixel-Perf-Boost-Mesa"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T08:56:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A set of patches were posted this past week by Intel open-source driver engineer Francisco Jerez with pixel pipeline optimizations that help all DG2/Alchemist platforms with double digit percentage improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EROFS With LZMA/MicroLZMA, XFS Footprint Improvements Sent In For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-XFS-EROFS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-XFS-EROFS"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T08:46:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with the Btrfs updates, other Linux file-systems have also been sending in their improvements destined for the Linux 5.16 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux už běží na stroji s Apple M1 Pro]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42973</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-uz-bezi-na-stroji-s-apple-m1-pro/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T07:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nové Macbooky s vyššími verzemi procesorů Apple M1 Pro a M1 Max již mají v rukou vývojáři z Asahi Linuxu. Hector Martin nyní informuje, že se na stroji s M1 Pro již podařilo nastartovat Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Khronos Group představuje API ANARI 1.0 pro škálovatelné 3D vizualizace]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42972</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/khronos-group-predstavuje-api-anari-1-0-pro-skalovatelne-3d-vizualizace/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T07:26:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ANARI je novým aplikačním rozhraním z dílen Khronos Group. Jde o bezplatné API, které by se mohlo stát příštím průmyslovým standardem v oblasti 3D vizualizací dat a jejich analytického renderování.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Number Of System76 Laptop Coreboot Ports Reach Mainline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=System76-More-Coreboot-Mainline</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=System76-More-Coreboot-Mainline"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number of System76 laptops saw their Coreboot open-source firmware ports merged to the mainline code-base today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Painbow Award]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2537/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2537/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AstriCon 2021 a Asterisk 19.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/astricon-2021-a-asterisk-19.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/astricon-2021-a-asterisk-19.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-03T00:48:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes a zítra probíhá online konference AstriCon 2021, tj. konference vývojářů a uživatelů svobodné softwarové implementace telefonní ústředny (PBX) Asterisk (Wikipedie). Při této příležitosti byl vydán Asterisk ve verzi 19.0.0.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch has added a category for livestreams of animals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-has-added-a-category-for-livestreams-of-animals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-has-added-a-category-for-livestreams-of-animals"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T23:44:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There's a segment in a 2003 episode of radio series This American Life from 2003, in which a man named Dan Fitzsimons talks about a cable television channel he tried to launch in the '90s. It was the "Puppy Channel". A 24/7 broadcast of nothing but puppies. 

At the time, no cable provider liked the idea enough to make it happen, but I think about the story a lot. I think about it on days like today, on which Twitch has just introduced a new "Animals, Aquariums, and Zoos" category to the livestreaming platform.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends Escape update is live now, including new hero and map]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-escape-update-is-live-now-including-new-hero-ash-and-new-map-storm-point</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-escape-update-is-live-now-including-new-hero-ash-and-new-map-storm-point"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T23:07:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Storm Point. It's a place where dreams come true," says a character at the end of Apex Legends' Escape mode trailer. Given the two preceding minutes, presumably the dreams have to involve being fired into the sky and then stabbing a bunch of dudes.

Apex Legends' new season, including Storm Point map and new character Ash, are all live now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jednotkové testování v PHP s knihovnou PHPUnit]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15740</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/jednotkove-testovani-v-php-s-knihovnou-phpunit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T23:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V první části budou vysvětleny základní pojmy včetně výběru knihovny PHPUnit.
Dozvíme se jaké jsou základní části jednotkového testu, jak začlenit testy do prostředí PhpStorm a jak pracovat s výsledky testů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Herout)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (3. 11. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15745</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-3-11-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T23:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes si představíme databázového klienta pro PostgreSQL, vytvoříme lokální certifikační autoritu, poohlédneme se po dalším git klientovi a nakonec se vypořádáme s příliš aktivní myší.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jiří Sluka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Can Boot On Apple's M1 Pro But More Work Remains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Apple-M1-Pro-Boots</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Apple-M1-Pro-Boots"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T22:37:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month Apple announced the M1 Pro and M1 Max SoCs while already the very latest Linux patches originally written for the Apple M1 that launched last year paired with some small changes is allowing the open-source platform to boot on the M1 Pro MacBook...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Avengers has removed the paid XP boosters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-avengers-has-removed-the-paid-xp-boosters</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-avengers-has-removed-the-paid-xp-boosters"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T22:27:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Avengers came to Xbox Game Pass at the end of September. A week later, Square Enix added paid, consumable XP boosters to its in-game store, to much predictable uproar from its players.

Today, Square Enix announced that they were removing the boosters, while apologising "for not responding sooner" to players' concerns.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow Tactics' Aiko's Choice expansion will emerge December 6th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-tactics-aikos-choice-expansion-will-emerge-december-6th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-tactics-aikos-choice-expansion-will-emerge-december-6th"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T21:50:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier today, Matthew offered up his thoughts on Aiko's Choice, the standalone expansion for ninja stealth 'em up Shadow Tactics: Blades Of The Shogun. In a synchronised attack, publishers Daedalic also spat out the release date: December 6th.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard gets a PC trailer and final system requirements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-gets-a-pc-trailer-and-final-system-requirements</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-gets-a-pc-trailer-and-final-system-requirements"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T21:27:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision have squirted out another Call Of Duty: Vanguard trailer, but the drippings are more specifically relevant to us this time. It's the game's "PC trailer", and it appears alongside a blog post offering more detail on download sizes, specs and so on.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Bowser souhlasí s odškodněním 4,5 miliónů dolarů pro Nintendo]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42971</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gary-bowser-souhlasi-s-odskodnenim-4-5-milionu-dolaru-pro-nintendo/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T19:08:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Bowser je údajným členem hackerské skupiny Team-Xecuter, která vyvíjí a prodává nástroje na obcházení ochran herních konzolí, v poslední době hlavně pro Nintendo Switch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Smrž)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Begins Landing Hyper-V Isolation VM Support In Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Hyper-V-Isolation-VM-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Hyper-V-Isolation-VM-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T19:02:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has submitted their set of Hyper-V hypervisor updates today for the Linux 5.16 merge window. This time around it's noteworthy with the initial enablement work around Hyper-V "Isolation VM" support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cluster-Aware Scheduling Lands In Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Sched-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Sched-Core"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T18:10:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The "sched/core" scheduler updates landed on Monday into the Linux 5.16 kernel. Notable this pull request is the cluster-aware scheduling support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft is now on Xbox Game Pass For PC in both Java and Bedrock forms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-is-now-on-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-both-java-and-bedrock-forms</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-is-now-on-xbox-game-pass-for-pc-in-both-java-and-bedrock-forms"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T17:12:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yeah yeah Xbox Game Pass For PC offers a load of great games at a suspiciously low price, but what about Microsoft's actually big games? Finally, the big'un has arrived: Minecraft. Both the original Java and cross-platform Bedrock versions of Minecraft arrived on Microsoft's subscription service today, packaged into a unified launcher. This comes ahead of plans to give all PC Minecrafters access to both versions next year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Genshin Impact banner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-banners</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-banners"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T15:01:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When does Hu Tao's rerun banner become available in Genshin Impact? Genshin Impact works on a gacha system, where players can spend various in-game and real-world currencies to Wish on a character's banner in the hopes of obtaining a playable version of them.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow Tactics: Aiko's Choice is shaping into a small, but sublime slice of ninja fun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-tactics-aikos-choice-is-shaping-into-a-small-but-sublime-slice-of-ninja-fun</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-tactics-aikos-choice-is-shaping-into-a-small-but-sublime-slice-of-ninja-fun"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In true Shadow Tactics fashion, here’s an expansion no one saw coming. Aiko’s Choice is a miniature campaign extension to 2016’s real-time tactics wonder. A standalone title, but one that slots into the original game’s main story. It feels like a DLC package that should have been released closer to the original, but I’m not going to drag developers Mimimi for tardiness - after all, this is a game where it takes me upwards of three hours to creep around a single map. Nothing about Shadow Tactics is rushed.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94 přináší EGL na Linuxu, vylepšenou podporu macOS i Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42970</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-94-prinasi-egl-na-linuxu-vylepsenou-podporu-macos-i-windows-11/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T14:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Devadesát-čtyřka Firefoxu přináší po omezenou dobu dostupných 6 barevných vzhledů (s dodatkem, že na Beta verzi používalo upravená barevná témata celých 32 % uživatelů). Na macOS je podporován režim s nízkou spotřebou při přehrávání videí na YouTube či Twitchi.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vydán Fedora Linux 35 s GNOME 41]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42969</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vydan-fedora-linux-35-s-gnome-41/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T14:07:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po dílčích odkladech vyšla finální Fedora 35, a to jak Fedora Workstation 35, tak Fedora Server 35. Novinek je nemálo, najdeme zde mimo jiné GNOME 41, nejnovější XWaylandu s podporou Nvidia GPU běžících na proprietárním ovladači a mnoho dalších aktualizací.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riders Republic review: a free roaming extreme sports theme park]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T14:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Riders Republic is a multiplayer open world sports game developed by Ubisoft Annecy, in which every single character talks like they’re your mum’s new boyfriend after they find a bong in your sock drawer. And, hey, like, we get it, y’know, we all like to “hang loose” on Tik Tok sometimes, but – at this point Gareth the 43-year-old divorcé grabs a chair, spins it 180 degrees and sits on it in one smooth motion – dope just isn’t on fleek, fam.
Insufferable cutscenes aside, this is a thrilling downhill racing simulator in which you, a new arrival to a vast landscape of snowy peaks, scorched desert badlands, towering forests and rain-lashed mud flats, must repeatedly hurl yourself down the side of a mountain faster or more stylishly than your opponents. The world is a compressed version of California with all of the San Franciscos taken out, leaving just a bizarre population of baggy jeans wearing Urban Dictionary acolytes, and a vast interconnected series of freely roamable tracks and wilderness littered with activities to complete and landmarks to discover.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Hogarty</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TDE R14.0.11 vylepšuje podporu HiDPI]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42968</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/tde-r14-0-11-vylepsuje-podporu-hidpi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T13:42:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová verze desktopového prostředí Trinity Desktop Environment, navazujícího na někdejší slávu KDE 3.x, přináší několik málo novinek. Tvůrci se soustředili napríklad na lepší běh s displeji s vysokou hodnotou dpi. Dále došlo na nové styly TWin (SUSE2 a DeKorator) a nové aplikace.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Linux 35 Released As Another Exciting, Feature-Packed Update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-35-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-35-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T13:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 35 is now officially available today as the latest major release of this Linux distribution developed by Red Hat and the open-source community. Fedora 35 is another very rich feature update at the forefront of Linux innovations from servers to the desktop...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Begins Offering Ubuntu Images Optimized For Intel CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-Intel-IoT-Optimized</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-Intel-IoT-Optimized"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T13:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical has begun publishing Ubuntu install images that are optimized for use on next-generation Intel IoT platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94.0 Released With Linux Build Using EGL For Better Performance, Power Savings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-94.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-94.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T13:22:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94.0 is now available and for a change it's quite exciting on the Linux front...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Khronos Prepares ANARI 1.0 API For Scalable 3D Data Visualization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Khronos-ANARI-1.0-Provisional</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Khronos-ANARI-1.0-Provisional"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Khronos Group this morning is rolling out the provisional specification for ANARI 1.0, its newest royalty-free, industry-standard API...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google dočasně ztrojnásobil odměnu za nalezení chyby v linuxovém jádře]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42967</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/google-docasne-ztrojnasobil-odmenu-za-nalezeni-chyby-v-linuxovem-jadre/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T12:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google zveřejnil speciální tříměsíční akci na lov bezpečnostních chyb v linuxovém jádře. Během této doby také ztrojnásobil odměnu pro případné úspěšné lovce, kteří si tak mohou přijít až na 50 337 dolarů, tedy více než milion českých korun. Samozřejmě jen za určitých a velmi konkrétně definovaných podmínek.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have a chill time moving house in Unpacking, out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/have-a-chill-time-moving-house-in-unpacking-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/have-a-chill-time-moving-house-in-unpacking-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T12:21:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I first heard about it, I didn't think Unpacking would appeal to me. Released today, it's a chill game about unpacking moving boxes, unloading all the items from someone's life into their new home. I've never liked unpacking in real life, it feels stressful and annoying trying to find space for all my stuff. But I'm starting to think that Unpacking (the game) might make me feel better about it. Perhaps next time I move house, I should go into it with the energy of this relaxed puzzler. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This mod lets you fight Crusader Kings 3 battles inside Mount & Blade 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mod-lets-you-fight-crusader-kings-3-battles-inside-mount-blade-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mod-lets-you-fight-crusader-kings-3-battles-inside-mount-blade-2"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T11:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Crusader Kings 3 is a great simulation of medieval political jostling, when this degenerate into war, it lacks a little pizzaz. Enter Crusader Blade, a new mod which lets you fight CK3 battles inside Mount & Blade II: Bannerlord. When it's time to rumble in CK3, it'll generate a Bannerlord battle based on your armies for you to fight in-person, then transfer the results back into CK3. Immensely impressive.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stardew Valley dev's next game Haunted Chocolatier will be more combat-focused]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stardew-valley-devs-next-game-haunted-chocolatier-will-be-more-combat-focused</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stardew-valley-devs-next-game-haunted-chocolatier-will-be-more-combat-focused"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T11:46:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago, Stardew Valley creator Eric "ConcernedApe" Barone revealed his next game, Haunted Chocolatier. It's about opening a chocolate shop staffed by ghosts, and you'll be able to venture out into fantastical places to collect ingredients. Honestly, it's exactly what I'd want from a Stardew follow-up. Barone says Haunted Chocolatier will have "a greater focus on combat" than Stardew, and has provided some detail on how the chocolate game's battles will work. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Echo Generation review: a spooky grab bag of familiar retro tropes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/echo-generation-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/echo-generation-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like anyone, I went into Echo Generation knowing it would be riding on Stranger Things’ coattails. With its young cast and retro, small town setting, this is a game that definitely falls into that familiar “gang of boys plus maybe someone’s girlfriend going on an occult adventure” vein of 80s nostalgia fests like The Goonies and It. But the question was, would it be an inspired homage to the Upside Down, or a cash grab with a voxel paint job designed to lure in 'the youth'? The answer, sadly, is neither.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Armstrong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Btrfs With Linux 5.16 Seeing More Performance Optimizations, NVMe ZNS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Btrfs-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Btrfs-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T11:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Btrfs file-system continues seeing new performance optimizations and other work, thanks in part to the renewed interest around the file-system with Fedora Workstation continuing to use it by default along with openSUSE and other Linux distributions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.2.197 Released With Dynamic Rendering Extension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-1.2.197-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-1.2.197-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T11:02:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.2.197 is out with a variety of documentation updates, clarifications to the specification, and other work. Plus there is one new extension this time around...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Razor build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-razor-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-razor-build"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T10:41:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Razor build in Genshin Impact? Raised by wolves and possessing a strong will to defend his clan, it’s no surprise that Electro Claymore Razor is a fierce fighter. He’s one of the best 4-stars in the game, and if you’re lucky enough to pull him at a low Adventure Rank, he’ll be able to carry you all the way to AR 55 thanks to the strong Physical DMG that makes him a great main DPS.
This guide will show you how to create the best Razor build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Razor, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy outfits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-outfits</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-outfits"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T10:35:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to get every outfit in Guardians Of The Galaxy? Star-Lord loves to look stylish, so there are plenty of outfits to collect in Guardians Of The Galaxy. Each Guardian has their own set of outfits, each taken from different Guardians storylines from the comics and movies. They're often hidden in secret passages, just like collectibles, so you might struggle to find them if you're focusing on the main story.
This guide will cover where to get every outfit in Guardians Of The Galaxy, so that you can relax and enjoy the story whilst knowing that you won't miss any costumes. You won't find outfits in every chapter, so don't panic when you notice some are missing. Below, we've listed every chapter in which you can find outfits.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World turns off all "wealth transfers" to stop gold duplication exploit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-turns-off-all-wealth-transfers-to-stop-gold-duplication-exploit</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-turns-off-all-wealth-transfers-to-stop-gold-duplication-exploit"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:29:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World has temporarily disabled "all forms of wealth transfers" due to an exploit that allows players to duplicate gold. In a post on the game's forum, a community manager warned that punishments would be served to players who used the exploit.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oslava 55 let od vzniku první implementace jazyka APL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15741</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/oslava-55-let-od-vzniku-prvni-implementace-programovaciho-jazyka-apl/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před 55 lety, tedy v listopadu 1966, byla vydána první verze programovacího jazyka APL. Jednalo se o přelomový jazyk, který byl založen na (tehdy) nové notaci zápisu matematických operací vymyšlenou Kennethem E. Iversonem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knot DNS: zónové transfery aneb přenos zón mezi servery]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15739</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/knot-dns-zonove-transfery-aneb-prenos-zon-mezi-servery/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V úvodním dílu jsme si zprovoznili automatickou synchronizaci zóny na sekundárním serveru. Dnes si ukážeme, jaké jsou další možnosti nastavení zónových transferů a co je jejich obsahem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Daniel Salzman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPV 0.34 umožňuje přepínání výstupu za běhu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42966</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mpv-0-34-umoznuje-prepinani-vystupu-za-behu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová verze multimediálního přehrávače MPV, jehož původ sahá až k MPlayeru. Přináší některé nové přepínače pro příkazovou řádku a také vylepšené vlastnosti. Například je přehrávač nyní schopen přepínat za běhu back-end výstupu videa a má vylepšenou podporu Waylandu (dotykové ovládání).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5 and Football Manager 2022 head to Xbox Game Pass in November]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-and-football-manager-2022-head-to-xbox-game-pass-in-november</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-and-football-manager-2022-head-to-xbox-game-pass-in-november"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:56:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost all of the games I'm interested in playing this November will launch on Xbox Game Pass. Microsoft's subscription service on PC will see the arrival of Forza Horizon 5, Football Manager 2022 and Unpacking.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox's three-day outage prompted by "subtle bug"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/robloxs-three-day-outage-prompted-by-subtle-bug</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/robloxs-three-day-outage-prompted-by-subtle-bug"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox is back online after an extended outage which lasted three days. In a post on the Roblox site, Roblox CEO David Baszucki wrote that the outage was caused by "a combination of several factors."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft want to be "key players" in blockchain gaming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-want-to-be-key-players-in-blockchain-gaming</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-want-to-be-key-players-in-blockchain-gaming"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T21:47:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not content with pivoting to free-to-play games that their audience doesn't want, Ubisoft also want to be one of the "key players" in blockchain gaming according to CEO Yves Guillemot. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aplikace eRouška končí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42965</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/aplikace-erouska-konci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:27:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aplikace ministerstva zdravotnictví pro mobilní zařízení s Androidem a iOS eRouška, která rok pomáhala pomocí Exposure Notification API trasovat kontakty s COVID-19 pozitivními lidmi, ode dneška končí. A to i přes to, že v současnosti počet COVID-19 pozitivních případů opět roste.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What a fool! I've only just realised glowing PC parts are secretly meant to be Christmas lights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-a-fool-ive-only-just-realised-glowing-pc-parts-are-secretly-meant-to-be-christmas-lights</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-a-fool-ive-only-just-realised-glowing-pc-parts-are-secretly-meant-to-be-christmas-lights"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:21:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Halloween behind us, it's time to ask: is the 1st of November too early to put up Christmas lights? Is it a grim sign of ravenous consumerism, or a welcome respite from the watching the year die slowly and painfully in its final months? As I untangled my strings of LED lights this morning, I realised that PC gaming is the most Christmassy of gamings. The colourful LEDs people cram into their PC's every orifice and pore aren't just any decoration, they're Christmas lights. That's their purpose. It always has been. Christmas is year-round for PC gamers. So here it is: merry Christmas.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The End Of Dyeus is built on the joy of discovery]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-end-of-dyeus-is-built-on-the-joy-of-discovery</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-end-of-dyeus-is-built-on-the-joy-of-discovery"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I almost don't want to tell you what The End Of Dyeus is. Surprise and discovery are among the things I enjoy most in games, and they're too often undermined in the modern age. Damned kids, with your wikis and your hashed tags. It's a first person fighting and exploration game that drops you in a pastoral fantasy world with no instruction beyond "find Dyeus" and some straightforward control explainers. The only thing I dislike is that I have no idea how to pronounce it, dramatically limiting my pun options.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[True horror is the fridge being left open in Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/true-horror-is-the-fridge-being-left-open-in-marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/true-horror-is-the-fridge-being-left-open-in-marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:49:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spooky season might be behind us now, but man, it’s still pretty scary out there. My inbox sits at 576 unread emails, and in another tab I’m browsing heated clothes airers; things that I now realise are frighteningly expensive. But it’s not just mundane things in real life that give me goosebumps, it now extends to virtual white goods as well.
Right, so, there’s this fridge in Marvel’s Guardians Of The Galaxy and no matter how many times I close it, it won’t stay shut. At first it was funny, but it’s since morphed from a sly chuckle to a howl of agony. My relationship with the game is like that thing Yoda from Star Wars says, “Fear leads to the Dark Side”. Well, I’m almost there, let me tell you.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi a Arduino kontroluje používání blinkrů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42964</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-a-arduino-kontroluje-pouzivani-blinkru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:44:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marc Radinovic vytvořil zařízení, které kontroluje řidiče, jestli při zatáčení používá blinkry. Senzorem jsou dva Arduino Nano 33 BLE moduly. Používá se jejich vestavěný akcelerometr ke zjištění polohy volantu a páčky blinkrů. Senzory pomocí BLE komunikují s Arduino UNO WiFi deskou. Ta je sériově pomocí USB propojena s Raspberry Pi 4.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird West is a smooth, smooth ride through a rough, rough place]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weird-west-is-a-smooth-smooth-ride-through-a-rough-rough-place</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weird-west-is-a-smooth-smooth-ride-through-a-rough-rough-place"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even though I’ve been dead excited about Weird West since its announcement last summer, when the time finally came for me to play a preview build last week, I found myself unusually hesitant. Primarily, this was because I loved the game’s concept so much (“What if Dishonored and Desperadoes III had a rooting tooting baby, then let it watch way too many horror movies?”), that I didn’t really want to face the possibility that developers WolfEye Studios might have fallen short on it. But more than that, I was worried I’d have to… well, make an effort.


For whatever reason, my enthusiasm to start new games has been taking one of its periodic dips over the last month or so, leaving me in the comforting arms of old favourites I can play on autopilot. Time and time again, I’ll get right to the point of hitting play on something, before convincing myself - completely unreasonably - that it’ll probably be a load of hassle for moderate reward. And however promising a sprawling, top-down immersive sim set in a world of haunted stetsons sounded, I was certain it would involve a lot of fiddling about with inventories, reading long screeds of text, and going on sidequests.


I’m delighted to say, however, that I was completely wrong. Because while Weird West does involve all those things (and features even more emergent complexity than the hefty dose I’d anticipated, to boot) I have not had a smoother time getting into a game in a long while. The build I played only featured one of the game’s five character campaigns, admittedly. But unless the other four are all set in a Tesco car park or something, I can heartily recommend it to you.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nate Crowley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 PC trailer shows off DLSS and ray tracing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-pc-trailer-shows-off-dlss-and-ray-tracing</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-pc-trailer-shows-off-dlss-and-ray-tracing"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T14:24:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 has a new trailer ahead of its November 19th release, and this one is aimed directly at us PC folk. While the action itself is more of the near-future mega-bangs you’ve probably seen in previous teasers (or, indeed, the open beta), it’s all in service of demonstrating the PC-exclusive features: chiefly ray tracing, Nvidia DLSS and Nvidia Reflex support.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dark Pictures Anthology will end first season in a Murder Castle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-will-end-first-season-in-a-murder-castle</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-will-end-first-season-in-a-murder-castle"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:19:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've already finished House Of Ashes, you'll have seen a wee trailer revealing that the next part of The Dark Pictures Anthology will be the "season one finale", named The Devil In Me. Bandai Namco have since publicly announced the next game in Supermassive's interactive horror story series, explaining a bit more of what's going on with the animatronic corpse. Bad news for would-be survivors: it's set in a replica of the infamous 'Murder Castle', a hotel built with traps and torture chambers by American serial killer H. H. Holmes.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Právě vydané jádro 5.15 bude LTS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42963</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/prave-vydane-jadro-5-15-bude-lts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:16:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera vydané jádro 5.15 bude LTS, tedy bude mít dlouhou podporu, jak dnes rozhodl Greg Kroah-Hartman. Podpora je zatím plánována na dva roky, ale podpora může být prodloužena, pokud dostatek uživatelů a společností projeví zájem a budou ochotni testovat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valorant's new agent Chamber spawns snazzy guns for himself]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-new-agent-chamber-spawns-snazzy-guns-for-himself</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-new-agent-chamber-spawns-snazzy-guns-for-himself"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:38:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The reason I enjoy Riot's FPS Valorant so much is because it has an excellent mixture of fun abilities and tactical gunplay, which is why I'm not sure what to make of its new character. Chamber is a French weapons designer who's set to arrive in the game's next Act on November 16th, and his abilities mostly involve spawning weapons. Not weapons you can buy normally in-game, but special weapons that he's made himself. Somehow, this feels like cheating.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 early access review: a bumpy start]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-early-access-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-early-access-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope you like animosity. Darkest Dungeon 2 will eat your eyes and call you selfish for wanting them back. The ferocity with which it treats its players shouldn’t be a surprise to anyone who clawed their way through the crypts of the first Darkest Dungeon, a turn-based homage to Lovecraft and slow-acting poison. It especially won’t surprise anyone who bled their way through the early access version of that game, either. A lot of the difficulty and madness in the sequel comes not from the dangerous creatures along its roguelike turnpike, but from the roughly shorn design of a road trip yet to be completed. This is a faithfully despondent, sometimes frustrating journey of attrition, decay and distrust. A journey you should maybe put off until the wobblesome wagon has all its wheels tightened.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AGDQ 2022 lineup includes blindfolded Sekiro speedrun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/agdq-2022-lineup-includes-blindfolded-sekiro-speedrun</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/agdq-2022-lineup-includes-blindfolded-sekiro-speedrun"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:27:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The clocks have gone back and the cold is creeping in, so now it's time for me to get too excited too early for the winter speedrunning event Awesome Games Done Quick. While it's too early for the full schedule right now, organisers have revealed the current list of accepted games, and there are already some absolute belters. A race to beat every Dark Souls boss and Deathloop's first GDQ outing are amongst the highlights. But the one I'm most looking forward to is a blindfolded Sekiro run. I couldn't finish that game even using my eyes.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Nemáte Windows 11? Vezměte si svůj licenční kód za 12 eur]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-nemate-windows-11-vezmete-si-svuj-licencni-kod-za-12-eur</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-nemate-windows-11-vezmete-si-svuj-licencni-kod-za-12-eur"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kupte doživotní licenci Windows 11 nebo Windows 10 a další software na GoodOffer24.com. Můžete si vybrat z nabízených bundlů, nebo projet celý tento prodejní web. Hlavně nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód AX30, na který získáte další slevu 35 %.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncharted director's new studio are making a Marvel game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-directors-new-studio-are-making-a-marvel-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-directors-new-studio-are-making-a-marvel-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T10:58:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skydance New Media, the studio led by former Uncharted director Amy Hennig, have announced they're making a game set in the wizarding world of Marvel. They describe the yet-unnamed game as "a narrative-driven, blockbuster action-adventure game, featuring a completely original story and take on the Marvel Universe". Mysteries!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Edge pro Linux v ostré verzi]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42962</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/microsoft-edge-pro-linux-v-ostre-verzi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prohlížeč Microsoft Edge je od minulého čtvrtka pro Linux v ostré verzi označené jako stable microsoft-edge-stable-95.0.1020.38–1 a není tak již označován jako beta. V pátek se objevila verze končící 40–1. Microsoft zatím nic neoznámil, na oficiálních stránkách Edge je stále napsáno „Není podporován pro Linux“. Změny si všimli pracovníci bezpečnostní firmy Sophos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se Kubernetes na našem dvoudenním školení]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41195</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-kubernetes-na-nasem-dvoudennim-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:41:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kubernetes je dnes nejrozšířenější platformou na hostovaní Docker kontejneru a je podporován velkými hráči na trhu (Google, Amazon, Microsoft) skrz Cloud Native Computing Foundation. Kuberneres pro provoz používají všechny velikosti firem, od startupu po korporace. Pojďme se naučit jej používat na dvoudenním kurzu Úvod do Kubernetes, který proběhne v naší pražské školicí místnosti ve dnech 25. a 26. listopadu. Školení proběhne kombinovaně: tedy prezenčně a zároveň je možné se účastnit online.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšlo jádro 5.15 s NTFS3 a KSMBD]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42961</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyslo-jadro-5-15-s-ntfs3-a-ksmbd/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T06:48:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds včera vydal jádro 5.15. Mezi novinky patří ovladač NTFS3 od Paragon Software, který má potenciál nahradit FUSE ovladač ntfs-3g. Dále je v jádře implementace Samba serveru KSMBD od Samsungu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtuální Bastlírna a Den Otevřených Spínačů (Dveří)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42960</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/virtualni-bastlirna-a-den-otevrenych-spinacu-dveri/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T06:28:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protože zima se blíží a pravděpodobnost znovuzavedení protiepidemických opatření každý den vzrůstá, rozhodli jsme se příští týden zorganizovat rovnou dvě pravidelné akce z repertoáru projektu MacGyver studentského klubu SiliconHill.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: bkralik)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wirecutter]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2536/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2536/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: jak si neobjednat drahé předplatné]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15736</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-jak-si-neobjednat-drahe-predplatne/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T23:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes se v týdenním souhrnu bezpečnostních novinek podíváme na podvodnou kampaň UltimateSMS, na platební terminály PAX, na krádež reklamy, na mobilní síť nové generace a na dvě nakažené knihovny na oficiálním úložišti.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CSIRT.CZ)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Začal vývoj Ubuntu 22.04 LTS, Project Trident končí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15737</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/zacal-vyvoj-ubuntu-22-04-lts-project-trident-konci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T23:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Začal vývoj Ubuntu 22.04 s dlouhodobou podporou. Distribuce vycházející z Void Linuxu s grafickým prostředím Lumina ukončuje svůj vývoj. AlmaLinux má nový nástroj pro aktualizaci Enterprise Linux systémů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-616</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-616"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for changing into your second Halloween costume and returning to that house who gave out KitKat Chunkys. Before you go to hell, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix's The Witcher gets a full season two trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-the-witcher-gets-a-full-season-two-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-the-witcher-gets-a-full-season-two-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T22:13:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, Netflix released the trailer for season two of their live action adaptation of The Witcher. And it's fun! You can watch it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté – ceny]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-tiskarny-behem-lockdownu-a-pote-ceny</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-tiskarny-behem-lockdownu-a-pote-ceny"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Polovina ajťáků v Praze vydělá 100 a více tisíc měsíčně. Notebooky a PC v uplynulém období. Dell rozšiřuje IT kapacity směrem na periferii. Servery Lenovo nově v portfoliu Entec Solutions. Hrozby na vzestupu: útoky na dodavatelské řetězce a krádeže výpočetních kapacit. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (3) Ceny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Trident končí, desktopového následovníka PC-BSD nemá kdo vyvíjet]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15738</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/project-trident-konci-desktopoveho-nasledovnika-pc-bsd-nema-kdo-vyvijet/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audacity 3.1 se snadnější editací, X.Org 21.1 s podporou proměnné obnovovací frekvence, Samsung a HDR10+ Gaming, KDE oddělí stavová data aplikací, vlajková loď Nikon Z9, IPTC přidává dva nové prvky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4's next free update will add challenge scenarios]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-next-free-update-will-add-challenge-scenarios</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-next-free-update-will-add-challenge-scenarios"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T21:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of people play The Sims 4 by pursuing community-created challenges, whether they're about building particular types of homes, having a particular number of babies, or many more. Next week a free update for The Sims 4 will add these kinds of challenges to the game itself, beginning with two new scenarios.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crusader Kings 3's first DLC delayed as Paradox aren't satisfied with its "stability"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crusader-kings-3s-first-dlc-delayed-as-paradox-arent-satisfied-with-its-stability</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crusader-kings-3s-first-dlc-delayed-as-paradox-arent-satisfied-with-its-stability"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T20:59:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox are going to take longer than first thought to finish Crusader Kings 3's first DLC. Royal Court didn't previously have an announced release date, but it's currently aiming for 2022 as Paradox say they are "not, at the moment, entirely satisfied with Royal Court's progress."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Devil Inside's world map is just as cute as its combat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-devil-insides-world-map-is-just-as-cute-as-its-combat</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-devil-insides-world-map-is-just-as-cute-as-its-combat"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T20:24:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At PlayStation's State Of Play earlier this week, we got another glimpse of Little Devil Inside. The action-adventure game has been rattling around for at least six years, but it's beginning to look more and more like an actual game. Watch the new trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developers write open letter asking Valve to reverse Steam's NFT ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/developers-write-open-letter-asking-valve-to-reverse-steams-nft-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/developers-write-open-letter-asking-valve-to-reverse-steams-nft-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T19:58:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group of developers have written an open letter to Valve asking them to reverse their decision to forbid games containing NFTs and other blockchain technologies on Steam. NFTs are great, they say, arguing that they "make games more decentralized, democratic, interactive, player focused systems." 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94 bude používat EGL - lepší výkon a menší spotřeba]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42959</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-94-bude-pouzivat-egl-lepsi-vykon-a-mensi-spotreba/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T13:21:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nadcházející Firefox 94 bude v Linuxu používat EGL backend místo dosavadního GLX. Ve výsledku bude lepší výkon WebGL a menší spotřeba díky podpoře částečného překreslení obrazovky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The weird folk horror of Mundaun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-weird-folk-horror-of-mundaun</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-weird-folk-horror-of-mundaun"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the first things that may strike you about Mundaun, a very unsettling horror game that released earlier this year, is just how comfortable with weirdness it is. There are hay people hunting you in the night, monstrous masks inspired by traditional Swiss carnival costumes, and the decapitated head of the goat Allegria, bleating and chattering from your backpack. 


Many horror games either try to establish a sense of mundane familiarity in a recognisable, contemporary world before shattering that familiarity, or else rely on the dusty, done-to-death setting of haunted manors. In most cases, neither approach does much to surprise. Horror often relies on the grotesque, but Mundaun’s weirdness is different. It is an earthy kind of weirdness, a strangeness with roots so deep that it might be confused with familiarity. It’s a horror that smells not of blood, but of hay and dung, snow and soot. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When did horror games become team sports?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/when-did-horror-games-become-team-sports</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/when-did-horror-games-become-team-sports"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By the time you read this I'll be playing Back 4 Blood, gunning down hordes of the undead until viscera and gore cake my player’s clothes, and my eyes become infinite pools of horror that have seen more than enough death for one lifetime. Or perhaps I’ll be creeping around a haunted house in Phasmophobia, my smudge stick in-hand and a cavalcade of petrified friends whimpering down their mics. Maybe I’ll be running from Pyramid Head in Dead By Daylight with my pals in tow. A thought has been brewing in the cold recesses of my mind for a while now, and it is simply this: when did horror become a team game?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Heaton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-167</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-167"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Halloween weekend, gang! Oh, hang on, I meant to say: BOO! Alright, there we go. But the greatest horror this weekend isn't any ghost or ghoulie, it's UK clocks switching back to GMT this weekend. Sure, your phone and computer will automatically update, but your heating will be irksome until you again dig out the manual to remember how to change it. And a secondary blast of horror comes from the fact that not every country changes their clocks just yet, so if you deal with business across timezones... good luck, pal. But, what are you playing this weekend?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$220 for a 27-in 1440p 144Hz ViewSonic monitor is an absolute steal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/220-for-a-27-in-1440p-144hz-viewsonic-monitor-is-an-absolute-steal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/220-for-a-27-in-1440p-144hz-viewsonic-monitor-is-an-absolute-steal"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T01:14:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's rare to see a legitimately good 1440p 144Hz monitor for less than $250, but right now ViewSonic's VX2758-2KP-MHD is on sale at Newegg for $220 - a stunning $110 (33%) reduction from its original price of $330. 
This 'Shell Shocker' sale ends in just a few hours, so do pick this up if you're in the market for a high-end gaming monitor at bargain basement prices!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD's 2TB SN550 NVMe SSD is well cheap on Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-2tb-sn550-nvme-ssd-is-well-cheap-on-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-2tb-sn550-nvme-ssd-is-well-cheap-on-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T00:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of our former best gaming SSD picks, the WD Blue SN550, is down to just £140 on Amazon for a massive 2TB model. That's a historic low price by around £15 and a good £40 what it cost just a few weeks ago, making this a very good time to pick up a high performance NVMe SSD on the cheap. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 43/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-43-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-43-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence a rekurzívní sebezdokonalování]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-rekurzivni-sebezdokonalovani</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-rekurzivni-sebezdokonalovani"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poločas rozpadu neutronu. Máme se bát, pokud umělá inteligence navrhne jinou umělou inteligenci? Superionický led. Počátky počítačů na Slovensku. Na Venuši žádné oceány být nemusely.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mushrooms, mould and killer plants: the best horror isn't animal, it's vegetable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mushrooms-mould-and-killer-plants-the-best-horror-isnt-animal-its-vegetable</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mushrooms-mould-and-killer-plants-the-best-horror-isnt-animal-its-vegetable"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since I witnessed a little red-and-blue plumber-man tumble into the gnashing jaws of a Piranha Plant, I knew vegetables weren’t to be trusted. I see my suspicion of all things green and floral as a natural, even instinctual thing. We ourselves aren’t vegetable, and differences so often motivate our deepest fears. The vegetal realm is entirely inaccessible to us, its behaviour strange and habitats dark. From the carnivorous Venus flytrap to the bleeding tooth fungus, from plants that smell like rotting corpses to one's that trap prey and dissolve them with digestive fluids, it’s an unknown, often dangerous world, and one that overlaps closely with our own. And it makes for a compelling game.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to convince the Worldmind in Guardians Of The Galaxy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-worldmind</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-worldmind"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:59:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to convince the Worldmind in Guardians Of The Galaxy? The adventure to save the galaxy doesn’t just involve shooting Chitauri and cracking jokes. Throughout Guardians Of The Galaxy, you engage in conversations with various characters, in which you can make decisions that will alter the course of the game. Most of these have small, fairly insignificant consequences. However, the conversation with the Worldmind in Chapter 9 could help you get some crucial help in a difficult fight later in the game.
This guide will show you the correct choices to make to convince the Worldmind that Raker can be defeated in Guardians Of The Galaxy.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An ode to Kain from Blood Omen and his Legacy - including Untitled Goose Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-kain-from-blood-omen-and-his-legacy-including-untitled-goose-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-kain-from-blood-omen-and-his-legacy-including-untitled-goose-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:38:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Steam user genre tags can be awful. Cyberpunk 2077 was, for example, tagged ‘masterpiece’ for months before the first gameplay trailer, while the much more reasonable and catchy ‘looks cool sure but too early to say anything definitive if we’re being adults about it’ tag was strangely absent. Happily, they are sometimes wonderful, like the tag alongside ‘comedy’ and ‘indie’ that categorises avian arsehole adventure Untitled Goose Game as having a ‘villain protagonist’. 


I’ve been thinking about villain protagonists a fair amount this week because GOG just graced our collective thinking tellies with 1996 Zelda-like Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain, in all its richly overwrought, gothic, inimitably voice-acted splendour. I would estimate this news finds you, reader, in one of two categories: those who give not a fig, and those who give so many figs they are currently scrabbling the world’s few remaining fig-bearing trees, searching vainly for an adequate quantity of figs.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PUBG company buying Subnautica studio Unknown Worlds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pubg-company-buying-subnautica-studio-unknown-worlds</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pubg-company-buying-subnautica-studio-unknown-worlds"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:10:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Krafton, the South Korean company behind Plunkbat and Tera, today announced that they're buying Unknown Worlds, the studio splendid subaquatic survival sim series Subnautica and the fantastic FPS-RTS hybrid Natural Selection. Huh! The professed plan is for them to keep on as usual, still working on the Subnauticae as well as a mystery game debuting next year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultimate Audio Bang #17: weird and wonderful FPS vocab]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-17-weird-and-wonderful-fps-vocab</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-17-weird-and-wonderful-fps-vocab"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This time, I've returned from a trip to Devon having spent too much time ignoring my friends and playing Hollow Knight instead. But what about FPSes? Well, I didn't play any of those. Thankfully Imogen has all of us covered on this week's episode of the Ultimate Audio Bang, with a news segment rammed with lots of exciting announcements. Namely, Apex Legends gets a new Legend and map, Halo Infinite sees a new trailer, and Call Of Duty's new anti-cheat Ricochet leaks early.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians of the Galaxy chapters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-length</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-length"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T14:47:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how many chapters there are in Guardians Of The Galaxy? This planet-hopping adventure takes you on the cosmic ride of your life in an original Guardians Of The Galaxy story, involving plenty of punching, shooting, and generally jumping around with jet boots. Throughout the adventure, you'll come across many classic characters, such as Cosmo the spacedog, Adam Warlock, Mantis, Fin Fang Foom, and Lady Hellbender. However, since it isn't based directly on a certain comic storyline or movie, it can be hard to judge how long you'll actually spend playing Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy.
This guide will break down how many chapters there are in Guardians Of The Galaxy, and explain how long it will take to beat the game.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carve pumpkins for a virtual pumpkin festival in this free indie game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/carve-pumpkins-for-a-virtual-pumpkin-festival-in-this-free-indie-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/carve-pumpkins-for-a-virtual-pumpkin-festival-in-this-free-indie-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T13:41:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last Halloween, Alice Bee visited Ghost Town's 999th Annual Pumpkin Festival, carving a pumpkin of her own to place amongst the spooky virtual showcase. It was a lovely little indie game from Adam "Adamgryu" Robinson-Yu, creator of the much-adored A Short Hike. Well, Halloween is upon us again, and Mayor Bones has returned with another gourd-o-rama, putting servers back online and inviting us to contribute new pumpkins. It's still lovely.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitman 3 and The Riftbreaker are the first games with Intel XeSS support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-3-and-the-riftbreaker-are-the-first-games-with-intel-xess-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-3-and-the-riftbreaker-are-the-first-games-with-intel-xess-support"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T13:32:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amidst all the excitement of Intel’s 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs, let’s not forget that the first Intel dedicated graphics cards are on their way. Codenamed Arc Alchemist, these GPUs will launch alongside XeSS (Xe Super Sampling), an Nvidia DLSS-style upscaling/anti-aliasing piece of tech that promises to boost performance while sharpening up those jagged edges. And we now know the first two games that will support XeSS: Hitman 3 and The Riftbreaker.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where are all the good Stephen King games?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/where-are-all-the-good-stephen-king-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/where-are-all-the-good-stephen-king-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Halloweekend is almost upon us and sitting on my coffee table is my battered old paperback copy of Skeleton Crew, a 1985 collection of short horror stories by Stephen King. Back in my wild teenage years I binged King's entire back-catalogue of published fiction, and now that it's been long enough for me to have forgotten most of the details, I'm treating myself to some selective re-reads. Fair to say some of his stuff hasn't aged brilliantly, but despite many rough edges he undeniably remains one of my all-time favourite authors. I am, after all, a self-confessed horror nerd.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proton nově umí hry chráněné DRM Valve CEG]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42958</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/proton-nove-umi-hry-chranene-drm-valve-ceg/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T12:24:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový Proton Experimental v beta verzi klienta Steam ze včerejška umí spustit windowsové hry chráněné starým ale rozšířeným DRM Valve CEG (custom executable-generation). Jde zatím jen o předběžnou podoru a může se stát, že některá hra s CEG nepojede. Úspěchy i neúspěchy lze hlásit na GitHubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rally Point: The Riftbreaker is light on strategy but carries a lot with it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-the-riftbreaker-is-light-on-strategy-but-carries-a-lot-with-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-the-riftbreaker-is-light-on-strategy-but-carries-a-lot-with-it"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hesitated. Not to play The Riftbreaker, you understand. I'd played its demo last year, which was enough to sell me on playing the full game. But to cover it as a strategy game is another matter.
It does games in particular a disservice to get prescriptive with genre, but there's no question that Riftbreaker falls under 'action strategy', with an even greater emphasis on action than, say, Hostile Waters or Sacrifice. But then, it also has detailed base building, tower defence, and a tonne of resource management. I've given up trying to categorise it, and it will always be distinct from most strategy games, but I think its peers could still learn a few things from it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome i Chromium zranitelné, aktualizujte na 95.0.4638.69]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42957</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chrome-a-chromium-zranitelne-aktualizujte-na-95-0-4638-69/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T11:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera Google vydal mimořádnou bezpečnostní opravu svého prohlížeče Chrome 95.0.4638.69 pro Windows, Linux i macOS, která se týká také Chromium. Opraveno je celkem 8 zranitelností, všechny s vysokou nebezpečností. Obzvlášť nebezpečné jsou chyby CVE-2021–38000 a CVE-2021–38003, protože jsou v současnosti aktivně zneužívány.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook parent company now named Meta, unveiling vision of a metaverse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/facebook-parent-company-now-named-meta-unveiling-vision-of-a-metaverse</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/facebook-parent-company-now-named-meta-unveiling-vision-of-a-metaverse"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T11:01:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The company behind Facebook and Oculus, previously known as Facebook, have unveiled a new name: Meta. Oh christ. Yes, it is named after the metaverse, because tech megacorps can't resist the delusion that their platform to sell adverts is elevating humanity to a new plane of existence. Mark Zuckerberg suggests that in the future they're building, you'll experience everything through virtual and augmented reality, and that definitely won't be a horrible world devoid of intimacy, okay, it'll be great.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Facebook se přejmenovává na Meta]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42956</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/spolecnost-facebook-se-prejmenovava-na-meta/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T05:47:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera CEO Facebooku Mark Zuckerberg řekl, že se společnost Facebook přejmenovává na Meta. Jména jednotlivých produktů jako Facebook, Whatsapp a Instagram zůstávají stejné. Výjimkou je Oculus s VR brýlemi. Ty budou nově prodávány pod značkou Meta a Oculus už se nebude používat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Cold Viruses]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2535/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2535/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Black SN750 1TB NVMe SSD is £87 for 1TB: good deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-wd-black-sn750-1tb-nvme-ssd-is-87-for-1tb-good-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-wd-black-sn750-1tb-nvme-ssd-is-87-for-1tb-good-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T22:16:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Black SN750 is a super-fast PCIe 3.0 SSD - and the 1TB model is down to £87 at Amazon UK, a historic low price. That's a fantastic price for what was once among the fastest NVMe SSDs on the planet, with read speeds up to nearly 3500MB/s... before the advent of faster (and more expensive) PCIe 4.0 drives in the last couple of years. 
Still, in terms of value for money, this TLC drive with a DRAM cache is going to be hard to beat - especially as the only real competitors tend to come with QLC NAND or without a DRAM cache, both of which sacrifice performance to hit lower price points!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer's Viper Ultimate mouse is nearly £100 off at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razers-viper-ultimate-mouse-is-nearly-100-off-at-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razers-viper-ultimate-mouse-is-nearly-100-off-at-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T21:26:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I've mentioned before, the Razer Viper is one of my favourite ultralight gaming mice of all time, and today the Ultimate wireless version is marked it down from £170 all the way to £73 at Amazon UK.
That's an incredibly good price considering this is the model that comes with a handy charging dock to ensure your mouse is always topped up without ever fussing with a cable. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unikly privátní klíče pro tvorbu očkovacích certifikátů, koluje certifikát Adolfa Hitlera]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42955</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/unikly-privatni-klice-pro-tvorbu-ockovacich-certifikatu-koluje-certifikat-adolfa-hitlera/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T20:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Privátní klíč určený k podpisu digitálních očkovacích certifikátů zřejmě unikl a koluje po nejrůznějších platformách včetně sociálních sítí a webových fór. Internetem se také šíří potvrzení o očkování vystavené pro Adolfa Hitlera narozeného 1. ledna 1900. Kromě toho je možné potkat také certifikáty pro jména Mickey Mouse, Sponge Bob a další známá jména. Mobilní aplikace pro kontrolu očkovacích certifikátů je považují za platné.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dění okolo generických typů v Go]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42954</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/deni-okolo-generickych-typu-v-go/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T19:54:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S blížícím se vydáním Go 1.18 dochází k posledním úpravám návrhu generických typů v Go. Tato zatím největší změna od vydání první verze jazyka zahrnuje rozšíření překladače a standardní knihovny. V případě knihovny budou zatím změny provizorní, bez zaručení zpětné kompatibility.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Calculon)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard CEO commits to waiving forced arbitration, and a temporary paycut]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-ceo-commits-to-waiving-forced-arbitration-and-a-temporary-paycut</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-ceo-commits-to-waiving-forced-arbitration-and-a-temporary-paycut"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T18:44:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick has detailed plans for the company to rebuild itself following numerous legal cases and protests over alleged harrassment, discrimination, and retaliation at the company. Key points include a policy of zero-tolerance for harassment and an end to forced abitration in claims of sexual harrassment and discrimination. An employee group call this "a huge win". And Kotick himself has volunteered to take a huge pay cut until they achieve their stated goals.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new hero Ash hunts squads with Titanfall-inspired abilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-hero-ash-hunts-squads-with-titanfall-inspired-abilities</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-hero-ash-hunts-squads-with-titanfall-inspired-abilities"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' next season, Escape, kicks off next week, and it introduces the new playable character Ash. She's a simulacrum (read: human brain in robot body) that you might recognise as the evil pilot from Titanfall 2's Into The Abyss level, or as the overseer of Apex Legends' 3v3 Arenas mode. Now she's descending into the Apex games herself, and having taken her for a spin already, I reckon she has some delightfully aggressive abilities that Wraith players in particular are going to enjoy. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends Ash tips and tricks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-ash-abilities-tips-tricks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-ash-abilities-tips-tricks"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know about Ash's abilities in Apex Legends? The upcoming addition to the Apex Legends roster will arrive next week, along with a brand new map, the new CAR SMG, and a host of weapon and Legend balance changes. Ash is turning a lot of heads thanks both to her complex and fascinating backstory and to her powerful and versatile array of abilities.
Below we'll walk you through how each of Ash's abilities work in detail, so you can get off to a great start with her once Season 11 drops. We'll also detail Ash's backstory for those who need to know every last detail about this dangerous new Legend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends CAR SMG stats [Season 11]]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-car-stats</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-car-stats"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for up-to-date and accurate CAR SMG stats for Apex Legends? The CAR is Season 11's addition to the Apex Legends weapons arsenal, and it's got a very impressive array of stats to show off. But what's truly unique about the CAR is its ability to use both Heavy and Light Ammo, and toggle between them at the touch of a button.
Keep reading for an in-depth look at the CAR SMG in Apex Legends, along with detailed stats covering everything from damage profiles and shots to kill to reload times and attachment slots.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new map Stormpoint comes with vicious wildlife and excellent cannons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-map-stormpoint-comes-with-vicious-wildlife-and-excellent-cannons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-map-stormpoint-comes-with-vicious-wildlife-and-excellent-cannons"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beach map! Beach map! Beach map! Apex Legends' next season, Escape, is right around the corner, and it's bringing a tropical island to fight on. It's also bringing a the new Legend Ash, the CAR SMG and more, but most importantly: beach map! I had a chance to play a little of Respawn's battle royale in this new arena, and it is delightful. Named Stormpoint, it's the FPS's fourth map, and not only is it lovely to look at, but it's full of cool locations to explore and dangerous wildlife to dodge. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption is horrifying because it does things games aren't supposed to]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-is-horrifying-because-it-does-things-games-arent-supposed-to</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-is-horrifying-because-it-does-things-games-arent-supposed-to"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Mullins says he's not sure that "horror" is the most accurate way to describe his gruesome new card battler Inscryption. He immediately follows this up by telling me a friend of his had nightmares because of the menacing figure you play cards against, so yeah, maybe it's a bit horror-like. But I kind of understand his point. 


At the start, Inscryption is like a hostage situation, where you're forced to play a card-based roguelike against a sinister games master. Then, just as you start getting the hang of things, the game evolves into something way more complex. If you've played Mullins' other games you'll know his work can go to some weird, meta places. I won't say more above the cut, because I'd hate to spoil it. But for those of you who've already played, read on for more detail on how Mullins created an excellently unsettling world.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix announce Star Ocean The Divine Force]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-announce-star-ocean-the-divine-force</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-announce-star-ocean-the-divine-force"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T13:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tri-Ace's action-RPG series Star Ocean will return with a new game next year, Square Enix have announced. Though the series started 25 years ago on the SNES, you needn't concern yourself with that history because Squeenix say Star Ocean The Divine Force will tell a new story with new characters. Come meet them and see some of the sci-fantasy world in the trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Performance Continues In The Right Direction For AArch64]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30647</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30647"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a good sign ahead of the important Ubuntu 22.04 LTS release in the spring, Ubuntu 21.10 further ups the 64-bit ARM (AArch64) performance. Here is a look at some of the gains in going from Ubuntu 21.04 to the recently released Ubuntu 21.10.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forget Far Cry 6, the bugs in Hollow Knight can send me snarky emails anytime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forget-far-cry-6-the-bugs-in-hollow-knight-can-send-me-snarky-emails-anytime</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forget-far-cry-6-the-bugs-in-hollow-knight-can-send-me-snarky-emails-anytime"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I've heard tales of Far Cry 6 players receiving snarky emails from Ubisoft about how much time they've spent in-game. They're supposed to read as if Anton Castillo, the game's evil dictator, is mocking you for not investing enough of it toppling his regime.
And even if you've spent a lot of time clearing Castillo's map markers, he'll still send you emails anyway. They feature stats like time played, checkpoints cleared, that sort of thing. Many people don't seem to like this, which I totally understand. But a part of me wishes these rude marketing emails were more of a thing. Specifically, I'd like it if the bugs from Hollow Knight spun some my way.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy tips]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T09:51:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know some tips and tricks for Guardians Of The Galaxy? The adventure will take you across the vast galaxy in search of fortune, fun, and a whole lot of kicking ass, but you won’t make it far without a solid grasp of the mechanics in Guardians Of The Galaxy.
This guide will offer some tips and tricks that you’ll need to get familiar with if you want to turn your rag-tag group of misfits into a heroic team to be feared. We'll cover tips for all of the main aspects of the game, including combat, exploring, and all of the chats that you'll have with your teammates during your adventure.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get the brand new SteelSeries Arctis 7P+ gaming headset for 12% off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-brand-new-steelseries-arctis-7p-gaming-headset-for-12-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-brand-new-steelseries-arctis-7p-gaming-headset-for-12-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The SteelSeries Arctis 7P+ is a brand new gaming headset, offering a series of small upgrades over the already-brilliant Arctis 7P. It's rare to see new items discounted right away, but today you can get this new model up for 12% off with code MOUNTAIN12.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PNY's great value DDR4 RAM is going cheap in the US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pnys-great-value-ddr4-ram-is-going-cheap-in-the-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pnys-great-value-ddr4-ram-is-going-cheap-in-the-us"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T00:45:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PNY isn't the first name you might think of when it comes to RAM, but they're sometimes a great value - including today, when a series of RAM kits are on sale in stores across the US. Here are the links - and some words about why you should consider them. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retractable Rocket]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2534/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2534/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 41-42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-41-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-41-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V říjnu bylo dosud vydáno Ubuntu 21.10, OpenBSD 7.0 nebo ruská, na Mandrivě založená ROSA Fresh Desktop R12. Na Debian „Bullseye“ přešly jeho deriváty bez systemd Devuan a MX Linux. Také byly aktualizovány distribuce KaOS, GhostBSD, Porteus Kiosk, Redcore Linux či NuTyX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Organizace letos vynaloží na technologie podporující budoucnost práce 656 miliard dolarů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-organizace-letos-vynalozi-na-technologie-podporujici-budoucnost-prace-656-miliard-dolaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-organizace-letos-vynalozi-na-technologie-podporujici-budoucnost-prace-656-miliard-dolaru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat novými aktualizacemi podporuje edge computing. Organizace letos vynaloží na technologie podporující budoucnost práce 656 miliard dolarů. HPE GreenLake přináší inovativní architekturu správy dat. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (2) Nedostatek dílů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence a signály odměn]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problém zpětnovazebného učení u skutečné umělé inteligence. Primordiální černé díry. Záhadné rádiové vlny. Nejchytřejší psi. Drony jako hasiči.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podzimní smršť novinek od Aceru. SentinelOne v ČR nabere 300 lidí a investuje miliardu. Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci. Dodávky a ceny osobních počítačů z pohledu výrobce. VMworld: Zabezpečení na principu nulové důvěry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence v kooperativních hrách]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový typ magnetismu nezpůsobují spiny. Beethovenovu slavnou 10. symfonii dokončila umělá inteligence  Studium neuronových sítí může pomoci při zkoumání toho, jak se do mozku ukládají konspirační teorie. Minirobot se pohybuje díky gradientům teploty. Splynutí obřích černých děr provázejí nejen gravitační vlny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>