<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-29T08:17:10.657Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-29T08:17:10.657Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Toy-Themed Shooter Hypercharge: Unboxed Just Got Its "Biggest" Switch Update Ever]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121568</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/the_toy-themed_shooter_hypercharge_unboxed_just_got_its_biggest_switch_update_ever"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New maps, enemies, weapons and more.

Digital Cybercherries has released the fourth major update for its toy-themed shooter Hypercharge: Unboxed.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallery: Nintendo Reflects On Super Smash Bros. Ultimate Ahead Of The Final Fighter Reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121566</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/gallery_nintendo_reflects_on_super_smash_bros_ultimate_ahead_of_the_final_fighter_reveal"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T05:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a long journey.
Last week, Nintendo confirmed the final Super Smash Bros. Ultimate DLC reveal would take place on 5th October. This will also seemingly be the last time we see the game's director Masahiro Sakurai showcasing a new fighter.
Ahead of this very special occasion, Nintendo's Smash Bros. Twitter account in Japan has been reflecting on just how much the game has grown since its 2018 reveal. Here's a look down memory lane:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Horrifying '90s-Style FPS Dusk Launches On Switch This Halloween]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121565</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/the_horrifying_90s-style_fps_dusk_launches_on_switch_this_halloween"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T04:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-orders are now available.
After skipping its Halloween release last year, DUSK - the '90s-style first-person shooter inspired by Doom, Quake, Hexen and even Half-Life - has now locked in release date.
It'll now arrive this Halloween on 28th October. If you pre-order now, you'll get the retro-inspired game Dusk '82 for free. And if you would prefer a physical copy, the pre-order period for the Limited Run physical edition has been extended:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Streaming Giant Netflix Acquires Its First Video Game Developer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121564</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/streaming_giant_netflix_acquires_its_first_video_game_developer"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Says it wants to deliver a "great collection of exclusive games".
There's been a lot of discussion in recent times about the streaming giant Netflix expanding into video games with its popular service and now it has announced its very first developer acquisition.
So, what's the company? It's Night School Studio - known for its debut game Oxenfree and also the upcoming release Oxenfree II: Lost Signals, en route to all platforms including the Nintendo Switch.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A (Playable) Game Boy For Ants]]></title>
        <id>1847764946</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/a-playable-game-boy-for-ants-1847764946"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T03:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know what my grandmother used to say? “That blasted Game Boy of yours, it’s too damn big!” She was right, the old woman was wise. And if this fictional gram were alive today maybe she’d smile upon hearing word of Thumby, a very, very small Game Boy-like device that launched a Kickstarter today. (Of course, she’d…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japanese Developer Treasure Teases Future Releases For Switch Online]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121563</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/japanese_developer_treasure_teases_future_releases_for_switch_online"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T02:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gunstar Heroes and Sin & Punishment have already been locked in.
One developer that showed up a few times during Nintendo's reveal of the N64 and Mega Drive NSO service was Treasure.
The famous Japanese company - known for hits such as Ikaruga on the Dreamcast and GameCube - appears to have two games on the way to Nintendo's digital retro libraries. Gunstar Heroes for the Mega Drive / Genesis and Sin & Punishment for the Nintendo 64 (it's even got a western box art now).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Check Out These Mock-Ups Of GameCube For Nintendo Switch Online]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121562</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/random_check_out_these_mock-ups_of_gamecube_for_nintendo_switch_online"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fan can dream...

Last week, Nintendo revealed N64 and Sega Mega Drive titles would be coming to the Switch Online service, as part of a new "expansion pack" tier. It's essentially opened the door once again for all sorts of retro systems to be added in the future.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Beta Improves Its Vulkan Pre-Caching System, PipeWire Capture Now Opt-In]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Better-VLK-Pre-Cache</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Better-VLK-Pre-Cache"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T00:51:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the initial Steam Deck release quickly approaching, Valve continues to be quite busy on a variety of improvements to enhance their Steam Linux builds...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 36-37/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-36-37-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-36-37-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na sklonku léta vyšel nový Whonix, podíváme se na systém pro klientské stanice ThinStation a aktualizovány byly také distribuce Finnix, Lakka, GhostBSD, Tails, Kali, Ubuntu LTS, Sailfish OS nebo Sparky Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soutěž pro mladé programátory: Youth Hacking 4 Freedom (YH4F)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/soutez-pro-mlade-programatory-youth-hacking-4-freedom-yh4f</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/soutez-pro-mlade-programatory-youth-hacking-4-freedom-yh4f"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T23:52:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE) organizuje soutěž pro mladé programátory ve věku 14 až 18 let s názvem Youth Hacking 4 Freedom (YH4F). Zaregistrovat se mohou do 31. října. Na vývoj svého svobodného softwaru budou mít pět měsíců, tj. do konce března. Šest nejlepších získá peněžitou výhru (2 x 4 096 €, 2 x 2 048 €, 2 x 1 024 €) a výlet do Bruselu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Software Defined Silicon (SDSi)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/intel-software-defined-silicon-sdsi</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/intel-software-defined-silicon-sdsi"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T22:55:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel poslal do Linuxu patche přinášející podporu pro Intel Software Defined Silicon (SDSi). Uživatelé procesorů Xeon budou moci získat licence pro další funkce procesoru.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix Acquires Oxenfree Dev As Its First Game Studio]]></title>
        <id>1847763973</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/netflix-acquires-oxenfree-dev-as-its-first-game-studio-1847763973"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T22:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Streaming giant Netflix has acquired Night School Studio, a developer founded by former Telltale Games employees that released Oxenfree, an intriguing supernatural mystery game, and Afterparty, a barhopping comedy journey through Hell. Though now a Netflix subsidiary, Night School Studio confirmed that Oxenfree 2‘s…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Driver Merges NGG Improvements, Other Optimizations For Mesa 21.3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-RadeonSI-More-NGG</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-RadeonSI-More-NGG"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T22:35:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD open-source driver developers today merged another big set of patches providing various micro-optimizations and other enhancements to the RadeonSI Gallium3D driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix have bought the developers of Oxenfree]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-have-bought-the-developers-of-oxenfree</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-have-bought-the-developers-of-oxenfree"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T22:35:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Night School Studio are "joining the Netflix team." The developers of Oxenfree and Afterparty are the first games studio to be bought by Netflix, with founder and creative director Sean Krankel writing in a blog post that they'll continue working on the in-development Oxenfree 2. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ULua: univerzální distribuce programovacího jazyka Lua]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15683</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/ulua-univerzalni-distribuce-programovaciho-jazyka-lua/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Představíme si projekt nazvaný ULua, což je distribuce tohoto programovacího jazyka pro všechny tři nejpoužívanější operační systémy, která kromě LuaJITu obsahuje i správce balíčků upkg.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (29. 9. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15682</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-29-9-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si představíme nástroj pro práci se snímky obrazovky, vyzkoušíme software pro práci s MPO 3D fotografiemi, přeložíme si texty do jiných jazyků a vytvoříme si nějaké ty vědecké grafy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Players Face Massive Queues, Wait Times On Overloaded Servers]]></title>
        <id>1847763621</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-world-players-face-massive-queues-wait-times-on-ov-1847763621"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T21:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon’s new massively multiplayer online role-playing game New World opened its doors earlier today, reaching a peak of over 700,000 players. That said, not even Jeff Bezos’ piggy bank has kept the MMO’s grand debut from being plagued with the usual launch day woes, including ridiculous wait times to just play the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can't be Jeff Bezos in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-cant-be-jeff-bezos-in-new-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-cant-be-jeff-bezos-in-new-world"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T21:41:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Picture the scene. You're playing newly released coloniast theme park New World when who should walk over to you but Amazon founder Jeff Bezos. The billionaire says that he's locked out of his bank accounts, but if you buy him several Amazon gift cards, he'll pay you back with "extra" once he gets his access back.

This situation probably can't happen, because "Jeff Bezos" and almost every variation of it aren't permitted names in Amazon's MMO.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bangle.js 2, open source chytré hodinky]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bangle.js-2-open-source-chytre-hodinky</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bangle.js-2-open-source-chytre-hodinky"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T21:40:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na Kickstarteru běží kampaň na podporu open source chytrých hodinek Bangle.js 2. Programovat je lze v JavaScriptu (Espruino Open Source JavaScript interpreter). Koupit je lze za £59 (1 744 korun). Dodání je plánováno na listopad.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can now play the demo for Pony Island dev's creepy card game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-now-play-the-demo-for-pony-island-devs-creepy-card-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-now-play-the-demo-for-pony-island-devs-creepy-card-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T21:11:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption is reportedly "inky black card-based odyssey that blends the deckbuilding roguelike, escape-room style puzzles, and psychological horror into a blood-laced smoothie." It's also from Daniel Mullins, the makers of Pony Island and The Hex, which means it's probably a few other, secret genres, too. It's coming October 19th, but there's a demo available now and a new trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SuperTuxKart 1.3]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/supertuxkart-1.3</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/supertuxkart-1.3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T21:02:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 1.3 svobodné multiplatformní závodní hry SuperTuxKart (STK). Přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu v traileru na YouTube. Kompletní seznam změn na GitHubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Linux 35 Beta]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fedora-linux-35-beta</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fedora-linux-35-beta"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána betaverze Fedora Linuxu 35, tj. o poslední zastávce před vydáním finální verze, která je momentálně naplánována na 19. října. Fedora Workstation přichází s GNOME 41. Nově vychází Fedora Kinoite s prostředím KDE Plasma založena na rpm-ostree, podobně jako Fedora Silverblue s prostředím GNOME.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Look At All The Ways You Can Kill People In Deathloop]]></title>
        <id>1847762409</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/look-at-all-the-ways-you-can-kill-people-in-deathloop-1847762409"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop has some of Arkane Studios’ biggest, most kinetic-feeling levels to date. Yes, they’re beautiful to behold, and a joy to traverse, but their best quality may be a little more subtle. They’ve proven to be perfect laboratories for players to experiment with ever more dastardly and amusing ways to kill…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Boss Fight That Proves Death’s Door Is On Another Level]]></title>
        <id>1847762964</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-boss-fight-that-proves-death-s-door-is-on-another-l-1847762964"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Death’s Door, an isometric dungeon-crawler that came out for PC and Xbox earlier this year, is a master class in elegant game design. Nowhere is that more apparent than in one late-game boss fight. In pretty much every way—visually, thematically, mechanically, musically—the bout is a tour de force. I cannot stop…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Dare Neopets Taint My Childhood With NFTs]]></title>
        <id>1847762677</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/how-dare-neopets-taint-my-childhood-with-nfts-1847762677"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Neopets developers recently revealed on their website that they are creating NFTs for over twenty thousand customized pets, all in partnership with several blockchain companies. So far, the public response from past and present community members has been overwhelmingly negative. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World is currently the most popular game on Steam]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-is-currently-the-most-popular-game-on-steam</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-is-currently-the-most-popular-game-on-steam"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:11:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon's MMO New World launched earlier today, and it's apparently great if you like queues. 

To put the login issues players are experiencing in context however, it's maybe worth noting that New World is currently the most popular game on Steam, knocking CS:GO from its perch within hours of release.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sable: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847762599</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sable-the-kotaku-review-1847762599"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I meet the mask crafter for the first time, I am unsure if I am touching a spirit, god, or machine. The machinists, whose ranks I plan to join today, would probably dismiss the distinction altogether. As I remember this, my hoverbike Simoon purrs outside the tent. She has been a good teacher.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Danganronpa S: Ultimate Summer Camp Will Have Gacha-Style Microtransactions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121558</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/danganronpa_s_ultimate_summer_camp_will_have_gacha-style_microtransactions"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spike Chunsoft confirms on their blog.
The Danganronpa Collection is coming to Nintendo Switch later this year, on the 3rd of December, but only one part of it is Switch-exclusive: Danganronpa S: Ultimate Summer Camp, an expanded standalone version of the board minigame "Ultimate Talent Development Plan" in Danganronpa V3: Killing Harmony.
Ultimate Summer Camp is set in an alternate universe where all the characters from the various Danganronpa games live in relative harmony on an island summer camp. They'll need to find ten "Hope Shards" in order to return home, which they can do by playing a Mario Party-esque board game where the squares you can land on include things like "Growth", "Battle", "Event", and "Friendship".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a 500W Seasonic SFX-L power supply for $35 at Newegg]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-500w-seasonic-sfx-l-power-supply-for-35-at-newegg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-500w-seasonic-sfx-l-power-supply-for-35-at-newegg"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T19:41:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seasonic is known the world over for their high-spec, high-reliability power supplies, and today one of their small form factor (SFX-L) PSUs is heavily discounted at Newegg. The fully modular Focus SGX-500 is a 500W PSU that comes with a ten-year warranty and a footprint of less than 5 x 5 inches. Normally you'd expect to pay $120 for it, but a combination of a Newegg discount, a $15 mail in rebate and a code for $10 off (NEOCTOBER) has dropped it to just $35 when all is said and done - pretty impressive! 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Dandy Ace' Looks Like Hades X Persona, And It's Out On Switch Today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121556</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/dandy_ace_looks_like_hades_x_persona_and_its_out_on_switch_today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plus new DLC!
Listen, we know there are quite a few roguelites on the market these days, but for fans of the genre, it's never enough. Give us a gimmick and a fresh art style, and we'll eagerly try them all.
Dandy Ace is the latest isometric action-adventure deckbuilding roguelite, in which you'll play as Ace, a magician trapped in a mirror dimension by an evil illusionist. By combining different cards, you can create your very own arsenal of magic, helping you to defeat the other monsters and bosses trapped here with you.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This RPS-approved ultrawide gaming monitor is £400 off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-rps-approved-ultrawide-gaming-monitor-is-400-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-rps-approved-ultrawide-gaming-monitor-is-400-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T19:24:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday we featured a cut-price 49-in Samsung ultrawide monitor, which was marked down to £1099. That's still stonking expensive, so how about something more reasonable? This is the Samsung CRG9, the Odyssey G9's predecessor, and it offers almost all the same specs for much less - just £699, down from £1099. Here's why it gets the sagely RPS nod of approval. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agatha Christie - Hercule Poirot: The First Cases Gets A Rather Dramatic Launch Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121540</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/agatha_christie_-_hercule_poirot_the_first_cases_gets_a_rather_dramatic_launch_trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out now in EU, next week in NA.
While it doesn't have the snappiest name, we've been rather intrigued to see how Agatha Christie - Hercule Poirot: The First Cases turns out on Switch. Though we don't yet have an answer on how well it stacks up on Nintendo's system (we do have a review planned), there is a rather dramatic launch trailer to enjoy.
It sets the scene nicely, though the heavy percussion-led cuts seem like a slightly odd approach for a detective game in which the protagonist presumably regularly fiddles with their moustache. In any case, it gets the juices flowing.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 To Expose AMD PSF Disable Bit To KVM Guests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PSF-Linux-5.16-KVM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PSF-Linux-5.16-KVM"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T18:48:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Linux kernel still hasn't added any formal control yet for AMD Predictive Store Forwarding to disable it short of also toggling Spectre V4 / SSBD, with the Linux 5.16 kernel the AMD PSF bit will now be exposed to KVM guest virtual machines so that they -- either with a patched/future kernel or for other operating systems -- may choose to toggle explicitly disable this AMD CPU feature...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nick Fighting Game Gives Nigel Thornberry Jigglypuff’s Rest From Smash]]></title>
        <id>1847761702</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nick-fighting-game-gives-nigel-thornberry-jigglypuff-s-1847761702"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel Thornberry, patriarch of the eponymously wild Thornberrys, is one of the weirdest characters in Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl. Earlier today, the developers behind this cartoony platform fighter released a breakdown of the nature documentarian’s moveset, which includes one very big homage to the undisputed king of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Splitgate's Big Update: Mantling, Plus Other Quality Of Life Tweaks]]></title>
        <id>1847761302</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/splitgates-big-update-mantling-plus-other-quality-of-1847761302"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developer 1047 Games has rolled out a massive update for its popular Portal shooter Splitgate. The patch introduces several quality-of-life improvements and bug fixes, as well as adding two important adjustments to make the game a little easier to play: the option to change the armor color of friends and foes, and the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switch Pre-Orders For Pokémon-Like 'Monster Crown' Go Live Today, October Launch Confirmed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121545</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/switch_pre-orders_for_pokemon-like_monster_crown_go_live_today_october_launch_confirmed"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Breed and fuse over 200 base monsters.
Sodesco has announced that pre-orders for Monster Crown, the Pokémon-like monster collecting game from developer Studio Aurum, will go live on Nintendo Switch today.
The game's been in the works for some time now, with a Kickstarter campaign going live back in 2018, and we actually shared an exclusive look at some of the game's monsters shortly afterwards. Now, we're just weeks away from seeing the game land on Switch, with a 12 October release date locked in.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 35 Beta Released With Many New Features, Countless Package Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-35-Beta-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-35-Beta-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:48:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After seeing some initial release challenges, Fedora 35 Beta was released today across the Fedora Workstation, Fedora Server, and Fedora IoT flavors as well as their other versions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FIFA Player Accused Of Rape Suspended And Removed From Roster]]></title>
        <id>1847761098</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/fifa-player-accused-of-rape-suspended-and-removed-from-1847761098"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Benjamin Mendy, a Manchester City defender in the real-life Premier League, was suspended after being charged with four counts of rape and one count of sexual assault of three women at his Cheshire home between October 2020 and August 2021.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon MMO New World, As Told By Steam Reviews]]></title>
        <id>1847759723</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/amazon-mmo-new-world-as-told-by-steam-reviews-1847759723"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a new world, if not exactly a brave one. New World, a massively multiplayer online role-playing game published by Amazon, is officially out today for PC, marking the first legitimately successful game release for the planet’s most valuable company. (Pour one out for the super-face-planted Crucible.)

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Kero Kero Bonito And Soccer Mommy's New Music Video Is All About Miis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121550</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/random_kero_kero_bonito_and_soccer_mommys_new_music_video_is_all_about_miis"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[...and Richard.
It's no surprise that UK band Kero Kero Bonito is really into video games — after all, they did the Bugsnax theme song. But their latest music video, for a song called "rom com 2021" recorded with American singer-songwriter Soccer Mommy, pulls inspiration from everyone's favourite avatar: Nintendo's Mii.
The music video has a distinctly retro aesthetic, with the Miis exploring a low-poly Katamari-like world until glitches make everything go all weird, and... is that Richard the dog from Ocarina of Time?
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latest Square Enix Switch Sale Offers Up To 60% Off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121551</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/latest_square_enix_switch_sale_offers_up_to_60_percent_off"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global discounts to celebrate Tokyo Game Show.
Tokyo Game Show kicks off later this week, and while a lot of the attention will be on live streams and showcases, some of the big publishers will no doubt ensure that it's a global event. Square Enix is doing its bit in that respect by kicking off a big ol' Switch eShop sale, live now in North America and Europe; it's running until 4th October.
You don't want any more preamble from us, right? The list of Switch and 3DS discount prices is below (in USD and Euros):
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Year With Genshin Impact]]></title>
        <id>1847760685</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/one-year-with-genshin-impact-1847760685"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exactly one year ago today, Genshin Impact was released. We were almost six months into the coronavirus pandemic, and now, looking back, I can’t imagine my adventure starting any other way. The fantasy world of Teyvat became my safe harbor in a year filled with grief, uncertainty, and disappointment.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Knockout Home Fitness - Too Limited And Lightweight To Be A Contender]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120533</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/knockout_home_fitness"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fails to pack a punch.
The Switch is slowly but surely becoming home to a new dawn of fitness games. The success of Ring Fit Adventure has clearly inspired a new batch of keep-fit titles, with the likes of Fitness Boxing 2, Active Life Outdoor Challenge and even Nintendo’s limited release Jump Rope Challenge all vying for a piece of the fitness pie. But not that big a piece: they need to watch their waistlines, after all.
Knockout Home Fitness is the latest contender to step into the ring and attempt to thwack the competition onto its backside. Sadly, though, it puts in more of an Anthony Joshua performance, and is ultimately underwhelming.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite's multiplayer reminds me of old Halo, and I mean that in the best way]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-multiplayer-reminds-me-of-old-halo-and-i-mean-that-in-the-best-way</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-multiplayer-reminds-me-of-old-halo-and-i-mean-that-in-the-best-way"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I adored Halo 3 and Halo Reach's multiplayer. So much so, I never want to play them again. In my mind, I view them through a next-gen lens, coloured by nostalgia and post-homework energy. I know that if I jump into the Halo: The Master Chief Collection, I simply won't be able to recapture those heady times. I'm genuinely afraid of tarnishing those memories.
Halo 4 didn't do it for me, and I skipped Halo 5 altogether. They just felt off, you know? But having spent some time with Halo Infinite's tech preview this weekend, though, I'm hopeful that this is the Halo that recaptures those former glory days. It's a step backwards in the best possible way.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruis'n Blast On The Switch Is Arcade Racing At Its Most Ridiculous]]></title>
        <id>1847759764</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/cruisn-blast-on-the-switch-is-arcade-racing-at-its-most-1847759764"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft and Sony can have their Forzas and Gran Turismos with hyper-realistic graphics, authentic engine noises, and true-to-life physics. The Nintendo Switch has Cruis’n Blast, in which your vaguely Nissan GT-R-shaped vehicle barrels off a cliff at breakneck speed toward a massive yeti which then cracks open a…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: The New Trailer For Pokémon Diamond & Pearl Confirms What We All Knew About Bidoof]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121547</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/random_the_new_trailer_for_pokemon_diamond_and_pearl_confirms_what_we_all_knew_about_bidoof"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bidoof, Bidoof, Bidoof is on fire.
Bidoof is a meme. He is a phenomenon. Where did the love for this weird little beaver guy come from? He certainly wasn't always this popular, and he's not actually that good of a Pokémon.
A large part of Bidoof's fame is due to his nature as an "HM slave" — the unofficial (and kinda mean) term used to describe a Pokémon that you keep in your party specifically to learn all of the useful real-world moves in the game. You don't want your championship Pokémon to have to learn a move like Flash or Rock Smash, after all — they might be vital for traversing the world, but they're absolute pants in battle.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 open beta dates confirmed, starts October 8]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-open-beta-dates-confirmed-starts-october-8</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-open-beta-dates-confirmed-starts-october-8"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:22:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the recent delay of Battlefield 2042's launch into November, Electronic Arts have now confirmed new timing for the open beta test of Dice's near-future shooter. It'll start on Friday the 8th of October and run until the morning of  Sunday the 10th, inviting everyone to play Conquest mod on the map Orbital.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodboy Galaxy Smashes Kickstarter Goal, Physical Game Boy Advance And Switch Editions Confirmed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121526</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/goodboy_galaxy_smashes_kickstarter_goal_physical_game_boy_advance_and_switch_editions_confirmed"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And you can still order a copy.
Remember Goodboy Galaxy, the new Game Boy Advance game that hit Kickstarter towards the end of last month? Well, we're happy to report that the project has smashed its funding goals – and that's an understatement.
With the campaign now wrapped up, Goodboy Galaxy surpassed 1000% funding, with almost 4,000 backers generating a whopping £203,929 in total. The original goal was a relatively modest £18,000, so you could certainly say the whole thing's been something of a success.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Echoes Of The Eye is sensational DLC for Outer Wilds - don’t let anyone spoil it for you]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/echoes-of-the-eye-is-sensational-dlc-for-outer-wilds-dont-let-anyone-spoil-it-for-you</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/echoes-of-the-eye-is-sensational-dlc-for-outer-wilds-dont-let-anyone-spoil-it-for-you"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Echoes Of The Eye, the new expansion for Outer Wilds, is out... now! And I’d like to congratulate Mobius Digital and Annapurna on just how little promoting their promotional campaign did. The reveal trailer did anything but, showing us the familiar solar system of Outer Wilds, only with the beginning of an eclipse followed by shots of murky caves and forests. And take a look at the official screenshots used in this article: obscured to the point of ugliness. Here’s a team so determined to keep their secrets they’d rather present the game in an unflattering light. It was worth it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weekspot podcast #055: eye and mighty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-055-outer-wilds-echoes-of-the-eye</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-055-outer-wilds-echoes-of-the-eye"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, the main point of discussion on this week's podcast is the Outer Wilds: Echoes Of The Eye DLC. Talking about it is tricky, because saying pretty much anything about it feels spoiler-y. Christ, I'm trying to be careful writing this blurb in case I say something that I shouldn't. But, somehow, I think we managed to talk about it, without talking about it. Know what I mean?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox players are making loads of Squid Game games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-players-are-making-loads-of-squid-game-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-players-are-making-loads-of-squid-game-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:51:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Squid Game is a South Korean survival drama show that's been taking Netflix by storm recently, and it's inspired a whole bunch of Squid Game games on Roblox. The show pits folks against each other in games like tug-of-war, where the winners earn cash, and the losers earn, well, death. It's a fun (read: somehow even more sinister) twist on the battle royale genre. It reminds me a bit of when the Hunger Games films inspired loads of Minecraft mods.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best New World weapons tier list: ranking the best weapons in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-new-world-weapons-tier-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-new-world-weapons-tier-list"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:35:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best weapons in New World? The highly-anticipated MMO New World from Amazon Game Studios is now available as a full release, and for most players getting stuck into life on Aeternum Island, putting together a good selection of weapons will be their number one priority. In this tier list, we've ranked each weapon according to our experiences, and also put together some pointers on choosing the best weapons for your play style.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Horizon Forbidden West’s Aloy Will Look Realistic AF On PS5, Peach Fuzz And All]]></title>
        <id>1847759467</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/horizon-forbidden-west-s-aloy-will-look-realistic-af-on-1847759467"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Horizon Zero Dawn, the 2017 open-world game about listening to Lance Reddick’s silky smooth pipes, was a looker, pushing the boundaries of how pretty a game could be on the PlayStation 4, despite coming out halfway through the console’s life cycle. It should come as little surprise that the sequel, next year’s Horizon…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show Your Love For Metroid Dread With These Officially Licensed Switch Accessories]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121504</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/show_your_love_for_metroid_dread_with_these_officially_licensed_switch_accessories"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Switch case and controller available to order now.
If Metroid Dread's super fancy Special Edition isn't exciting enough, there are now even more goodies to buy that'll let you really celebrate the game's release next month.
From accessory maker PowerA, a brand new controller design and Switch case featuring Metroid Dread artwork are set to launch just after the game's release in October. They're both available from Amazon US as we speak (the controller is $27.99 and the case is $12.99), and will ship from 15th October.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Nintendo Switch Pokémon Will Have Bits That Look Kinda Like A Game Boy]]></title>
        <id>1847759349</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-nintendo-switch-pokemon-will-have-bits-that-look-ki-1847759349"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl got a new trailer Tuesday morning, showing off all kinds of neat new details. For example, there will be an improved Pokétch utility watch, Pokémon hangout parks, and surfing Bidoofs. It also sounds like all those pesky HMs present in the original games won’t be a bother…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Maligned Avengers Get Second Chance on Xbox Game Pass]]></title>
        <id>1847759332</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-maligned-avengers-get-second-chance-on-xbox-game-pa-1847759332"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a world where blockbuster comic book video games flounder due to repetitive endgame content, one subscription game service takes Earth’s mightiest heroes under its wing. It’s Xbox Game Pass to Marvel’s Avengers’ rescue as the multiplayer superhero game joins Microsoft’s service this Thursday.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soapbox: Wave Race 64 Is Now 25 Years Old, And It Still Rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121508</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/soapbox_wave_race_64_is_now_25_years_old_and_it_still_rules"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maximum Power!

Let's get the controversial early opinion out of the way, just so any pitchfork wielders can start sharpening their implements right away: a lot of Nintendo 64 games haven't aged very well. Of course they haven't, because it was a console in which Nintendo was at the bleeding edge of 3D graphical technology, a bold move that seized it a place in history as the company delivered genre-defining home console experiences that simply hadn't been possible before. In terms of consoles, it was a system with games that set the 3D standards in platformers, first-person shooters, action-adventure games, you name it. Mario, The Legend of Zelda and even good-old 007 blew minds back in the late-'90s.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Arceus Introduces 'Noble' Monsters]]></title>
        <id>1847759096</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-arceus-introduces-noble-monsters-1847759096"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new Pokémon Legends: Arceus trailer has just hatched, and alongside lots of new footage of the game, it reveals the existence of a whole new class of monsters: Noble Pokémon. The first of which is Kleavor.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Pac-Man: Birth Of An Icon' Celebrates One Of Gaming's Most Timeless Characters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121538</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pac-man_birth_of_an_icon_celebrates_one_of_gamings_most_timeless_characters"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Waka-waka-wonderful.
Namco's Pac-Man is a video game that needs no introduction. Toru Iwatani's 1980 coin-op smash-hit has spawned sequels, TV shows, songs, merchandise and much more besides, and the character is so famous he's even included in the Super Smash Bros. Ultimate roster. Plenty has been written about the pill-shaped hero over the past 40 years, but Pac-Man: Birth of an Icon aims to be the definitive account of his creation, success and legacy.
Published by Cook and Becker and written by Arjan Terpstra and Tim Lapetino, this impressive tome charts the early history not just of Pac-Man, but of Namco itself. Peppered with insightful interviews, it looks at the history of the Japanese coin-op industry, and how Japanese games dominated the arcade scene in the west. Even the interesting story of how the unofficial-then-official sequel Ms. Pac-Man came to be is covered here.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time looping arena shooter Lemnis Gate is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/time-looping-arena-shooter-lemnis-gate-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/time-looping-arena-shooter-lemnis-gate-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA['Tis the season of the time loop. If you have any space left in your brain after Deathloop for more groundhog day-like shenanigans, you might be interested in Lemnis Gate, a strategic first-person shooter that launched today. It pits players against each other in 1v1 and 2v2 matches, letting you plan out moves in 25 second-long rounds. It sounds a little confusing, but seems pretty fun. It also has some excellent-looking sci-fi backgrounds and laser guns, which is truly the most important part.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cult GameCube Shmup 'Castle of Shikigami 2' Is Headed To Switch This December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121522</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/cult_gamecube_shmup_castle_of_shikigami_2_is_headed_to_switch_this_december"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With new modes and a fresh translation.
Publisher Degica Games and developers Alfa System and Cosmo Machia have confirmed that they will be releasing an updated version of the cult GameCube shoot ’em up Castle of Shikigami 2 on Switch in December.
The vertically-scrolling blaster first appeared in arcades in 2003 and was ported to the GameCube in October of the same year. PlayStation 2, Dreamcast, Xbox and PC ports followed in 2004. The third game in the series launched on Nintendo Wii.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Little Golf Journey Brings A Relaxing Take On The Sport To Switch Next Month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121516</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/a_little_golf_journey_brings_a_relaxing_take_on_the_sport_to_switch_next_month"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Intriguing narrative with puzzles aplenty".
Remember earlier this summer when Playtonic Friends announced A Little Golf Journey for Switch? Well, it may have come a little later than expected, but a solid release date has now been announced for the title – and we don't have long to wait.
The game will be swinging onto the eShop on 14th October, bringing some pleasantly soothing vibes along for the ride. Developed by Okidokico, the game is said to be "all about the journey, not the driver", as players explore different biomes, uncover secrets, and – if the trailer above's anything to go by – enjoy a wonderfully peaceful soundtrack.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything we know about Dripstone in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-dripstone-infinite-lave-source</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-dripstone-infinite-lave-source"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:01:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn more about Dripstone in Minecraft? Caves are getting a huge revamp in Minecraft 1.18, and Dripstone is going to be an important new block, as you can use it to make an infinite lava source in your base.
This guide will explain everything you need to know about Dripstone, including where you will be able to find it and how to use Pointed Dripstone to create a lava farm in Minecraft.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl - Nigel Thornberry Move Set Showcase]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121450</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/exclusive_nickelodeon_all-star_brawl_-_nigel_thornberry_move_set_showcase"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing!
The launch of Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl is just one week away. Come 5th October, fans of Nickelodeon series such as Spongebob, Ninja Turtles, The Loud House, Rugrats, Hey Arnold!, Ren & Stimpy and more will be able to scrap in a Smash Bros.-style free-for-all, and today Nintendo Life has an exclusive first look at one of the fighters: Nigel from The Wild Thornberrys.
The developer-hosted showcase video above gives you a good idea of the animalistic abilities and smashing moves of one Nigel Archibald Thornberry, animal lover, moustachioed pilot and nasally gifted patriarch of the Thornberry clan. Below we've got his full move set broken down in a handy chart:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Brilliant Diamond & Shining Pearl Trailer Shows New Pokétch HM App, Poffins And More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121534</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pokemon_brilliant_diamond_and_shining_pearl_trailer_shows_new_poketch_hm_app_poffins_and_more"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Use HMs directly from the Pokétch!
Not content with only giving us a new look at Pokémon Legends: Arceus today, The Pokémon Company has also shared a brand new trailer for Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl.
This latest clip gives us our first glimpse at how the Pokétch will work in the remakes – you'll notice some familiar apps being used on the device, as well a function which appears to let you use HMs. Handy!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ampere Altra Max M128-30 Linux Performance Preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30562</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30562"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past month we have started our testing of Ampere's Altra Max M128-30, the company's new 128 core server processor, and in this article today are our initial benchmarks of this promising chip for high core count servers in both 1P and 2P configurations tested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.2.194 Brings New Extension For Google's Fuchsia OS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-1.2.194-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-1.2.194-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:29:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.2.194 is out as the latest spec revision to this high performance graphics and compute API...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Pokémon Legends: Arceus Trailer Reveals Brand New Pokémon, Kleavor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121532</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/new_pokemon_legends_arceus_trailer_reveals_brand_new_pokemon_kleavor"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And a deeper look at the game's features.
A brand new trailer has dropped for Pokémon Legends: Arceus, giving us another close look at the game and even revealing a brand new Pokémon.
The new footage offers a deeper dive into some of the game's menus and customisation options, while also showing off new ways to catch Pokémon – did you spot the moment the player throws a Poké Ball while riding on a Basculegion?!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picolibc Continues Maturing As Very Lightweight C Library For The Embedded World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Picolibc-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Picolibc-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Keith Packard is known for his work on X11/X.Org, the past few years he has also been developing Picolibc as a C library intended for embedded systems. He also recently jumped from SiFive to Amazon and appears at the ecommerce giant to be working on Picolibc in an official capacity, presumably for use on Amazon's growing hardware devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XIV Player Literally Dabs On Boss With Kinect]]></title>
        <id>1847756494</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-player-literally-dabs-on-boss-with-ki-1847756494"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XIV, like most video games, is far from physically taxing despite the often-incredible feats performed by your character on-screen. But what if you, say, actually had to dance to get the Dancer job moving? Absolute madman Super Louis 64 answered this question earlier today, and the results are pretty…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Steel Assault - A Quick Bite To Savour With Classic Castlevania Flavour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121087</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/steel_assault"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[*furiously shreds guitar*.
Steel Assault is a pretty simple game. You play as a badass good guy whose job is to kill the badass bad guys, and you do so by violently blowing up a lot of minions, ninjas, and mech suits with the power of a lightning whip. It’s hard. Like, really hard. And just when it feels like it’s running short on ideas, the credits roll. Sometimes that’s all you need to have fun with a game; just a few good ideas that are done extremely well. Steel Assault gets what it’s going for and doesn’t waste any more of your time, and in that respect, it’s almost impossible to dislike.
In terms of gameplay, Steel Assault plays like a more fluid, but no less difficult, take on the classic Castlevania platformers. Taro Takahashi’s main means of disposing of enemies is a super cool electric whip that dispatches most foes in a single crack, making you feel quite powerful once you get the rhythm of it down and scourge dozens of enemies in quick succession. He can fling it in eight directions and there’s a nice feeling of momentum behind each swing, as Taro takes that important brief pause after each button press to wind up before initiating the attack.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Next 'Musou' Game, Touken Ranbu Warriors, Launches On Switch In May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121521</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/the_next_musou_game_touken_ranbu_warriors_launches_on_switch_in_may_2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Based on the popular browser-based card game.
Did you like Hyrule Warriors and Fire Emblem Warriors? Then you might be interested to learn that Koei Tecmo has revealed that it is bringing Touken Ranbu Warriors to North America and Europe.
Known as Touken Ranbu Musou in Japan, it's the next entry in the long-running 'Musou' series of video games. Touken Ranbu – which translates as "Wild Dance of Swords" – is a browser-based free-to-play collectable card game that launched in Japan in January 2015, with a worldwide release taking place in April 2021. It has since spawned two anime series, stage plays and a live-action film. The series is especially popular with female players.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OmniOS Adds VirtFS File Sharing For Bhyve, Better System Console Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OmniOS-r151038</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OmniOS-r151038"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T12:09:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Solaris/Illumos ecosystem certainly isn't vibrant these days like back during the Sun Microsystems times with OpenSolaris, but OmniOS continues progressing as one of the few still-active and useful Solaris/Illumos-powered platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How NEO: The World Ends With You captures the 15 year evolution of Shibuya, and is a better game for it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-neo-the-world-ends-with-you-captures-the-15-year-evolution-of-shibuya-and-is-a-better-game-for-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-neo-the-world-ends-with-you-captures-the-15-year-evolution-of-shibuya-and-is-a-better-game-for-it"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NEO: The World Ends With You is out on PC today (via the Epic Games Store), and marks the grand return of a franchise that, despite a rabid fanbase and numerous re-releases, is only receiving its first sequel after 15 years. The original The World Ends With You impressed audiences on Nintendo DS as much for the game’s stylish Tokyo setting as it did for a unique battle system that saw players control multiple characters on multiple screens simultaneously. Yet what made this game really memorable was how it transformed the fashion and pop-cultural power of Shibuya into its own JRPG battle system. Your drip gave you strength, your armor made you a trendsetter, and the music and energy of the city were translated into a story about coming-of-age, self-worth and finding strength in yourself and your friends by embracing the things that make you unique. 
Now, NEO: The World Ends With You has arrived, but this long-awaited sequel is far from a simple retread of what the first game did 15 years ago. Shibuya itself has changed a lot in the intervening years and it's fascinating to see how NEO's setting and its gameplay mechanics have evolved alongside it. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alicia Haddick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gigabyte G5 review: a ray tracing gaming laptop at a good price]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gigabyte-g5-review-a-ray-tracing-gaming-laptop-at-a-good-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gigabyte-g5-review-a-ray-tracing-gaming-laptop-at-a-good-price"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T11:35:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With graphics card prices being what they are, gaming laptops like the Gigabyte G5 have been making a lot more sense. Believe it or not, this particular model is – at £850 / $969 – one of the cheapest routes possible into a complete PC gaming system with Nvidia’s RTX ray tracing and DLSS powers.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD dosáhla 16% podílu v serverech, Xeony Ice Lake stále nedostatkové]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42857</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-dosahla-16-podilu-v-serverech-xeony-ice-lake-stale-nedostatkove/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T10:53:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před lety varoval tehdejší šéf Intelu Brian Krzanich před tím, aby AMD získalo 15–20% podíl v serverech (resp. že jej získá), na úkor firemních výdělečných Xeonů. Intel ale stále není schopen dodat novou generaci Xeonů v množství dostatečném pro saturování zákazníků, takže ti častěji pokukují po EPYCech od AMD, které ostatně nabízí lepší parametry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK advertising authority set guidance for in-game purchases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uk-advertising-authority-set-guidance-for-in-game-purchases</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uk-advertising-authority-set-guidance-for-in-game-purchases"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T10:49:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As various UK agencies and organisations continue to regard microtransactions and loot boxes with escalating curiosity and suspicion, the Advertising Standards Authority have laid out new guidelines for advertising in-game in purchases. Basically, they think games should be clear about what they're selling and how much things cost in real money, and that advertising shouldn't pressure or mislead. The ASA are relatively toothless but fairly prolific, and their interest might lead to more official interest.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon's MMO New World is out now, but the servers are struggling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazons-mmo-new-world-is-out-now-but-the-servers-are-struggling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazons-mmo-new-world-is-out-now-but-the-servers-are-struggling"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T10:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At long last, Amazon's MMO New World has launched. After multiple delays and two rather popular betas, folks can now jump onto the supernatural island of Aeternum and stay there for as long as they please. The EU servers are already live, with the rest of the world to follow throughout today. Do watch out if you're jumping in this morning though, because some players are reporting long queue times, while others are struggling to get into the queue in the first place.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Mattress Designed For Gamers Goes On Sale In Japan]]></title>
        <id>1847757874</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/a-mattress-designed-for-gamers-goes-on-sale-in-japan-1847757874"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are gaming chairs, gaming keyboards, and gaming energy drinks. All that is old hat! In Japan, there are now mattresses for gamers. 
That’s right, gaming mattresses! Japan’s Bauhutte has made its name by selling loungewear for gamers, as well as gaming desks, chairs, and even beds. The latest item it’s added to…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard commit to $18 million settlement with Equal Employment Opportunity Commission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-commit-to-18-million-settlement-with-equal-employment-opportunity-commission</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-commit-to-18-million-settlement-with-equal-employment-opportunity-commission"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:59:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard have agreed to create a claims fund of $18 million (£13m) for employees who experienced harm from "sexual harassment, pregnancy discrimination and/or related retaliation". This is part of a settlement with the USA's Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), who had taken Actiblizz to court with allegations of those issues. This is only one of Activision Blizzard's current legal battles over alleged workplace problems, and not the big one you're probably thinking of. The company also had to agree to, like, not do any of those bad things—but the settlement is not an admission of guilt.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora's Java Packages Have Fallen Into Rough Shape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-Java-Rough-Shape</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-Java-Rough-Shape"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T09:51:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While many years ago Fedora's Java support was in great shape with quickly integrating OpenJDK going back to IcedTea, these days Fedora's Java packages are barely maintained and largely fallen into disrepair...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Studios Japan Is Adding A New Donkey Kong-Themed Area]]></title>
        <id>1847757646</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/universal-studios-japan-is-adding-a-new-donkey-kong-the-1847757646"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T05:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Super Nintendo World first opened at Universal Studios Japan in Osaka earlier this March, yet the theme park area is already set to get its first expansion. Opening in 2024, it will be Donkey Kong-themed and will increase the size of Super Nintendo World by about 70 percent. 
“Super Nintendo World creates a whole new…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Posts Code Enabling "Cyan Skillfish" Display Support Due To Different DCN2 Variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Cyan-Skillfish-DCN-2.01</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Cyan-Skillfish-DCN-2.01"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since July we've seen AMD open-source driver engineers posting code for "Cyan Skillfish" as an APU with Navi 1x graphics. While initial support for Cyan Skillfish was merged for Linux 5.15, it turns out the display code isn't yet wired up due to being a different DCN2 variant for its display block...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ars Technica: pohled na Btrfs, věčně nedodělaný linuxový souborový systém]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ars-technica-pohled-na-btrfs-vecne-nedodelany-linuxovy-souborovy-system</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ars-technica-pohled-na-btrfs-vecne-nedodelany-linuxovy-souborovy-system"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T02:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim Salter na webu Ars Technica ve stručnosti shrnuje vlastnosti souborového systému Btrfs ve srovnání s alternativami (OpenZFS, mdraid+LVM+ext4) a ve zbytku článku varuje před jeho implementací RAID. V navazujících textech se plánuje věnovat dalším funkcím Btrfs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard Settles With Federal Employment Agency For $18 Million (Updated)]]></title>
        <id>1847756366</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/now-there-are-three-u-s-government-groups-suing-activi-1847756366"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T23:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update 09/27/2021 7:45 p.m. ET: Activision Blizzard just put out a press release indicating that it has reached an agreement to settle the just-revealed U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission lawsuit. It states in part:
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[League Of Legends series Arcane premieres throughout November]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/league-of-legends-series-arcane-premieres-throughout-november</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/league-of-legends-series-arcane-premieres-throughout-november"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T22:37:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yet another beefy trailer and launch date exploded out of Netflix's corner this weekend. Their upcoming animated series Arcane, set in the universe of Riot's League Of Legends, has gotten one of each. The new trailer down here digs into the dynamic between protagonist sisters Vi and Jinx. The release date, at least the first of them, is coming up pretty quick too, scheduled for November 6th.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTubers Show Old Switch And New OLED Model Running Side By Side]]></title>
        <id>1847755781</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/youtubers-show-old-switch-and-new-oled-model-running-si-1847755781"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T22:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nintendo Switch — OLED Model is coming out soon, and Nintendo recently held events at which the press could try it out alongside Metroid Dread. YouTube channel Nintendo Prime, a gaming enthusiast channel with a preference for Nintendo games, obtained footage of a Switch OLED sent to them by an anonymous viewer.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam may be planning to restrict player access to old game builds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-may-be-planning-to-restrict-player-access-to-old-game-builds</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-may-be-planning-to-restrict-player-access-to-old-game-builds"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T21:55:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As they always do, things in Steam are likely to change again. Unlike Valve's Steam Labs experiments for storefront discoverability or downstream effects of the upcoming Steam Deck, this one is a little more under the hood. As spotted by the unaffiliated Steam tracking site SteamDB, the beta version of Steam's client now has a new method that is capable of preventing users from accessing former builds of games they own. The majority of players likely aren't pulling up old game builds often, if ever, but this change could make life a lot tougher for modders, speedrunners, and anyone trying to roll back a buggy game update while they wait for a hotfix.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 To Bring Initial DisplayPort 2.0 Support For AMD Radeon Driver (AMDGPU)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-DP-2.0-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-DP-2.0-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T21:46:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A batch of feature updates was submitted today for DRM-Next of early feature work slated to come to the next version of the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Unite Survey Suggests Huge Changes Could Be Coming]]></title>
        <id>1847754725</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-unite-survey-suggests-huge-changes-could-be-com-1847754725"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that Pokémon Unite has made its Android and iOS debut, developer TiMi Studio Group has pushed out an in-game survey for players to complete. The questionnaire suggests that some new features, like additional game modes and more ways to interact with your monsters, might come to the popular MOBA in the future.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oculus announces Resident Evil 4 VR release date for October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oculus-announces-resident-evil-4-vr-release-date-for-october</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oculus-announces-resident-evil-4-vr-release-date-for-october"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:14:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October is creeping up on us all and, like a proper jump scare just before I'd expected it, so has Resident Evil 4 VR. Leon Kennedy's spooky cult adventure begins again in the first-person and hands-on version that's arriving on the Oculus Quest 2 next month. Now that you'll be getting all up close and personal with Salazar and Saddler and El Gigante and all, they've gotten some fresh pixels as well, which you can catch a look at once again in a new trailer.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rune Factory 5 Will Finally Let The Gays Marry]]></title>
        <id>1847754456</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/rune-factory-5-will-finally-let-the-gays-marry-1847754456"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a lengthy blog post, Rune Factory 5’s publishers confirmed that the English localization will allow same-gender marriages. This decision marks the first time that Rune Factory players can get gay married without a workaround.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastward: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847753920</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/eastward-the-kotaku-review-1847753920"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eastward is a phenomenally constructed video game. All of its music hits. The characters are relentlessly charming. Its art and level design are nothing short of extraordinary. Disregarding a few pacing missteps, the game fires on all cylinders for its entire duration. Hell, they even put a second video game in the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Intel Software Defined Silicon" Coming To Linux For Activating Extra Licensed Hardware Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Software-Defined-Silicon</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Software-Defined-Silicon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:45:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has been talk of Intel moving to offer more license-able/opt-in features for hardware capabilities found within a given processor as an upgrade. We are now seeing the Linux signs of that support coming with a driver for "Intel Software Defined Silicon" to allow for the secure activation of such features baked into the processor's silicon but only available as an up-charge option...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix's lady assassin movie Kate is getting an action roguelike tie-in game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-lady-assassin-movie-kate-is-getting-an-action-roguelike-tie-in-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-lady-assassin-movie-kate-is-getting-an-action-roguelike-tie-in-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been positively held hostage by the lady assassin action movie trend—having been in the same room as my partner relentlessly devouring the likes of The Old Guard, Ava, Terminal, and Gunpowder Milkshake. No surprise then that I also got sucked into watching Kate, Netflix's new action movie starring assassin Mary Elizabeth Winstead and her teen hostage slash sidekick Miku Martineau. What is surprising—even though Netflix have shown an increasing interest in games—is that Kate is getting a tie-in action game called Kate: Collateral Damage. It's a fast-paced and arcade-y roguelike with some twin-stick style shooting coming out in October.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This 27-in 240Hz Samsung monitor is £229 right now (£70 off)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-27-in-240hz-samsung-monitor-is-229-right-now-70-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-27-in-240hz-samsung-monitor-is-229-right-now-70-off"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T17:55:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a while, I was super into Counter-Strike: Global Offensive, and I took getting better at the game very seriously. I swapped out my mouse and headset, practiced grenade line-ups for hours and even learned a few Russian phrases to try and get the respect of my match-making teammates. All these steps worked, but the real results came when I swapped my old 144Hz monitor for a 240Hz model, the Samsung CRG5. Hitting such a high frame-rate in Counter-Strike isn't difficult even on old hardware, and the increase in clarity meant hitting shots a lot easier. 
If you want to follow in my footsteps, then it's good news: this 240Hz screen is going cheap on Amazon today. They're asking £229 for it, £70 off its regular price of £299, and I think that's a great deal. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung's 2TB 870 Evo SSD is down to £197.50 at Amazon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/samsungs-2tb-870-evo-ssd-is-down-to-19750-at-amazon</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/samsungs-2tb-870-evo-ssd-is-down-to-19750-at-amazon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:55:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We reckon that Samsung's 870 Evo is the best SATA SSD for gaming, and today the mammoth 2TB model has been reduced on Amazon. It's now retailing for £197.50, the best price we've seen on this drive since the Chia mining craze began and some £45 below RRP. It's even cheaper than the (older and slower) 860 Evo. Here's a link to the deal and a few more words on why we like this particular drive so very much. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix shows off more The Witcher season 2 clips and announces season 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-shows-off-more-the-witcher-season-2-clips-and-announces-season-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-shows-off-more-the-witcher-season-2-clips-and-announces-season-3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you thought there was any risk of Netflix dumping Geralt and company in the near future, you can rest your head easy after this weekend. They've now shown off several more clips for the upcoming second season of their main, Cavill-powered Witcher TV series and also announced that they're definitely going to be going for a third season. Not just that, but there are even more Witcher projects on the way: another animated movie, that Blood Origin series, and—for some unfathomable reason—a children's show. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commuting home from work turns mighty spooky in this indie game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/commuting-home-from-work-turns-mighty-spooky-in-this-indie-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/commuting-home-from-work-turns-mighty-spooky-in-this-indie-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:56:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Plane Effect is a moody isometric adventure game about a guy trying to get home. Pretty normal stuff, except there is a cosmic anomaly looming over the city that seems to be causing some weirdness, so good luck with that. Out now, the game will have you puzzling through levels full of high-contrast moody lighting. It reminds me a bit of Inside, if Inside had rooms full of scary-looking red lasers.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing ingredients in Potion Craft is better than meditation or yoga]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/smashing-ingredients-in-potion-craft-is-better-than-mediation-or-yoga</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/smashing-ingredients-in-potion-craft-is-better-than-mediation-or-yoga"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T14:39:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Potion Craft came out in early access last week, and while I still think the economy and haggling bits need a little tweaking, I am really enjoying the methodical nature of being an alchemist. It's part art, part science, because you have to sort of feel your way around the potion map and fudge recipes with the ingredients you have. Your recipe book is limited, so I've started writing down extra recipes in real life, crossing things out and updating them as I find better combinations. It's just like being a real backwoods alchemist throwing twigs in a bucket!
But my favourite thing is the pestle and mortar. Smashing ingredients up (and grinding them into sludge) awakens their properties so they move further on your potion map, like how crushing mint will make for a livelier mojito. And I love it intensely.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 will make murderbot Bastion more mobile]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-will-make-murderbot-bastion-more-mobile</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-will-make-murderbot-bastion-more-mobile"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rejoice! The absolute pain in the arse that is Bastion is getting a rework for Overwatch 2, and he'll no longer be able to heal himself or turn into a murderous tank. He will be a lot more mobile and have a sticky grenade however, so watch out for that. Over the weekend, Blizzard revealed the changes coming to both Bastion and Sombra in the sequel. While Sombra's tweaks are a little more minimal, it looks like Bastion's will make him play a whole lot differently. Importantly, he'll also wear one of Torbjorn's caps. Fashion.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghostscript 9.55.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ghostscript-9.55.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ghostscript-9.55.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:57:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze 9.55.0 interpretu PostScriptu (PS) a Portable Document Formatu (PDF) Ghostscript. Mimo jiné byla opravena bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2021-3781, na kterou byl nedávno zveřejněn exploit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that we know about the Warden in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-warden-deep-dark</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-warden-deep-dark"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:07:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about the Warden in Minecraft? The Warden is a new mob that will arrive in Minecraft 1.18, otherwise known as the Caves and Cliffs update. It is set to be a terrifying addition, making every adventure underground a trip that could result in a particularly scary death.
This guide will cover everything that we currently know about the Warden in Minecraft, including its behaviour and where it will spawn.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing The New ASUS Platform Profile Support In Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30554</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30554"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:15:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the in-development Linux 5.15 kernel there is now support for ACPI Platform Profiles on supported ASUS laptops. This ASUS laptop platform profile support joins the likes of HP, Dell, and Lenovo laptops already having this support exposed under Linux that allows users to control their power/performance preference. Here are some tests with the ASUS ROG Strix G15 AMD Advantage laptop with the platform profile options under Linux 5.15.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření HTTPS Everywhere míří do důchodu, už není potřeba]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42856</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rozsireni-https-everywhere-miri-do-duchodu-uz-neni-potreba/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Frontier Foundation se připravuje na postupné ukončení podpory pro rozšíření HTTPS Everywhere, které na webech automaticky přepíná z HTTP na HTTPS. To už podle organizace začíná být zbytečné, protože rozšíření HTTPS zažilo v posledních letech výrazný nárůst a prohlížeče navíc přišly s vlastním řešením automatického přechodu na HTTPS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSSH 8.8 vypíná podporu protokolu ssh-rsa]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42855</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/openssh-8-8-vypina-podporu-protokolu-ssh-rsa/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:03:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili novou verzi balíku OpenSSH s označením 8.8. Hlavní novinkou je vypnutí podpory protokolu ssh-rsa, který staví na slabém hašovacím algoritmu SHA-1. Na změnu upozorňovalo několik předchozích verzí, většina uživatelů si navíc ničeho nevšimne, protože OpenSSH podporuje algoritmy RSA/SHA-256/512 (RFC8332) od verze 7.2 a automaticky je použije.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astria Ascending review: peak tedium]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/astria-ascending-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/astria-ascending-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the face of it, Astria Ascending should be right up my street. With its lush visuals, intriguing character designs and often engaging turn-based battle system, this handsome hand drawn adventure could have been a surprise dark horse to rival recent JRPG greats such as Tales Of Arise and Bravely Default II. Colombian RPG Cris Tales managed it, so why not Astria Ascending?
French Canadian developers Artisan Studios have certainly tried hard to fulfill J part of this Japanese-inspired RPG, acquiring the talents of Final Fantasy XII composer Hitoshi Sakimoto and Final Fantasy X writer Kazushige Nojima to bolster their small team, but even these big name veterans can't salvage this game from the depths of its own tedium. Between its bewildering, colour-swap dungeons, cringeworthy voice acting and uneven focus on its large cast, Astria Ascending stumbles before it ever has the chance to soar. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim food and cooking: all recipes, what buffs they provide, and where to cook them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-food-cooking</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-food-cooking"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:25:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you cook in Valheim? Valheim has never been short on food and recipes, but with the recent Hearth & Home update, the game's cooking system has been significantly expanded and overhauled. Gone are the days when nearly every animal dropped the same generic type of meat, or when you could cook sausages without the right spices (ugh, so bland, you monster). The buffs offered by some of the original foods have also been rebalanced, so read on for an up-to-date culinary guide to Valheim.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected players still can't access some of their characters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-players-still-cant-access-some-of-their-characters</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-players-still-cant-access-some-of-their-characters"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:23:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected launched last week, letting players dive into a remaster of Blizzard's hellish action-RPG. Alas, "hellish" seems appropriate in more ways than one, because players are still struggling with launch bugs. While the developers issued a number of fixes over the weekend, some players are still experiencing "lockout", meaning they can't play with certain characters because the game thinks they're already in use.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kampaň na programovatelnou kameru OAK-D-Lite na Kickstarteru]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42853</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/kampan-na-programovatelnou-kameru-oak-d-lite-na-kickstarteru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:22:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na Kickstarteru před několika dny začala kampaň na novou verzi kamery OAK-D-Lite. Umožní snadno a rychle vytvořit aplikaci, která bude pracovat s obsahem videa. Může například rozpoznávat SPZ, překládat znakový jazyk, rozpoznávat gesta rukou a podobně.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[23. stretnutie komunity ohľadne technológií Cloud Native – Kubernetes - ONLINE]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42854</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/23-stretnutie-komunity-ohladne-technologii-cloud-native-kubernetes-online/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dňa 29. 9. 2021 od 18:00 do 20:00, 23. stretnutie komunity ohľadne technológií Cloud Native – Kubernetes – ONLINE]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elder Scrolls Online video shows Nvidia’s new DLAA tech in action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elder-scrolls-online-video-shows-nvidias-new-dlaa-tech-in-action</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elder-scrolls-online-video-shows-nvidias-new-dlaa-tech-in-action"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T10:37:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls Online is the first game to implement Nvidia DLAA (Deep Learning Anti-Aliasing), and thanks to YouTuber MxBenchmarkPC you can now see how the AI-powered edge-smoothing system looks in the fantasy MMO. DLAA is a new spin on Nvidia’s existing DLSS (Deep Learning Super-Sampling): whereas DLSS involves rendering a game at a lower resolution then upscaling, reducing the performance hit of the AA it applies, DLAA skips the upscaling part and keeps the resolution native.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSSH 8.8]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/openssh-8.8</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/openssh-8.8"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T10:09:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 8.8 sady aplikací pro SSH komunikaci OpenSSH. Dle plánu je ve výchozím nastavení zakázán algoritmus ssh-rsa kvůli možnému útoku na SHA-1. V blízké budoucnosti bude scp pro přenosy používat SFTP místo SCP/RCP. Řešena je bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2021-41617.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ELK Stack: naučte se Elasticsearch, Logstash a Kibana (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40262</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/elk-stack-naucte-se-elasticsearch-logstach-a-kibana-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:53:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Většina počítačových programů generuje logy – tedy zprávy a záznamy o své činnosti. ELK Stack – ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana – je populární nástroj, který umí logy efektivně zpracovávat, ukládat a zpřístupňovat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs Merges Support For Btrfs-Like Snapshots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bcachefs-Lands-Snapshots</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bcachefs-Lands-Snapshots"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:34:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a while since having any news to report on Bcachefs as the promising open-source file-system born out of the Linux kernel's block cache code. However, Kent Overstreet continues working tirelessly on it and has now merged Bcachefs' snapshot support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Crypto Driver Being Worked On For Linux, Yields Much Better AES Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Nintendo-AES-Crypto-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Nintendo-AES-Crypto-Driver"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:22:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel support around the Nintendo Wii and Wii U game console hardware continues to improve and now a new Nintendo crypto driver is being tackled based on reverse-engineered documentation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lavapipe Mesa Software Driver Enables Vulkan 1.2 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lavapipe-Vulkan-1.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lavapipe-Vulkan-1.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:10:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adding to the growing list of Mesa 21.3 features for next quarter's feature release is Lavapipe now supporting Vulkan 1.2...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MediaTek Hoping To Bring nanoMIPS Support Upstream Into GCC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MediaTek-2021-nanoMIPS-GCC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MediaTek-2021-nanoMIPS-GCC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The nanoMIPS architecture that was announced by MIPS in 2018 for embedded devices to lower power consumption and yield smaller code footprints was announced for the MIPS I7200 but since then there hasn't been much of nanoMIPS. However, MediaTek is now looking to contribute upstream the compiler support for this processor ISA into GCC...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toothpaste]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2521/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2521/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TeXstudio 4.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/texstudio-4.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/texstudio-4.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T23:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TeXstudio (Wikipedie), tj. integrované prostředí pro vytváření dokumentů v LaTeXu, bylo vydáno ve verzi 4.0.0. Přehled novinek v changelogu. Díky podpoře Qt6 byla vylepšena podpora HiDPI.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chcete vědět kolik byste mohli vydělávat u konkurence na stejné pozici?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/chcete-vedet-kolik-byste-mohli-vydelavat-u-konkurence-na-stejne-pozici</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/chcete-vedet-kolik-byste-mohli-vydelavat-u-konkurence-na-stejne-pozici"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peníze jsou ožehavé téma, obzvlášť jedná-li se o výplaty v zaměstnání. Člověk přemýšlí, zda kolegové nevydělávají víc nebo jestli by si u jiného zaměstnavatele nepolepšil. Jak to ale zjistit? Teď naštěstí jednoduše, protože IT pracovní portál No Fluff Jobs u všech nabídek zveřejňuje nabízené platové ohodnocení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: velká úroda malwaru i zranitelností]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15681</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-velka-uroda-malwaru-i-zranitelnosti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tentokrát se podíváme na zranitelnosti WordPressu, Drupalu, Apache OpenOffice a Nagiosu, na malware Capoae a OpenSUpdater. Naopak potěší, že provozovatel DDoSových serverů i mafiáni dojdou zasloužené odplaty.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CESNET CERTS)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční věstník: Ubuntu 21.10 v betě, LineageOS podporuje nová zařízení]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15677</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/distribucni-vestnik-ubuntu-21-10-v-bete-lineageos-podporuje-nova-zarizeni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical vydal veřejnou betu Ubuntu 21.10 „Impish Indri“. Tým kolem operačního systému FreeBSD plánuje změnit výchozí root shell. Operační systém LineageOS 18.1 rozšířil seznam podporovaných zařízení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc3 Released - Looking "Pretty Normal" Plus Performance Fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T21:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds has now issued the third weekly release candidate of the forthcoming Linux 5.15 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 92 vs. Chrome 94 Browser Benchmarks On Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-92-Chrome-94-Benchmarks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-92-Chrome-94-Benchmarks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T17:29:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given last week's release of Chrome 94, here are some fresh browser benchmarks looking at Firefox 92 stable against Chrome 94 running on Ubuntu Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Wget2 2.0 Released With HTTP2 & SSL Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Wget2-2.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Wget2-2.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T14:06:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Wget2 2.0 has been released for this successor to GNU Wget. There are many improvements to this GPLv3+ licensed program. Over the original GNU Wget, Wget2 is faster, supports more protocols especially around HTTP/2 and compression, supports multi-threading / parallel connections, and other improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-612</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-612"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for watching Antiques Roadshow with all your might. Before you tune in, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated AMD P-State Driver Published For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-amd-pstate-v2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-amd-pstate-v2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T10:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month AMD published their "amd-pstate" Linux driver that leverages ACPI CPPC data to make more informed CPU frequency scaling decisions with an aim to boost the performance-per-Watt for Zen 3 (and eventually Zen 2) processors on Linux. The second spin of that "amd-pstate" Linux kernel driver is now available for testing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fly-Pie 7]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fly-pie-7</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fly-pie-7"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T10:41:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření GNOME Shellu Fly-Pie přidávající do GNOME koláčové menu (marking menu, varianta pie menu) bylo vydáno ve verzi 7. Podporován je GNOME Shell 40 a novější. Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitHubu. Ukázka na YouTube.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux IO_uring Can Now Achieve Up To ~3.8M IOPS Per-Core]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-IO-3.8M-IOPS-Per-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-IO-3.8M-IOPS-Per-Core"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T10:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just last month when ~3.5M IOPS per-core was impressive with the code for Linux 5.15 to further push Linux's I/O limits. Now for code likely to be included in Linux 5.16 it's currently at 3.8M IOPS with a single tread...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm going to use the new N64 controller on PC and you can't stop me]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-going-to-use-the-new-n64-controller-on-pc-and-you-cant-stop-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-going-to-use-the-new-n64-controller-on-pc-and-you-cant-stop-me"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:57:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During this week's Nintendo Direct, we found out that N64 games would soon be playable on Switch via Nintendo's online subscription. More importantly, we found out that Nintendo are making a new wireless N64 controller for use with the Switch.

You can connect the Switch Pro controller to PC with or without a wire, so it stands to reason I'll be able to use this new N64 controller on PC too, right? Because if so, I'm gonna.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Umělá inteligence uprostřed jihoamerických lesů pomáhá zachránit psího samotáře]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-umela-inteligence-uprostred-jihoamerickych-lesu-pomaha-zachranit-psiho-samotare</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-umela-inteligence-uprostred-jihoamerickych-lesu-pomaha-zachranit-psiho-samotare"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Video, se kterým konečně pochopíte rozdíl mezi běžným a moderním úložištěm. Digitalizace zákaznické péče: jak vybrat nejlepší řešení kontaktního centra. Jaké novinky přináší Arcserve UDP 8.1? On-line konference VMworld 2021: stovky přednášek a tutoriálů zdarma. Gartner na křivce seřadil klíčové nastupující technologie. Studie Dell Technologies: hrozba ztráty dat po kyberútoku je větší, než kdy jindy. Umělá inteligence uprostřed jihoamerických lesů pomáhá zachránit psího samotáře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nový textový editor pro GNOME, 100% evropské RISC-V procesory EPI EPAC1.0]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15680</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/novy-textovy-editor-pro-gnome-100procentne-evropske-risc-v-procesory-epi-epac10/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beta verze Ubuntu 21.10, MidnightBSD 2.1 přechází na LLVM 10, Apple vydal iPhony 13, nabídne i ProRes video, vývojová verze Wine 6.18, Joe Biden jmenoval šéfku AMD do svého poradního týmu, AMD a Mediatek dohromady.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foxhole's Entrenched update makes the massive multiplayer shooter even bigger]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foxholes-entrenched-update-makes-the-massive-multiplayer-shooter-even-bigger</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foxholes-entrenched-update-makes-the-massive-multiplayer-shooter-even-bigger"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T21:44:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Foxhole has made foxholes better. The Entrenched update for the massive, multiplayer sandbox war game adds a lot, but top of the pile is new building tools for crafting better bunkers, trenches, and frontline defenses. The update is live now, and there's a video introducing its many features below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Signal State is a Zachlike about rewiring synthesizers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-signal-state-is-a-zachlike-about-rewiring-synthesizers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-signal-state-is-a-zachlike-about-rewiring-synthesizers"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T21:10:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it still a Zachlike if it's not made by Zachtronics? Because The Signal State sure looks like a Zachlike. It's about solving logic puzzles inspired by modular synthesizers, which means you'll tinker with ornate machinery by twisting knobs and changing wiring. It's also wrapped in a post-apocalyptic story in which your actions will "change the fate of agriculture."

It's out now. Check out the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitman is now on GOG, but getting slammed for its lack of offline features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-is-now-on-gog-but-getting-slammed-for-its-lack-of-offline-features</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-is-now-on-gog-but-getting-slammed-for-its-lack-of-offline-features"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T20:22:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news! Hitman: Game Of The Year Edition is now on GOG and 70% off. Bad news! The game requires an internet connection for so many singleplayer features that customers on the DRM-free digital store are real mad about it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BattlEye Anti-Cheat will support Steam Deck and Proton, too]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battleye-anti-cheat-will-support-steam-deck-and-proton-too</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battleye-anti-cheat-will-support-steam-deck-and-proton-too"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T19:45:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's claim that the Steam Deck would run every game in your Steam library is looking more and more like fact. Yesterday Easy Anti-Cheat announced support for Linux and the Proton compatibility laters the Deck relies upon. 

Today, BattlEye Anti-Cheat followed suit, announcing they'd support the Steam Deck and Proton in a tweet.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.24 On Wayland To Support DRM Leasing For VR Headsets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Plasma-5.24-DRM-Leasing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Plasma-5.24-DRM-Leasing"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T17:34:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the KDE Plasma 5.23 release quickly approaching, feature development is already heating up for Plasma 5.24 while concurrently driving many fixes into the v5.23 codebase...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Has Been Working On BOLT'ing The Linux Kernel For Greater Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Facebook-BOLTing-The-Kernel</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Facebook-BOLTing-The-Kernel"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T13:20:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For several years now Facebook engineers have been working on BOLT as a way to speed-up Linux/ELF binaries. This "Binary Optimization and Layout Tool" is able to re-arrange executables once profiled to generate even faster performance than what can be achieved by a compiler's LTO and PGO optimizations. One of the latest BOLT efforts has been on optimizing the Linux kernel image...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's User Interrupts With Sapphire Rapids Looking Quite Great For Faster IPC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-x86-User-Interrupts-LPC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-x86-User-Interrupts-LPC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T12:32:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month Intel engineers posted their initial Linux kernel enablement around x86 User Interrupts with this feature premiering with Xeon "Sapphire Rapids" CPUs. As implied by the name, the User Interrupt functionality allows for interrupts to bypass the kernel for more efficient, low-latency, low-utilization interrupts being received by other user-space tasks. Intel talked more about User Interrupts this week at LPC2021...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Úvahy o Borrow Checkeru pro C++]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42851</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/uvahy-o-borrow-checkeru-pro-c/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T10:43:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server This Week in Rust přinesl odkaz na zajímavý článek z pera tří vývojářů projektu Chromium. Autoři v něm rozvíjejí myšlenku implementovat v C++ stejná, nebo alespoň podobná pravidla paměťové bezpečnosti na úrovni typového systému, jako má Rust (tzv. Borrow Checking).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: klokan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenZFS 2.0.6 Released With Support For Newer Kernels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-2.0.6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-2.0.6-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T10:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the OpenZFS 2.1 feature release has been available since July, for those still using the OpenZFS 2.0.x series and not yet prepared to make the jump to that big new release with dRAID and other changes, OpenZFS 2.0.6 was released this week...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine-Staging 6.18 Released With 616 Patches Atop Upstream]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-6.18</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-6.18"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T09:52:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off yesterday's Wine 6.18 development release is now the next Wine-Staging installment that has more than six hundred extra patches on top...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-163</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-163"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, here we are: it is now autumn. I'm ready. I've folded my summer bedding away, pulled out the big duvet, and bought a bigger Thermos. And this is the nice part of autumn, when things are cosy and transitionary, before the feeling of death sets in. I was cheered by reading about your favourite autumn games this week. But anyway, what are you playing this weekend? Here's what we're clicking on.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XWayland GLX Path Enables sRGB Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-sRGB-Support</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-sRGB-Support"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another item is now crossed off the XWayland TODO list with OpenGL sRGB support wired up...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Handcop is a hilariously horrifying "fist person shooter" in development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/handcop-is-a-hilariously-horrifying-fist-person-shooter-in-development</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/handcop-is-a-hilariously-horrifying-fist-person-shooter-in-development"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:39:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handcop is a work in progress "fist person shooter" that's just as neat as it is horrifying. This wacky prodecurally-animated cop hand has three legs and chest hair for goodness sake. I can't decide if three "legs" is better or worse than three finger "arms". Oh, and of course officier Michael McWrist is running about carrying a giant gun. It's relatively early days for Handcop right now, it sounds like, but its wacky animations are already catching the internet's attention.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.18 Released With HID Joystick Enabled By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.18-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.18-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.18 has been popped as the newest bi-weekly development release of this software that allows Windows applications and games to run under Linux and in turn what also powers Steam Play's Proton...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 38/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-38-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-38-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frankenstein and Dracula are roomies in this moody narrative adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frankenstein-and-dracula-are-roomies-in-this-moody-narrative-adventure</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frankenstein-and-dracula-are-roomies-in-this-moody-narrative-adventure"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T21:36:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Dracula and Frankenstein are modern day 20-something flatmates who never see one another and only exchange sticky notes. Also they are both very sad. Also Dracula wears puple shades," is the kind of message I'd expect to see from one of my writing acquaintances with the timestamp [2:15am]. It's also the kind of thing I'd respond to with a "yes, do it," eager to find out exactly how the hell they would. That's the energy that I downloaded Frank And Drake's demo with, and it sure is a moody, somber narrative adventure about two unlikely housemates.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Castlevania Advance Collection whips out four classics now on PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/castlevania-advance-collection-whips-out-four-classics-now-on-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/castlevania-advance-collection-whips-out-four-classics-now-on-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T20:11:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dracula's back from the dead again and so are four Castlevania games from the aughts. Three different vampire stomping adventures originally hailing from the Game Boy Advance—and one SNES—have made their way into a new collection on PC via Steam. Two Belmonts, a Graves, and a Cruz all get their time to shine against those undead baddies in Castlevania: Circle Of The Moon, Harmony Of Dissonance, Aria Of Sorrow, and Dracula X. Konami launched the Castlevania Advance Collection yesterday, complete with some modern conveniences for us PC players in the year 2021.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BattlEye To Support Valve's Steam Deck / Proton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BattlEye-Proton-Steam-Deck</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BattlEye-Proton-Steam-Deck"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T19:52:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday it was Epic Games confirming Easy Anti-Cheat for Linux and Wine/Proton ahead of the Steam Deck launch and today it's BattlEye confirming Proton / Steam Deck support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IBM Engineer Has Been Exploring Possible Rust Modules For GRUB]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IBM-Possible-Rust-GRUB</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IBM-Possible-Rust-GRUB"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T18:50:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM engineer Daniel Axtens presented at this week's Linux Plumbers Conference on the prospects of using the Rust programming language for creating modules for the GRUB2 boot-loader...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This mod adds a universal photo mode to over 300 Unreal Engine games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mod-adds-a-universal-photo-mode-to-over-300-unreal-engine-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mod-adds-a-universal-photo-mode-to-over-300-unreal-engine-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T18:46:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo modes are undeniably in fashion now, so much so that I've just started assuming most major RPGs and third-person action games will have one built in at launch. I've never put in the time to get particularly skilled at lining up the best shots, but I'm always well impressed by those who do. It's a bummer though when a looker of a game doesn't have a way to really get up close and personal with its pretty cast and environments. Tales Of Arise, which just launched this month, doesn't have one yet, for instance. That's where the extremely nifty and very handy Universal Unreal Engine 4 Unlocker comes in. It's a mod that lets you toggle a free camera to take amazing screenshots in over 300 Unreal Engine games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Coreutils 9.0: cp Now Enables CoW By Default + Copy Offload, wc Now Uses AVX2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Coreutils-9.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Coreutils-9.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T17:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coreutils 9.0 is now available and it's a significant update to this collection of common open-source utilities found on effectively all Linux systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["TMORPG" Book Of Travels will launch in early access on October 11th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tmorpg-book-of-travels-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-11th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tmorpg-book-of-travels-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-11th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T16:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Might And Delight's "tiny Multiplayer Online RPG" Book Of Travels has scheduled itself a new early access launch date after its most recent delay. As M&D previously reassured fans, it is indeed a shorter wait than I'd feared. Their cozy online RPG is now setting out into early access on October 11th, with plans to work towards a full launch in two years.  

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[8 Minecraft castle ideas to build in 1.17]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-castle-ideas</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-castle-ideas"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T15:41:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to build an epic Castle in Minecraft? How about 8 castles? That’s how many we’ve got for you in this list, so you’d best get building! These castles look truly stunning, but we're sure they'll be even better atop the new mountains that are coming when the Minecraft 1.18 update launches later this year.
Check out all of these builds to get some inspiration for your own world in Minecraft, or just follow along with the Youtube tutorials if you like what you see!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squid Game is the perfect Netflix show for Zero Escape & Danganronpa likers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/squid-game-is-the-perfect-netflix-show-for-zero-escape-danganronpa-likers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/squid-game-is-the-perfect-netflix-show-for-zero-escape-danganronpa-likers"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Listen up, escape room fans. There's a new Korean drama you need to watch. It's called Squid Game, it's on Netflix, and it's real good. It's a show about 456 down and outers - folks with no life, family or who are in huge piles of debt - who enter a deadly competition to win a truck ton of money to help them turn their life around. All they need to do is compete in six games. Easy peasy, everyone thinks. How hard can that be? Only the first of those games, a riff on the classic children's game Statues / Grandma's Footsteps / Red Light Green Light - involves running toward a giant automaton with motion sensors in her eyes, as well as a team of snipers waiting in the rafters to take down anyone who does stay perfectly at the right time. 
It's grim, but it's also the perfect blend of some of my favourite things ever: Zero Escape, Danganronpa and Battle Royale (the Japanese thriller, not the game genre) - and I implore you to give it a go.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TFI Friday: 3 new indie games about soaking things in water]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-3-new-indie-games-about-soaking-things-in-water</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-3-new-indie-games-about-soaking-things-in-water"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T15:07:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love doing this column because it means a) it is the end of a working week (working hard or hardly working, amiright?) and b) I get to play something nice and (often) small, and usually a bit weird. I am also, as it turns out, really smug about the theme I discovered for this week. Last night I had a bath, so am ideally positioned to extoll the benefits of dunking things in water. May I present to you three brand new indie games: a frog's tea party, a potion workshop and a rainy walk.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge Of Spirits Warrior Path walkthrough]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-warrior-path-walkthrough-toshis-love</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-warrior-path-walkthrough-toshis-love"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:19:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck on the Warrior Path in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? You're not alone. The sheer number of portals and zipping between locations throughout the Warrior Path has led many a player to distraction and frustration. At least, until they found this handy walkthrough, which guides you carefully through every part of the Toshi's Love quest, through every combat area and puzzle, until you reach the end and defeat the Warrior himself.
Keep scrolling to read our written and our video walkthrough of the Warrior Path in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomb Raider reboot studio now working on Perfect Dark reboot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tomb-raider-reboot-studio-now-working-on-perfect-dark-reboot</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tomb-raider-reboot-studio-now-working-on-perfect-dark-reboot"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:18:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After rebooting Lara Croft with 2013's Tomb Raider, Square Enix's Crystal Dynamics studio are now helping reboot another vintage hero: Joanna Dark. They'll be chipping in on Microsoft's mysterious new Perfect Dark, helping out the mysterious Santa Monica studio named The Initiative. Secrecy might be thematically appropriate for a game about a futuristic superspy but we don't know much of anything about it so all you can really say is "Yup, I guess they're doing that."
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embrace the machine gun, Metal Dogs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embrace-the-machine-gun-metal-dogs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embrace-the-machine-gun-metal-dogs"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's all very silly. Having survived the grey, po-faced gruntman domination of the 2000s, I love that games can still be very silly.
Metal Dogs is a twin stick (sort of) shooter about sending heavy weapons platforms into irradiated future deserts to fight giant insects, ghost tanks, and robot hippos. Naturally, those heavy weapons platforms are strapped onto dogs.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave vydal Brave Talk: službu pro bezpečné videohovory]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42850</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/brave-vydal-brave-talk-sluzbu-pro-bezpecne-videohovory/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:35:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Brave, známá především svým internetovým prohlížečem zaměřeným na soukromí představila novou službu na bezpečné videohovory. Jmenuje se Brave Talk, v základu je zdarma, běží na Jitsi as a Service a je open-source. Začít můžete na talk.brave.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: spajk)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to install RAM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-ram</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-ram"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:31:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Installing RAM is both one of the easiest steps to building a PC and one of the simplest ways to upgrade an existing gaming rig. In a physical sense, anyway. Just like installing an M.2 SSD, there are no power or data cables to worry about, and as long as your RAM sticks fit the RAM slots on your motherboard, ultimately you just need to push them in. There is room for error, though, hence why this article is going to continue beyond the introductory paragraph. See? RAM can be interesting.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robot beings rule Mystery Steam Reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mystery-steam-reviews-054-video-games-robots</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mystery-steam-reviews-054-video-games-robots"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humans are boring. All fleshy and feelings and Netflix. Like this quiz, robots don't have hidden agendas. Robots want to wish Paulie a happy birthday, and we want to entertain you for quarter of an hour. It's the perfect match.
  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Send Thatcher back to Hell in this new Doom 2 mod today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/send-thatcher-back-to-hell-in-this-new-doom-2-mod-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/send-thatcher-back-to-hell-in-this-new-doom-2-mod-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following a short delay caused by Tennent's Lager (actual true story), Margaret Thatcher has returned from Hell to menace us once more. Thankfully, one doomed space marine will stand up and venture into the tenth circle of Hell (aka the UK) to put the reviled British prime minister down for good. Thatcher's Techbase is its name, and Doom 2 is the game you'll need to play this free mod now it's out. It is quite the thing, and even has a custom soundtrack from Paradise Killer's composer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cult classic SNES platformer ActRaiser now on PC with a remaster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cult-classic-snes-platformer-actraiser-now-on-pc-with-a-remaster</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cult-classic-snes-platformer-actraiser-now-on-pc-with-a-remaster"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:02:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What's up 90s kids, how would you like to jump back into a SNES platforming city-builder that was first released 30 years ago? Last night's Nintendo Direct had a surprising amount of PC news on offer, including the announcement that a remake of ActRaiser is available to play on PC right now. Named ActRaiser Renaissance, Square Enix say they've given the game a "complete graphical overhaul", as well as added some new features for players to try.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 Minecraft tower ideas to build in 1.17]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-tower-ideas</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-tower-ideas"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:56:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for a cool tower to build in Minecraft? This list is filled with exciting tower ideas that you can try out in Minecraft, with everything from a simple base to a magical Wizard tower.
Take a look through all of these suggestions to get inspired, or follow along with one of the videos and get building right now!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim Crystal: how to get crafting materials for the Crystal Battleaxe and Crystal Wall]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-crystal-shards</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-crystal-shards"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:39:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where do you get Crystal Shards in Valheim, and what are they used for? Crystal has existed as a resource in Valheim for a while, but like many crafting materials in this Early Access cult hit, it's only recently been given a use. The Hearth & Home update has added Crystal Battleaxe and Crystal Wall recipes, and now this previously purely decorative resource is in high demand.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge Of Spirits Incense Pots puzzle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-incense-pots-puzzle-toshis-fear</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-incense-pots-puzzle-toshis-fear"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:34:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to solve the Incense Pots puzzle in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? If you've followed the Mask Maker path as part of the Toshi's Fear quest and you're stuck on these infernal Incense Pots, you've come to exactly the right place. There's not much to say here, so let's jump right into our walkthrough of how to solve this particular puzzle in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim Obliterator: how to craft and use an Obliterator]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-obliterator-thunder-stones</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-obliterator-thunder-stones"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:37:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you craft and use the Obliterator in Valheim? The Obliterator was added to Valheim with the Hearth & Home update, and exists to address a recurring problem experienced by Valheim players in older iterations of the Early Access smash hit. Previously, there was no way to actually get rid of items you didn't need — which could include a surplus of crafting materials and even trophies made from the body parts of slain enemies. The Obliterator gives you the option to neatly dispose of all the inventory junk you don't want to display or store.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise announces Sunbreak expansion before even hitting PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-announces-sunbreak-expansion-before-even-hitting-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-announces-sunbreak-expansion-before-even-hitting-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though Monster Hunter Rise isn't even out on PC for months yet, Capcom have announced an expansion is coming our way. During last night's Nintendo Direct stream they revealed Monter Hunter Rise: Sunbreak, which will launch simultaneously on Switch and PC in summer 2022. Hey, at least that means while consoleers had to wait over a year for the expansion, we'll have it after only a few months. Have a peek in the announcement trailer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšla konečná betaverze Ubuntu 21.10, vydání je plánováno na 14. října]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42849</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vysla-konecna-betaverze-ubuntu-21-10-vydani-je-planovano-na-14-rijna/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:35:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili konečnou betaverzi připravovaného Ubuntu 21.10 s kódovým označením Impish Indri (rošťácký lemur). Vše jde podle připraveného časového harmonogramu, čeká nás ještě kandidát na vydání a poté přijde 14. října ostrá verze.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice Of Cards: The Isle Dragon Roars is Yoko Taro's new card-based RPG]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voice-of-cards-the-isle-dragon-roars-is-yoko-taros-new-card-based-rpg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voice-of-cards-the-isle-dragon-roars-is-yoko-taros-new-card-based-rpg"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nier director Yoko Taro is making a new role-playing game in which everything is depicted through cards, and somehow it's not called Yoko Tarot. Story? There are cards for that. Combat? Turn-based card battles, of course. Travelling through the world? Flip over some cards, see what you find! It's called Voice Of Cards: The Isle Dragon Roars, and it's set to release this October. On top of that, a demo will be available later today if you fancy trying it out. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ansible: úvod do automatizace, role a AWX (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40036</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ansible-uvod-do-automatizace-role-a-awx-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:51:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na internetu píšou, že začít s automatizací správy serverů můžete do půl hodiny. Dokážeme vám, že s Ansible to je pravda. Stačí navštívit naše pražské školení Ansible – úvod do automatizace a pak navazující Ansible – role a AWX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine adds DLC in surprise 'Anniversary Edition']]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-adds-dlc-in-surprise-anniversary-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-adds-dlc-in-surprise-anniversary-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:43:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rise, brothers, to venerate Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine as it celebrates its tenth birthday this month. Relic Entertainment and Sega have a surprise for us all too, turning the third-person ork-smasher into an 'Anniversary Edition' which includes all the DLC as well as bonuses like the soundtrack. That's all for free, which is nice.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck compatibility conundrum partially solved with Easy Anti-Cheat support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-conundrum-partially-solved-with-easy-anti-cheat-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-conundrum-partially-solved-with-easy-anti-cheat-support"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:17:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck has just broken through a major compatibility barrier: one that would have made it difficult for some of Steam’s most-played multiplayer games to properly function on the Valve handheld. Gabe and co. have Epic to thank for this one, though, as the latter’s Easy Anti-Cheat (EAC) tech is now extending support to Linux and it Wine and Proton compatibility layers. The same layers, you may recall, that the Steam Deck relies on to run games without native Linux ports. In other words, games with multiplayer components that wouldn’t have worked on the Steam Deck - because their use of EAC precluded Linux/Wine/Proton compatibility - should, in theory, be able to run in full.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to find Slimes and make a Slime Farm in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-slimes-how-to-find-slimes-make-slime-farm</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-slimes-how-to-find-slimes-make-slime-farm"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T08:49:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to find Slimes in Minecraft? Slimes can vary in size from annoying little blobs to giant monstrosities, but there’s one thing they all have in common. They all drop Slimeballs, which are extremely useful in Minecraft.
This guide will take you through everything that you need to know about Slimes, including how to find them, what you can use Slimeballs for, and how to make your own Slime farm.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sourcetrail končí, vývoj je příliš náročný]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42848</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/sourcetrail-konci-vyvoj-je-prilis-narocny/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T07:20:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sourcetrail je open-source program, který slouží k statické analýze a vizualizaci zdrojových kódů v jazycích C, C++ a Python. Dnes jeho vývojáři na svém blogu oznámili ukončení jeho vývoje.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: D.A. Tiger)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symbols]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2520/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2520/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fuga: Melodies Of Steel is a strategy RPG with a giant child-powered tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fuga-memories-of-steel-is-a-strategy-rpg-with-a-giant-child-powered-tank</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fuga-memories-of-steel-is-a-strategy-rpg-with-a-giant-child-powered-tank"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T23:05:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fuga: Melodies Of Steel is set during an anthropomorphic animal anime World War 2 in which your parents have been taken by the dog Nazis. Still with me? You and your fellow cat children find Howl's Moving Tank in a cave and set about getting your families back, with turn-based, RPG battles.

You also discover at the end of the tutorial that your giant angry house has a "Soul Cannon", which is a gun that only fires if you feed it the soul - and permanently kill - one of the children.

Still with me?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Planety v centru Mléčné dráhy]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-planety-v-centru-mlecne-drahy</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-planety-v-centru-mlecne-drahy"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moudrost davu. Dokážeme úspěšně předpovědět, kdy k nám dorazí světlo supernovy? Kvasary jako standardní svíčky. Neutron má na povrchu záporný náboj. Proč se zlato vyskytuje vedle arsenu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evropská komise chce jednotnou nabíječku s USB-C a Power Delivery]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15678</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/evropska-komise-chce-jednotnou-nabijecku-s-usb-c-a-power-delivery/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exekutivě Evropské unie došla trpělivost a chystá nařízení, kterým sjednotí roztříštěný svět nabíječek (nejen) smartphonů. Postihne to všechny, kdo se vymykají standardu USB-C, v čele s Apple.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite's multiplayer test will go ahead as planned]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-multiplayer-test-will-go-ahead-as-planned</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-multiplayer-test-will-go-ahead-as-planned"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T21:58:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking news: everything is normal and fine. Yesterday Halo Infinite developers 343 Industries mentioned during a livestream that they might need to delay this weekend's beta. Today they confirmed that's not the case, and posted an overview of what to expect.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CS:GO's Operation Riptide revives the riot shield]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/csgos-operation-riptide-revives-the-riot-shield-and-makes-a-major-change-to-dust2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/csgos-operation-riptide-revives-the-riot-shield-and-makes-a-major-change-to-dust2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T20:52:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The riot shield was probably the most divisive item ever added to Counter-Strike - and now it's back. New update Operation Riptide, out now, introduces the defensive item to Counter-Strike: Global Offensive's casual mode, alongside major tweaks to Dust2, new missions, shorter matches, and private matchmaking queues.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected characters keep disappearing, among many launch issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-characters-keep-disappearing-among-many-launch-issues</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-characters-keep-disappearing-among-many-launch-issues"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T19:24:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected launched earlier today, offering players the chance to relive the classic hack-and-slasher. But why recreate the experience of one Diablo game when you could recreate the experience of two? Resurrected is also experiencing a bunch of launch issues related to its online mode, just like Diablo 3 before it.

Those issues include players being unable to see their existing characters, create new characters, or launch the game. Some might say essential features.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected's hotkeys are still a goddamn mess]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-hotkeys-are-still-a-goddamn-mess</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-hotkeys-are-still-a-goddamn-mess"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terrible news continues to pour out of Blizzard like pus from of a festering wound around a splinter you forgot about and left for way too long. You should really get that looked at. Still, they must be drawing some comfort from the fact that Diablo II: Resurrected is out today, one of Blizz's most beloved games of all time.
Naturally, a lot of people will be excited for the remastered version. But if my tone is more immediately aggro than the last time I wrote about Diablerrected, that's because I was previously playing the beta through the rose-tinted haze of this game being very important to me and a big part of my childhood, and bonding with my older brother, and so on. This time, I have been playing the final version for several hours, and am cross.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rally Point: Putting Mech Engineer on trial (and error)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-putting-mech-engineer-on-trial-and-error</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-putting-mech-engineer-on-trial-and-error"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:05:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you've played a lot of games, or seen a lot of films, or probably eaten at a lot of restaurants or generally oversaturated your life with one subject, it's easy to start making rules and codes for How It Should Be. I given a lot of games a hard time for being opaque and failing to explain themselves. And yet here I am, finally writing about Mech Engineer after watching and playing it for nine months, waiting for it to hit the point where I can almost, sort of, not exactly recommend it... but share my fascination with it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard will, sadly, fix dognados]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-will-sadly-fix-dognados</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-will-sadly-fix-dognados"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:50:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The primary function of ragdoll physics in video games, everyone knows, is to freak out and make people laugh. Everyone knows this. The technology was created explicitly to bring a subversive touch of merry mayhem to po-faced murdergames. Everyone knows this. But developers are wary of overdoing it or openly acknowledging this fact which everyone knows. This is why, sadly, Call Of Duty: Vanguard will indeed 'fix' the 'bug' which could make attack dogs turn into a giant maelstrom of limbs, teeth, and mashing meat noises, a phenomenom known as the 'dognado'. Tragic.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to set up two monitors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-set-up-two-monitors</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-set-up-two-monitors"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s funny to think how different the use cases are for setting up two monitors for your gaming PC, compared to setting up three. A trio of displays lets you play in ultrawide with a wraparound effect that even most purpose-built ultrawide monitors can’t match, but while you can configure a dual-monitor setup to run games across displays, it doesn’t make nearly as much sense. With the borders of each screen running straight down the middle, most of the best ultrawide PC games would be nigh-unplayable. Still! If you can budget for it, two remains better than one. It’s an expanded but focused setup for when you’re playing a full-screen game but also want a browser tab, video, or streaming controls visible at the same time.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Diablo 2: Resurrected classes and builds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-diablo-2-resurrected-classes-and-builds</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-diablo-2-resurrected-classes-and-builds"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:20:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best classes and builds in Diablo 2: Resurrected? The shiny new remaster is finally here, but the gameplay of Diablo 2: Resurrected will be very familiar to veterans. If you’re playing for the first time, however, the game’s complex character progression can seem overwhelming. The foundations of your experience are your choice of class, and the skill(s) you build around on that class. Each of Diablo 2’s seven classes features multiple talent trees that grant you new abilities and define how you approach the game.
If you’re planning to play on Hardcore mode or push deep into Hell difficulty, you will want a quality build. Blizzard has not made balance adjustments to Diablo 2: Resurrected, so the long-established meta still holds in the remaster. Prepare for Hell with our guide to the best classes and builds in Diablo 2: Resurrected.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected Runes and Runewords]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-runes-runewords</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-runes-runewords"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:20:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trying to wrap your head around Runes in Diablo 2: Resurrected? Runes are the cornerstone of Diablo 2’s gear system. As there are no balance changes in Diablo 2: Resurrected, longtime players will be familiar. If you’re new, however, this system will look entirely unfamiliar, even if you’ve played Diablo 3 or Path of Exile. There’s nothing quite like Diablo 2’s Rune system in the ARPG genre. If you’re having trouble wrapping your head around the quirks of Runes and Runewords, we’re here to help.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected farming spots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-farming-level-85</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-farming-level-85"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:20:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best farming spots in Diablo 2? An ARPG would be nothing without a grind. The grind in Diablo 2 is the foundation of the genre’s last 20 years. The genre-defining classic has seen very few changes for the remastered version, Diablo 2: Resurrected, so veterans of the original will have their strategies in place. If you’re a new player looking to optimize your character after beating the game though, you’ll need to know where to farm your gear. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 157: the best animal companions special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-episode-157-the-best-animal-companions-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-episode-157-the-best-animal-companions-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on The Electronic Wireless Show podcast I was inspired by the extremely cute little monsters the Rot, who are you besties in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits, to ask Matthew and Nate about their favourite animal companions in video games. You will probably be able to predict some of their answers. Others, not so much.
A big digression about trains and commuter rage this week, as well as a shocking update from Matthew re. the farewell fizzy drink tour. But most exciting is that the Cavern Of Lies is replaced this week by a Cavern Of Announcements! Yes, we have very special news indeed, and you have to listen to at least two thirds of the podcast to find out what it is. But it is genuinely incredible.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim Tar: how to find Tar Pits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-tar-pits</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-tar-pits"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:42:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where can you find Tar Pits in Valheim? Tar is a new resource introduced in Valheim's Hearth & Home update. It's a versatile crafting resource that you'll need before you can make many of the update's new items, including Darkwood furniture and building materials, Raven and Wolf Adornments, and — last but never least — the hot tub.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea Of Thieves explores the Sunken Kingdom in new season today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sea-of-thieves-explores-the-sunken-kingdom-in-new-season-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sea-of-thieves-explores-the-sunken-kingdom-in-new-season-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:11:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new Sea Of Thieves content update heralds the start of a new season today, encouraging pirates to plunge overboard and explore the beautiful halls and mysteries of the Sunken Kingdom. All sorts of coral-y PvE surprises await, with Shrines to quietly explore and Treasures to plunder by force. As beautiful as the game's water is from above, I'm very keen to see more from below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chorus is an exhilarating space combat shooter with a rhythm all its own]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chorus-is-an-exhilarating-space-combat-shooter-with-a-rhythm-all-its-own</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chorus-is-an-exhilarating-space-combat-shooter-with-a-rhythm-all-its-own"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since Chorus first broke out of hyperspace during Microsoft's Xbox Series X showcase last year, Fishlabs' enigmatic space shooter has been a tricky thing to pin down. The first trailer gave us a taste of its high speed combat and third-person battles, but its deep, ominous narration, hints of a mysterious cosmic power, and that final image of a planet being sucked into a black hole almost looked like it was verging into horror territory rather than plain sci-fi. Having now played around an hour of Chorus, I can safely say it's very much a pure breed of space combat shooter, following in the same, adrenalin-fuelled vein as EVE: Valkyrie and Star Wars Squadrons. 
Forsaken, the sentient ship you control in Chorus that's piloted by the rebel cultist Nara, is probably a similarly slippery thing to nail down in the eyes of your enemies, too. Thanks to one of Nara's special Rite powers, bestowed on her by that aforementioned cosmic power you'll be hunting down over the course of the game, Forsaken is able to shift and teleport right behind enemy ships for brutal, bullet-ridden takedowns. It's immensely satisfying, and can also make for daring, last-minute escapes from incoming crosshairs. But you'll need much more than Nara's crafty Rite powers to survive Chorus' unforgiving dogfights. Forsaken went up in flames more times than I care to admit in my hour of hands on time, but I'm very much looking forward to going back for more when it finally launches on Steam and the Epic Games Store on December 3rd later this year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discord testing YouTube integration to let you watch videos with pals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/discord-testing-youtube-integration-to-let-you-watch-videos-with-pals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/discord-testing-youtube-integration-to-let-you-watch-videos-with-pals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T13:43:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discord has started testing official YouTube integration, rolling out a new feature named Watch Together which, well, allows users watch YouTube vids together. It comes just a few weeks after Google's lawyers shut down several third-party Discord bots with a similar function. Watch Together has reportedly been enabled in a limited number of Discord servers for now, with plans to roll it out to everyone by the end of October.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Tales of Arise rose up for a new audience]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-tales-of-arise-rose-up-for-a-new-audience</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-tales-of-arise-rose-up-for-a-new-audience"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bandai Namco's first Tales Of game, Tales Of Phantasia, weighed in at a previously unheard of 48MB when it released in 1995. That's a mere wisp of data nowadays, but a veritable beast for a Super Famicom game cartridge. The cost of these high capacity carts, combined with westerners' ho-hum attitude towards RPGs at the time, likely axed any chance it had of being translated. Later Tales games have had better success in the west - 2003's Tales Of Symphonia was arguably its first breakout hit outside Japan - but the series as a whole has always seemed to exist on the fringes of the JRPG dynasty. While the Tales games certainly have a following outside Japan, western JRPG fans still tend to gravitate toward Square Enix's Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest games, or Atlus' Persona series. 
But the Tales series' low-key existence is seemingly coming to an end thanks to the recently released Tales Of Arise. With its bright, eye-catching visuals and its uniquely frantic battle system, it turns monster slaying from a chore into an addiction, and has won the hearts of many curious newcomers in the process (including yours truly). With this influx of new blood, Tales might stand a chance of grabbing a throne at the heart of the JRPG genre. I recently talked to Arise producer Yusuke Tomizawa, who worked hard to tailor the adventure for a new Tales audience as much as its established fans. He explains how Arise's development went down a long, risky road, but it paid off in excellent review scores, happy fans, and a refreshing new direction for Tales.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Oxford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to open the Storehouse Door in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-storehouse-door-puzzle</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-storehouse-door-puzzle"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:39:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Puzzled about how to open the Storehouse Door in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? The smallest area of the game, the Storehouse, is also one of the more confusing and puzzle-dense areas of the world - and the confusion isn't helped by the fact that you've just been given a new power and must quickly learn how it works in order to get through the Storehouse in one piece.
Below we'll walk you through exactly how to activate the two Power Crystals and open the Storehouse Door in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits. You'll find both a written and a video walkthrough of the Storehouse puzzle below, so what are you waiting for? Let's dive in.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Dark's story campaign continues with Episode 4 in October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-darks-story-campaign-continues-with-episode-4-in-october</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-darks-story-campaign-continues-with-episode-4-in-october"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:05:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Splendid snowy survival sandbox The Long Dark will launch the much-anticipated fourth episode of its story campaign on the 6th of October, developers Hinterland Studio have announced. Named 'Fury, Then Silence', episode 4 of the 'Wintermute' campaign sees one of our protagonists captured by murderers sheltering from the strange superfreeze in a prison complex. Have a peek at that in the new trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends still has stability issues after patch that should've fixed them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-still-has-stability-issues-after-patch-that-shouldve-fixed-them</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-still-has-stability-issues-after-patch-that-shouldve-fixed-them"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T10:34:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've tried to play Apex Legends over the last week or so and noticed that things have been pretty slow, you're not alone. Since the game's Evolution Collection event launched last week, the battle royale and its servers have been struggling, and Respawn Entertainment have been tinkering away to try and sort it all out. Yesterday, they issued a patch to resolve a number of bugs and improve stability, but having played a few matches myself last night, it seems we're not out of the woods just yet.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck FAQ confirms you can use it as a giant PC controller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-faq-confirms-you-can-use-it-as-a-giant-pc-controller</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-faq-confirms-you-can-use-it-as-a-giant-pc-controller"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T10:10:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Valve haven't been overly secretive with the Steam Deck, there are still plenty of burning questions to ask about the upcoming handheld PC. For me, these are usually along the lines of “Will it slip into my big coat pockets as easily as the Switch does?” or “Will it survive my cat pushing it off literally any flat surface?” but the newly-launched Steam Deck FAQ covers enquiries of a generally more techy nature.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I beg you, enable multiplayer in Deathloop and embrace mortality]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-beg-you-enable-multiplayer-in-deathloop-and-embrace-mortality</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-beg-you-enable-multiplayer-in-deathloop-and-embrace-mortality"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The dastardly multiplayer invasions of Deathloop are some murderous hijinks. But not everybody wants to see a player-controlled assassin with vicious human instincts pop up as they sneak through their time loop adventure. That's fine, say developers Arkane, you can simply switch to single player mode, which will replace player incursions with periodic visits from an NPC Julianna who is (let's be diplomatic) a less feisty opponent. I am here to ask, nay, beg: do not do this. Leave it in Online mode. Welcome malice, embrace pain, receive with warmth that sudden mortal stab in the back. You are strong and capable of overcoming such things. I'm not just giving you an ego boost here. As the tenacious Colt, the fight is fixed in your favour.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blood Bowl 3 delays early access launch following beta feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blood-bowl-3-delays-early-access-launch-following-beta-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blood-bowl-3-delays-early-access-launch-following-beta-feedback"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T09:49:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fantasy sports management sim Blood Bowl 3 is delayed again, with the early access launch now pushed out of September and into the nebulous future. The official word is that after beta feedback, they realised yeah it wasn't ready. They say, "our teams are more committed than ever to make Blood Bowl 3 the most comprehensive and polished instalment in the series yet." Yeah go on, please do that.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MikroTik zažívá další vlnu DDoS útoků]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42846</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mikrotik-zaziva-dalsi-vlnu-ddos-utoku/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T07:13:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na základě článku laboratoře QRATOR labs firma MikroTik na svých stránkách upozorňuje na další vlnu DDoS útoků.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME 41 přináší vylepšení výkonu a novinky v podpoře Waylandu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42847</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gnome-41-prinasi-vylepseni-vykonu-a-novinky-v-podpore-waylandu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T07:10:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili pravidelnou půlroční aktualizaci desktopového prostředí GNOME, tentokrát s označením 41. Mezi hlavní novinky patří vylepšení správce software, nastavení multitaskingu a vylepšení power managementu. Kromě toho je tu nová aplikace Connections, aktualizovaná aplikace Music a vylepšení výkonu v celé řadě komponent.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brewing and haggling sim Potion Craft opens for business in early access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/brewing-and-haggling-sim-potion-craft-opens-for-business-in-early-access</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/brewing-and-haggling-sim-potion-craft-opens-for-business-in-early-access"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:52:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Step on in and please don't mind the badly-labelled vials I've left lying about the shop. Potion Craft is now in early access with all its myserious brewing and haggling and alchemy-ing. I've been quite taken with the demos and playtests for this one so far, not least because it brings some spirit back to the act of crafting. It's out now in early access, during which Niceplay Games will be adding even more crafting options to toy with before its full launch.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sable review: a beautiful adventure beset by troubling bugs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sable-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sable-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you might expect from a game set on a desert planet, Sable has a lot of sand. You traverse it on your floating motorbike as the titular character, a young woman who's part of a nomadic culture where adolescents leave home to complete their Gliding. During this gap year of sorts, the Glider does odd jobs and explores the world until they figure out what they want to be for the rest of their life. Sand is a feature. But as they say, sand is coarse and rough and irritating, and it gets everywhere. Each individual grain of sand is small, but a pinch of sand in your bed will change how you feel about your entire sleep experience.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kořen Let's Encrypt na konci měsíce vyprší, dotkne se to starších klientů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15675</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/koren-let-s-encrypt-na-konci-mesice-vyprsi-dotkne-se-to-starsich-klientu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na konci září vyprší platnost kořenového certifikátu DST Root CA X3, na kterém od začátku stála podpora certifikační autority Let's Encrypt. Ta už sice používá nový kořen, ale staré systémy budou mít problém.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PC-BASIC: reinkarnace populárního i zatracovaného GW-BASICu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15676</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/pc-basic-reinkarnace-popularniho-i-zatracovaneho-gw-basicu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V první polovině osmdesátých let patřilo k dobrému vychování dodávat domácí i osobní počítače vybavené nějakým dialektem programovacího jazyka BASIC. Výjimkou není ani IBM PC, pro které byl dodáván mj. i GW-BASIC, později QBasic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop chose to boot its melee system in favor of that excellent kick]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-chose-to-boot-its-melee-system-in-favor-of-that-excellent-kick</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-chose-to-boot-its-melee-system-in-favor-of-that-excellent-kick"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T21:44:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time-looping murder puzzle Deathloop sure seems like it's worth putting on repeat. For all the usual action romp reasons that Arkane are good with, but also for some of its sillier bits. Kicking baddies off ledges sounds like it's the real backbone of Deathloop's comedy. Colt has one damn powerful boot and, according to a new chat with Deathloop director Dinga Bakaba, it's all thanks to Arkane's choice to scrap most of their melee combat system. Here's why Colt traded arm day for leg day. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Řada kritických chyb ve VMware vCenter]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42845</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rada-kritickych-chyb-ve-vmware-vcenter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T20:42:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera večer byla vydána opravná verze VMware vCenter 6.5, 6.7 a 7.0. Tato nová sada verzí opravuje několik kritických zranitelností, od XSS, přístupu k skrytým endpointům API, neoprávněnou manipulaci s nastavením sítě virtuálních strojů, vzdálené mazání souborů na vCenteru až po asi nejzávažnější vzdálené spuštění kódu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: LD)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple won't let Fortnite back on the App Store until they run out of appeals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apple-wont-let-fortnite-back-on-the-app-store-until-they-run-out-of-appeals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apple-wont-let-fortnite-back-on-the-app-store-until-they-run-out-of-appeals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T20:32:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The legal battle between Epic Games and Apple continues as it seems that both are probably willing to cut the proverbial Fortnite baby in half. Earlier this month, the court ruled that Apple must allow third-party payment systems, which was apparently not enough for Epic, who decided to submit an appeal last week. Now, Apple have informed Epic that they will not be allowing Fortnite back into the App Store clubhouse until they've exhausted all their own avenues to appeal. Which means Fortnite could remain off the store for years yet, according to Epic.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Lesbian road trip RPG" Get In The Car, Loser! has just hit the road]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lesbian-road-trip-rpg-get-in-the-car-loser-has-just-hit-the-road</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lesbian-road-trip-rpg-get-in-the-car-loser-has-just-hit-the-road"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T18:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get In The Car, Loser! begins as all RPGs about young protagonists with magical powers do—just a lot more bluntly. The world is being threatened by the evil Machine Devil and the Machine Devil cultists, and apparently no one is going to save it if not your plucky party of heroes. So hop on in the back seat, you dork. Get In The Car, Loser!, a free game written by Christine Love of Ladykiller In A Bind fame, is now fueled up and headed out on its self-proclaimed "lesbian road trip RPG".

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jett: The Far Shore's fictional language started life as gibberish choral music]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jett-the-far-shores-fictional-language-started-life-as-gibberish-choral-music</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jett-the-far-shores-fictional-language-started-life-as-gibberish-choral-music"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lots of good sci-fi has made up languages, but I don't think many could claim their fictional languages were developed through song. Enter Jett: The Far Shore. It's an upcoming interstellar adventure made by Sword & Sworcery developers Superbrothers with Pine Scented Software, in which a team of scouts take off in their jetts to explore an uncharted planet. Better yet, it features its very own language that sound designer Priscilla Snow developed after finding meaning in the gibberish words she used to form the game's music. 


While the initial plan was never to have their own in-game language, the Jett team now have a dictionary around 2000 words strong, and I had a chance to talk to them about how it all came to be. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4 just added a massive 1200 new color swatches to 149 build items]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-just-added-a-massive-1200-new-color-swatches-to-149-build-items</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-just-added-a-massive-1200-new-color-swatches-to-149-build-items"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T16:27:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh rejoice, a Sims 4 update that's all for me. Maxis have just dropped a free update which they say their art team totally took over by whipping up around 1200 new color swatches for 149 different Buy and Build Mode objects. There are tons of new window drape colors, new countertop swatches, wood furniture choices, and even plants. That is a lot of new color choices for a lot of items and oh boy I will probably use them all. Fellow builders, this one is for us. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's better: unit designers, or handcrafted art?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whats-better-unit-designers-or-handcrafted-art</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whats-better-unit-designers-or-handcrafted-art"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T16:16:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last time, you decided that fiddling with environmental objects (henceforth known as fiddlebits) is better than rocket jumping. A toughie there, no doubt; I thank you for your careful deliberation. Next up, we're settling an issue of whose hand shapes  game, whether you're getting hands-on with your mens or having someone else lovingly handcraft the entire world for you.
What's better: unit designers, or handcrafted art?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 94 nasazuje sRGB u elementu canvas a přidává WebGPU]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42844</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chrome-94-nasazuje-srgb-u-elementu-canvas-a-pridava-webgpu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T15:45:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Možná nejvýznačnější novinkou v Chrome/Chromium 94 pro uživatele je to, že element canvas je nyní implicitně kalibrován na barevný prostor sRGB, nicméně stránka může specifikovat jiný, podporován je i DCI-P3. Pete LaPage dále doporučuje na web.dev věnovat pozornost textu Eugena Zemtsova o WebCodecs s příklady využití přímého videa pomocí hardwarově akcelerovaných kodeků, které již prohlížeč má (aneb blíží se konec nutnosti dodávat v kódu vlastní neakcelerovanou WASM verzi kodeků). Podpora kodeků skrze WebCodecs se týká jak přehrávání, tak komprese.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make and activate a Beacon in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-beacon-how-to-make-activate-beacon</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-beacon-how-to-make-activate-beacon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T14:39:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to make and activate a Beacon in Minecraft? Beacons have two very important uses in Minecraft, as they give you status effects whilst also emitting a beam of light that can act as a waypoint marker to guide you and your friends home.
This guide will walk you through everything you need to know to make and use a Beacon in Minecraft, including how to get a Nether Star, which is one of the ingredients you will need.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An ode to cutting off boss tails in Dark Souls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-cutting-off-boss-tails-in-dark-souls</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-cutting-off-boss-tails-in-dark-souls"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy 10th anniversary Dark Souls! Here's to you, Sin the Slumbering Dragon. And to you, Crossbreed Priscilla. Chin-chin! Oi, not to you Ornstein, or to you, Smough. How did you even get in, anyway? This is an invitation only event for bosses who have cuttable tails.
There's a tinge of sadness to this celebration, though. Cuttable tails were all the rage back in the original Dark Souls but now they're lost to time, never to be seen again, just like the tails you cut off themselves. Although a part of me hopes that the cycle will renew (like the sort of tails that grow back after you cut them off). And just like skinny jeans are slowly going out of fashion in favour of the 90s wide leg, I'm hoping FromSoftware's bosses won't cling so closely to their tails in Elden Ring and maybe, just maybe, they'll let us lop them off again.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy's chaotic combat owes more to JRPGs than you think]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxys-chaotic-combat-owes-more-to-jrpgs-than-you-think</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxys-chaotic-combat-owes-more-to-jrpgs-than-you-think"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I went hands-on with roughly an hour's worth of Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy last week, and I have come away pleasantly surprised. I'll admit, I judged a book by its cover on this one, thinking it would be an action adventure game only Marvel stans with decades worth of MCU facts beamed into their brains could rally behind. But no, even I, who's watched precisely three Marvel films in the last ten years, had a lot of fun with it. Good fun, at that.
Mainly, I liked how the game's combat takes cues from JRPGs, of all things, cribbing off the likes of Final Fantasy XV and Tales Of Arise so your fellow guardians feel just as - if not more - important than yourself.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are your favourite autumn games?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-your-favourite-autumn-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-your-favourite-autumn-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T12:40:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today brings the autumn equinox and the start of the season where things, like, fall. It's a good season! I will always mourn the end of summer but I relish the brief window to hike through golden forests, swimming through shoals of leaves in rivers, cosy up around bonfires with cocoa, and break out the warm duvet again. But while we wait for the season to properly kick in, I'm curious: which autumns in video games do you enjoy? Yes, Halloween included.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webové stránky politických stran obsahují zranitelnosti]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42843</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/webove-stranky-politickych-stran-obsahuji-zranitelnosti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T08:12:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test deseti webových prezentací politických stran odhalil v pěti případech kritické zranitelnosti, nejčastěji se jednalo o cross-site scripting, objevily se ale zranitelné zastaralé knihovny a v jednom případě také děravý jedenáct let starý Apache. Více ve zprávě na webu spajk.cz.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: spajk)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 přinese podporu senzorů dalších základních desek ASUS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42841</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-5-16-prinese-podporu-senzoru-dalsich-zakladnich-desek-asus/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V Linuxu 5.16 dojde ke změně v ovladači nct6775, který obstarává čtení dat ze senzorů mnohých základních desek značky ASUS. Ovladač dostane podporu přístupu k ASIC za použití funkcí ASUS WMI (desky od Asusteku nepoužívají standardní cestu přes ACPI, kterou ovladač disponuje již nyní). S úpravou pak logicky do jádra zamíří i podpora níže uvedeného seznamu základních desek:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 2.10.28 opravuje další chyby]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42840</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gimp-2-10-28-opravuje-dalsi-chyby/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na GIMP 3.0 si ještě chvíli počkáme, vezměmež tedy zavděk dalším, víceméně opravným vydání dva-desítkové řady. GIMP 2.10.28 totiž přináší solidní množství oprav.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sloped Border]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2519/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2519/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino Mega na zbernici s PC]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15662</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/arduino-mega-na-zbernici-s-pc/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Platforma Arduino sa stala veľmi rozšírenou najmä vďaka tomu, že umožňuje veľmi jednoducho naprogramovať rôzne typy kontrolérov pre najrozmanitejšie úlohy. Zároveň využívame väčšinu výhod kontrolérov.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ferenc Lengyel)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (22. 9. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15671</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-22-9-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes si představíme jednoduchý editor odvozený z projektu lite, budeme optimalizovat velikost obrázků, začneme si vést vlastní deník a nakonec využijeme průzkumníka slovníků EPWING, LingvoDSL a StarDict.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jiří Sluka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podpora Ubuntu 14.04 LTS a 16.04 LTS se prodlužuje na 10 let]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42839</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/podpora-ubuntu-14-04-lts-a-16-04-lts-se-prodluzuje-na-10-let/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical rozhodl o prodloužení podpory starších LTS vydání operačního systému Ubuntu na 10 let od první vydané verze. To znamená, že řada Ubuntu 14.04 LTS „Trusty Tahr“ bude podporována až do dubna 2024 a řada Ubuntu 16.04 LTS „Xenial Xerus“ až do dubna 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nová mobilní Datovka nabízí další způsob platby za odesílané poštovní datové zprávy]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42842</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nova-mobilni-datovka-nabizi-dalsi-zpusob-platby-za-odesilane-postovni-datove-zpravy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T20:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Laboratoře CZ.NIC vydaly další verzi mobilní Datovky (1.13.0). Kromě oprav nalezených chyb, jako jsou oprava chyby při načítání uložených informací o datovém trezoru nebo vypnutí upozornění na vypršení platnosti hesla, pokud je zvoleno přihlašování Mobilním klíčem, byl podobně jako v případě desktopové aplikace přidán výběr způsobu platby za odesílané poštovní datové zprávy, pokud má uživatel k dispozici více možností.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V seznamáckém hackathonu zvítězil tým EasyPeasy.Net]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42838</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/v-seznamackem-hackathonu-zvitezil-tym-easypeasy-net/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T10:06:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Celodenní soutěžní hackathon pro programátory od české technologické společnosti Seznam.cz zná své vítěze. Nejlepší výkon předvedl tým s názvem EasyPeasy.Net ve složení Tomáš Jurásek, Michal Mrnuštík, Michal Motyčka a Adam Jež (zleva).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ondřej Nový)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test terabajtových SSD pro rozhraní PCIe 4.0 od WD, Samsung, Adata, Seagate, Aorus]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42837</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/test-terabajtovych-ssd-pro-rozhrani-pcie-4-0-od-wd-samsung-adata-seagate-aorus/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T06:34:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kolegové ze serveru Cnews.cz otestovali pět terabajtových SSD pro rozhraní PCIe 4.0. Konkrétně šlo o disky značek WD, Samsung, Adata, Seagate a Aorus, jejichž cena se pohybuje okolo 5500 Kč. Testován byl výkon po připojení na novou sběrnici PCIe 4.0, ale zároveň i ve zpětně kompatibilní PCIe 3.0.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot-clone: nástroj umožňující získat obraz připojeného disku]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/hot-clone-nastroj-umoznujici-ziskat-obraz-pripojeneho-disku/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chcete-li vytvořit bitovou kopii souborového systému, asi není úplně dobrý nápad používat nástroje jako dd, je-li disk zároveň připojen. Vytváření obrazu bude určitou dobu trvat a pokud se během této doby na disk zapisuje, bude výsledný obraz velmi poškozený.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ondřej Caletka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SMB3 server v jádře 5.15 KSMBD už má první vážnou opravu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42835</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/smb3-server-v-jadre-5-15-ksmbd-uz-ma-prvni-vaznou-opravu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:22:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SMB3 server implementovaný v jádře s názvem KSMBD, za kterým stojí Samsung, se dostal do jádra 5.15. To ještě ani nevyšlo a už se v KSMBD objevila závažná zranitelnost, kdy pomocí znaků .. v cestě je možné přistupovat k souborům mimo sdílené adresáře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Co očekáváme ve Fedoře 35]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42834</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/co-ocekavame-ve-fedore-35/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 35 beta by měla vyjít každým dnem. Ostrá verze se očekává 19. října, nebo o týden později. Na serveru mojefedora.cz vyšel dnes článek shrnující novinky očekávané ve Fedoře 35 Workstation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumpers and Splitters]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2518/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2518/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Komunikace má zvyšovat produktivitu vývojářů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-komunikace-ma-zvysovat-produktivitu-vyvojaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-komunikace-ma-zvysovat-produktivitu-vyvojaru"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hlavní trendy umělé inteligence: Malá a rozprostřená data. Nový typ kybernetických útoků – zneužívání proxyware platforem. Roboti, kteří udělají přesnou díru do hlavy, zachraňují životy. O vstupu do nebe rozhoduje sv. Petr, pro síť je tu ClearPass. Kouzla zbavené? Nepravděpodobné řešení hrozící personální krize ve finančních službách. Honeywell u nás investuje do R&D. Komunikace má zvyšovat produktivitu vývojářů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Přepínané zrcadlo z roztaveného kovu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-prepinane-zrcadlo-z-roztaveneho-kovu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-prepinane-zrcadlo-z-roztaveneho-kovu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Černá díra vyžrala hvězdu. Nanotechnologie s černým oxidem titaničitým. Život v atmosféře subneptunů. Maličké hory na neutronových hvězdách.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 37/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-37-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-37-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 10 pouze za 12 €, super slevy až 91%!]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pořiďte si doživotní aktivační klíč k Windows 10 za 12,52 EUR na prodejním portálu GoodOffer24.com. Kromě toho nástrojů produktivity od Microsoftu zde lze získat i hry a další software. Nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód  AX30.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 34-35/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Závěr letních prázdnin a začátek školního roku přinesly několik významných vydání, LibreELEC s novým Kodi, příručky Linux From Scratch nebo novou stabilní větev OpenWrt, a také aktualizace Clonezilly, Ubuntu LTS, EndeavourOS, EasyOS či NuTyXu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo představuje hybridní tablety budoucnosti. Canon rozšiřuje nabídku A3 multifunkcí pro hybridní pracovní prostředí. Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>