<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-06-24T16:13:45.294Z</id>
    <title>Pitlovo RSS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-24T16:13:45.294Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feature: The One Thing Wii Did Much Better Than Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-150909</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/the-one-thing-wii-did-much-better-than-switch"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Point taken.
The Sensor Bar. Flimsy little plastic box with the world's longest, spindliest cable. An irritation to every Wii owner who has ever had to move their console. What was it good for?
There's not a lot to the Sensor Bar. A little device that emits some infrared light. If the Wii Remote is pointed at one, it recognises that's where the TV is. It's not high-tech. Famously, its functionality can be replicated by two candles. Cheap, cheerful, reliable.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Fall Of Porcupine – A Prickly Hospital Game That Needed A Little More Care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-150889</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/fall-of-porcupine"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A test of patients.
The past few years have reminded us that many countries’ healthcare systems are not in good shape. Even so, it’s hard to appreciate the challenges that healthcare workers face if you’re not one. Fall of Porcupine aims to do this in an approachable way by putting players in the scrubs of 2D animal doctors. Unfortunately, the latest release from Critical Rabbit isn’t the hard-hitting medical drama wrapped in a fuzzy waffle blanket that we would’ve liked. This cute game has so much potential, but it needed more care and a focused narrative to really soar.
An impressive amount of research and interviews have gone into the game’s much-needed commentary – everything from full beds to alternative medicine to corporate hospital management. It’s a shame all that research results in a flatline story with repetitive mechanics. You control Finley, an anthropomorphised pigeon and the newest doctor at St. Ursula's Hospital in the town of Porcupine. As you tend to patients, your boss, white cheetah Dr Krokowski, is constantly less than impressed with you. There’s also a fellow newbie doctor, a suspicious janitor, a chief physician, and MANY more characters who take the form of various animals.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Are You Playing This Weekend? (June 24th)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151753</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-june-24th"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shed enough Tears?
Another week has come and gone, but goodness, it was a great one, wasn't it? Yes, the surprise Nintendo Direct aired and brought with it some absolutely killer announcements, including the likes of Super Mario Bros. Wonder, a Super Mario RPG remake, Metal Gear Solid: Master Collection Vol. 1, and Batman: Arkham Trilogy.
That's not all though, so be sure to check out our full round-up on all the announcements in the article below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-242</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-242"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hot one today, huh? And every day at the moment. I'm in the UK for a few days and long for my new/current homeland, where it is also very hot but at least the biscuits and chicken fillet rolls are very good. Still, this weekend I might get a walk-in tattoo and eat some eggy bread, which I am told adults refer to as French toast. I tell you what I probably won't be doing though: playing some video games! I'm away from home and didn't bring any portables with me. Luckily the rest of the team can make up for me.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The FTC Doesn't Seem To Think Switch Is A Serious PlayStation & Xbox Competitor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151780</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/the-ftc-doesnt-seem-to-think-switch-is-a-serious-playstation-and-xbox-competitor"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's Phil Spencer says it's "incorrect".
Microsoft is currently locked in a courtroom battle with the Federal Trade Commission over its proposed $69 billion acquisition of Activision Blizzard, and although the focus is mostly on Xbox, on day two of the proceedings, the Nintendo Switch has already been dragged into the fight.
According to The Verge, the FTC has been attempting to argue the Switch is "very different" to the Xbox Series X and PlayStation 5 - suggesting it's not really part of the same market by comparing its technical capabilities, with lines about its frame rate and how it compares in terms of GPU teraflops.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Frontiers Free 'Birthday Bash' DLC Is Out Now, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151762</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/sonic-frontiers-free-birthday-bash-dlc-is-out-now-here-are-the-full-patch-notes"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Game + speeds into the game.
Original story :
Happy birthday to Sonic the Hedgehog! It's the blue blur's birthday today, if you didn't know, so it's only appropriate we have some way to celebrate, right?
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Superstars' Release Date Might Have Already Been Revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151778</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/sonic-superstars-release-date-might-have-already-been-revealed"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T02:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Super Mario Bros. Wonder is scheduled for the same week.
Sega gave blue blur fans another look at the upcoming release Sonic Superstars at its recent Sonic Central broadcast, but one thing it didn't lock in was a release date.
It's due to arrive at some point in Fall 2023 and there's now apparently been "multiple retailer listings" for Sonic Superstars - suggesting the game will be released on 17th October. This specific date can be found on websites like Target and GameStop in the US, with the price locked at $59.99.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Batman Arkham Trilogy For Switch Only Includes One Title On The Game Cartridge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151777</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/batman-arkham-trilogy-for-switch-only-includes-one-title-on-the-game-cartridge"/>
        <updated>2023-06-24T01:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You'll have to download Arkham City & Knight.
One of the third-party highlights of the latest Nintendo Direct earlier this week was the announcement Batman: Arkham Trilogy would be coming to the Switch this Fall.
As exciting as it is, some new information about the physical version has now surfaced. The Switch version's FAQ has revealed the hard copy will only include Batman Arkham Asylum on the game card, with the other two titles (Batman: Arkham City and Batman: Arkham Knight) requiring a download:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men Of War 2 is another game you'll be juggling with Starfield this September]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/men-of-war-2-is-another-game-youll-be-juggling-with-starfield-this-september</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/men-of-war-2-is-another-game-youll-be-juggling-with-starfield-this-september"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T21:59:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Best Way have announced the release date for their WW2 RTS Men Of War 2, and it's coming in one of the busiest months of the year so far for big PC releases. Arriving on September 20th on Steam and the Epic Games Store, Men Of War 2 joins the likes of Lies Of P, Cyberpunk 2077's Phantom Liberty expansion, Pay Day 3, Mortal Kombat 1 and Life By You in the fight for your attention in the wake of Bethesda's epic space RPG Starfield, which launches just two weeks beforehand on September 6th.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI Has A Neat Neon Genesis Evangelion Anime Nod]]></title>
        <id>1850572342</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-neon-genesis-evangelion-ps5-anime-1850572342"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T21:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI, a more action-focused take on the RPG franchise, clearly pulls inspiration from a lot of other popular media. As Game Informer reported back in May, Square Enix was inspired by blockbuster films and hit series like Game of Thrones, Godzilla, and Neon Genesis Evangelion during the game’s development.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ladies Of The Witcher Are Storming Fortnite]]></title>
        <id>1850572369</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-witcher-ciri-yennefer-item-shop-vbucks-1850572369"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T21:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games’ battle royale shooter Fortnite has some new characters joining in on the quest for the W: The Witcher 3’s Ciri, Geralt of Rivia’s adopted daughter, and his love interest Yennefer of Vengerberg are now available in the game’s item shop.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Levi Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kotaku's Weekend Guide: 9 Awesome Games To Play]]></title>
        <id>1850571987</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-system-shock-zelda-totk-diablo-4-1850571987"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another weekend is upon us. And perhaps in these next few days you’ll find yourself facing an Xbox, PlayStation, gaming PC, or other such contraption and staring into a blank screen of endless, unlit pixels wondering, “What should I play?”
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Diablo IV Quest Rewards You With Great Loot And A Heartfelt Story]]></title>
        <id>1850572300</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-taissa-quest-mark-of-the-conclave-occultist-1850572300"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T21:29:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One quest line in Diablo IV is drawing in players not just for good loot, but because it has a strong mental health message that makes it feel meaningful beyond the actual perks.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Mario Bros. Wonder Is Full Of Amazing Little Details]]></title>
        <id>1850571917</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-bros-wonder-nintendo-switch-2d-graphics-1850571917"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T20:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo revealed its latest 2D side-scrolling Mario game at its June 21 Direct, and to the unsuspecting eye it might have looked like a familiar return to the New Super Mario Bros. spin-offs of old. But longtime fans quickly noticed that Super Mario Bros. Wonder looks full of extra animated flourishes that set it up…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controversial World Of Warcraft Quest Removed After Fan Backlash]]></title>
        <id>1850571919</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/world-of-warcraft-ptr-alexstrasza-quest-a-missing-soul-1850571919"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T20:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Popular fantasy MMO World of Warcraft has come under fire for a questline that pushed up against some of the darker parts of the franchise’s lore, and it was not flattering.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Pikmin 2 - Still A Sublime Time, Even Without The 7-Up Bottle Cap]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151645</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/pikmin-2"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pik of the bunch.
Not content with dropping an HD port of the original Pikmin during the June 2023 Nintendo Direct, the platform holder also saw fit to furnish us with this slightly revamped version of its sequel, the very excellent Pikmin 2. Hooray!
Yes, Nintendo has planted us firmly in the Pikmin 4 hype zone prior to that game's launch and, if you've yet to play this 2004 GameCube gem, you're in for a great big treat. Pikmin 2 takes the wonderfully unique and inventive foundations of its timeless predecessor and gently adds more variety to the mix, resulting in a game that's arguably the pik (we are so clever) of this franchise thus far.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s Every Video Game Release Date For 2023]]></title>
        <id>1849945704</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/upcoming-video-game-release-date-2023-ps5-xbox-pc-1849945704"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T19:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have awoken from my sliced ham and prosecco-induced holiday slumber and am ready to acknowledge (with only a little bit of a tremor) that we are in a new year. New year, new me? No. Spiral ham and prosecco remind me that it’s okay for some things to always remain the same. New year, new set of video game release…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This gorgeous fantasy roguelite is my favourite new discovery from June's Steam Next Fest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-gorgeous-fantasy-roguelite-is-my-favourite-new-discovery-from-junes-steam-next-fest</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-gorgeous-fantasy-roguelite-is-my-favourite-new-discovery-from-junes-steam-next-fest"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T19:32:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Steam Next Fests go, I think the one this June has easily been one of the best Next Fests in a little while. Seeing all the great demos this week has made me far more excited about the future of video games than any of the notE3 streams did the other week, and I'm not gonna lie, a large part of my excitement stems from the brilliant Let's! Revolution!, a beautifully animated tile-based roguelite that has a touch of Minesweeper about it. I highlighted it in our big demo rec list at the start of the week, but 150-odd words simply wasn't enough to really get across just how excellent this is. So indulge me a bit while I tell you more about it.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Alan Wake Intro Only Exists Because Stephen King Sold His Quote For $1]]></title>
        <id>1850571668</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/release-date-alan-wake-remastered-steam-stephen-king-1850571668"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T19:31:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The opening shot of Alan Wake, the 2010 action-adventure horror remastered fairly recently, in 2021, finds us winding around a dusky mountain pass. As we watch spruce trees come and go and the orange sunset give way to chalky fog, protagonist Alan Wake says the following in a voiceover: “Stephen King once wrote that…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Is The Overpowered Final Fantasy XVI Build You Want To Run]]></title>
        <id>1850571573</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-ultima-bahamut-mercy-genji-gloves-ps5-1850571573"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T19:13:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By the time you reach Final Fantasy XVI’s endgame after a minimum of 35 hours, protagonist Clive Rosfield can call upon the might of eight different magical beings called Eikons, each the warden of a specific element. The fire of the Phoenix offers several different ways to scorch enemies, and Shiva’s ice can freeze…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Corey Plante</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weby Českého rozhlasu byly včera pod útokem]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44869</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/weby-ceskeho-rozhlasu-byly-vcera-pod-utokem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:58:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weby Českého rozhlasu byly včera pod útokem a nebyly dostupné. Útok byl patrně v souvislosti s konferencí Média a Ukrajina, která včera pod záštitou rozhlasu probíhala. K hostům patřili prezident ČR Petr Pavel a starosta Kyjeva Vitalij Kličko.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything Sega Announced For Sonic The Hedgehog’s 32nd Anniversary]]></title>
        <id>1850571369</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-anniversary-stream-superstars-1850571369"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:44:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today is Sonic the Hedgehog’s 32nd anniversary, and Sega released a 20-minute Sonic Central showcase to talk about upcoming projects, and alongside talking about upcoming 2D throwback Sonic Superstars, there were a lot of non-game announcements during the show. If you want to watch the whole stream, you can do so …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Legend Of Zelda: Tears Of The Kingdom: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1850570840</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-the-kotaku-r-1850570840"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I climb up onto a giant lilypad floating in the middle of a lake and it sinks under my weight, leaving me submerged up to my shins.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carolyn Petit</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI: 8 Useful Settings To Adjust For The Best Experience]]></title>
        <id>1850571116</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-settings-graphics-frame-rate-ps5-tips-1850571116"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest in the legendary series of Japanese role-playing games, Final Fantasy XVI features a very different tone in both story and combat. And with a vast story covering complex fictional political plotlines, it can all be a little overwhelming. The good news, however, is that Final Fantasy XVI features a number of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Your Cosplay Says About You: Brutal Callout Edition]]></title>
        <id>1850570816</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/cosplay-eddie-munson-kratos-anime-marvel-dc-star-wars-1850570816"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten years ago I went to my first New York Comic Con dressed in a perfectly fine Doctor Who cosplay (Tenth Doctor, of course). My outfit was more a collection of H&M pieces and a pair of Converse I already owned rather than a bespoke look crafted by me in my parents’ garage, but donning such a getup and attending a…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alyssa Mercante</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go 1.21 bude umět PGO - rychlejší programy i kompilace]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44868</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/go-1-21-bude-umet-pgo-rychlejsi-programy-i-kompilace/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:18:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve středu vyšlo Go 1.21 RC2. V RC1 se totiž objevila chyba, ta byla opravena a vydáno bylo hned RC2. Mezi hlavní změny patří PGO (profile based optimization). To už bylo k testování v Go 1.20, ale v 1.21 již bude k ostrému nasazení. Stačí mít v hlavním adresáři soubor default.pgo a PGO bude použito. Očekává se zrychlení 2–7 %. Vlastní Go 1.21 je také kompilováno s PGO a kompiluje o 2–4 % rychleji (záleží na architektuře).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feature: 20 Things You Might Have Missed In The Super Mario Bros. Wonder Reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151677</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/20-things-you-might-have-missed-in-the-super-mario-bros-wonder-reveal"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Power-ups, princesses, persons unknown.
The June 2023 Nintendo Direct showcase gave us a lot to look forward to over the next year on Switch, but the star of the show had to be the reveal of a brand new 2D Mario game, Super Mario Bros. Wonder.
Thoughts after our first viewing of the trailer were mainly dominated by the elephant in the room — we mean the literal elephant — but we soon managed to pull ourselves together and begin to take in some of the other, hidden features.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Fighter 6’s Modern Controls Are Great For The Game]]></title>
        <id>1850570729</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/street-fighter-6-modern-classic-controls-capcom-1850570729"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Schulkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind Blown: Across The Spider-Verse Has Multiple Versions Out In Theaters]]></title>
        <id>1850570713</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/spider-man-across-the-spider-verse-different-versions-1850570713"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spider-Man: Across The Spider-Verse viewers’ collective spidey senses have unearthed yet another spectacular detail in the record-breaking box-office animated film: There are multiple versions of the film doing the rounds in theaters.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Best Switch Games In Nintendo's Hyper Max eShop Sale (North America)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151359</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-switch-games-in-nintendos-hyper-max-eshop-sale-north-america"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Sale ends this weekend.

Update: The Hyper Max eShop Sale ends on 25th June, so make sure you check out our favourite games that have been discounted.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hideo Kojima Documentary Is The Worst Kind Of Fan Service]]></title>
        <id>1850570684</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/hideo-kojima-connecting-worlds-review-death-stranding-1850570684"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T16:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima: Connecting Worlds—PlayStation Studios and Kojima Productions’ hour-long documentary on Metal Gear Solid creator Hideo Kojima—is too in awe of its subject to see him clearly. Premiered at Tribeca Festival on June 17, the documentary inflates Kojima’s mythology as an untouchable auteur until it totally…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Is Giving Away Some Great PC Games, Overwatch Levels For Free]]></title>
        <id>1850570632</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/amazon-prime-day-free-prey-redfall-overwatch-2-diablo-4-1850570632"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Day is still a couple weeks away, but from now until July 12 you can begin picking up some extra free gaming perks for those already subscribed to the service. First up is Prey, the excellent 2017 immersive sim that Arkane Austin made before shipping the troubled Game Pass exclusive, Redfall. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto V PC Players Are Getting Left Behind Thanks To Updates]]></title>
        <id>1850570554</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/gta-online-5-pc-ps5-next-gen-features-content-missing-1850570554"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T16:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technically, Grand Theft Auto Online is alive and well on PC, receiving all the same updates the console versions of the popular online crime sim get, as they get them. Well, most of them. Because see, Rockstar has begun sneaking more and more exclusive features into the two next-gen console ports, leaving PC players…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto V Immortalizes Lost Titanic Submarine With Fan Mod]]></title>
        <id>1850570385</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/gta-5-online-mod-oceangate-titanic-titan-sub-mod-pc-1850570385"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the biggest slow motion tragedies in recent memory appears to have wrapped up with a bad if not altogether shocking ending. The lost OceanGate Expeditions Titan submersible is now believed to have imploded on its way to the Titanic wreck, and in fact the U.S. Navy apparently knew this shortly after the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hearthstone and Inscryption heads should pay attention to Cross Blitz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hearthstone-and-inscryption-heads-should-pay-attention-to-cross-blitz</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hearthstone-and-inscryption-heads-should-pay-attention-to-cross-blitz"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T15:57:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know when the look of a game instantly captures your attention, and then you play a demo for it and it's even better? That's the journey I've been on with deckbuilding RPG Cross Blitz this week. I first heard about it last month back when word hit that it was coming to early access this year, and I was instantly taken with its chunky animal character sprites. There was something a bit Advance Wars about the look and style about its burly lion pirate captain, but just, you know, in a high seas card battle kind of setting instead of dealing with sergeants, tanks and air support. But its Steam Next Fest demo has really sunk its teeth into me this week, offering up turn-based card duels that scratch exactly the same kind of itch as Inscryption did for me a couple of years ago.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI’s Cid Is The Game’s Breakout Star]]></title>
        <id>1850570377</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-cid-voice-actor-ralph-ineson-ramuh-1850570377"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T15:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Characters named Cid are a Final Fantasy mainstay, but I wasn’t prepared for Final Fantasy XVI’s iteration, and neither were many people playing the action RPG this week.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LEGO Sonic Is Drop Dashing Into Sonic Superstars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151764</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/lego-sonic-is-drop-dashing-into-sonic-superstars"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Block off your calendars.
During today's Sonic Central showcase, Sega announced that it is collaborating with Lego to bring Lego Sonic the Hedgehog to Sonic Superstars.
The appearance doesn't seem to be anything more than an aesthetic change, but the visuals retain all the subtle nuances that have been showcased in the Sonic the Hedghog Lego sets.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands On: The Tomb Raider Returns To A Nintendo System In A Promising Package]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151341</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/hands-on-the-tomb-raider-returns-to-a-nintendo-system-in-a-promising-package"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Lara Lara laughs.
It’s been a bit of a barren six years or thereabouts for Switch-owning Tomb Raider fans, without so much as a remastered golden oldie or even (mercifully, perhaps) a quickie cloud version of one of the new-fangled reboots to enjoy on Nintendo’s platform. However, all of that is just about to change with the imminent arrival of The Lara Croft Collection, which hits the eShop on the 29th June.
Not to be confused with The Tomb Raider Collection, which gave lucky PC players a massive 13 games from across this hallowed franchise to dig into, this much slighter package comes courtesy of Feral Interactive (Alien Isolation, GRID Autosport) and contains 2010’s Lara Croft and the Guardian of Light and its follow-up, 2014’s Lara Croft and the Temple of Osiris. On the one hand, it’s perhaps a little disappointing that we don’t get to have any of the old Tomb Raider classics involved here but, on the other, what we are getting is two surprisingly great isometric spin-offs from the mains series that do a fantastic job of delivering the thrills and spills of the franchise proper in a portable-friendly form.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play as a radio DJ whose callers are being murdered live on air in Killer Frequency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/play-as-a-radio-dj-whose-callers-are-being-murdered-live-on-air-in-killer-frequency</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/play-as-a-radio-dj-whose-callers-are-being-murdered-live-on-air-in-killer-frequency"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am having an absolute riot playing Killer Frequency. It’s a first-person puzzle horror where you're trying to help folks escape a rampaging murderer. Usually, when I read a game description like that, I’m already grabbing my cushion to hide behind and readying my cute puppy compilation video on a second screen, but Team17 have heavily leaned into the campy side of slasher horror with humour serving as the perfect buffer. No safety cushion or puppies needed here, folks. 
Here’s the set-up: You’re playing as Forrest Nash, a big-time radio DJ who has found himself stuck in Small Town, Nowhere, USA. While you're working as the host for the town’s local station, it turns out the police chief has only gone and gotten themselves stabbed by a serial killer. With them out of action, you’re roped into acting as a stand-in 911 operator - and with the murderer still on the loose and ready to strike again, that line is going to be pretty busy.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Watts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Best Switch Games In Nintendo's eShop Summer Sale (Europe)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151161</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-switch-games-in-nintendos-eshop-summer-sale-europe"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update #2: Ends this weekend!

Update 2: You've only got a few more days to snap up some cheap Switch games on the eShop. the sale ends on 25th June, so check out our picks for the best of the best.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Shareholder Meeting Disrupted By Fan Who Spent $3.5K To Complain About Splatoon]]></title>
        <id>1850569794</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/splatoon-3-nintendo-switch-hairstyles-options-guns-1850569794"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T14:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s no other video game company quite like Nintendo, and the same thing appears to be true about its fans. One reportedly spent roughly $3,500 on company stock to interrupt the most recent shareholders meeting and seemingly rant about the lack of male hairstyle customization options in Splatoon 3. Nintendo…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that went down in day one at court for Microsoft, Sony, and the FTC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everything-that-went-down-in-day-one-at-court-for-microsoft-sony-and-the-ftc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everything-that-went-down-in-day-one-at-court-for-microsoft-sony-and-the-ftc"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T14:10:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday marked the first day of proceedings in the legal battle between Microsoft and the US Federal Trade Commission as the FTC seeks a preliminary injunction on Microsoft and Activision Blizzard. The injunction would further prevent Microsoft's acquisition deal of Activision Blizzard from going through. 

Several of Xbox's high profile figures testified at the first day of trial, including the likes of Sarah Bond, corporate vice president of gaming partnerships and business development at Microsoft, Bethesda head of publishing Pete Hines, and Xbox Game Studios head Matt Booty. They were questioned on a range of things including cloud gaming, Call Of Duty exclusivity, and Bobby Kotick's revenue share demands.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Where To Pre-Order Detective Pikachu Returns On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151600</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/where-to-pre-order-detective-pikachu-returns-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physical pre-orders are live now!
The original Detective Pikachu game launched on 3DS back in 2016, and following on from the hit movie, the series is due to return on Switch later this year with the aptly named Detective Pikachu Returns.
The game launches on 6th October 2023 and pre-order options are already starting to appear. We'll be keeping track of all retail options for you on this page, highlighting the best deals and cheapest prices available as and when they go live. Keep this page bookmarked or grab a copy below!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft’s Call of Duty Clone Is Actually Pretty Good]]></title>
        <id>1850568211</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/xdefiant-open-beta-review-call-of-duty-black-ops-test-1850568211"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft’s big, crossover first-person shooter XDefiant isn’t out until later this year. However, a short open beta is currently being held until June 23. And after playing a few hours of Ubisoft’s new Call of Duty-like shooter, I’m surprised by just how much I like it. But I’m also concerned that it might not stand…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hip-Thrusting Is Just One Of The Weird Minigames In Everybody 1-2-Switch!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151749</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/hip-thrusting-is-just-one-of-the-weird-minigames-in-everybody-1-2-switch"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All 17 have been revealed.
A month ago, Everybody 1-2-Switch!'s existence was shrouded in mystery, with reports circling about apparent dislike of the game from internal Nintendo employees. Today, we're just a week away from the game's launch, and Nintendo has shared details of all 17 minigames in this upcoming sequel.
Nintendo has launched an official Japanese website for Everybody 1-2-Switch, and recently, it's been updated to include clips of all 17 minigames that will feature (thanks, GoNintendo!).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI's RPG Elements Are Barely There]]></title>
        <id>1850567705</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-xvi-rpg-combat-action-square-enix-ps5-1850567705"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For three decades the Final Fantasy franchise has been known for reinventing itself, whether it’s the cyberpunk-esque stylings of Final Fantasy VII or the push into online multiplayer with Final Fantasy XI. The next watershed moment for the franchise is here, with Final Fantasy XVI trying to push into a more mature…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayes Madsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Pikmin 1 - A Bare-Bones Port, But A Joyous Adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151644</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/pikmin-1"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pik it out.
Nintendo gave Pikmin fans a couple of lovely surprises during the June 2023 Nintendo Direct, prepping players for Pikmin 4's debut by stealth-dropping the original Pikmin and its wonderful sequel in HD remastered form. Exciting!
Yes, if you've played these two beauties before, you'll know they're among some of Nintendo's loveliest work, and digging into the 2001 original here reveals a game that's stood the test of time remarkably well. Pikmin 1 is still a joyous, playful, cute and colourful adventure to undertake and, although this HD remaster isn't quite up to the standards we'd expect from the Big N — and nowhere near the level of remaster we got with the recent Metroid Prime Remastered — it's still a must-play in our book, especially if you've yet to sample the delights of this GameCube classic.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Summer 2023 Anime Guide: What To Watch And Where It's Streaming]]></title>
        <id>1850567228</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/jujutsu-kaisen-crunchyroll-netflix-hidive-anime-guide-1850567228"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations, you survived watching (and/or backlogging) last season’s whopping 50 new anime shows. Your reward: a helpful guide to yet another wave of new and returning anime shows and movies coming to your favorite 2D streaming service.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Disgruntled Splatoon 3 Fan Complains Directly To Nintendo's President About Male Poses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151742</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/random-disgruntled-splatoon-3-fan-complains-directly-to-nintendos-president-about-male-poses"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bought shares just to access Nintendo's annual shareholder meeting.
Imagine saving up money to buy shares so you can attend a shareholder meeting with the company president and complain about something in a video game. That's exactly what one Splatoon 3 fan has reportedly done. GLHF reports that a Splatoon 3 player saved up enough cash to attend a recent Nintendo shareholder meeting simply to complain about an apparent lack of poses for male inklings and octolings in the ink-based team shooter.
The attendee reportedly held up the meeting for a while with their complaints, stating that Nintendo has "given boys the cold shoulder" (as translated by GLHF's Georgina Young), accusing the Big N of favouring the female characters. They've previously written to Nintendo about their concerns before, but claim to have been ignored as things "didn't seem to improve".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tartarus Key's theming rules because it's tropey, not scary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-tartarus-keys-theming-rules-because-its-tropey-not-scary</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-tartarus-keys-theming-rules-because-its-tropey-not-scary"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are a bunch of reasons I like The Tartarus Key (enough to make it our RPS Game Club pick this month), and one of them is that it's not actually scary. Like, sure, you could attach the horror tag to it on Steam if you wanted, but it's more of a costume for you to enjoy - like the family down the street who are really into Halloween and turn their suburban semi into a haunted house with a movie-quality zombie in the front yard. It's really cool and you like it on its own terms, but being frightened isn't so much the point as it is to remember you have enjoyed being frightened in the past. Also, for some reason the family won't let you out of the living room until you complete a logic puzzle involving maths.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Problém Nouveau s jádrem 6.3 vyřešen v 6.3.9]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44867</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/problem-nouveau-s-jadrem-6-3-vyresen-v-6-3-9/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T12:07:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Open source ovladač Nouveau pro grafické karty NVIDIA měl chybu typu use-after-free v jádře 6.3. Bylo doporučeno se těmto jádrům zatím vyhnout. Chyba byla celkem rychle opravena a poslána do jádra 6.4.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tears of the Kingdom Is Another Zelda That's Low Key A Horror Game]]></title>
        <id>1850562373</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/tears-of-the-kingdom-totk-horror-depths-gloom-switch-1850562373"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though The Legend of Zelda franchise often dips into the eerie and the occult, its dominant mode is one of high adventure. Rather than associating the Japanese series with horror, we imagine a blonde boy swinging his sword in service of rescuing the princess against a backdrop of soaring music. Its world is populated…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Scaife</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Kart Tour Gains New City Circuit In Upcoming Night Tour Update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151744</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/mario-kart-tour-gains-new-city-circuit-in-upcoming-night-tour-update"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T11:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When in Rome.
We are now heading into the final lap of Mario Kart Tour's 'Mario vs. Luigi Tour' and that means that it is time for us to see what's up next.
As shared today via the @mariokarttourEN Twitter, we got our first look at the 'Night Tour', which is set to see Wii Moonview Highway speeding into the game along with a brand new city circuit, Rome Avanti. This circuit will see you driving through the Italian capital, navigating quaint streets and drifting around the Colosseum — might we see this one come to Mario Kart 8 Deluxe soon?
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Fire Emblem - The Blazing Blade Is Still As Sharp As Ever]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-45592</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/gba/fire-emblem"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So much to love Lyndis game.
This review originally went live in 2015, and we're updating and republishing it to mark the game's arrival in the Nintendo Switch Online Expansion Pack GBA library.

Before Fire Emblem: Awakening kicked off 2013 (the Year of Luigi, you'll recall) with a bang, there was a great deal of concern at Nintendo regarding its future viability as a franchise. Sales were at an all-time low, and series producer Hitoshi Yamagami was given an ultimatum: at least 250,000 copies of the latest entry needed to be sold in order to ensure the franchise had a future. Of course, we know now that the 3DS masterpiece went on to sell more copies in the US than any other series entry at the time, bringing the game to a bigger audience than ever before and cementing the Fire Emblem brand's value.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't worry, the PC port of Final Fantasy 16 is definitely still in the works]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-worry-the-pc-port-of-final-fantasy-16-is-definitely-still-in-the-works</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-worry-the-pc-port-of-final-fantasy-16-is-definitely-still-in-the-works"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T10:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Will it or won't it?" has been the big question. That is, will Final Fantasy 16 actually be released on PC or won't it. It's been emotional whiplash for some PC fans. A PC version was specified in the game's announcement trailer, and then FF16 producer Yoshi-P walked it back and said that didn't happen, and then Yoshi-P addressed his previous words and said he'd like to bring the game to PC eventually. Just don't expect it within six months. Or before 2024, actually.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Reveals Range Of Pikmin 4 Homewares Heading For FamilyMart Stores In Japan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151741</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/nintendo-reveals-range-of-pikmin-4-homewares-heading-for-familymart-stores-in-japan"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ice, ice Pikmin.
Here at Nintendo Life, you will regularly catch us getting envious of region-exclusive game merchandise, and such envy has hit us today as we got a first look at the range of Pikmin 4 homewares that will soon be coming to FamilyMart stores in Japan as well as the Nintendo stores in Tokyo and Osaka.
Shared via a blog post on the official Nintendo Japan site, the collection will be released in three waves over the next month beginning on 4th July. There are a lot of awesome-looking products available from notebooks to handbags, and we thought that we would share some snaps of our favourites with you below so that we can be united in our envy.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matfyz pořádá letní tábor s matematikou, fyzikou a informatikou]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44866</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/matfyz-porada-letni-tabor-s-matematikou-fyzikou-a-informatikou/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T10:22:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matfyz již tradičně pořádá začátkem prázdnin Letní ŠMF – Školu Matematiky a Fyziky. Na tento tábor pro středoškoláky se mohou přihlásit všichni, kteří se chtějí naučit něco zajímavého z matematiky, fyziky nebo informatiky a zároveň poznat kamarády s podobnými zájmy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jirka Setnička)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Super Smash Bros. Melee Cards From UK Nintendo Magazine Uploaded Online]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151739</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/random-super-smash-bros-melee-cards-from-uk-nintendo-magazine-uploaded-online"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T09:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blast from the past.
Man, we really miss the days when print magazines were all the rage. Yes, call us old, we don't care!
There was something special about picking up the latest issue of Nintendo Official Magazine (later succeeded by Official Nintendo Magazine, or ONM) and NGamer, especially when they included bonus goodies that you couldn't find elsewhere.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pour one out for Call Of Duty: Warzone Caldera, which is shutting down in September]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pour-one-out-for-call-of-duty-warzone-caldera-which-is-shutting-down-in-september</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pour-one-out-for-call-of-duty-warzone-caldera-which-is-shutting-down-in-september"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T09:23:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision are shutting down Call of Duty: Warzone Caldera later this year to "focus on future Call Of Duty content including the current Warzone free-to-play experience". Caldera, the new name for the original Warzone, was first released in March 2020, and was later renamed after Warzone 2 launched in November 2022.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Datová Akademie: naučte se analyzovat a zpracovat data (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42299</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/datova-akademie-naucte-se-analyzovat-a-zpracovat-data-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T09:05:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Datová Akademie je prezenční kurz vyvinutý s experty v oblasti datové analýzy. Na kurzu se budete zabývat strukturou a pochopením dat, jejich vizualizací a zpracováním v různých systémech. Postupně projedeme všechny klíčové oblasti a technologie potřebné k práci datového analytika.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fate/Samurai Remnant Brings The Action To Edo Japan This September On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151737</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/fatesamurai-remnant-brings-the-action-to-edo-japan-this-september-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Holy Grail War returns.
The latest entry in the Fate series, Fate/Samurai Remnant, is launching on Nintendo Switch alongside PlayStation and PC on 29th September 2023, publisher Koei Tecmo has announced.
This gargantuan multimedia franchise started way back in 2004 with the visual novel Fate/stay night and has spawned multiple sequels, anime, manga, and other genres of video games. Most of the series focuses on the Holy Grail Wars, in which the winning dup of a Master and Servant can win an artefact that grants wishes.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RPS are partnering up with the Rezzed Zone at EGX 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-are-partnering-up-with-the-rezzed-zone-at-egx-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-are-partnering-up-with-the-rezzed-zone-at-egx-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frequent EGX goers will know that the Rezzed Zone has always been home to the best and most interesting games at the UK’s biggest gaming show, and RPS will be there on the ground this year, highlighting our favourites, bringing you various audio visual delights and more across the course of the weekend. 
EGX 2023 runs from October 12th - 15th at London’s Excel this year, and RPS supporters can get 50% off Early Entry tickets (which is on top of the current 10% off discount available until July 7th for everyone else, I might add). Keen to hear more about exactly what we’ll be getting up to? Read on below for all the details. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vlastní ONT v GPON síti PODA]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16661</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/vlastni-ont-v-gpon-siti-poda/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T08:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PODA jako jeden z mála českých ISP umožňuje na GPON síti použití vlastního ONT. Umožňuje to využít SFP modul a zbavit se tak samostatné krabičky, která z optiky dělá ethernet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rocky Linux a AlmaLinux reagují na omezení přístupu ke zdrojovým kódům RHEL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44865</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rocky-linux-a-almalinux-reaguji-na-omezeni-pristupu-ke-zdrojovym-kodum-rhel/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T08:47:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve středu společnost Red Hat oznámila, že kompletní zdrojové kódy distribuce RHEL uzavírá za zákaznický portál. Už tedy nebudou přístupné prostřednictvím gitového repozitáře CentOSu a přístup ke všem opravám budou mít jen platící zákazníci. To samozřejmě komplikuje život tvůrcům odvozených distribucí, jejichž cílem je vytvořit plnohodnotný klon RHEL včetně všech dostupných oprav.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora ulehčí nasazení systemd-boot jako náhrady GRUBu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44864</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/fedora-ulehci-nasazeni-systemd-boot-jako-nahrady-grubu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T08:06:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora v současnosti používá GRUB a shim pro start UEFI počítačů. Tak to zůstane i nadále, ale podle návrhu by mělo jít místo GRUB a shim alternativně používat již od instalace systemd-boot, který se již stejně s Fedorou dodává.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cuphead-Like 2D Platformer Enchanted Portals Coming To Switch This Summer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151735</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/cuphead-like-2d-platformer-enchanted-portals-coming-to-switch-this-summer"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T05:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physical release also confirmed.
Back in 2019, a Kickstarter was launched for a "magical" 2D platformer known as Enchanted Portals. It was accused at the time of being a Cuphead clone, and although there were a few things to overcome along the way, it hasn't stopped developer Xixo from seeing out the project.
In an update, the studio has now officially confirmed it will be coming to the Nintendo Switch this summer. This cartoon-like adventure, which supports two-player co-op, sees a pair of "rookie magicians" stuck between dimensions as they journey through a variety of enchanting worlds in an attempt to "reclaim the Magic Book".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zelda: Tears Of The Kingdom Was One Of Twitch's "Most Watched" Games In May]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151732</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-was-one-of-twitchs-most-watched-games-in-may"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[37 million hours watching Link.
May was an absolutely massive month for Nintendo this year with the arrival of the highly anticipated release, The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom. It dominated the charts in the same month, and its success actually carried over to the streaming platform Twitch.
A story over on GamesIndustry.biz reveals Tears of the Kingdom was able to crack the top 10 "most watched" games for the month of May, coming in at ninth place. Viewers racked up a whopping 37 million hours in total. Here's how it compared to other games on the platform:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E3 2024 And 2025 Have Supposedly Been Cancelled]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-151731</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2023/06/e3-2024-and-2025-have-supposedly-been-cancelled"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T02:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ESA claims "no final decisions" have been made.
E3 2023 was cancelled earlier this year in March, and now in an update, it seems the events for 2024 and 2025 have also been axed. This information was featured in a slide during a Los Angeles City Tourism Board meeting.
The Entertainment Software Association has come out with a statement, mentioning how "no final decisions" about next year's event had been made yet. It's reportedly "having conversations" about 2024 and beyond at this stage.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Favorite Cosplay From Dreamhack Melbourne 2023]]></title>
        <id>1850568395</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/cosplay-gallery-melbourne-dreamhack-2023-genshin-1850568395"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Comic-Con to C2E2, the vast majority of cosplay coverage you see on this website comes from American conventions. Which is fine! This is an American website, many of the world’s biggest shows are in the US and our intrepid cosplay photographer Mineralblu is also American.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novinky pro Linux 6.5: podpora vektorových instrukcí RISC-V či aktualizovaný Rust]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16660</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/novinky-pro-linux-6-5-podpora-vektorovych-instrukci-risc-v-ci-aktualizovany-rust/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aktualizovaný Rust Toolchain, asynchronní zápis dat pro F2FS, podpora Qualcomm Adreno 690, senzorů základních desek s Nuvoton NCT6799D i funkční herní ovladač Nvidia Shield s přípravou na nový typ.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fortnite: Chapter 4 Season 3 Week 3 Quests And NPC Locations]]></title>
        <id>1850567669</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-weekly-quest-mud-slide-pod-plants-reveal-1850567669"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re three weeks into Fortnite’s latest season and hopefully you’ve been able to cross off the weekly quests without much trouble thus far. This week, however, you might’ve come across a few challenges that aren’t as familiar, including one involving one of the new mechanics: Mud. Insert joke about getting dirty and…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Says Xbox Has Been Losing The Console Wars Since 2001]]></title>
        <id>1850567636</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-series-x-ps5-switch-microsoft-sony-nintendo-sales-1850567636"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Microsoft dukes it out with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) over its $69 billion acquisition of Activision Blizzard, the Xbox maker has admitted something everyone probably already knew by now: It’s lost the console wars.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Levi Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E3 2024 And 2025 Have Seemingly Been Canceled, Too [Update]]]></title>
        <id>1850285081</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/when-is-e3-canceled-electronic-expo-summer-games-fest-1850285081"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T20:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update 06/22/2023 4:20 p.m. ET: As spotted by ResetEra, on Wednesday, June 21, 2023, the Los Angeles City Tourism Board of Commissioners held its regularly scheduled meeting and announced updates on tourism-related business and the like. Not usually the kind of thing that gets reported on Kotaku, sure. But in the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best And Worst Parts Of Every Mainline Final Fantasy]]></title>
        <id>1850567242</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-best-worst-game-rpg-square-enix-ff-16-1850567242"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T20:18:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Final Fantasy series’ charm is that, because every game is so different from the others, they each have their own strengths and faults. Some games excel in aspects others crash and burn trying to emulate, and it makes the series fascinating to compare and contrast. We even tried to rank these disparate games and …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Upcoming Indiana Jones Game Will Be Xbox Only, Intensifying The Console Wars]]></title>
        <id>1850566856</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-activision-indiana-jones-bethesda-exclusive-court-1850566856"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T19:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During Thursday’s big Xbox vs Federal Trade Commission court hearing, Pete Hines of Bethesda (Fallout, Starfield) confirmed that the upcoming Indiana Jones game from MachineGames was originally planned to be a multiplatform release, meaning available to more people. But after Xbox bought up Bethesda, things changed…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Players Angry That OG Call of Duty: Warzone Will Shut Down This Fall]]></title>
        <id>1850566598</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-warzone-1-caldera-verdansk-shutdown-1850566598"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s official: Warzone Caldera, formerly known as the original Call of Duty: Warzone, is shutting down later this year so developers can focus on the battle royale’s sequel and players are angry. The announcement came in a Call of Duty blog post titled “An update on Call of Duty: Warzone Caldera” published on June 22. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alyssa Mercante</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Overwatch, Healing Is The Real Gay Agenda]]></title>
        <id>1850071120</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-best-healer-gay-character-support-role-1850071120"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a phenomenon in the Overwatch community that has persisted through the original game’s 2016 release, its gradual decline, and the launch of the sequel. This phenomenon is an interesting one, a sort of “IYKYK” situation that requires membership in a specific community in order to recognize its members: in …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alyssa Mercante</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nightmare Submarine Game Gets Popular As Search For Titanic Sub Continues]]></title>
        <id>1850566034</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/submarine-missing-titan-titanic-iron-lung-steam-horror-1850566034"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T17:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you likely are aware, five people are currently missing onboard a tourist sub that was heading down to the remains of the HMS Titanic. We don’t yet know what went wrong and if those onboard are still alive—it seems unlikely at this point—but a large-scale search for the Titan and its crew is still underway.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokimane Says Moving From Twitch To Kick Isn't Worth Compromising Morals, Is 'Cringe']]></title>
        <id>1850566055</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/xqc-pokimane-kick-twitch-amouranth-streamer-drama-1850566055"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imane “Pokimane” Anys would never stream on rising platform Kick, which already lured big names xQc and Amouranth away from Twitch with high profile contracts. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is PlayStation Really Worried About Losing Call of Duty To Microsoft? Private Emails Say No]]></title>
        <id>1850565999</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/ps5-call-duty-xbox-activision-blizzard-deal-exclusive-1850565999"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T17:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PlayStation boss Jim Ryan has been fighting Microsoft’s acquisition of Activision Blizzard tooth-and-nail, claiming it jeopardizes Call of Duty on PlayStation 5. But in a private email when the deal was first announced, Ryan apparently wrote that he didn’t think it was an “exclusivity play” to take away Call of Duty,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nejvýkonnější superpočítač Aurora je nainstalován: 2 ExaFLOPS, desítky tisíc CPU a GPU]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44863</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nejvykonnejsi-superpocitac-aurora-je-nainstalovan-2-exaflops-desitky-tisic-cpu-a-gpu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T16:52:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Národní laboratoř Argonne a společnost Intel ve čtvrtek oznámily, že nainstalovaly všech 10 624 uzlů pro superpočítač Aurora, který byl ohlášen již v roce 2015. Systém slibuje špičkový teoretický výpočetní výkon přes 2 ExaFLOPS s využitím pole desítek tisíc procesorů Xeon Max Sapphire Rapids s integrovanou pamětí HBM2E a také výpočetních grafických procesorů Max Ponte Vecchio.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Mania team's next game is a ridiculously colourful 3D platformer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-mania-dev-next-game-pennys-big-breakaway</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-mania-dev-next-game-pennys-big-breakaway"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T16:11:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Evening Star, a new studio made up of the team that made Sonic Mania, have announced their first game, Penny's Big Breakaway. While Sonic Mania was a 2D platformer, the studio's first game under their new name brings them into the realm of 3D, taking an incredibly vibrant colour palette that would certainly work in any classic Sonic game, and marrying it a world that one could say is mildly reminiscent of the hedgehog's rival Mario.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tartarus Key is great when you've got a clever friend who can do the puzzles for you]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-tartarus-key-is-great-when-youve-got-a-clever-friend-who-can-do-the-puzzles-for-you</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-tartarus-key-is-great-when-youve-got-a-clever-friend-who-can-do-the-puzzles-for-you"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T15:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Alice Bee selected thriller-puzzler The Tartarus Key as this month's RPS Game Club pick, I naively signed up for it thinking I'd be fine tackling a game where most puzzles can't be solved with a few trigger pulls. So, I did the smart thing and roped in my pal Ed. Yes, my pal is also called Ed, so parts of this post sound like I'm referring to myself in the third-person. This isn't the case, but if you'd like to imagine that I, in fact, solved the puzzles myself, then please feel free to do so.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tears Of The Kingdom: 10 Surprising Ways Fans Are Using Recall]]></title>
        <id>1850565308</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/tears-of-the-kingdom-totk-zelda-recall-best-use-1850565308"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T15:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Tears of the Kingdom, Link gets a whole new suite of abilities granting him mastery over the physical world around him as well as control over time itself. With Recall, Link can stop time, select an object previously in motion, and send it backwards. It’s an essential tool for getting around some of the game’s…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funday Games on how a beer with a friend spawned Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/funday-games-on-how-a-beer-with-a-friend-spawned-deep-rock-galactic-survivor</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/funday-games-on-how-a-beer-with-a-friend-spawned-deep-rock-galactic-survivor"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T15:23:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the bug-squishing autoshooter is itself still in the larva stage, Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor already looks like a worthwhile Vampire Survivors-like. It apparently helps to crib the mining, mineral hoarding, and maladroit approach to industrial safety that makes source material Deep Rock Galactic one of the best FPS games going.
Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor is in the works at Funday Games, not original DRG devs and fellow Danish outfit Ghost Ship Games. But it does fall under the latter’s new publishing arm, Ghost Ship Publishing, and can trace its origins back to a casual meeting between Funday co-founder Anders Leicht Rohde and Ghost Ship CEO Søren Lundgaard – and beyond.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starfield Director Todd Howard Explains What You’ll Find On Its 1,000 Planets]]></title>
        <id>1850565329</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-rpg-planets-xbox-pc-gaming-todd-howard-1850565329"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T15:05:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Bethesda revealed that Starfield would have over 1,000 planets, it sounded both impressive and like a potential nightmare. What if instead of a dozen bespoke locations, the open world sci-fi RPG was scattered across hundreds of lifeless rocks filled with the same old stuff. Director Todd Howard suggests it’s…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EA Games is dead, long live EA Entertainment and EA Sports]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-games-is-dead-long-live-ea-entertainment-and-ea-sports</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ea-games-is-dead-long-live-ea-entertainment-and-ea-sports"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T14:51:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[EA are cutting themselves down the middle, with EA Games and EA Sports now making up two separate units, and the former getting a rebrand. From now on, EA Games will be known as EA Entertainment, which really doesn't have as good a ring to it (no one's going to be quoting "it's in the entertainment," any time soon are they?). The name change does imply a broader expansion into more than just games, but it's obviously a bit of a wait and see kind of situation until EA show off something that isn't a video game.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children's Game Roblox Now Lets You Make Games For Players Aged 17 And Up]]></title>
        <id>1850565154</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/play-roblox-game-update-adult-content-minecraft-pc-1850565154"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox, the online game creation system once populated mostly by kids under 13, is adding a new 17+ category to account for its recent growth in adult players. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh No, Diablo IV Will Make You Create A New Character For Every Season]]></title>
        <id>1850565167</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-4-new-season-one-date-character-battle-pass-1850565167"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T14:36:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have yet to dive into Diablo IV, even as my coworkers are raving about it, but I’m starting to think I never will now that I know you apparently have to create a new character each season to take part in its battle passes.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone's Learning About Gabe Newell's Deep-Sea Submarine Now]]></title>
        <id>1850563956</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/steam-gabe-newell-submarine-submersible-valve-science-1850563956"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have seen a story going around this week with the headline “The only manned submersible that could reach the missing Titan is owned by Steam’s Gabe Newell,” in reference to the leader of the world’s biggest PC gaming platform. This is true, in a purely hypothetical sense, but also kinda pointless since said…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1850558485</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/review-final-fantasy-16-ffxvi-ps5-rpg-release-date-1850558485"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bold and risky pivot toward action for Square Enix’s beloved RPG franchise, Final Fantasy XVI is a stunning achievement that revitalizes the series for a new age—and it just may be the best the series has been in more than 20 years.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Corey Plante</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sand Land's vehicular combat might have potential, but its desert world is a worry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sand-lands-vehicular-combat-might-have-potential-but-its-desert-world-is-a-worry</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sand-lands-vehicular-combat-might-have-potential-but-its-desert-world-is-a-worry"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shown off at this year's Summer Game Fest showcase, Sand Land is an upcoming RPG from the folks over at Ilca Inc, the developers of One Piece Odyssey, and the creator of Dragon Ball, Akira Toriyama. It's an adaptation on one of Toriyama's lesser-known mangas, which features a band of misfits who aim to right the wrongs of a king who's hogged the desert's vital water supply. I got to play it for all of 20 minutes, in a demo that was as stripped back as a grated cactus. Still, I got to sample a bit of roaming about in a tank, one brief stop at a town, an opening of one (1) chest, and some fighting. It seemed okay, I guess? But my main worry is whether its desert is interesting enough to hold people's attention.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony Won’t Share PS6 Info With Call Of Duty Devs If Owned By Microsoft]]></title>
        <id>1850564895</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-ps6-xbox-activision-microsoft-ps5-sale-1850564895"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T13:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If the sale of Activision Blizzard to Microsoft for $69 billion goes through, it could have big consequences for the future of Call of Duty on PlayStation. At least that’s what Sony Interactive Entertainment CEO Jim Ryan keeps saying. In a new deposition for the current lawsuit by the Federal Trade Commission, the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario's New Short King Design May Be An Old-School Throwback]]></title>
        <id>1850563129</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/super-mario-rpg-wonder-nintendo-switch-art-classic-1850563129"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo just dropped trailers for its next big Super Mario games, and while they look cool, you’ve probably noticed the plumber himself looks a little different. The hallmarks of iconic Mario’s design are still there, like his blue overalls and red cap, but his actual silhouette is now way more compact. The effect is…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patricia Hernandez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Early Final Fantasy XVI Abilities To Unlock And Upgrade ASAP]]></title>
        <id>1850561859</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-xvi-abilities-tips-eikon-power-upgrade-1850561859"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When protagonist Clive Rosfield takes to the battlefield in Final Fantasy XVI, he channels the otherworldly magical power of the Eikons, enormous and incredibly powerful magical entities. This new interpretation of classic Final Fantasy Summons like Shiva and Ifrit is at the center of the game’s story: A single person…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Corey Plante</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Pass prices are going up on Xbox, but no changes planned for PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-pass-prices-are-going-up-on-xbox-but-no-changes-planned-for-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-pass-prices-are-going-up-on-xbox-but-no-changes-planned-for-pc"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T12:32:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft have announced they're raising the price of Game Pass, but PC players don't need to worry too much about it (for now, at least). As reported by The Verge, come July 6th, Xbox Game Pass will be going up from £8/ $9 a month to £9/ $11, and Game Pass Ultimate will increase from £11/ $15 a month to £13/ $17. If you're just a PC player though, you've got nothing to worry about, as Microsoft hasn't announced any changes for PC Game Pass at this point in time.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Critical Tips To Know Before Jumping Into Final Fantasy XVI]]></title>
        <id>1850562387</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-16-ps5-release-date-tips-xvi-embargo-1850562387"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI brings some big changes to the long-running franchise. It’s the first true action-RPG in the main series, meaning even longtime fans will have a bit of learning to do.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayes Madsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sega announce a Sonic Central for tomorrow showing, you guessed it, Sonic stuff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-announce-a-sonic-central-for-tomorrow-showing-you-guessed-it-sonic-stuff</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-announce-a-sonic-central-for-tomorrow-showing-you-guessed-it-sonic-stuff"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T11:48:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sega are once again hosting another Sonic Central, promising a look at a suite of Sonic projects currently in the works. The live stream will be airing tomorrow on both the official Sonic the Hedgehog YouTube and Twitch accounts, starting at 4pm BST/ 5pm CEST. "Tune in for a sneak peek of some of our upcoming projects, partnerships and events happening in 2023," reads the announcement post from the official Sonic Twitter account.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saddle up horses and make nectar in The Sims 4's next expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/saddle-up-horses-and-make-nectar-in-the-sims-4s-next-expansion</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/saddle-up-horses-and-make-nectar-in-the-sims-4s-next-expansion"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T09:56:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Horses are trotting their way into The Sims 4 as part of the game's next expansion, with leaks sharing some specific details ahead of its full reveal. The official Sims Twitter account did show a short teaser trailer earlier this week of a Sim imagining a life out in the desert, promising a "rootin' tootin' expansion, two bold kits," and a Behind the Sims presentation. You can check out the full trailer for that when it debuts later today, but leaks regarding the expansion were shared on the Sims Community fan site after details and screenshots were mistakenly shared on Steam earlier this week.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's Index VR headset kit is available for $599.99 refurbished from GameStop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valves-index-vr-headset-kit-is-available-for-59999-refurbished-from-gamestop</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valves-index-vr-headset-kit-is-available-for-59999-refurbished-from-gamestop"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T07:32:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's Index remains one of the very best PC VR headsets for playing games like Half-Life Alyx, Beat Saber or Star Trek: Bridge Crew, but it does cost a fair amount - $999 for the full kit in the US, for example. However, it is possible to get used/refurbished models for much cheaper, including at GameStop where you can now pick up the full kit for just $599, a solid $400 off the usual price. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google blokuje vyhledávání přes IPv6 tunely od Hurricane Electric]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44862</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/google-blokuje-vyhledavani-pres-ipv6-tunely-od-hurricane-electric/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T07:27:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Celosvětově nejpoužívanější vyhledávač Google výrazně znepříjemňuje život uživatelům populární služby Hurricane Electric IPv6 Tunnel Broker. Po předchozí krátké epizodě, kdy vynucoval při vyhledávání trénink své AI prostřednictvím vnucování vyplnění reCAPTCHA, nyní přistoupil k úplnému zablokování vyhledávání.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Lol Phirae)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšel darktable 4.4.0, vylepšuje práci se styly a presety]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44861</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vysel-darktable-4-4-0-vylepsuje-praci-se-styly-a-presety/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T07:25:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt darktable, software pro zpracování fotografií, dnes vydal verzi 4.4.0. Mezi hlavní změny patří vylepšení práce se styly a presety, přepracované rozhraní pro kreslené masky, nabídka alternativního workflow s modulem sigmoid místo filmic rgb a řada výkonnostních vylepšení. Detaily naleznete v podrobném přehledu změn.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Kubeček)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XPG's Gammix D10 16GB DDR4-3200 CL16 kit is down to £29.99 plus shipping]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/xpgs-gammix-d10-16gb-ddr4-3200-cl16-kit-is-down-to-2999-plus-shipping</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/xpgs-gammix-d10-16gb-ddr4-3200-cl16-kit-is-down-to-2999-plus-shipping"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T07:14:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days back, we spotted a 16GB Corsair Vengeance RAM kit at a low £36 - and today the bottom has dropped out even further with a deal on Adata's XPG Gammix D10 RAM, where a 16GB DDR4-3200 CL16 kit costs just £29.99 plus £1.50 shipping at Ebuyer, versus their previous price of £38. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam's Subreddit Is Running An Excellent Protest]]></title>
        <id>1850563517</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/steam-reddit-subreddit-valve-protest-api-apollo-huffman-1850563517"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T01:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As we’ve been covering, things are not going well over on Reddit at the moment, with the site’s ownership currently engaged in a running battle with readers and moderators. Users are so annoyed at attempts to monetise the site that they’re working through a variety of protests, but one of the larger gaming…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Marvel TV Show's Credits Were 'Made' By 'AI', Look Terrible]]></title>
        <id>1850563329</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-secret-invasion-credits-ai-machine-learning-tv-1850563329"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T23:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hollywood’s writers are currently striking for a number of reasons, but one of the big ones is to ensure their work is safeguarded from the advances of “AI”. And right in the middle of it all, Disney has dropped its new Marvel TV series, Secret Invasion, which features an opening credits made by an “AI vendor”.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police Catch Bombing Suspect After He Left Behind Pokémon Cards]]></title>
        <id>1850563169</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/bombing-suspect-arrest-pokemon-cards-left-behind-crime-1850563169"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man suspected of building and detonating multiple explosives in Maryland was arrested by police after they connected some Pokémon cards left behind at a bomb site to him.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podrobnější popis možností zvukového čipu řady AY-3–8910 na ZX Spectru 128k]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16659</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/podrobnejsi-popis-moznosti-zvukoveho-cipu-rady-ay-3-8910-na-zx-spectru-128k/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ještě jednou se vrátíme ke zvukovému čipu řady AY-3–8910. Ukážeme si průběhy i frekvenční charakteristiku signálů, které lze naměřit na zvukovém výstupu ZX Spectra. Nezapomeneme ani na možnost tvorby šumu a práci s obálkou.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pick up the gorgeous Starfield Xbox Wireless Controller for £5 off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-the-gorgeous-starfield-xbox-wireless-controller-for-5-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-the-gorgeous-starfield-xbox-wireless-controller-for-5-off"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T21:05:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has done a great job making some truly inventive special edition Xbox Series controllers, and their latest effort is one that uses the 'NASA-punk' aesthetics of upcoming big budget Bethesda RPG Starfield. The controller looks phenomenal, but it does cost a fair bit - so I thought it was worth letting you know that the early adopter tax has been lifted, and the controller is now down to £65. 
That's still fairly expensive, but given that this controller seems destined to sell out - as it has done in the US - then I thought it was worth bringing up regardless. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Of The Internet’s Urgent Final Fantasy XVI Questions, Answered]]></title>
        <id>1850562523</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xvi-release-ffxvi-reviews-ps5-pc-clive-1850562523"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T20:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You could think of Final Fantasy XVI as just the latest in a line of many games developer Square Enix made to re-energize its now almost 40-year-old series. But unlike many of those other titles, which fans and developers alike have said struggled to invigorate the franchise (despite its still imposing name), FFXVI is…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Crash Bandicoot Game Has The Odds Stacked Against It]]></title>
        <id>1850562358</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/crash-team-rumble-price-battle-pass-free-to-play-1850562358"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T20:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At its best, Crash Team Rumble is a pretty fun romp in the Crash Bandicoot universe with the potential for great team-based play. At its worst, it can feel mindless and like you’re just throwing toy versions of Crash and his friends at each other until a disembodied voice declares one of you the victor. However, I…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenneth Shepard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Diablo 4 dev wrote a surprisingly heartfelt item description to “help someone remember things will get better”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/one-diablo-4-dev-wrote-a-surprisingly-heartfelt-item-description-to-help-someone-remember-things-will-get-better</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/one-diablo-4-dev-wrote-a-surprisingly-heartfelt-item-description-to-help-someone-remember-things-will-get-better"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T18:46:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world of Diablo 4 is full of misery and sadness. There are flayed corpses everywhere, fathers are haunted by the ghosts of their dead sons, blokes cram flaming eyeballs into their skulls and sometimes a guy turns up at random just to stomp you (and a lot of other people) into fleshy jam on the ground. Given all the abject suffering that the game and its predecessors make their stock and trade, it was an especially nice surprise to see real, genuine positivity emerge out of the literal hellscape of Sanctuary.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Spreadsheets in Space’, EVE Online, now has actual spreadsheets thanks to Microsoft Excel compatibility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spreadsheets-in-space-eve-online-now-has-actual-spreadsheets-thanks-to-microsoft-excel-compatibility</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spreadsheets-in-space-eve-online-now-has-actual-spreadsheets-thanks-to-microsoft-excel-compatibility"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T18:22:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Because nothing is just a joke anymore, EVE Online - CCP’s sprawling starship MMO jokingly nicknamed ‘Spreadsheets in Space’ due to its intense level of complex management - now has an official Microsoft Excel add-in that lets you directly export data to the spreadsheet app.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Ocean: The Second Story R will bring the ‘90s PlayStation RPG to PC with a hot new 2.5D look]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-ocean-the-second-story-r-will-bring-the-90s-playstation-rpg-to-pc-with-a-hot-new-25d-look</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-ocean-the-second-story-r-will-bring-the-90s-playstation-rpg-to-pc-with-a-hot-new-25d-look"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T17:55:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Science-fantasy RPG Star Ocean: The Second Story is back with a remake that gives the ‘90s PlayStation game a gorgeous lick of 2.5D paint and its first-ever outing on PC.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pick up Samsung's 1TB 980 NVMe SSD for less than £40]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-samsungs-1tb-980-nvme-ssd-for-less-than-40</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-samsungs-1tb-980-nvme-ssd-for-less-than-40"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T17:11:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung's 980 SSD is the company's latest mainstream offering, combining PCIe 3.0 speeds with a DRAM-less design and TLC NAND. That makes it a cheaper alternative to their PCIe 4.0 drives with DRAM, but still more than fast enough for PC gaming. Therefore, it's worth knowing that the 1TB 980 is now available for less than £40 at Amazon, a £16 reduction from its usual price and less than half the cost it debuted at back in 2021. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid 3 is headed to PC for the first time, as Konami confirms Steam release for Master Collection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/metal-gear-solid-3-is-headed-to-pc-for-the-first-time-as-konami-confirms-steam-release-for-master-collection</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/metal-gear-solid-3-is-headed-to-pc-for-the-first-time-as-konami-confirms-steam-release-for-master-collection"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T17:09:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid 3: Snake Eater will see its first-ever release on PC thanks to the upcoming release of the series’ Master Collection, freshly confirmed for a Steam release this autumn.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm really looking forward to tucking into Nour: Play With Your Food later this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-really-looking-forward-to-tucking-into-nour-play-with-your-food-later-this-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-really-looking-forward-to-tucking-into-nour-play-with-your-food-later-this-year"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T17:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Olivia, get the bowls and chopsticks ready to eat dinner," my mum asks 10 year old me. I do as I'm told, taking them to the dinner table. In childish, whimsical fashion as a childish, whimsical child, I grab my pair of chopsticks and start hitting them together as if I'm a drummer. "Olivia, don't do that," my mum scolds me. "Your grandma always used to tell me off when I did that as a child." Sullenly, I put the chopsticks back down on the table.

Well, 10 year old me, you're in for a treat. If you wait a couple of decades, you'll learn of Nour: Play With Your Food, a game which allows you to bang together chopsticks. The game wants you to. Nour is a physics simulation of a variety of foods, where you can choose the ingredients for the dish and add various "effects" of a non-culinary nature.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors is getting four-player couch co-op so you can slay bloodsuckers with BFFs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vampire-survivors-is-getting-four-player-couch-co-op-so-you-can-slay-bloodsuckers-with-bffs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/vampire-survivors-is-getting-four-player-couch-co-op-so-you-can-slay-bloodsuckers-with-bffs"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T16:36:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As if you needed more of a reason to while away the hours listening to Vampire Survivors’ strangely entrancing OST while mowing down thousands of skeletons, ghosts and vampires, 2022’s more moreish and BEST game is getting local co-op.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zdrojové kódy RHEL už jen skrze CentOS Stream, hlásí Red Hat]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44860</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/zdrojove-kody-rhel-uz-jen-skrze-centos-stream-hlasi-red-hat/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T14:14:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat oznamuje, že odteď bude CentOS Stream jediným místem, kde budou veřejně přístupné zdrojové kódy RHEL a souvisejícího. Platících zákazníků Red Hatu se změna nijak nedotkne, nadále budou mít vše přístupné skrze Red Hat Customer Portal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prime Gaming members can claim bonus games for Prime Day 2023 celebrations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prime-gaming-members-can-claim-bonus-games-for-prime-day-2023-celebrations</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prime-gaming-members-can-claim-bonus-games-for-prime-day-2023-celebrations"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T13:49:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prime Gaming is giving away four extra games in June and July to celebrate Prime Day 2023, on top of the June freebies already announced. Prey (2017) is already available to claim on GOG, and the next three games will drop weekly.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sending forest animals to reclaim the land in Growth is my dream come true]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sending-forest-animals-to-reclaim-the-land-in-growth-is-my-dream-come-true</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sending-forest-animals-to-reclaim-the-land-in-growth-is-my-dream-come-true"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T13:43:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's no secret that I love Dorfromantik. It opened my eyes to the world of tile-based puzzler strategy games, and I've looked out for similar ones ever since. Thankfully for me, there's been a fair few riffs on Dorformantik's formula recently - a focus on nature, a soothing soundtrack, and some good old puzzling. Growth is one of these, and I'm hooked on the demo that's playable as part of Steam Next Fest. Taking place on a hexagonal grid, the aim is to uncover the map using a range of wildlife, fertilising the land in the process. Each tile you reveal gives you points, and you'll have to navigate around mountains, water, and special landmarks.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC má schválen vlastní Kodex chování]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44859</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gcc-ma-schvalen-vlastni-kodex-chovani/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T12:19:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jason Merrill z Red Hatu na webu GNU GCC oznamuje, že projekt schválil svůj Kodex chování (Code of Conduct). Tím se budou nově řídit vývojáři i další přispěvatelé projektu v různých komunikačních systémech jako mailing listech, bugzille, IRC i jinde.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nová Opera One integruje vlastní AI Aria s propojením na GPT]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44858</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nova-opera-one-integruje-vlastni-ai-aria-s-propojenim-na-gpt/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T11:14:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová verze webového prohlížeče Opera nemá číselné označení 100, ale jmenuje se prostě One. Do vínku dostala vlastní AI zvanou Aria, která je – jak už je u Opery zvykem – přímou součástí prohlížeče, nikoli jen nějaké rozšíření.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox is introducing "experiences" for people aged 17+]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-is-introducing-experiences-for-people-aged-17</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-is-introducing-experiences-for-people-aged-17"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:58:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox is launching new regulation in order to allow creators to make content specifically for users aged 17 and above. From what Manuel Bronstein, Roblox's Chief Product Officer, shared in an official blog post yesterday, it seems that it'll be on creators to label their experiences as mature, which "may contain more violence, blood, or crude humour" than usual experiences.
The introduction of age appropriate access is not for safety primarily, as Roblox say they want to "simulate and even go beyond what's possible in the real world". Bronstein also added that, "We want to replicate that dynamic on Roblox," referring to the idea of getting older and legally being allowed to enter places such as nightclubs. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix staff keep asking for a Final Fantasy 6 remake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-staff-keep-asking-for-a-final-fantasy-6-remake</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-staff-keep-asking-for-a-final-fantasy-6-remake"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:54:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 6 is so popular within Square Enix that staff keep asking FF brand manager Yoshinori Kitase for a remake. Although the game has been re-released as part of the Pixel Remaster bundle, fans within the company have been asking for a full blown remake.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Python Akademie: začněte s programováním v oblíbeném jazyce (online kurz)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41123</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/online-python-akademie-zacnete-s-programovanim-v-oblibenem-jazyce-kurz/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T07:27:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chceš začít s programováním? Python je oblíbený programovací jazyk mezi vývojáři i zaměstnavateli a zároveň super vstupenka do světa programování. Nauč se přemýšlet jako programátor a efektivně využívat Python na řešení nejrůznějších problémů. Online Python Akademie znamená celkem 12 týdnů, vždy jedna lekce týdně, večer od 18:00 do 21:00. Následující kurz začíná 12. července.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SDL2 přechází do režimu údržby, vše směřuje k SDL3]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44857</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/sdl2-prechazi-do-rezimu-udrzby-vse-smeruje-k-sdl3/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T07:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Knihovna SDL2 v současné nové verzi 2.28 je zkrátka hotova a vývojáři projektu ji překlápí do módu, kdy už bude dvojka jenom opečovávána a novinky už budou směřovat do budoucího vydání SDL3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (21. 6. 2023): ukládejte záznam obrazovky ve formátu GIF]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16651</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-21-6-2023-ukladejte-zaznam-obrazovky-ve-formatu-gif/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si řekneme o programu pro čtecí zařízení, představíme si další textový editor, vyzkoušíme editor pro LaTeX a vytvoříme si animované GIFy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The RTX 3060 Ti is down to $275 in the US, cementing it as the best 4060 Ti alternative]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rtx-3060-ti-is-down-to-275-in-the-us-cementing-it-as-the-best-4060-ti-alternative</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rtx-3060-ti-is-down-to-275-in-the-us-cementing-it-as-the-best-4060-ti-alternative"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T21:43:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stop me if you've heard this one before: the RTX 4060 Ti just came out but you should probably buy the RTX 3060 Ti instead. It's around 85 to 90 percent of the performance at less than 70 percent of the cost - although you do give up better power efficiency and DLSS 3 on the newer model. 
We've highlighted a few UK RTX 3060 Ti deals before, but here's one for the US market courtesy of Best Buy - on a PNY unit with a simple dual-fan design, plenty of cooling potential and a price that makes a lot of sense: $275, down from a previous price of $320 and considerably less than the $399 Nvidia is asking for their 4060 Ti FE. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Radeon RX 7900 XTX GPU is discounted in the US and UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amds-radeon-rx-7900-xtx-gpu-is-discounted-in-the-us-and-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amds-radeon-rx-7900-xtx-gpu-is-discounted-in-the-us-and-uk"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T21:26:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news, everyone! AMD's fastest graphics card is now available for less money, in what deals scientists are calling a "sale" or "limited time promotion". According to the latest research, this phenomena can be observed on both sides of the Atlantic Ocean, specifically the UK and the US, with discounts applied on both sides. This makes it a better time to buy this particular item than times when it is more expensive, generally speaking. 
The specifics are as follows: the Sapphire Pulse Radeon RX 7900 XTX has been discounted from $1000 to $900 in the US (tick the $100 code on the product page), while Sapphire's AMD reference design has dropped from £1099 to £949 in the UK (no ticking required). 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dota 2 is ditching battle passes for more regular, year-round updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dota-2-is-ditching-battle-passes-for-more-regular-year-round-updates</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dota-2-is-ditching-battle-passes-for-more-regular-year-round-updates"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T21:14:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dota 2 is moving away from releasing new content via a pattle pass in favour of more varied and regular updates. Valve explained the change on the Dota 2 blog, saying that the heavy focus on the Compendium - the Battle Pass released alongside Dota 2's yearly esports event, The International - was leaving "the rest of the year feeling barren by comparison."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magical shooter Immortals Of Aveum has been delayed until August]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/magical-shooter-immortals-of-aveum-has-been-delayed-until-august</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/magical-shooter-immortals-of-aveum-has-been-delayed-until-august"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T20:41:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immortals Of Aveum is a magic-fisted first-person shooter with a name that reminds me, every time, of another EA-published fantasy game, Kingdoms Of Amalur. I can't tell if that's a good thing or not. 

I can tell that Immortals Of Aveum has been delayed. Aveum had been aiming for a July 20th release, but has now been pushed back a month until August 22nd.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[June's next batch of Game Pass additions have stylish racing, idyllic farming and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-pass-pc-games-june-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-pass-pc-games-june-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T15:50:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another day, another batch of Game Pass additions, with this selection being spread out across the end of June and beginning of July. The Xbox Wire blog shared this half of the month's Game Pass additions earlier today, and there seems to be a little something for everyone. First up is Need for Speed Unbound via EA Play, the most recent and incredibly stylish entry in the racing game series, which you'll be able to play on PC from June 22 - you'll be able to stream it through the cloud too.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Steam Deck accessories 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-accessories</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-accessories"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T15:04:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been meaning to round up the best Steam Deck accessories for a while now – ambushing Liam with homemade Etsy gadgets is one thing but now that there are literally millions of Decks in owners’ hands, quite literally, it’s time to put a serious face on and consider which accessories genuinely are the best buys.
This guide is keeping separate from the best Steam Deck microSD card list, mainly because a good microSD card is less of an accessory and more of a core essential (especially if you’ve gone for the 64GB Steam Deck model). Still, this guide will cover an array of addons, from alternative cases to thumbstick covers and USB-C docking stations. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pozvánka na OWASP Czech chapter meeting 22. června v Brně]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44855</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/pozvanka-na-owasp-czech-chapter-meeting-22-cervna-v-brne/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T14:54:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve čtvrtek 22. června se uskuteční OWASP Czech chapter meeting, který tentokrát zavítá do Brna. Registrovaným jako vždy nabídne přísun zajímavostí z oblasti IT bezpečnosti a to ve formě dvou večerních přednášek, na které je registrace zcela zdarma. Detaily programu a registraci naleznete na eventbrite.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: dmr)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[El Paso, Elsewhere gets the vibes right in its Next Fest demo, available now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/el-paso-elsewhere-gets-the-vibes-right-in-its-next-fest-demo-available-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/el-paso-elsewhere-gets-the-vibes-right-in-its-next-fest-demo-available-now"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T14:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[El Paso, Elsewhere, the Max Payne inspired shooter where you fight werewolves and vampires in a reality-shifting motel, has a demo now, and it's looking pretty promising so far. It's the next title on the docket for developer Strange Scaffold, a team whose projects just constantly have strong hooks (how good is An Airport For Aliens Currently Run By Dogs as a title though). El Paso, Elsewhere is no different, and you can even try it out now as part of this season's Steam Next Fest in a new demo. And yeah, the vibes are about as tight as you'd expect.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The joy of slow living in Story Of Seasons: A Wonderful Life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-joy-of-slow-living-in-story-of-seasons-a-wonderful-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-joy-of-slow-living-in-story-of-seasons-a-wonderful-life"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My Dad likes to tell this story from when I was a teenager. I had grumpily asked if he could pick me and a friend up from a local park one afternoon, and he remembers us bundling into the back of his car all smelly and sweaty and terrible as teenagers so often are. But as he pulled away, he caught a snippet of our conversation that was so unusual it's the reason this seemingly normal car ride has cemented itself as a core memory. We were talking about the price of eggs. And tomatoes. And the order in which we were planting crops to ensure the greatest yield.


My poor father interrupted us, turning in his seat to ask what the hell we were talking about. “It’s a game we’re both playing called Harvest Moon” I scoffed in his direction. “You wouldn’t understand”.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Callisto Protocol wraps things up with its first and only story DLC next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-callisto-protocol-story-dlc-release-date</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-callisto-protocol-story-dlc-release-date"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T12:08:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Callisto Protocol will be getting its first and only bit of story DLC next week, which Striking Distance are describing as the game's "heart-pounding final chapter". Entitled Final Transmission, a short teaser trailer has been released giving us a look at what protagonist Jacob Lee will be getting up to, but it doesn't really show us all that much. There seems to be some kind of fleshy robot monster that says he'll "never escape," but that's all we've got to go off right now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyzkoušejte KDE Plasma 6, už funguje dobře, hlásí vývojář]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44856</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyzkousejte-kde-plasma-6-uz-funguje-dobre-hlasi-vyvojar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T11:56:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do vydání KDE Plasma 6.0 sice zbývá ještě půl až tři čtvrtě roku, nicméně již nyní Nate Graham hlásí, že pro běžné užití už nepředstavuje problémy a sám ji takto jako hlavní desktop už mnoho týdnů používá. Mírně adrenalinoví uživatelé linuxového desktopu tak mohou naskočit do tohoto next-gen vláčku.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 12 new Game Gear games in Sonic Origins Plus expansion sound weird, according to early reports]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-origins-plus-game-gear-bad-audio-quality</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-origins-plus-game-gear-bad-audio-quality"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T11:41:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upcoming expansion pack for Sonic Origins (aptly named Sonic Origins Plus) appears to be out in the wild early ahead of its launch on June 23rd, but fans don't seem to be particularly happy with the game's sound quality. The Plus expansion will bring remastered visuals, bonus characters, new modes and challenges to the original Sonic Origins compilation, but it's the audio quality of the 12 new Sonic Game Gear additions that fans seem to have taken issue with. As spotted by TheGamer, fans who have got their hands on copies of the game early, such as YouTuber belmont gr, are reporting that the Game Gear games sound off, like there's some kind of echo effect.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 gets surprise murder mystery prequel that puts everyone in the detective seat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-browser-game-prequel</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-browser-game-prequel"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T09:41:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the game's release in August, Baldur's Gate 3 has received a prequel murder mystery game that lets you vote on how things unfold. Playable for free in your browser, it's titled Blood in Baldur's Gate, and is set 15 years before the events of Baldur's Gate 3. Developer Larian Studios revealed the project yesterday. In it, you play as a detective tasked with solving a murder, and by you, I quite literally mean all of you, as this one will take a bit of collaboration.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I would like every developer to make an escape room game, thank you]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-would-like-every-developer-to-make-an-escape-room-game-thank-you</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-would-like-every-developer-to-make-an-escape-room-game-thank-you"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I really like escape rooms IRL, and have a tremendous amount of respect for the people who devise them. But seeing as how they last about an hour and cost approximately the same as it would for Wales to secede from the United Kingdom, I can only afford to pay an immersive experience what it deserves every so often (the rest of the time I'm honourbound by my fatherland to donate to causes supported by Michael Sheen). I'm therefore pleased that there seems to be an uptick in escape room video games. Plese do more of those, developers.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVT-AV1 1.6 je o třetinu rychlejší]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44854</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/svt-av1-1-6-je-o-tretinu-rychlejsi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová verze AV1 kodéru SVT-AV1 1.6 zrychluje kódování AV1 videí v nastaveních s vyšší kvalitou kódování o výtečných 30 až 40 %. Kromě toho došlo k dalšímu ladění parametrů pro profily M1 až M13, vylepšení BD-rate jsou zhruba v rozmezí 1 až 4 % pro výkonnostně rychlejší profily kódování.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tails 5.14 přechází na LUKS2]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44853</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/tails-5-14-prechazi-na-luks2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T08:55:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operační systém Tails zavádí v nové verzi 5.14 automatickou migraci na LUKS2 a Argon2id. Důvodem je, že dosud používané šifrování LUKS v Tailsu 5.12 či starších verzích je nedostatečné proti získání přístupu k datům ze strany státní moci držící fyzicky daný počítač / notebook. Tails 5.14 tedy automaticky převede persistentní úložiště na LUKS2 s Argon2id.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proč se instalační CD Debian netinst zvětšilo o 350 MB?]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16657</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/proc-se-instalacni-cd-debian-netinst-zvetsilo-o-350-mb/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Netinst bylo vždycky malé plnohodnotné instalační médium Debianu se základními balíčky. V čerstvé verzi Debian 12 Bookworm ale docela dramaticky narostlo. Rozhodl jsem se podívat, proč to tak je.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Konference OpenAlt 2023 hledá přednášející]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44852</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/konference-openalt-2023-hleda-prednasejici/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T06:35:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pořadatelé konference OpenAlt spustili registraci přednášek a hledají přednášející pro letošní ročník. Ten se uskuteční druhý týden v listopadu, tedy 11. a 12. listopadu 2023 na brněnské Fakultě informatiky Masarykovy univerzity. OpenAlt je fórem, kde se každoročně sdružují lidé, kteří se zajímají o vývoj a používání svobodného a otevřeného softwaru a hardwaru. Otevřený přístup nejen umožňuje opravitelnost a rozšiřitelnost zařízení, ale také poskytuje možnost auditovat zdrojový kód, což přináší vysokou úroveň zabezpečení a soukromí, vysvětluje za organizátory Jozef JoeJoe Mlích.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statické typové kontroly zdrojových kódů Pythonu prováděné nástrojem Mypy (2.část)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16656</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/staticke-typove-kontroly-zdrojovych-kodu-pythonu-provadene-nastrojem-mypy-2-cast/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ukážeme si práci s typově bezpečnými slovníky, typovou inferencí, práci s typově bezpečnými funkcemi (Callable) a ve druhé polovině pak převod aplikace bez určení datových typů ke kódu s doplněnými typovými informacemi.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warhammer Age Of Sigmar: Realms Of Ruin's story campaign will have plenty of "meat" on its bones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-age-of-sigmar-realms-of-ruins-story-campaign-will-have-plenty-of-meat-on-its-bones</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-age-of-sigmar-realms-of-ruins-story-campaign-will-have-plenty-of-meat-on-its-bones"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next month's open beta for Frontier Developments' new Warhammer RTS Age Of Sigmar: Realms Of Ruin may be focused on testing its 1v1 multiplayer mode, but the Elite Dangerous studio have told me there's still plenty to look forward to in its single-player story campaign. I got to chat with principal designer Sandro Sammarco last week, and he told me they've been hard at work making sure it's "filled with loads of cool new stuff that people really haven't seen before". He also said that their partnership with Games Workshop has allowed them to "really go to town in terms of the visuals, the lore, [and] the story that we're telling", and he hopes that the way they've characterised the campaign's principal faction, the Stormcast Eternals, will give players plenty to sink their teeth into when it launches in full.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Time at Portia devs’ management sim Let’s School has a demo and release date]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-time-at-portia-devs-management-sim-lets-school-has-a-demo-and-release-date</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-time-at-portia-devs-management-sim-lets-school-has-a-demo-and-release-date"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T18:22:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s School, the whimsical headteacher sim from My Time at Portia devs Pathea, will be out next month.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Screenshot Saturday Mondays: Throw that egg]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/screenshot-saturday-mondays-throw-that-egg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/screenshot-saturday-mondays-throw-that-egg"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T18:05:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every weekend, indie devs show off current work on Twitter's #screenshotsaturday tag. And every Monday, I bring you a selection of these snaps and clips. This week is another shortie because Twitter is once again broken and refusing to show all the weekend's posts, which sure feels ominous for the social media platform. The games are still good. Come on in for an immersive sim with a clever little technology trick, an adventure game set in a city on a giant octopus, the throwing of an egg, and more attractive and interesting indie games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aliens: Dark Descent review: decent, if desperate to sit with the cool console kids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/aliens-dark-descent-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/aliens-dark-descent-review"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the same way that Alien: Isolation is, for many, now the definitive Ridley Scott’s Alien game, I’ve got no problem getting all ‘game critic who wants to feel important by making wild declarative statements’ and saying that Aliens: Dark Descent is now, for me at least, the definitive James Cameron’s Aliens game. It’s the first to really capture the white-knuckle vibe of setting up perimeters, quipping out that last line of top-tier banter you’ve been saving, and seeing the shapes on the motion tracker creep closer and squeal louder. It really does do the license justice, so if that’s what you’re looking for, dig in. I just wish it trusted me to be able to count higher than one. Not that much higher, either. Just four.
Dark Descent is not a game for strategy game fans nearly as much as it’s one for Aliens fans. You order your entire squad around at the same time, pausing or slowing time to issue commands like grenades or suppressive fire, using a stock of command points that refill over time. It’s a game that’s (rightly) decided that a very particular type of strategy game is the best format to convey Aliens’ whole schtick, but then seems to have realised, hang on, we’re at risk of (alien) isolating and possibly even (alien)ating a lot of potential customers here. What if there was a way to do XCOM but without all the knobbly bits?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojář restartoval Linux 6.4 téměř 300 tisíc krát, aby našel chybu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44851</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyvojar-restartoval-linux-6-4-temer-300-tisic-krat-aby-nasel-chybu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T17:56:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojář Red Hatu Richard Jones narazil na chybu, která celkem brzy po startu zasekne jádro 6.4, ale jen v jednom z asi 1000 případů. S procesorem Intel se to stává méně často, než s procesorem AMD.  Aby našel zdroj chyby, bylo potřeba dělat bisekci jader 6.0–6.4 a každé jádro bylo nutno pustit 1000×, aby se vyloučila chyba. Pokud se jádro zaseklo dříve, mohlo se pokračovat půlení intervalu dříve.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arc Raiders, extraction shooter from ex-Dice CEO, opens sign-ups for its closed alpha later this month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-extraction-shooter-from-ex-dice-ceo-opens-sign-ups-for-its-closed-alpha-later-this-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-extraction-shooter-from-ex-dice-ceo-opens-sign-ups-for-its-closed-alpha-later-this-month"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T17:50:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arc Raiders is yet another extraction-style shooter sat in this year’s calendar of releases, but this one’s been kicking around a while longer than most: it was originally announced at The Game Awards back in 2021, before being delayed into 2023.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slay the Spire modders’ roguelike auto-battler Tales & Tactics gets an early access launch date]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/slay-the-spire-modders-roguelike-auto-battler-tales-tactics-gets-an-early-access-launch-date</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/slay-the-spire-modders-roguelike-auto-battler-tales-tactics-gets-an-early-access-launch-date"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T17:20:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We already knew the folks behind Slay the Spire mod Downfall were making their own standalone game, Tales & Tactics, and now we know when we’ll be able to play it. Tales & Tactics, in case you’ve forgotten, is best pitched as a mixture of Slay the Spire and Dota Auto Chess; in other words, it’s a fantasy roguelike (like StS), where you can pick up abilities, gear and whatnot during each run, with auto-battling combat (like Auto Chess) - except here it’s on a hex board.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[14 Steam Next Fest demos you should absolutely check out this June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/14-steam-next-fest-demos-you-should-absolutely-check-out-this-june</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/14-steam-next-fest-demos-you-should-absolutely-check-out-this-june"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just in case your Steam wishlists weren't already stocked up from this year's Summer Geoff Fest bonanza, here we are with another edition of Valve's Steam Next Fest, which has unleashed hundreds, if not thousands of free game demos on us, starting from today, June 19th, until Monday June 26th. You can view the entire June Next Fest line-up right here if you'd rather browse at your leisure, but we've also been playing some of the demos in advance to bring you some curated highlights of what we've enjoyed so far. We haven't have access to every demo in this year's Next Fest, I should note, but think of these more as some initial tasting suggestions to get you started, rather than a complete overview of what's worth playing.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima wants someone to send him to space, so he can make a game to play in space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hideo-kojima-wants-someone-to-send-him-to-space-so-he-can-make-a-game-to-play-in-space</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hideo-kojima-wants-someone-to-send-him-to-space-so-he-can-make-a-game-to-play-in-space"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T16:43:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After creating Metal Gear Solid, founding his own studio to develop Death Stranding and becoming best pals with most of Hollywood, Hideo Kojima’s next big ambition is apparently to be blasted into space to make a game.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This £116 motherboard supports the Core i9 13900K and cheap DDR4 RAM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-116-motherboard-supports-the-core-i9-13900k-and-cheap-ddr4-ram</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-116-motherboard-supports-the-core-i9-13900k-and-cheap-ddr4-ram"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One mistake I often see novice PC builders making is overspending on the motherboard. It's true that higher-end models offer more features and can support better overclocking performance, but for the vast majority of people you're better off putting your budget towards the highest-tier graphics card and processor you can afford - as these actually determine in-game performance! - then slotting in the cheapest motherboard that gets decent reviews and supports your components. 
One excellent example of just such a motherboard is the Gigabyte B760M Gaming X DDR4, a simple option that supports 12th/13th-gen Intel processors all the way up to the 13900K. With an asking price of just £116 right now, you can pick up this plus a cheap 16GB DDR4 RAM kit for just £152, letting you spend the vast majority of your PC budget where it really matters. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build your next gaming PC in this discounted Phanteks Eclipse G500A case]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/build-your-next-gaming-pc-in-this-discounted-phanteks-eclipse-g500a-case</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/build-your-next-gaming-pc-in-this-discounted-phanteks-eclipse-g500a-case"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're after a clean white case with RGB lighting and great thermals without spending a fortune, then this discounted Phanteks Eclipse G500A D-RGB ATX case is a strong choice at £93.99, following a £56 discount at Currys. 
For the money, you get a critically-acclaimed and good-sized mid-tower case, complete with support for modern (ie giant) components, three fans, and mesh panels used throughout to ensure a great balance between noise, dust and thermals.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voidigo, the best roguelite shooter since Nuclear Throne, has left early access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voidigo-the-best-roguelite-shooter-since-nuclear-throne-has-left-early-access</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voidigo-the-best-roguelite-shooter-since-nuclear-throne-has-left-early-access"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T14:49:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boy howdy, Voidigo is lively. Think Nuclear Throne but weirder. Every sprite oozes a frantic combination of energy and personality, from the steel-eyed sprint of your starting gun-bird-thing to the bobbing scuttle of the cyclops clayfish boss. Guns have punch, stomps have oomph, reward boxes have merry jingles. It's a top-down roguelike shooter that does everything right, and seldom have I seen a game more deserving of its Overwhelmingly Positive rating on Steam. 
It left early access 11 days ago, which is 11 days you could have spent splatting crustaceans and wasps with skeleton trombones and deadly finger guns. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hra zdarma na GOG.com Eschalon Book II]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44850</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/hra-zdarma-na-gog-com-eschalon-book-ii/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T14:31:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na GOG.com můžete nyní zdarma získat hru Eschalon Book II. Jde o druhou část RPG z bájné země Eschalon. Zemi hrozí válka a jediná naděje na mír leží v minulosti.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shaky cam footage emerges of Edmund McMillen's turn-based cat-tics Mewgenics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shaky-cam-footage-emerges-of-edmund-mcmillens-turn-based-cat-tics-mewgenics</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shaky-cam-footage-emerges-of-edmund-mcmillens-turn-based-cat-tics-mewgenics"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T13:25:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If Mewgenics were an actual cat, it would be approaching its twilight years. It's been nearly 11 years since Edmund Mcmillen, known for Super Meat Boy and Binding Of Isaac, first announced that the mysterious cat breed 'em up would be Team Meat's next game. The cats wound up waiting outside while they worked on other things, but we now have a much more concrete idea of what the game is.
The developers have actually been posting extensive development updates since January, but McMillen also just recorded an adhoc TikTok video where he points his phone at his screen. Turns out Mewgenics is a turn-based strategy roguelike with wizard cats who can cut their paws while opening windows. Could be worth the wait! 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chystaný Python 3.13 bude ještě rychlejší]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44849</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chystany-python-3-13-bude-jeste-rychlejsi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T13:24:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Koncem loňského roku vyšel Python 3.11, který přinesl asi 40 % zrychlení oproti předchozím verzím díky PEP 659 (Specializing Adaptive Interpreter). Toto zrychlení se označuje jako tier 1.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classic XCOM-like Xenonauts 2 pops out of its little spaceship on July 18th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/classic-x-com-like-xenonauts-2-pops-out-of-its-little-spaceship-on-july-18th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/classic-x-com-like-xenonauts-2-pops-out-of-its-little-spaceship-on-july-18th"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fans of clicking on little men (and aliens) will be pleased to hear that Xenonauts 2 is releasing via Steam early access on July 18th, packing a mildly modernised dose of old school XCOM from back when turn-based action was more gritty and hyphenated. You'll futz about with fighter planes, build listening posts around the globe, and send hapless soldiers to get their faces torn off. Merry Xenonauts!
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Komunitní setkání CSNOG 2024 se bude konat 23. a 24. ledna ve Zlíně]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44848</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/komunitni-setkani-csnog-2024-se-bude-konat-23-a-24-ledna-ve-zline/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T11:12:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Šestý ročník komunitního setkání nejen českých a slovenských správců sítí (CSNOG 2024) se příští rok uskuteční 23. a 24. ledna, opět v prostorách zlínské Univerzity Tomáše Bati. Posláním setkání komunity CSNOG je umožnit sdílení zkušenosti a praktických řešení, která mohou zvýšit kvalitu českých a slovenských sítí, a podělit se o názory na aktuální síťařská témata. Další informace budou organizátoři postupně zveřejňovat na komunitních webových stránkách a na sociálních sítích Facebook nebo Twitter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Vilém Sládek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pro Philosopher 2: Governments & Grievances will let you shout at Confucius next year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pro-philosopher-2-governments-grievances-will-let-you-shout-at-confucius-next-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pro-philosopher-2-governments-grievances-will-let-you-shout-at-confucius-next-year"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T10:59:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been ten years since Intelligible Games graced us with Socrates Jones: Pro Philosopher, an Ace Attorny style argue 'em up where you confront a cavalcade of philosophers in an attempt to uncover the ultimate nature of morality. Also you're dead, and there are lots of silly jokes. 
I loved it, so I'm very pleased that the devs have just announced that Pro Philosopher 2: Governments and Grievances will be out at some point in 2024. It's nearly time to get down and dirty with political philosophy, baby.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Problém Nouveau s jádrem 6.3 vyřešen]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-44847</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/problem-nouveau-s-jadrem-6-3-vyresen/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T08:26:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minulý týden jsme informovali o problému open source ovladače Nouveau pro karty NVIDIA. Chyba typu use-after-free byla opravena. Zdá se, že tam byla už dávno, ale nepěkné věci dělá až kvůli souběhu s novou opravou.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Devil May Cry dev dubs Final Fantasy 16's combat his "personal masterpiece"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-devil-may-cry-dev-dubs-final-fantasy-16s-combat-his-personal-masterpiece</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-devil-may-cry-dev-dubs-final-fantasy-16s-combat-his-personal-masterpiece"/>
        <updated>2023-06-19T08:08:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The single most interesting thing you could tell me about Final Fantasy 16 is that it will have actually good combat. One of the developers has just said that, as of course they would, but not just any dev: we're talking about Devil May Cry 5 design lead Ryota Suzuki, who's dubbed FF16's sword-slinging his "personal masterpiece". 
I don't take that at face value, but it has given me my first pangs of regret over selling my PS5. Those who didn't sell their PS5 for travel money get to play in a few days, while PC players are in for an indefinitely long wait. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: zneužívaná zranitelnost v produktech Fortinet]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16654</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-zneuzivana-zranitelnost-v-produktech-fortinet/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-18T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V dnešním díle Postřehů se podíváme na aktivní zneužívání zranitelnosti XORtigate, dopady útoku skupiny Cl0p na systémy MOVEit nebo nové nařízení požadující odstranění konfiguračních rozhraní z internetu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Kopřiva)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operační systém /e/OS pro Pixel 5, vyjde openSUSE Leap 15.6]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16650</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/operacni-system-e-os-pro-pixel-5-vyjde-opensuse-leap-15-6/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-18T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt openSUSE oproti původní předpokladům vydá ještě openSUSE Leap 15.6. Vývojáři linuxové distribuce Ubuntu chtějí začlenit rozšíření Tiling Assistant do výchozí instalace GNOME.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-683</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-683"/>
        <updated>2023-06-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for recovering from jet lag. Before you get up at 3am, let's read this week's best writing about games (and game related things).
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valorant is getting a team deathmatch mode later this month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorant-is-getting-a-team-deathmatch-mode-later-this-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorant-is-getting-a-team-deathmatch-mode-later-this-month"/>
        <updated>2023-06-17T22:14:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On June 27th, Riot's hero shooter Valorant will get a team deathmatch mode. Teams of five will be able to do battle without the need to buy weapons at the start of each round, Counter-Strike-style, as they do in the main game. There will also be three new maps to play on.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kingdoms And Castles gets larger everything in latest update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kingdoms-and-castles-gets-larger-everything-in-latest-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kingdoms-and-castles-gets-larger-everything-in-latest-update"/>
        <updated>2023-06-17T22:12:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had a single, relaxing weekend with citybuilder Kingdoms And Castles almost six years ago, and I still look back on it as if it was a revitalising holiday I took. A city break, if you will.

Likewise, six years later and Kingdoms And Castles is still getting updates. The Infrastructure & Industry update was released earlier today, and it adds several community-suggested buildings.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squarespace a Google se dohodly, Firefox dostane PipeWire webcam]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16655</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/squarespace-a-google-se-dohodly-firefox-dostane-pipewire-webcam/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-17T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi-end GPU na Ubuntu 23.04 s Waylandem vs X.Org, KDE nejen o Plasmě 6, Squarespace a doménový byznys Googlu, Lisa Su o AMD ROCm, experimentální podpora webkamerky přes PipeWire míří do Firefoxu 116.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action-RPG Flintlock: The Siege Of Dawn has been delayed until 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/action-rpg-flintlock-the-siege-of-dawn-has-been-delayed-until-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/action-rpg-flintlock-the-siege-of-dawn-has-been-delayed-until-2024"/>
        <updated>2023-06-17T20:46:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm still mostly only excited about Flintlock: The Siege Of Dawn because it's from the makers of Ashen. I'll need to wait longer to find out whether it can justify that excitement on its own terms. Developers A44 announced today that the action-RPG has been delayed until 2024.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim's beta branch update adds difficulty modes, new trader and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheims-beta-branch-update-adds-difficulty-modes-new-trader-and-more</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheims-beta-branch-update-adds-difficulty-modes-new-trader-and-more"/>
        <updated>2023-06-17T20:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim's latest update to the public test branch adds a new merchant: Hildir, the sister of existing dwarven trader Haldor. Hildir offers up fashionable items of clothing to buy, but the more exciting part of the update is its new difficulty levels, which let you try the open world multiplayer survival sim in either easy or hard modes.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-241</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-241"/>
        <updated>2023-06-17T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One bonus treat in all this beautiful weather is the experience of everyone on my road having their windows open. We're letting each other into our daily lives a little more, and I'm hearing and smelling things I've never smelled before. I may not know your name, downstairs neighbour, but by god I certainly know you use Lynx Africa. Lots of Lynx Africa. Honestly, about seven bodies' worth of Lynx Africa. Anyway, what are you playing this weekend? Here's what we're clicking on!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dicefolk is like a Pokémon roguelike with dice, and it’s got a new demo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dicefolk-is-like-a-pokemon-roguelike-with-dice-and-its-got-a-new-demo</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dicefolk-is-like-a-pokemon-roguelike-with-dice-and-its-got-a-new-demo"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T21:32:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I spend quite a lot of my time thinking about dice games, so my attention was piqued by the new demo for Dicefolk - a sort of Pokémon battler but with dice (and also it’s a roguelike).

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWI survival RTS Last Train Home is Frostpunk meets Company of Heroes, on literal rails]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wwi-survival-rts-last-train-home-is-frostpunk-meets-company-of-heroes-on-literal-rails</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wwi-survival-rts-last-train-home-is-frostpunk-meets-company-of-heroes-on-literal-rails"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T21:04:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming RTS Last Train Home will task you with protecting an armoured train as it barrels through post-World War I Russia to escape the civil war. And boy, does it look cold out there.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No, Skyrim Grandma isn’t in Starfield]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-skyrim-grandma-isnt-in-starfield</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-skyrim-grandma-isnt-in-starfield"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T20:26:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shirley Curry - better known to the internet as ‘Skyrim Grandma’ thanks to a viral Let’s Play in 2015 - has shot down rumours that she made a cameo in the recent Starfield Direct, adding that she won’t even touch Bethesda’s much-hyped space RPG while she waits for Elder Scrolls 6.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Trek: Infinite’s first gameplay glimpse looks like Stellaris: The Next Generation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-trek-infinites-first-gameplay-glimpse-looks-like-stellaris-the-next-generation</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-trek-infinites-first-gameplay-glimpse-looks-like-stellaris-the-next-generation"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T19:42:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve been given our first proper look at Star Trek: Infinite, the new grand strategy game from Stellaris makers Paradox, in action - and yep, it’s definitely a Star Trek game from the makers of Stellaris.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redfall’s disastrous reception hasn’t put devs Arkane Austin at risk of closure (yet, anyway)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/redfalls-disastrous-reception-hasnt-put-devs-arkane-austin-at-risk-of-closure-yet-anyway</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/redfalls-disastrous-reception-hasnt-put-devs-arkane-austin-at-risk-of-closure-yet-anyway"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T18:40:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s fair to say that Arkane’s vampire-slaying co-op game Redfall was… not well received when it released back in early May. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Jarvis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The new Spirit Swap demo introduces its hella queer cast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-new-spirit-swap-demo-introduces-its-hella-queer-cast</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-new-spirit-swap-demo-introduces-its-hella-queer-cast"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T16:22:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spirit Swap: Lofi Beats To Match-3 To has been on our radar for a while now, and with its appearance at this year's Wholesome Direct during Summer Game Fest, I knew I had to go and check out the new demo.

It's different to the endless demo that Alice wrote about in February, which isn't available here. Instead, you get a taster of the game's story and versus modes. And with that, an introduction to some of the characters you'll meet (and maybe even date).

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fallout 76's lead artist is building a creepy single-player open world in The Axis Unseen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-76s-lead-artist-is-building-a-creepy-single-player-open-world-in-the-axis-unseen</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-76s-lead-artist-is-building-a-creepy-single-player-open-world-in-the-axis-unseen"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Look at any image of heavy metal horror game The Axis Unseen and you’ll recognise an archetype: the stealth archer. For a certain sort of Elder Scrolls player, it’s the only way to travel through a fantasy open world - perma-crouched, bow stretched lazily across the lower third of the screen. And it’s an appeal that creator Nate Purkeypile understands perfectly, having spent the larger portion of his career working on Bethesda’s RPGs, from Fallout 3 and Skyrim all the way through to Fallout 76.
“It’s probably not the best idea for most people to do a solo open world,” he says. “But at the same time, this is like my sixth one. I’m pretty sure what goes into these.”

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Peel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To Hell With The Ugly is a cracking name and even better game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/to-hell-with-the-ugly-is-a-cracking-name-and-even-better-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/to-hell-with-the-ugly-is-a-cracking-name-and-even-better-game"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T15:47:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A decent name is one thing, but one like To Hell With The Ugly plain demands to be looked up. That's when you see the striking art style, and yeah okay, I'm already on on board.
Based on a French novel by Boris Vian, this tells a strange and surprisingly dark story about a famously handsome young himbo who gets caught up in a sinister plot in 1950s Los Angeles and has to adventure, talk, fight, and - horrors - reason his way to the truth. It's an adventure game with quick-time event bits, and a 50s America setting, all of which could put me off it entirely, but I can't bring myself to say anything bad about it at all.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our pals at VG247 are giving away a custom Company Of Heroes 3 controller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-pals-at-vg247-are-giving-away-a-custom-company-of-heroes-3-controller</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-pals-at-vg247-are-giving-away-a-custom-company-of-heroes-3-controller"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T15:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excellent real-time strategy game Company Of Heroes 3 came out on PC earlier this year, and now its console edition has arrived on yer Xboxes and PlayStations. Listen, I know such console talk is considered heresy around these parts, but our corporate friends/siblings at sister site VG247 are running a competition right now to win a custom Company Of Heroes 3 Xbox controller. Sure, you might not want to play Company Of Heroes 3 specifically with said controller, but controllers in general are useful things that we at RPS use a lot for playing other types of games, and hey, we thought you might want to know about it, just in case. You can enter here if you fancy your chances.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>RPS</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our favourite games from not-E3 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-favourite-games-from-not-e3-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-favourite-games-from-not-e3-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T14:42:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Geoff Keighley announced in 2020 that he would be filling the space left by the recently cancelled E3 with his own gaming festival, none of us suspected that from that point on we would be doomed to an endless stream of   livestreams from now until the heat death of the universe. Did 2020's summer of gaming ever end? It did not. It is a constant. Like the stars in the sky or the ocean blue. Geoff is here. He has a game to show you. It's probably a horror game set in space. Doesn't that look great? Now let's take a look at the first game by a new studio comprised of ex-Bioware devs.


Yep, that's right. Not-E3 2023 is over (I think?) and once again I've commanded team RPS to dig their microphones out of storage before forcing them to tell me about their favourite game from the cavalcade of directs, showcases and presentations that have replaced my once beloved E3 weekend.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Rock Galactic season 4 is now live, adding new enemies and a special beer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-season-4-is-now-live-adding-new-enemies-and-a-special-beer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-season-4-is-now-live-adding-new-enemies-and-a-special-beer"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T14:42:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor, Ghost Ship Games continue to update the original co-op, space dwarf FPS game. Deep Rock Galactic went live with its season 4 content yesterday. Titled Critical Corruption, the update has added a new event with plenty of new enemies, and fulfilled some community requests.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startopia meets Theme Hospital in this jaunty space hospital sim]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/startopia-meets-theme-hospital-in-this-jaunty-space-hospital-sim</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/startopia-meets-theme-hospital-in-this-jaunty-space-hospital-sim"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T14:40:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know me, folks: I love management sims, and I love people in physical distress. Wasn't I only delighted, then, to play a bit of Galacticare, an upcoming hospital management sim in the same sticky vein as the hospitals Theme or Two Point. The twist? These hopsitals are in space! Like those managment games, your task is to build a hospital that runs as smooth as some kind of alien baby's bottom (the alien probably has tentacles), where you want to treat people and prevent them from dying as much as possible, but largely because death is bad for your profit margin more than any altruistic impulse. I mean you can be altruistic if you want, I suppose, but if you run out of money it's harder to build more weird bone-fixing machines.
The tone - though Galacticare has strange diseases like being eaten from the inside out by a singularity, and wacky treatments including a sort of laser disco machine - is actually much closer to kind of satire-ish hijinks of spacestation management game Startopia than I had expected, thanks in part to the extremely dry AI helper offering input, and the many alien species who'll come to you for treatment.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 4 kills another high level Hardcore character, this time with a bug]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-4-kills-another-high-level-hardcore-character-this-time-with-a-bug</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-4-kills-another-high-level-hardcore-character-this-time-with-a-bug"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T12:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just one week after Diablo 4's first level 100 Hardcore character was killed by a lost connection, the game has brutally (and unfairly) claimed another Hardcore character. Unlike Carn's Barbarian, Quin69's Druid wasn't level 100 yet, but he was pretty darn close at level 91. His Druid had 172 hours and 50 minutes of play time. That's more than a week's worth of playing and the game's only been out for 10 days (or 15, if we're including early access).
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dordogne review: don't brush off this sweet summer adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dordogne-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dordogne-review"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T12:06:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Memory can be a fickle thing. For thirty-something Mimi, everything before her thirteenth birthday is a blank. What happened before that point is never really interrogated during Dordogne's three-hour run time, but we do know her father is a stubborn old goat who cut ties with Mimi's really quite nice grandmother Nora after a summer she spent there as a shy, sheltered twelve-year-old. It's this summer that seems to be the cork in Mimi's memory bottle, and it's also the window in which Dordogne frames its sweet, coming of age tale. As Mimi in the present comes to terms with her grandmother's recent passing, the objects she finds in Nora's now-empty summer house trigger important flashbacks to that golden summer, and maybe also the answer to Mimi's apparent amnesia. Dordogne never demands very much of you during these sequences, but it does know how to luxuriate in life's little details, and find pleasure in a more leisurely lifestyle.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yakuza devs share more details on Like A Dragon Gaiden and Infinite Wealth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yakuza-devs-share-more-details-on-like-a-dragon-gaiden-and-infinite-wealth</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yakuza-devs-share-more-details-on-like-a-dragon-gaiden-and-infinite-wealth"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T11:29:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yakuza developer RGG Studio held their latest RGG Summit overnight, and the showcase contained more details on upcoming releases Like A Dragon Gaiden: The Man Who Erased His Name and Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth. We got a small extra look at Gaiden last week during Summer Game Fest, where Kiryu looks like he's meant to be starring in the next John Wick film, but the RGG Summit went into a lot more detail. Here's what you need to know.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rockstar co-founder and GTA writer Dan Houser founds new company Absurd Ventures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-co-founder-and-gta-writer-dan-houser-founds-new-company-absurd-ventures</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-co-founder-and-gta-writer-dan-houser-founds-new-company-absurd-ventures"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T09:46:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dan Houser, the co-founder of Rockstar Games and former head writer at the company, has founded a new company called Absurd Ventures. Houser left Rockstar in 2020, after co-writing some of the company's biggest games including GTA V and Red Dead Redemption 2. He's now returned with Absurd Ventures, headquartered in Santa Monica, California.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liv Ngan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skrytý svět Internet of Dildos aneb Kybernetické hrozby v erotických pomůckách]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16653</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/skryty-svet-internet-of-dildos-aneb-kyberneticke-hrozby-v-erotickych-pomuckach/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jak hodně je rizikové, když si do svých intimních záležitostí pouštíme výrobky vybavené moderními technologiemi? Hrozby rozebírá ve svém textu Zbyněk Pospíchal, Network Architect ze společnosti Quantcom.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade your Steam Deck or ROG Ally with this 2TB SSD for £160]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/upgrade-your-steam-deck-or-rog-ally-with-this-2tb-ssd-for-160</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/upgrade-your-steam-deck-or-rog-ally-with-this-2tb-ssd-for-160"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:40:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck and ROG Ally are brilliant little devices - but you do end up paying a lot more for a high-capacity version, with a £220 difference between the cheapest and most expensive Steam Decks. If you opted for one of the smaller capacities to save space, then consider this deal for a Sabrent Rocket Q4 2230 NVMe drive that offers a massive 2TB of storage for £160 - down from a usual price of £205. 
To get this deal, you'll need to tick the box on the Amazon product page to get a 7% discount, then use the code SH4KDU9Z to unlock an extra discount. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immortals Of Aveum is more Doom than magic Call Of Duty, but it's far too serious for its own good]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/immortals-of-aveum-is-more-doom-than-magic-call-of-duty-but-its-far-too-serious-for-its-own-good</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/immortals-of-aveum-is-more-doom-than-magic-call-of-duty-but-its-far-too-serious-for-its-own-good"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immortals Of Aveum is EA and Ascendant Studio's upcoming first-person shooter where, instead of propelling metal at high speeds, you're slinging magic with your hands. We got another good look at said magic slinging at this year's Summer Game Fest, which has seemingly resulted in several reports of it being like a wizardy Call Of Duty. But having played a 30 minute demo of it this week, I reckon it's nothing like COD at all, really. Instead, it's more like Doom / your other retro shooter of choice, but one that carries itself with a frightening seriousness. Sometimes, that's fine. There have been plenty of these smaller sorts of blockbusters that have successfully struck the right balance of silly to serious, with the best ascending to a place of endearment. But so far, Immortals Of Aveum hasn't filled me with hope that it'll join the likes of Psi-Ops: The Mindgate Conspiracy, or like, The Darkness, as a twinkling beacon of silly fun.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor is already mere pickaxe strokes from striking autoshooter gold]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-survivor-is-already-mere-pickaxe-strokes-from-striking-autoshooter-gold</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-survivor-is-already-mere-pickaxe-strokes-from-striking-autoshooter-gold"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:26:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m sure that describing Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor as a mix of Deep Rock Galactic and Vampire Survivors sounds like it’s betraying a terminal lack of imagination. But, come on, look at it. It’s a top-down autoshooter/bullet heaven where defeated beasties drop XP blobs that fuel an escalating series of weapon and stat upgrades, playing out in the whimsical sci-fi/fantasy/corporate nightmare universe inhabited by DRG’s dwarves. "It’s a mix of Deep Rock Galactic and Vampire Survivors" is the most apt and succinct description that currently or will ever exist for it. So there.
And yet, being derivative doesn’t always preclude the opportunity for bloody good fun. I’ve played just over three hours of a very early Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor build, and while it’s both missing some parts and could benefit from the odd tweak, it’s already capable of pumping out dopamine as efficiently as any established VampSurvs-alike.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Electronic Wireless Show S2 Episode 20: the best of Summer Game Fest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-s2-episode-20-the-best-of-summer-game-fest</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-s2-episode-20-the-best-of-summer-game-fest"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:15:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Game Fest, Not-E3, Keigh3... whatever you want to call this festival of hype, its annual takeover of the game industry’s collective headspace meant there was only ever going to be one topic for the Electronic Wireless Show podcast this week. Alice even made up for her recording absence by pre-emptively tying Nate to a chair and forcibly making him watch trailers, like that bit in A Clockwork Orange but with "WORLD EXCLUSIVE" flashing up every thirty seconds. Still, we keep it light by focusing on the games we actually like the look of, from The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria to Starfield, Nova Roma to Dungeons of Hinterberg.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logitech's G Pro X Superlight wireless mouse is down to $104 when you recycle an old peripheral at Best Buy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/logitechs-g-pro-x-superlight-wireless-mouse-is-down-to-104-when-you-recycle-an-old-peripheral-at-best-buy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/logitechs-g-pro-x-superlight-wireless-mouse-is-down-to-104-when-you-recycle-an-old-peripheral-at-best-buy"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:13:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Logitech's G Pro X Superlight gaming mouse is perhaps the most popular mouse in esports, offering reliable wireless, a superb lightweight design and high-end components throughout. 
It normally retails close to its $159.99 MSRP, but today you can pick one up for $103.99 at Best Buy when you bring in any old peripheral for recycling - a pretty great deal for a brand new mouse of this calibre. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Check out this wild-looking follow-up to one of 2021's weirdest games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foreign-gnomes-reveals-everhood-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foreign-gnomes-reveals-everhood-2"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:12:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week, self-proclaimed "unconventional ARPG" Everhood 2 was revealed as part of IGN's Summer of Gaming, and yep, it's looking like a suitably weird follow-up to its 2021 predecessor. According to a press release, the sequel is due out in early 2025, so about a year and a half away as it stands, and you'll of course be able to pick it up on Steam when it does. Come and watch its reveal trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rally Point: Jagged Alliance 2 is still unique, and it shouldn't be]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-jagged-alliance-2-is-still-unique-and-it-shouldnt-be</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-jagged-alliance-2-is-still-unique-and-it-shouldnt-be"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are old games that are plain too hard to get into now, even I have to concede. Ancient ruins of a house to be admired and contemplated, but not fit to live in. The ceilings are too low, the stairs too narrow, the pipes an afterthought. Jagged Alliance 2 isn't that far gone, but it’s getting there. It gives lots of options for fine control but using them is largely gated behind esoteric, repetitive keyboard shortcuts, which get doubly cumbersome during its awkward transitional moments between real and turn-based movement. 
It's about leading a group of mercenaries to overthrow the tyrannical queen of a fictional island. A guerrilla warfare sim with great strategic freedom and probably the best turn-based tactical combat ever, all buoyed away from self-seriousness by a campy, irreverent tone and intentionally over the top characters.
What I'm saying is: it's still worth it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead Island 2's first story expansion features a perfectly normal billionaire with a techno-death cult]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dead-island-2-expansion-roadmap-detailed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dead-island-2-expansion-roadmap-detailed"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T15:42:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dambuster Studios have offered up a rough roadmap of what we can expect from the pair of upcoming Dead Island 2 story expansions. The first of the two expansions, titled Haus, asks the question, "How does a billionaire prepare for the zompocalypse?" and answers that with "a techno-death cult with a healthy splash of debauchery and gore!". Sounds about right. This first expansion has quite a vague release window, expected to launch some time between October and December this year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince Of Persia creator Jordan Mechner is "excited and very eager to play" The Lost Crown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prince-of-persia-creator-jordan-mechner-is-excited-and-very-eager-to-play-the-lost-crown</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prince-of-persia-creator-jordan-mechner-is-excited-and-very-eager-to-play-the-lost-crown"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T15:08:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've said it once, and I'll say it several times again. I'm exceedingly pumped for Prince Of Persia: The Lost Crown - and so is Prince Of Persia creator, Jordan Mechner. When I visited Ubisoft Montpellier at the end of May, one of things game director Mounir Radi told me about during my visit was how relieved he felt after showing Mechner a very early prototype. And in speaking to Mechner earlier this week about how he feels about The Lost Crown now, he tells me that "what I've seen so far of their modern 2D Metroidvania take on [Prince Of Persia] has got me excited and very eager to play."
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Park Beyond review: more style than substance, but sometimes that's the point]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/park-beyond-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/park-beyond-review"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T14:38:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Much as I adored Theme Park, it's a bit of a weird game to have inspired so many descendants. The latest is Park Beyond, and for the most part it's exactly what you'd expect. Build rides to attract crowds, shops to fill their stupid mouths, doctors to treat the vomitous and cleaners when the doctors were too late. Punters pay to use any ride, they pay for entry, for toilets and cash machines, and for every item you price in every shop.
That's as close as it gets to micromanagement, unless you count finely tuning the position of every rock, shrub, and decorative roof panel. It's more Planet Coaster than the cynical money grubbing of Theme Park, so if you're here for rollercoasters that do stunt jumps over canyons, it's mostly good news.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teardown's Creative Mode lets you build fully destructible dioramas, out today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/teardown-creative-mode-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/teardown-creative-mode-out-now"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T14:13:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week Tuxedo Labs unveiled their snazzy-looking Creative Mode in Teardown, and it's available for you to play right now. The new mode joins the game as part of its 1.4 update, and looks to be all about what it says on the tin - being creative! Essentially, the big thing it lets you do is build your own unique voxel structures by, essentially, painting them in the air. Think of it as a sort of paired back, voxel-focused approach to a piece of 3D modelling software like Blender.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft recruit Outriders dev People Can Fly to make a game based on a preexisting IP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/people-can-fly-working-on-microsoft-ip</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/people-can-fly-working-on-microsoft-ip"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T13:26:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It looks like Bulletstorm and Outriders developer People Can Fly are working on a Microsoft IP, but no one knows which one just yet. This comes from People Can Fly themselves via a statement provided to Polish financial site Interia Biznes, where the studio shared that the game currently has the title Project Maverick (via Eurogamer). All of the funding is coming from Microsoft, with a budget ranging from $30-50m.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel’s Core rebranding exercise offers a glimpse at Meteor Lake CPU specs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intels-core-rebranding-exercise-offers-a-glimpse-at-meteor-lake-cpu-specs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intels-core-rebranding-exercise-offers-a-glimpse-at-meteor-lake-cpu-specs"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T13:02:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fresh info on Intel Meteor Lake, the blue team’s upcoming 14th Gen CPU family, has arrived from an unlikely yet still very official source. See, Intel haven’t revealed the chips themselves, but have announced a rebranding for future Core processors – one that will start taking effect with Meteor Lake. And, in doing so, they’ve let slip some details on the new range's design and capabilities.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Superstars will satisfy old-school fans and I'm definitely not one of them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-superstars-will-satisfy-old-schools-fans-and-im-definitely-not-one-of-them</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-superstars-will-satisfy-old-schools-fans-and-im-definitely-not-one-of-them"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T12:09:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At every single video game thing I've flown out to, there's been a Sonic game. The speedy hog is forever occupying a booth and starring in some new-fangled thing, which oscillates between a 2D sidescroller laser-targeted at old-school fans, or 3D ones like Frontiers that try their utmost to push the series forwards.
So, I've gone and played another Sonic haven't I? This time I spent around 15-minutes with Sonic Superstars at this year's Summer Game Fest, a new 2.5D sidescroller that seems to successfully combine the feel of Sonic Mania with a modern art style and some new tricks. If you like old Sonic games, there's no doubt in my mind you'll love it. If you don't, there's no doubt in my mind you'll think it's agony.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam's latest update isn't that exciting, but it does let you take notes now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-update-introduces-notes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-update-introduces-notes"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T11:09:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest update for Steam is here, bringing with it a number of quality of life changes and a slightly updated look. Valve announced the desktop update back in April, where the new version has been in beta for some Steam users to try out. In Valve's post from yesterday announcing the update is available for all, it did note that the "most impactful changes in this update aren’t immediately visible," as a lot of the work put into the update was today with how it "[shares] code across the Steam Desktop Client, Big Picture mode, and Steam Deck." According to Valve, these changes should mean that future features should be more quickly implemented and iterated upon.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lies of P modders are already turning the game into Bloodborne]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lies-of-p-bloodborne-mod</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lies-of-p-bloodborne-mod"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T11:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lies Of P isn't even out yet, but a group of modders have already tried turning the Soulslike into Bloodborne. The mod comes from Garden of Eyes, a YouTube channel and group of modders that typically work on FromSoftware titles (they're the ones that made that long COVID mod for Elden Ring). Yesterday, though, they showed off a mod for Lies of P that lets you turn the game's Timothy Chalamet-looking twink into a hunter from Bloodborne.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oisin Kuhnke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung's premium Odyssey Neo G7 Mini LED monitor is £200 off with this code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/samsungs-premium-odyssey-neo-g7-mini-led-monitor-is-200-off-with-this-code</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/samsungs-premium-odyssey-neo-g7-mini-led-monitor-is-200-off-with-this-code"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T22:54:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just finished promoting our previous deals post on a Samsung ultrawide, and now I've spotted another deal using the same 48HR20 discount code on another model - Samsung's immensely impressive Odyssey Neo G7. 
This 32-inch curved VA monitor offers a mighty 4K resolution, 165Hz refresh rate and a Mini LED backlight that provides superb, almost OLED-like HDR performance - without the burn-in potential or agressive brightness limiters that often feature on OLED panels. Now this is a premium option, with a normal price point of £999, but today with the 48HR20 code it's a slightly more palatable £799 at the Samsung UK store. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a 34-in gaming ultrawide for £240 with this Samsung Store code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-34-in-gaming-ultrawide-for-240-with-this-samsung-store-code</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-34-in-gaming-ultrawide-for-240-with-this-samsung-store-code"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T22:34:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get an ultra-wide Samsung gaming monitor for less than £240? It sounds a bit too good to be true, but it's possible thanks to the code 48HR20 over at Samsung's UK site, which knocks this 34-inch ultrawide down from £299 to £239. That's an awesome price for a monitor with a 3440x1440 resolution, 100Hz refresh rate and a VA panel with excellent contrast. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's better: snap-to construction, or fighting a little beastie then meeting the giant adults]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whats-better-snap-to-construction-or-fighting-a-little-beastie-then-meeting-the-giant-adults</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whats-better-snap-to-construction-or-fighting-a-little-beastie-then-meeting-the-giant-adults"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T19:41:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last time, you decided that by a mere two votes that glowing wings are better than slipstreaming. Two votes! Honestly, I am surprised by the outcome but if that's what our infallible method rules, so be it. This week, I ask you to choose between a thing which helps you create something big, and a thing which gives you consequences after destroying something small. What's better: snap-to construction, or fighting a little beastie then meeting the giant adults?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>