<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-06-07T03:15:14.363Z</id>
    <title>Pitlovo RSS</title>
    <updated>2022-06-07T03:15:14.363Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.14.4</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Wars: KOTOR II Receiving Limited Run Games Physical Switch Release]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132572</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/star-wars-kotor-ii-receiving-limited-run-games-physical-switch-release"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arriving "this summer".
Another one of the highlights during the Limited Run Summer Showcase was the news Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic: The Sith Lords would be receiving a physical release on the Switch.
This version is based on Aspyr's recent port and follows on from Limited Run Games' release of the original game on the Nintendo Switch. The second game will be arriving on the hybrid system at some point this summer.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprise! Doom Eternal Is Getting A Limited Run Physical Release On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132570</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/surprise-doom-eternal-is-getting-a-limited-run-physical-release-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T02:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-orders open next month.

A month before Doom Eternal got released in 2020 on the Nintendo Switch, Bethesda confirmed this platform would no longer receive a physical version and pre-orders for hard copies would be refunded.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time For Another Moebius-Looking Video Game]]></title>
        <id>1849026742</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/moebius-jean-giraud-xtal-pc-steam-true-colors-indie-vid-1849026742"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T02:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The brilliant French artist Jean “Moebius” Giraud had one of the most recognisable art styles around, and while his works have inspired video games for decades—including the ones he worked on directly—few have been able to truly look like one of his illustrations come to life.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Round Up: Every Physical Game From Limited Run's Summer Showcase Coming To Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132568</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/round-up-every-physical-game-from-limited-runs-summer-showcase-coming-to-switch"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T01:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are even some 3DS, N64 and SNES releases.
Limited Run Games earlier today aired its LRG3 Summer Showcase. As usual, there were a lot of Switch announcements. There were also some other Nintendo-related announcements for platforms like the 3DS, Nintendo 64 and Super Nintendo.
We've included a full video recap of the show (above) if you would like to see how all the action unfolded. It certainly went out with a bang - with the reveal of a DOOM Eternal physical edition for Switch. According to LRG, the titles revealed during this event are scheduled for release between 2022 and 2023. All up, 33 games were revealed, with more than 25 announced for Nintendo platforms.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo's Big Piracy Case Is A Very Sad Story]]></title>
        <id>1849026479</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-piracy-case-bowser-xecuter-team-prison-pirate-1849026479"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T00:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in February, Gary Bowser—who in most media reports has been described as a ‘hacker’—was sentenced to 40 months in prison for his role in selling cheat and modification devices for Nintendo hardware. Being a court case, most of the reporting dealt only with names on a page and cold facts, but a transcript of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom Announces A New Digital Showcase, Streaming Live June 13th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132565</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/capcom-announces-a-new-digital-showcase-streaming-live-june-13th"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T00:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["news and updates for upcoming Capcom games".
Hot off the heels of Sega's Sonic Central announcement, Capcom has now announced its own livestream digital event - bringing fans the "latest Capcom game information".
It'll be broadcast on the 13th of June via the official Capcom YouTube and Twitch channels and is expected to run for "around" 35th minutes. You can expect to see "news and in-depth updates" on previously announced upcoming Capcom titles.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XIV Devs Brainstormed A Battle Royale Mode That Sounds Fun As Hell]]></title>
        <id>1849026347</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-battle-royale-pvp-blue-mage-naoki-yos-1849026347"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a recent interview with Gamer, a prominent Japanese gaming website, Final Fantasy XIV producer Naoki Yoshida let slip that his team was at one point mulling the possibility of adding a competitive battle royale to the online role-playing game. It sounds like it’d be a whole lot of fun, too.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Central Broadcast Airing On YouTube And Twitch June 7th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132562</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/sonic-central-broadcast-airing-on-youtube-and-twitch-june-7th"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T23:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A "sneak peek" at upcoming projects & more.
It's been a rather busy period for Sonic the Hedgehog. He's just released his second movie, his retro collection Sonic Origins is out at the end of this month, and later this year his new 3D adventures Sonic Frontiers will be released.
With this in mind, Sega has announced it will be airing another 'Sonic Central' broadcast. Fans of the blue blur will be able to tune in for a "sneak peek" at some of the company's upcoming Sonic projects, partnerships, and events happening in 2022.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl Update Adds Long-Awaited Character Voices]]></title>
        <id>1849026232</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-character-voices-update-free-1849026232"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T23:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last October, after a surprising amount of hype, Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl debuted on all major platforms. While the game was well-received, one big complaint arose from the lack of voiced characters, making the whole thing feel a bit quiet and dead, especially compared to its competition. But now, a new update out…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Netflix Resident Evil series has a whole bunch of undead monsters in its latest trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328358</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/netflix-resident-evil-june-trailer-zombies-horde-streaming/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=netflix-resident-evil-june-trailer-zombies-horde-streaming"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T23:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plus some Umbrella lore
The latest trailer for Netflix's Resident Evil live-action series is out. Amid the Umbrella messaging and world full of zombies, it really does seem to be doing its own thing with the source material.
The series looks to take place in two different eras: in a world overrun by zombies, and in the past, showing events leading up to the fall.
The past shows Umbrella developing new advancements that come at a cost. As Lance Reddick's Wesker states, the T-Virus is contained in some products, leading to "monsters." And you can guess what will follow.
We jump forward to the future, and it goes from impending horror to all-out World War Z. The world seems essentially overrun with various biological horrors.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uIdjcDTc9Vk
Evil in residence
This …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Van Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[macOS 13 Adding Ability To Use Rosetta In ARM Linux VMs For Speedy x86_64 Linux Binaries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=macOS-13-Rosetta-Linux-Binaries</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=macOS-13-Rosetta-Linux-Binaries"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T22:44:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to announcing the M2 SoC, Apple used its WWDC keynote to also announce macOS 13 "Ventura". One of the interesting technical changes with macOS 13 is the ability to use Apple's Rosetta software for speedy execution of Linux x86_64 binaries running on ARM Linux VMs from Apple Silicon...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new Sonic Central is airing on June 7]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328366</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/sonic-central-airing-june-projects-partnerships-events-stream/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sonic-central-airing-june-projects-partnerships-events-stream"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T22:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Blue Blur speeds into the June lineup
There's a new entry in the June showcase lineup, and it's speeding in fast. A new Sonic Central is airing tomorrow, June 7, with information on upcoming projects involving Sonic himself.
Announced on social media today, the Sonic Central will air June 7 at 9 a.m. PT / 12 p.m. ET. You can find the stream either on YouTube or Twitch.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cxJ5_ovBC_g
The stream will show a look at what projects, partnerships and events are in store for 2022. No estimation on how long it will run.
https://twitter.com/sonic_hedgehog/status/1533931741592752128
New frontiers
A few Sonic the Hedgehog projects are already in the works that could easily appear here. There's Sonic Frontiers, which has been steadily rolling out new looks at gameplay as part of IGN's First program this month. The early looks at open-world exploration, puzzle-solving, and combat have been getting some mixed reception though. Sega has said Sonic Frontiers is arriving in 2022.
There's also the retro collection Sonic Origins. This packages in a bunch of Sonic the Hedgehog classics, including Sonic the Hedgehog 3 and Sonic & Knuckles. We got a glimpse at the Mirror Mode option recently, which looks wild. We already know the release date for Sonic Origins though, and it's not far off. The retro collection is aiming for June 23, 2022.
As for expanded content, there is a third Sonic the Hedgehog movie in the works. Knuckles is getting his own live-action series as well, and the Sonic Prime series on Netflix. Sonic media is growing to encompass a lot, and we could get hints about what's in store along those lines.
The Sonic Central does arrive right at the vanguard of a stacked week for streams too. Thursday is the Summer Game Fest Live kickoff, followed by several days of streams including Xbox, the Wholesome Direct, and the PC Gaming Show. You can find a full schedule of all the upcoming streams here.
The post A new Sonic Central is airing on June 7 appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Van Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No. Power Punch II wasn’t going to be a sequel to Punch-Out!!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328338</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/weekly-kusoge-power-punch-ii-nes-punch-out/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-kusoge-power-punch-ii-nes-punch-out"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T22:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three rounds, that's all I ask
Punch-Out!! was one of the games I played for the first time, later in my life, that saved retro gaming for me. I still haven’t beaten it. I’ve reached Super Macho Man, I think. Progress is just so slow at that point that I eventually get distracted and move on to something else.
That has nothing to do with Beam Software’s Power Punch II. Well, not nothing. You would have to be blind to not look at it and see it as having lifted Punch-Out!!’s formula. That’s nothing new for the industry, though. Power Punch II just happens to have been catapulted to notoriety due to a rumor and its uncanny resemblance. It’s a rather strange game, but it’s one where the ability to judge it by its own merits has been lost.

I could wallop you all day with this surgical 2x4
The …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoey Handley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IPv6 deset let poté: kam jsme se dostali dekádu po velkém zapnutí?]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16082</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/ipv6-deset-let-pote-kam-jsme-se-dostali-dekadu-po-velkem-zapnuti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IPv6 je tu s námi oficiálně už deset let, v praxi ale ještě mnohem déle. Někdy to vypadá, že IPv6 vlastně nikdo nepotřebuje, kromě několika nadšenců. Je tomu ale skutečně tak? Nepotřebujeme nakonec IPv6 všichni?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Základy tvorby her pro herní konzoli NES: mikroprocesor 6502 a assembler ca65]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16081</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/zaklady-tvorby-her-pro-herni-konzoli-nes-mikroprocesor-6502-a-assembler-ca65/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve druhém článku o tvorbě her a grafických či zvukových dem pro osmibitovou herní konzoli NES se seznámíme s programátorským modelem mikroprocesoru MOS 6502 (resp. Ricoh 2A03.) a vysvětlíme si, jak vlastně skutečně pracuje kostra reálného programu pro NES.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple ohlásil procesor M2, výkon narostl až o 35 %]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43712</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/apple-ohlasil-procesor-m2-vykon-narostl-az-o-35-procent/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Druhá generace 5nm procesu TSMC a 20 miliard tranzistorů, to jsou dva klíčové parametry, které předurčují výkon nového ARM SoC pro počítače Apple. Nakousnuté jablko posouvá dál hranice, nový procesor nabízí propustnost 128bit LPDDR5 paměťového subsystému na 100 GB/s (adresovat umí až 24 GB RAM), kombinaci 4+4 CPU jader (4 výkonná, 4 efektivní).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Blockchain Game Coming To The Epic Store Looks Like Garbage]]></title>
        <id>1849025194</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/epic-games-web3-pc-blockchain-nft-video-game-grit-1849025194"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T21:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developer and publisher Epic Games will make its official foray into crypto with Grit, a battle royale game from blockchain video game company Gala Games. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stylish Cel-Shaded Skating Shooter Rollerdrome Looks To Be Pure Joy On Wheels]]></title>
        <id>1849014241</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/rollerdrome-roll7-olliolli-world-jet-grind-radio-pc-pla-1849014241"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T21:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Schulkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This full-size Razer optical-mechanical keyboard is down to £80 from £200]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-full-size-razer-optical-mechanical-keyboard-is-down-to-80-from-200</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-full-size-razer-optical-mechanical-keyboard-is-down-to-80-from-200"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T21:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Razer Huntsman Elite is one of the company's best mechanical keyboards, courtesy of advanced opto-mechanical switches, a comfy palm rest and full-size UK layout, but its RRP of £200 is enough to put off even the most craven mechanical keyboard enthusiasts. Today though, Amazon UK has discounted the board to just 80 of your British pounds, a 60% reduction that brings it below some of the best value gaming keyboards. That's an awesome price for a full-size UK layout with this kind of tech on board.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Annapurna Interactive’s internal studio announces team of seasoned indie developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328356</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/annapurna-interactives-internal-studio-announces-team-of-seasoned-indie-developers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=annapurna-interactives-internal-studio-announces-team-of-seasoned-indie-developers"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T21:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Solar Ash and Hyper Light Drifter devs are on board
Annapurna is well-known for publishing some of the most imaginative, polished, and moving indie games out there, so we're pretty excited for them to venture into developing their own stuff -- they announced their own internal studio back in 2020. Of course, a publisher with that much prestige is pulling some pretty impressive talent, including some names you might recognize if you keep up with the indie crowd.
Chelsea Hash (who was the technical art lead of What Remains of Edith Finch) will be heading up the studio's project as game director, along with technical director Brett Lajzer (Solar Ash), senior producer Evan Hembacher (Solar Ash), art director Cosimo Galluzzi (Solar Ash, Hyper Light Drifter), and environment artist Nate Grove (S…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noelle Warner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WWDC22. Apple M2]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/wwdc22.-apple-m2</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/wwdc22.-apple-m2"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T21:04:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes začala vývojářská konference Applu WWDC22. V rámci keynote byla představena řada novinek: MacBook Air s čipem Apple M2, iOS 16, macOS Ventura, iPadOS 16, watchOS 9, MacBook Pro 13″ s čipem Apple M2, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Horizon Forbidden West update 1.14 adds New Game+ and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328282</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/horizon-forbidden-west-update-1-14-patch-notes-new-game-plus-aloy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=horizon-forbidden-west-update-1-14-patch-notes-new-game-plus-aloy"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T21:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running Up That Hill
For those of you still exploring the luscious-but-deadly pastures of Horizon Forbidden West, Guerrilla Games has a brand new update for you. As revealed during last week's Sony State of Play presentation, Update 1.14 brings new several new features and modes to the stunning open-world adventure.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3worI7QeCHQ
First and perhaps foremost, Horizon Forbidden West update 1.14 adds the much-requested New Game+ mode for those who have already completed Aloy's adventure. These players can now restart the story, locked and loaded with gear, skills, and abilities for a low-intensity run through the epic campaign. For those who wish to press themselves further forward, the new Ultra Hard difficulty option will test your hunting and acrobatic skills to the absolute limit.
For players who feel they may have perhaps focused Aloy's growing talents in the wrong areas, the new Respec option will rebank all of your acquired skill points, allowing for a fresh build on Aloy's skill tree. And for the fashion-forward, the new Transmog option will allow you to select any of your gathered gear (including all respective effects) while retaining the visual appearance of any other outfit. So if you have a favorite look for yer girl, then you can keep on rocking that visual style regardless of your actual equipped clothing, armour, and headgear.
Last, but by no means least, the new update features a fresh round of bug stomps and visual tweaks, the details of which you can find in the official patch notes right here.
Horizon Forbidden West is available now on PlayStation platforms.
The post Horizon Forbidden West update 1.14 adds New Game+ and more appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant Bomb Co-Founder Jeff Gerstmann Leaving Site After 14 Years]]></title>
        <id>1849025179</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/giant-bomb-jeff-gertsmann-14-years-leaving-departure-bo-1849025179"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, Giant Bomb announced that the website’s co-founder, Jeff Gerstmann, was leaving the popular video game website after nearly 15 years. In a blog post announcing the departure, it was explained that “Giant Bomb and Jeff Gerstmann have agreed to go our separate ways.”
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon Age QA Workers Vote Unanimously To Form Labor Union]]></title>
        <id>1849025110</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-4-bioware-labor-union-keywords-edmonton-1849025110"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T20:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This morning, quality assurance testers on Dragon Age: Dreadwolf unanimously voted to form Canada’s first video game labor union. They filed the motion on April 20, and the election concluded 16-0 in favor of unionizing. This came after the devs mounted an organized campaign focused on bad pay and a troubling…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl's Voice Acting Update Is Now Live On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132545</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/nickelodeon-all-star-brawls-voice-acting-update-is-now-live-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T20:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Surprise! It's ready!
Update: When someone says "soon", we expect maybe a couple of days, but just over an hour ago, the devs announced on Twitter that Switch owners don't need to wait much longer, and that the update is ready to download!
Also, Mark DeCarlo — the voice for the upcoming DLC fighter Hugh Neutron — revealed that he will be reprising the role of the beloved character when he arrives in Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl later this year!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pick up an RX 6900 XT graphics card for £100 under RRP at Ebuyer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-an-rx-6900-xt-graphics-card-for-100-under-rrp-at-ebuyer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-an-rx-6900-xt-graphics-card-for-100-under-rrp-at-ebuyer"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T20:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[High-end graphics cards are getting more affordable, and AMD's top-end* RX 6900 XT is now available at £100 below the model's UK RRP. This particular unit is a Gigabyte OC card, with a 2285MHz boost clock (compared to 2250MHz on the reference design) and a hefty triple-slot thermal solution. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design Your Own Pokémon T-Shirt With Original Stitch's New Line (Japan)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132469</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/design-your-own-pokemon-t-shirt-with-original-stitchs-new-line-japan"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Casual wear, I choose you.
Are you a stylish Pokémon trainer? Check out these new T-Shirts from Poké-partner Original Stitch, which are much simpler and suitable for casual wear than their usual out-and-proud shirt designs.
Here's the website spiel:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yout.com Operator Rejects Deal Offered By Brazil’s Criminal Prosecutor]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219729</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/yout-com-operator-rejects-deal-offered-by-brazils-criminal-prosecutor-220606/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T19:51:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Popular stream-ripping site Yout.com has rejected a deal from Brazil's public prosecutor to 'resolve' a criminal lawsuit. The agreement would allow the site's operator to avoid a prison sentence with relative ease. However, that would come at a significant financial cost and a permanent ban on Brazilian visitors.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xbox Fans Think Phil Spencer Is Sending Them Secret Messages Through His Banjo-Kazooie Achievements]]></title>
        <id>1849024948</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-phil-spencer-banjo-kazooie-remake-sequel-rumor-ach-1849024948"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft executive vice president of gaming Phil Spencer recently played Nintendo 64 classic Banjo-Kazooie, according to his Xbox Live account. But where most might simply see a public figure enjoying a bit of nostalgia, a specific brand of diehard took it as a personal wink and a nod from the Xbox head of things to…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Granblue Fantasy: Versus update adds Overdrive, Rush, and Backshift mechanics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328305</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/granblue-fantasy-versus-update-adds-overdrive-rush-and-backshift-mechanics/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=granblue-fantasy-versus-update-adds-overdrive-rush-and-backshift-mechanics"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T19:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rush, Rush, Shift into Overdrive
CyGames has released its previously teased major update for attractive fighter Granblue Fantasy: Versus. Now available on both PlayStation and PC platforms, Update 2.80 adds three major new mechanics to the super-stylish and surprisingly sexy anime ring rocker.
The first new mechanic, "Rush", is a quick forward dash that can be activated at the cost of half of your SBA meter. The dash is strike-invincible just after startup, but can still be shut down by projectiles. The purpose of dash is to perfect the timing of the player's advance in order to gain ground in the face of a heavy assault from the opponent. Think of it ala tactical rolls in The King of Fighters, except lacking projectile invincibility. Rush can also be linked with certain attacks in order t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What To Expect From Summer Game Fest’s Big Not-E3 Event]]></title>
        <id>1849024576</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/summer-game-fest-2022-starfield-where-to-watch-what-to-1849024576"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With E3 2022 canceled, there’s a vacuum at the center of the video game marketing season. Many eyes are on Summer Game Fest for being both the lengthiest and the widest-ranging presser on the horizon. But the host, Geoff Keighley, recently saw fit to temper expectations ahead of the show, saying that it won’t be flush…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter From The Editor #08: a note about your RPS supporter subscription]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/letter-from-the-editor-08</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/letter-from-the-editor-08"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:56:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello folks. Sorry it’s been so long since I’ve written one of these Letters From The Editor. Things have been… manic, to say the least. Manic in the traditional ‘busy’ sense (hello Elden Ring, PAX, V Rising and now notE3 planning), but also in the ‘man, there are so many cool things I want to talk to you about but aren’t quite ready to announce yet’ sense. I’ve been on the cusp of writing about these things every single month since, err, March, but then something falls through, the weeks go by, and we’re back to square one again. So I’m sorry about that, I really am. 
What I’m writing to you about today still isn’t one of those exciting things, unfortunately, but it is nonetheless very important. When we relaunched our RPS Supporter Programme last year, we did so on June 17th, which means its one-year anniversary is just around the corner. It also means that those of you who signed up for our yearly supporter tier will be coming to the end of your subscription soon, and I wanted to explain a little bit about the renewal process as it’s… err, a bit convoluted. Sorry again about that.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Game Tests Your Nerve As You Cheat At Cards To Rob The Rich]]></title>
        <id>1849024359</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/card-shark-switch-steam-review-cheating-poker-tricks-ha-1849024359"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m on a ship, the waves rocking the boat as I deal cards to a former pirate and my friend (who is also my accomplice). We are trying to cheat this ex-pirate out of information and travel costs via a card game. To help us win, I use a small shiny object on the table to slyly peek at each card that is dealt and signal…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Announces Its New M2 Processor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M2"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:35:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple's WWDC keynote this year was used to announce the M2 processor alongside a slew of other announcements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl gets full character voice-over in free update today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328347</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-free-update-voice-over-items-today/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-free-update-voice-over-items-today"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No longer a silent brawl
Nickelodeon's cartoon mash-up brawler is getting a much-requested addition today. Full character voice-over for the whole roster hits Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl today alongside items in a free update for PlayStation, Xbox, and PC.
When Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl first launched, its lack of voice-over for its roster was notable. Today, GameMill Entertainment and Ludosity are updating the brawl to add exactly that.
The voices behind characters including SpongeBob (Tom Kenny) and Patrick (Bill Fagerbakke), Ren & Stimpy (Billy West), Garfield (Frank Welker), and Korra (Janet Varney) will be included in this new update. So now, it won't be so ominously quiet as SpongeBob and Korra duke it out in the arena.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BIuGYhVDAis
The other major addition in today's free update to Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl is items. The cartoon brawler launched without any pick-up-and-use items. Now, items like Sokka's boomerang, a Krabby Patty, and a Reptar toy will be optional drops.
Are you ready?
The lack of both voice-over work and items were big detractors from Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl, so it's good to see both finally being added. The update is rolling out now for PlayStation, Xbox, and PC. Nintendo Switch owners will get it "soon," according to GameMill.
Maybe with this addition, the brawls will have a little more life to them. Games like Super Smash Bros. might have developed prominent competitive scenes, but a lot of the charm in those platform fighters also comes from the characters themselves. Captain Falcon is visually recognizable, but so is his declaration of "FALCON PUNCH."
The good news is, if you're now eager to try Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl after its addition of voices, it's easy to do so. The cartoon brawler is one of this month's PlayStation Plus games, so subscribers can pretty easily hop on and try out the update for themselves.
The post Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl gets full character voice-over in free update today appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Van Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon GO's Revenue Smashes Past $6 Billion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132544</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/pokemon-gos-revenue-smashes-past-usd6-billion"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That's $1 billion a year.
Pokémon GO just can't stop catching success! According to data from Sensor Tower, the augmented reality app has surpassed $6 billion in lifetime player spending across the world. If you do the maths quick, the game launched back in 2016, which means Pokémon GO has continued to make $1 billion a year.
The Pokémon Company and Niantic's game now joins the likes of PUBG Mobile, Honor of Kings, Candy Crush Saga, and Clash of Clans, all of which have also surpassed this Mamoswine-sized figure.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Fighter's Ken Has Fallen On Hard Times (And Fans Are Laughing)]]></title>
        <id>1849024285</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/ken-masters-street-fighter-6-memes-divorce-eliza-shoryu-1849024285"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While many in the fighting game community were happy to finally see Street Fighter 6 in action during last week’s PlayStation State of Play, a very vocal majority of FGC connoisseurs who enjoy the games for their, err, riveting storylines have been absolutely reveling in the sorry state of former golden boy Ken…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Even The Morbius Memes Couldn’t Stop It From Flopping In Theaters (Again)]]></title>
        <id>1849024089</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/morbius-memes-jared-leto-movie-theaters-marvel-sony-bom-1849024089"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After weeks of Morbius memes dominating the internet, Sony had the strange idea to bring Jared Leto’s living vampire back to more than 1,000 theaters this past weekend. Maybe the PlayStation maker was hoping for Morbius to reveal itself as a The Room-style cult classic here, but the bloodsucking superhero flick bombed…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jeremy winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: Should Sonic Frontiers Be Delayed? We Discuss Its Bizarre Debut And Fan Reaction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132539</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-should-sonic-frontiers-be-delayed-we-discuss-its-bizarre-debut-and-fan-reaction"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic's latest 3D entry stumbles out the gate.
After what feels like a lifetime of waiting, we've finally been treated to a glimpse at what the gameplay for Sonic Frontiers will look like — two glimpses, in fact! Thanks to IGN's month-long coverage deal with SEGA, we now have a better idea of how exploration and combat will work in the game, with the two core aspects given their own spotlight in separate videos (scroll down for them).
The internet isn't short on opinions, and the backlash has been fierce, if not entirely unexpected. We've also got opinions; oh boy, do we have opinions!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python 3.11 Performance Benchmarks Are Looking Fantastic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=31183</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=31183"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month Python 3.11 Beta 1 was released as their first preview of this major update to the Python programming language. Besides new language features and other improvements, Python 3.11 performance is looking fantastic with very nice performance uplift over prior Python 3.x releases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open-Source AMDVLK Vulkan Driver Preparing Mesh Shader Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDVLK-Mesh-Shaders-WIP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDVLK-Mesh-Shaders-WIP"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T17:58:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to Mesa's Radeon "RADV" Vulkan driver prepared for mesh shading with an upcoming Vulkan mesh shader extension besides NVIDIA's NV_mesh_shader, it looks like AMD will be punctually supporting the cross-vendor mesh shader extension too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Diablo Immortal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?post_type=eg_reviews&amp;p=328291</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-diablo-immortal/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=review-diablo-immortal"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T17:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No, he's actually quite mortal
The last time we checked in with Diablo Immortal, things were going decent enough. Immortal shows pretty well on mobile, but with the pre-release review period ending, I shifted gears a bit into the PC edition to see how that one held up.
I wasn't ready for the dark underbelly of microtransactions, which reared up in the live version.

Diablo Immortal (Android, iOS, PC [reviewed])
Developer: Blizzard, NetEase
Publisher: Blizzard
Released: June 2, 2022
MSRP: Free-to-play (with microtransactions)
So we already talked about the core fundamentals in the review in progress: suffice to say everything still holds up. The game runs well on my iPhone 11, and the ability to swap between traditional pads and touch controls is a great compromise. In theory, the gameplay …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Carter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Lost Ruins' Brings Stunning Pixel Art And Survival Action To Switch Today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132519</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/lost-ruins-brings-stunning-pixel-art-and-survival-action-to-switch-today"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lost in pixels.
If there's one thing we love about the summer of video game announcements, it's a surprise. And DANGEN Entertainment has one pretty snazzy one for us today. Released on Steam last year, Altari Games' action survival game Lost Ruins is coming to the Switch... today! And it's an absolute stunner.
With anime-inspired pixel art and huge, beautiful-looking bosses, Lost Ruins is — according to the publisher — "so kawaii it hurts"! We'll have to play this to find out what that means, but if controlling a school girl in some dark, dangerous ruins tells us anything, it's that there's definitely something sinister lurking here.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model identifies self as the face of Resident Evil 4 Remake’s Ashley Graham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328274</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/resident-evil-4-remake-ashley-graham-ella-freya-capcom/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=resident-evil-4-remake-ashley-graham-ella-freya-capcom"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T17:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA['LEONNNNN!'
It was two long years ago that we first wrote about the rumor that Capcom had begun development on a remake of one of its most iconic and beloved releases, Resident Evil 4. On Thursday, we finally got the good word, as Sony's State of Play presentation gave us the first official unveiling of the survival horror classic's return. We got to see some new and familiar places, along with some familiar faces.
Very shortly after the teaser trailer's premiere, model Ella Freya took to social media to excitedly identify herself as the face model for spritely damsel-in-distress, Ashley Graham. Writing on her Twitter, the Dutch native spoke of her incredible pride and excitement in becoming part of the Resident Evil family, noting that she cried with shock and joy when the trailer finally…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cuddle Up To These Stubbins 'Monster Hunter' Plushies On Your Next Quest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132533</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/cuddle-up-to-these-stubbins-monster-hunter-plushies-on-your-next-quest"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Always take a friend along.
Being a dedicated Monster Hunter isn't always easy. Capcom's series is well known for its often brutal and unforgiving nature, pitting players against some of the most fearsome beasts video gaming has ever witnessed.
Fans of the franchise can take some comfort, then, in knowing that famed plush brand Stubbins has just released a range of officially-licenced Monster Hunter Rise products, and they're perfect for cuddling up to when a bold hunt has just gone south.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.20 + Mesa 22.2 To Allow Conformant Mali G57 OpenGL ES 3.1 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mali-G57-Conformant-GLES-3.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mali-G57-Conformant-GLES-3.1"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:52:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Panfrost Gallium3D patches landing today into Mesa 22.2 and Panfrost DRM kernel driver support slated to land for the Linux 5.20 cycle later this summer, the Mali G57 GPU has conformant OpenGL ES 3.1 support on this open-source driver and the first Mali GPU of the Valhall generation to have this achievement following the Panfrost driver's successes for the older Bifrost and Midgard architectures...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consent And Compassion: How Devs Are Reshaping The Conversation Around Content Warnings]]></title>
        <id>1849022977</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/content-warnings-consent-glitchhikers-psychonauts-2-tak-1849022977"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It should be no surprise to anyone that the very mention of “trigger/content warnings” is likely to spark politically driven, reactionary rejections that whine about “snowflakes” and spoiled experiences. Years of poisoning the well in this area have made the terms frustratingly charged. But if we move on from the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTuber posits that it takes over $100,000 to max out gear in Diablo Immortal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328303</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/diablo-immortal-microtransactions-explained-pay-to-win-issues/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=diablo-immortal-microtransactions-explained-pay-to-win-issues"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to sully hard developer work: part one
So we knew that Diablo Immortal would have microtransactions. The team has been kind of mum on them overall outside of general platitudes that they wouldn't impact the game that much: but several posts and YouTube channels are actually breaking this down the new monetization model scientifically, and things aren't looking good for Diablo Immortal max stat requirements.
That material includes a Reddit post by daymeeuhn that showcases how far the stat and gem rabbit hole goes, a full explanation of pay-to-win from Gregg2G, and a rundown from the Bellular News channel. Let's break this down. A lot of the onus on the cracks in this system falls on legendary gems.
Legendary gems can drastically increase your stats, to the point where they can outweigh …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Carter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rakudo 2022.06]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/rakudo-2022.06</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/rakudo-2022.06"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:18:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rakudo (Wikipedie), tj. překladač programovacího jazyka Raku (Wikipedie), byl vydán ve verzi 2022.06. Programovací jazyk Raku byl dříve znám pod názvem Perl 6.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Files New Company Copyrights For Illumination Mario Movie]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132540</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/nintendo-files-new-company-copyrights-for-illumination-mario-movie"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trailer incoming?
Just over a month ago, Illumination's upcoming untitled Super Mario movie was delayed from a 2022 holiday date to April 2023. But while we're still a ways off from being able to sit down and watch the films, in the background, Nintendo has been making preparations for the plumber's motion picture.
Earlier today, Twitter user @MichaelO2k shared some copyright records connected to the film which likely confirm the names of the studios that the Mario motion picture will be listed under — Nintendo Studios, LLC and M Brothers Productions, LLC.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xbox is hosting an extended games showcase on June 14]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328307</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/xbox-games-showcase-extended-june-news-trailers-interviews-stream/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xbox-games-showcase-extended-june-news-trailers-interviews-stream"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T16:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keep the showcase train rolling
Xbox is hosting not one, but two showcases over the next week or so. While the Xbox and Bethesda Showcase airs on June 12, an Xbox Games Showcase Extended will air on June 14.
This bonus showcase will feature some new trailers and deeper looks at the news from the preceding Games Showcase. Developers and game creators will appear on the stream too. It'll last about 90 minutes, airing at 10 a.m. PT / 1 p.m. ET on Twitch, YouTube, and other major streaming platforms.
The Xbox Games Showcase Extended will air in English, Latin America Spanish, Brazilian Portuguese, German, and French. Audio Descriptions and American Sign Language will also be available live.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pYqyVpCV-3c
The Xbox and Bethesda showcase is airing at 10 a.m. PT / 1 p.m. ET on June 12, and is expected to contain info about the lineup coming to both Xbox and PC, as well as some updates on Game Pass.
The show goes on
This extension now brings the end of the summer showcase streaming out from Sunday and into Tuesday. That said, for Xbox fans, it's a good sign they'll be seeing some more of the games talked about at the Xbox and Bethesda presser.
With both Starfield and Redfall slipping out to 2023, it'll be interesting to see what ends up populating the showcase Microsoft over these two days. Even if the games have moved forward, I'm hopeful there will be some news to share either way.
There are also some big titles we haven't heard from in a while, like the upcoming Fable and Senua's Saga: Hellblade II. And other studios at Microsoft have been quiet for a little while now too. Maybe we even hear some more about that Indiana Jones project?
We'll see what Xbox, Bethesda, and the many Xbox studios have in the works on both June 12 and June 14.
The post Xbox is hosting an extended games showcase on June 14 appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Van Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone Uses The Steam Deck To Play Games That Are Perfect For The Switch]]></title>
        <id>1849023047</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/valve-steam-deck-most-played-games-hades-stardew-valley-1849023047"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve’s Steam Deck promises all the same handheld freedom as the Nintendo Switch, but with vastly more powerful tech under the hood, capable of running the most lavishly produced AAA games. A few months in, according to a blog post from Valve, it turns out everyone’s just using the thing to play a bunch of those “this…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ripout is a co-op horror FPS that's a bit like a roguelike Doom 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ripout-is-a-co-op-horror-fps-thats-a-bit-like-a-roguelike-doom-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ripout-is-a-co-op-horror-fps-thats-a-bit-like-a-roguelike-doom-3"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past few weeks I've sampled so many retro-styled FPSes, I'd class it as a form of training. I'm now attuned to their look, their pacing, their good and bad points. So, it came as no surprise when I found myself testing out the closed alpha of yet another of their ilk: Ripout, an upcoming sci-fi horror FPS that's very Doom 3.
What's nice is that vidbud Liam joined me! Both because he's a fan of the FPS genre and to be present with a jar in hand, lest I crumbled into dust. Thankfully this didn't happen and we had a pretty swell time, I'd say. It's early days for the game but there's potential there.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This internal Nintendo safety video from Wario is a wild snapshot of 2004]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328285</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/this-internal-nintendo-safety-video-presented-by-wario-is-wild/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=this-internal-nintendo-safety-video-presented-by-wario-is-wild"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T15:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Take it easy Wario"
Internal safety videos, especially in the YouTube era, are a great source of comedy without even having to try too hard. That's why this Nintendo safety video rules so hard: it dials up that absurdity by adding Wario, master of chaos, into the mix.
For the most part, the 15 minute video isn't all that different from a run of the mill requirement you may have been forced to watch for employment at some point, but this one has random injerctions from Wario, which is clearly not voiced by Charles Martinet. Here's the rundown from Forest of Illusion, who uploaded the video to YouTube:
"We have preserved an internal Nintendo employee safety video disc from 2004! The video was intended for Nintendo Merchandising Inc representatives and features Wario, who mentions that he is his own supervisor at Nintendo, as he assists the narrator in walking new hires through the safety precautions one must take when working with Nintendo retail products within stores."

One of the best moments of the video is the near the start. Wario tells the soothing grandpa-voiced narrator to "shut up," and he just responds with "take it easy, Wario." No exclamation point needed: it's that soothing. Also that music is extremely Wii Sports adjacent!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5WNQfEUbByw
The post This internal Nintendo safety video from Wario is a wild snapshot of 2004 appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Carter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GOG's Summer Sale kicks off with Alien Isolation going DRM-free at 75% off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gogs-summer-sale-kicks-off-with-alien-isolation-going-drm-free-at-75-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gogs-summer-sale-kicks-off-with-alien-isolation-going-drm-free-at-75-off"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T15:24:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CD Projekt have thrown the doors open on the GOG Summer Sale today, and hiding in plain sight is Creative Assembly’s space survival horror Alien: Isolation. The scary stealth ‘em up is the first of a series of games published by Sega that are going DRM-free on GOG. Two Point Hospital and Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine – Anniversary Edition will be joining the store at an unspecified date too. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hidekazu Yukawa, Former Managing Director Of Sega, Has Passed Away]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132532</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/hidekazu-yukawa-former-managing-director-of-sega-has-passed-away"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The face of the Dreamcast in Japan.
Hidekazu Yukawa, former managing director of SEGA at the time of the Dreamcast's release and dubbed by fans as 'Mr. Sega', has passed away, it has been revealed.
Famitsu shared the news that Yukawa, 78, passed due to complications from pneumonia last June. His family chose to keep this news private until today.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sega says don’t hold your breath for a Saturn or Dreamcast Mini]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328269</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/sega-saturn-mini-dreamcast-mini-mega-drive-mini-2-famitsu-interview-retro/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sega-saturn-mini-dreamcast-mini-mega-drive-mini-2-famitsu-interview-retro"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T15:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Economy crash puts paid to retro hardware rereleases
At the weekend, Sega Japan announced that it was releasing a new piece of portable hardware in the form of the Sega Mega Drive Mini II, a pint-sized edition of the 1993 console that will come pre-loaded with 50 Sega Mega Drive and Mega CD classics. Given that the Mega Drive Mini already exists, some fans might be puzzled as to why Sega has not instead focused on releasing a scaled-down model of its 1994 console, Sega Saturn, or its 1998 big brother, the Sega Dreamcast.
Speaking with Famitsu, Sega hardware producer Yosuke Okunari offered up the unfortunate news that a Sega Saturn Mini or a Sega Dreamcast Mini are both very unlikely to ever see the light of day. Okunari understands that the audience is there for such consoles, but states that a combination of expensive components, further hampered by the COVID-19 pandemic's effect on manufacturing costs, has simply made the project uneconomical from both a production and finance perspective.
Okunari also suggested that the components used by Sega's Mini consoles are not quite up-to-spec in regards to running Sega Saturn titles — a console that is notoriously difficult to authentically emulate. Okunari jokes that the process of producing a Sega Saturn Mini in 2022 might see it launch with a price rivaling that of modern-day consoles. So it seems, for now at the very least, the Mega CD is as far as we are going in regards to the Sega Mini range.
The Sega Mega Drive Mini 2 launches in Japan October 27, priced at ¥9,980 (roughly $75 USD). Sega is yet to confirm whether this edition will also be released in the west. For more details on the console, check out @gosokkyu's Twitter thread translating/paraphrasing the Famitsu interview.
Sega producer says high costs are preventing a Dreamcast or Saturn mini [VGC]
The post Sega says don’t hold your breath for a Saturn or Dreamcast Mini appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python 3.11 beta 1 ukazuje podstatné zrychlení]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43711</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/python-3-11-beta-1-ukazuje-podstatne-zrychleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T14:42:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server Phoronix dnes otestoval výkon Pythonu 3.11 Beta 1, který vyšel minulý měsíc. Python 3.11 by již měl zahrnovat zrychlení z projektu „Faster CPython Project“. Podle oficiálního testu pyperformance je 3.11 o 25 % rychlejší než 3.10. Ale podle druhu zátěže lze očekávat zrychlení v rozmezí 10–60 %.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geoff Keighley Urges Fans To 'Manage Expectations' For Summer Game Fest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132525</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/geoff-keighley-urges-fans-to-manage-expectations-for-summer-game-fest"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show will focus on already-announced games.
Geoff Keighley has urged fans to "manage your expectations" ahead of the Summer Game Fest live stream this week, stressing that the show will primarily focus on games that have already been announced.
In a Twitter Spaces session transcribed by VGC, Geoff Keighley - who is normally exceptionally bullish when it comes to building hype - stated that it's a "really exciting week" for him as he will "finally see things we’ve been talking about to people for months". Specific games mentioned by Geoff include the recently announced Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2, The Callisto Protocol, and Cuphead: The Delicious Last Course.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Voice Chat Is Often A Sexist Nightmare (But It Doesn't Have To Be)]]></title>
        <id>1849016726</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/discord-voice-chat-anxiety-harassment-girl-gamers-1849016726"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your voice is revealing—it can give up a constellation of personal details, including your age, where you’re from, and how you’re feeling. This isn’t always an issue and can even be a benefit. Your voice can let you bond with a stranger from your hometown, your friend’s voice fills you with relief when you hear it on…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Bardhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Pi 800: počítač v klávesnici a alternativa k Raspberry Pi 400]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43710</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/orange-pi-800-pocitac-v-klavesnici-a-alternativa-k-raspberry-pi-400/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:50:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alternativa k počítači v klávesnici Raspberry Pi 400 od čínského výrobce Orange Pi se jmenuje Orange Pi 800. Je postavena na CPU Rockchip RK3399 (šest jader, 2× Cortex-A72 1,8 GHz a 4× Cortex-A53 1,4 GHz) a obsahuje 4 GB RAM, 64 GB eMMC a microSD kartu, HDMI výstup s rozlišením 4k a VGA výstup s rozlišením FullHD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Strikers: Battle League's File Size Seemingly Revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132524</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/mario-strikers-battle-leagues-file-size-seemingly-revealed"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Less than football-sized.
Next Level Games' Mario Strikers: Battle League launches this Friday, and fans got their first hands-on with the game's online play over the weekend. But just how big are the numbers for the upcoming outlandish soccer game?
Well, it seems like you won't need to make a ton of room for the game's initial kick-off, as Mario Strikers will take up 1.8GB of your Switch's storage. That's... not much! Not far off of Mario Tennis Aces' 2GB at launch, but a little off of Mario Golf: Super Rush's initial 4.2GB size.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom acknowledges Street Fighter 6 fans saw ‘things they weren’t supposed to see’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328264</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/street-fighter-6-leak-capcom-acknowledges-characters-costumes-rumor/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=street-fighter-6-leak-capcom-acknowledges-characters-costumes-rumor"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But is pleased with the hugely positive response
It's been an incredibly exciting weekend for Street Fighter fans, not only did we receive our first look at the colorful gameplay of upcoming release Street Fighter 6, but this official reveal was swiftly followed by a very unofficial leak, revealing what appeared to be 22 pieces of character art, with further in-game clips later surfacing on various social media platforms.
Several hours after the exciting images had been circulating on the information superhighway, publisher Capcom took to Twitter to address the leak, hinting toward it in non-too-subtle fashion. The general consensus seemed to read that Capcom was understandably frustrated about the leak, but was very pleased that the new characters, costumes, and official gameplay video ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recap: Today’s Fortnite Collision event got extremely anime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328245</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/recap-todays-fortnite-collision-event-got-extremely-anime/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=recap-todays-fortnite-collision-event-got-extremely-anime"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choose your favorite mecha/sentai homage
It's time for a Fortnite Collision recap. The event played out similar to many other prior "end of season" activities, but this time it involved a giant mech. So it's one of the coolest ones by default.
This particular one ushered in the end of Chapter 3 Season 2: with another confrontation between the IO faction (the bad guys) and The Seven (the people the players are collaborating with currently), over the Zero Point (basically the equivalent of Kingdom Hearts in Kingdom Hearts): with the intent of taking down The Collider (a structure that's basically a comic-book-esque Doomsday Machine).

Collision kicked off around 4:10PM ET today
After joining the Collision playlist (and fending off a modest queue time of around three minutes) I zoned in 20 mi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Carter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pozdní nahrávání mikrokódu pro x86 je pokládáno za loterii]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43709</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/pozdni-nahravani-mikrokodu-pro-x86-je-pokladano-za-loterii/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:20:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do jádra 5.19 se dostala záplata od Thomase Gleixnera a Borislava Petkova, která ve výchozím stavu vypíná pozdní nahrávání mikrokódu, protože to v některých případech nefunguje a jedná se tedy o loterii. Tato konfigurace MICROCODE_OLD_INTERFACE (deprecated) je přejmenována na MICROCODE_LATE_LOADING (dangerous). Pozdní aktualizace mikrokódu používala /dev/cpu/microcode a nástroje iucode_tool nebo microcode.ctl. Nově bude při použití pozdní aktualizace jádro také označeno (tainted).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Videozáznam přednášek ze semináře IPv6: deset let poté]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/videozaznam-prednasek-ze-seminare-ipv6-deset-let-pote</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/videozaznam-prednasek-ze-seminare-ipv6-deset-let-pote"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:06:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes na ČVUT v Praze a také online proběhl seminář IPv6: deset let poté. Videozáznam přednášek je k dispozici na YouTube.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo will not be in attendance for Gamescom 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328278</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/nintendo-gamescom-2022-no-show-not-in-attendance-e3/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=nintendo-gamescom-2022-no-show-not-in-attendance-e3"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Publisher to appear at 'regional events'
With Friday's Sony State of Play presentation, the summer gaming news season is officially underway. But before we have even gotten close to the season's Gamescom 2022 showcase, developer/publisher Nintendo has already announced that it will not be in attendance for the August event.
In a statement to German news outlet Games Wirtschaft, (later republished by VGC), Nintendo Europe noted that it will not be joining the other industry figureheads gathering in Cologne, and will instead be low-key showcasing its various wares at several smaller, regional trade shows in and around Germany.
"Gamescom is a key event in Nintendo’s calendar of events," writes Nintendo. "This year, however, after careful consideration, we have decided against participating in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Screenshot Saturday Mondays: ultraviolence, shoving, and shrooms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/screenshot-saturday-mondays-ultraviolence-shoving-and-shrooms</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/screenshot-saturday-mondays-ultraviolence-shoving-and-shrooms"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every weekend, indie devs show off current work on Twitter's #screenshotsaturday tag. And every Monday, I bring you a selection of these snaps and clips. This week, my eye has been caught by several high-speed first-person shooters, some good wizarding, and a cute mushroom friend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mini Review: Behind The Frame: The Finest Scenery - A Short Tale With Lovely Ghibli-Esque Art]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132342</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/behind-the-frame-the-finest-scenery"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An art game we can get behind.
Behind the Frame: The Finest Scenery is the first game from Taiwanese developer Silver Lining Studio. Released on Steam and mobile last year, it has collected its fair share of rewards and strong user reviews. With its launch on console this month, it gains an additional epilogue to play through, offering a new slant on the original story.
Smoothly combining animated interludes, 2D interactive scenes, and 360-degree viewing of 3D spaces, the rich, hand-drawn art describes a European town and the apartment-cum-studio of a young artist finishing off the final piece of a gallery submission. The original music and songs complete the mood upon pressing play on an old cassette player.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: You'll Love Strolling In The Rain With These Super Mario Umbrellas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132518</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/random-youll-love-strolling-in-the-rain-with-these-super-mario-umbrellas"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These sure aren't dire dire.
Rain can be pretty dispiriting, right? Granted, epic downpours are often quite exciting, particularly if you happen to be inside all warm and cosy, but if you live in certain parts of the world (shout out to our temperate climate homies), the incessant drizzle of rain during the spring and fall months can be depressing, to say the least.
It doesn't have to be, though! If you happen to be based in Japan or are okay with importing products, WPC Store is now stocking some awesome Super Mario themed umbrellas in partnership with Nintendo. There are four designs to choose from, including the classic underwater level from Super Mario Bros., a block border design, a logo design, and a design featuring various character and object sprites.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4's Werewolves transformation is set for June 16th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-werewolves-transformation-is-set-for-june-16th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-werewolves-transformation-is-set-for-june-16th"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T12:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pop your collar because EA and Maxis have confirmed that the next expansion for The Sims 4 is growing a bit hairy thanks to the return of werewolves on June 16th. The Sims 4: Werewolves is the 12th game pack released for the ever-growing life sim so far, and will add the new world of Moonwood Mill, which is simply heaving with the canine monstrosities. Howl at the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[30 Years On, The Fan-Made 'Final Fight Ultimate' Is Set To Reignite The 16-bit Console War]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132516</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/30-years-on-the-fan-made-final-fight-ultimate-is-set-to-reignite-the-16-bit-console-war"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Punching up.
Final Fight is one of the definitive games of the side-scrolling beat 'em up genre, no doubt about it. Released in arcades in 1989, the game was ported to the SNES the following year, with multiple things missing such as Level 4, an entire character, and no two-player mode. Despite being something of a flawed conversion, the fact that Nintendo had one of the hottest arcade titles as a home console exclusive was a real coup at the time.
That's not the only port the game got, of course, but for envious Genesis / Mega Drive owners, Streets of Rage had to substitute, and many Sega fans missed out entirely on Final Fight unless they had a Mega / Sega CD, which got its own port a short time later that had much of what was missing from the SNES version.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardwarově akcelerované virtuální počítače na jailbreaknutém iPhonu 12 s iOS 14.1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/hardwarove-akcelerovane-virtualni-pocitace-na-jailbreaknutem-iphonu-12-s-ios-14.1</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/hardwarove-akcelerovane-virtualni-pocitace-na-jailbreaknutem-iphonu-12-s-ios-14.1"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T11:33:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhuowei Zhang popsal, jak rozchodil hardwarově akcelerované virtuální počítače na jailbreaknutém iPhonu 12 s iOS 14.1. Ve videu na YouTube ukazuje Fedora Linux 36 v modifikovaném UTM, tj portu QEMU na iOS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Escape From Tarkov Arena is a new standalone gladiatorial FPS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/escape-from-tarkov-arena-is-a-new-standalone-gladiatorial-fps</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/escape-from-tarkov-arena-is-a-new-standalone-gladiatorial-fps"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T11:17:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiplayer FPS Escape From Tarkov is getting a dedicated PvP spin-off in the form of Escape From Tarkov Arena, developers Battlestate Games have announced on Twitter. Battlestate say Arena will be a “standalone” game, so you won't need to own the original Tarkov in order to play it, but clarified that anyone who owns Escape From Tarkov’s ‘Edge of Darkess’ pack will have free access to it as DLC. Watch the teaser trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Ruby & Rusty - Save The Crows' Is The Latest Game Boy Title From Bitmap Soft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132513</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/ruby-and-rusty-save-the-crows-is-the-latest-game-boy-title-from-bitmap-soft"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-orders available now.
Bitmap Soft is continuing its noble crusade in producing brand new physical titles for the Game Boy, and its latest entry is a rather charming side-scrolling platformer from developer Max Oakland.
Ruby & Rusty - Save the Crows is available to pre-order from Bitmap Soft right now, with the company pledging to fulfil orders within six weeks. It will come complete with a full colour manual, but if you're one of the first 100 customers to pre-order, you'll also bag an original soundtrack on CD and a sticker sheet.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First 4 Figures Opens Pre-Orders For Zelda: Breath Of The Wild Mipha Statue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-131632</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/first-4-figures-opens-pre-orders-for-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-mipha-statue"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Early bird pricing ends tomorrow.
Update: If you're interested in picking up the Zelda: Breath of the Wild Mipha statue from First 4 Figures, you'll probably want to get your order in within the next few hours. The discounted early bird pricing shown below ends tomorrow, 7th June, at 9am BST (that's 1am PDT / 4am EDT).

Original Article (Wed 18th May, 2022 17:00 BST): First 4 Figures has unveiled its latest collectable statue, this time giving The Legend of Zelda fans yet another opportunity to liven up their shelves at home.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.19 Features: AMD SEV-SNP + Zen 4 Prep, Intel TDX + IFS, LoongArch, Big TCP, Apple M1 NVMe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=31179</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=31179"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T10:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the Linux 5.19 merge window complete, here is my usual look at all of the interesting changes I've been watching for this next version of the Linux kernel. Linux 5.19 is quite a big summer time upgrade to this open-source kernel with many new and improved features coming for this kernel that will debut as stable in late July.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Mario Odyssey's VFX Artist On Combining Mario With The 'Real' World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132511</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/super-mario-odysseys-vfx-artist-on-combining-mario-with-the-real-world"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Ideas were taken from both themes and blended together".
When Super Mario Odyssey was first announced, the very first thing we saw was a realistic-looking city. It could've been New York with its yellow taxi cabs and bright billboards littered all across the skyline. People with actual, believable human proportions were walking around this city. Then, our favourite Italian plumber leaps out of a manhole cover, and we knew we were in for something special.
Super Mario Odyssey is a game where Mario is thrown into a plethora of different worlds, from a prehistoric island, a crimson sand desert, a kingdom made entirely of colourful foods and even the moon. We're being selective here, but the point we're making is that Super Mario Odyssey's worlds are creative, bizarre, and combine multiple different art styles seamlessly.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: The Powkiddy X51 Emulation Console Tries To Rope In Switch Fans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132509</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/random-the-powkiddy-x51-emulation-console-tries-to-rope-in-switch-fans"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T09:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It looks like a Switch, but...
Powkiddy, a company known for producing retro gaming consoles, has introduced its latest effort: the Powkiddy X51. It looks pretty familiar, right?
Yes, in designing the X51, Powkiddy has unashamedly tried to emulate (chortle!) the look and feel of a Nintendo Switch, right down to the neon red and blue casing. As expected, however, the console doesn't offer any of the Switch's functionality; yes, you can play the system on a TV ("big screen, more happy") or via a 'table top mode', but additional controllers are mandatory if you wish to do so.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.19 Frowns On x86/x86_64 Late Microcode Loading - "It's Just Lottery & Broken"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-Late-ucode-Loading</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-Late-ucode-Loading"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T09:28:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A last minute change sent in on Sunday and merged prior to Linux 5.19-rc1 disables late microcode loading by default for x86/x86_64 processors over its sad state of affairs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Old GLSL Code Is Gutted From Mesa 22.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-GLSL-Unrolling-Delete</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-GLSL-Unrolling-Delete"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T09:18:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's not only the Linux kernel that's been seeing some spring cleaning but Mesa developers have also been quite busy on working to remove some old, poorly maintained code from their open-source 3D driver components...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Wario Is Your Unlikely Safety Advisor In This Nintendo Employee Video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132508</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/random-wario-is-your-unlikely-safety-advisor-in-this-nintendo-employee-video"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Waaaah stay safe!
We've been thinking about this a lot, but we're not sure there are many Nintendo characters we'd trust our lives, or even basic safety, with. Look at Mario jumping around over huge gaps and wielding fire without protective gear. Luigi isn't much better! Kirby eats everything and we're not sure that's a good idea. And The kind of racing Captain Falcon does? We'll never get in a car again after driving with him.
So who did Nintendo of America choose to use in an internal safety video? Ah yes, the incredibly sensible, resourceful, selfless Wario.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Mint převezme vývoj zálohovacího software Timeshift]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43708</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-mint-prevezme-vyvoj-zalohovaciho-software-timeshift/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T08:02:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zálohovací software Timeshift je podobný jako Time Machine pro macOS nebo System Restore ve Windows. Používá buď rsync a hardlinky, nebo BTRFS snapshoty. Od běžných zálohovacích programů se liší v tom, že zálohuje jen operační systém a ne soubory uživatelů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Where To Pre-Order Mario Strikers: Battle League On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-127212</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/where-to-pre-order-mario-strikers-battle-league-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Best deals, cheapest prices and pre-order bonuses detailed.
First announced in the February Nintendo Direct, Mario Strikers: Battle League (or Mario Strikers: Battle League Football as it's known in Europe) will bring the much-loved Mario Strikers series to Switch for the first time.
It's launching on 10th June 2022 and will support up to eight players – four players on each team – on a single Switch console. As well as single-player content and the ability to customise your team, online play will have an intriguing Strikers Club mode that lets 20 players join up and compete to become the world’s top club.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Court Orders For All US ISPs to Block Pirate Sites Have Been Suspended]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219436</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/court-orders-for-all-us-isps-to-block-pirate-sites-have-been-suspended-220606/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T07:11:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month we broke some rather unusual news. Successful judgments against three pirate streaming sites required every ISP in the United States to implement blocking measures, so that no subscriber could access them. However, after winning the Holy Grail of anti-piracy measures, the plaintiffs have now asked the court to suspend enforcement against ISPs.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vytvořte si bezpečnou VPN pomocí OpenVPN (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41285</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vytvorte-si-bezpecnou-vpn-pomoci-openvpn-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T07:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VPN umožňuje bezpečně propojit různá zařízení pomocí šifrovaných tunelů. Umožňuje také zapojit uživatele do vnitřní sítě přes zabezpečený přístupový bod. Na našem školení VPN a bezpečné připojení k síti s OpenVPN si prakticky ukážeme, jak to celé nastavit a zprovoznit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RIP Fantasy Artist Ken Kelly, 1946-2022]]></title>
        <id>1849021772</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/ken-kelly-art-kiss-rainbow-manowar-star-wars-conan-fant-1849021772"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T01:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ken Kelly, one of the most talented fantasy artists of the past 50 years, has passed away at the age of 76.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phoronix Turns 18 Years Old For Covering Linux Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Phoronix-18</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Phoronix-18"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was eighteen years ago today that I started Phoronix.com to focus on Linux hardware reviews. Back then it was difficult getting peripherals working under Linux from 56k modems to printers and other components today where Linux support can just be assumed. Open-source graphics drivers back then were also in their infancy and lacking vendor support while NVIDIA was well regarded then for their proprietary driver being at least featureful and performant. It's been quite a journey...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.19-rc1 Released With Intel TDX, AMD SEV-SNP, LoongArch, Big TCP & A Lot More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-rc1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-rc1"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T00:47:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following a rather eventful Linux 5.19 merge window the past two weeks, Linus Torvalds just released Linux 5.19-rc1. It's a great way coincidentally to mark the end of the Phoronix 18th birthday...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Souhrn dění v Linux Mintu za květen 2022]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/souhrn-deni-v-linux-mintu-za-kveten-2022</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/souhrn-deni-v-linux-mintu-za-kveten-2022"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T00:15:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clement "Clem" Lefebvre publikoval souhrn dění v Linux Mintu za květen 2022. Vývojáři Linux Mintu forkli utilitu Timeshift (GitHub). Její tvůrce Tony George se soustředí na jiné projekty. Utilita Blueberry pro práci s Bluetooth není kompatibilní s GNOME 42 a bude v Linux Mintu 21 nahrazena utilitou Blueman. V dubnu přispělo na vývoj Linux Mintu 327 dárců celkovou částkou 7 064 dolarů. Dalších 629 patronů přispívá na Patreonu celkovou částkou 2 838 dolarů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jaderné noviny – přehled za květen 2022]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-kveten-2022</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-kveten-2022"/>
        <updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Přehled květnových vydání Jaderných novin: stav vydání jádra, citáty týdne a seznam článků týkajících se jádra.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gotham Knights Game Distances Itself From Gotham Knights TV Show]]></title>
        <id>1849021683</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/gotham-knights-video-game-tv-series-cw-confusion-tweet-1849021683"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T23:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a video game coming out called Gotham Knights. It’s about some kids from the Batman universe who band together after Batman is killed. There’s also a TV show coming out called Gotham Knights. It’s about some kids from the Batman universe who band together after Batman is killed. They have nothing in common.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince Of Persia Remake Somehow In Even More Trouble]]></title>
        <id>1849021624</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/prince-persia-sands-time-remake-ubisoft-delayed-deliste-1849021624"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T23:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might remember that classic time-shifting platformer Prince of Persia: The Sands Of Time is getting a fancy remake. Announced in 2020, it was originally due out in January 2021. Then it was delayed. And delayed again, as the project moved studios. Now it has been delayed once more, only this time it has been…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 10 Most Pirated Movies of The Week – 06/06/2022]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=186926</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/top-10-most-torrented-pirated-movies/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T22:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every week we take a close look at the most pirated movies on torrent sites. What are pirates downloading? 'Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore' tops the chart, followed by ‘Morbius'. 'Top Gun: Maverick' completes the top three.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: počítač infikovaný náhledem souboru či e-mailu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16078</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-pocitac-infikovany-nahledem-souboru-ci-e-mailu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes se dozvíte, jak infikovat počítač pouhým náhledem souboru nebo otevřením e-mailu, jak otevřít auto bez klíčků a také o úspěšném boji proti malware, který terorizoval mobilní zařízení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CESNET CERTS)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unikla databáze uživatelů Linuxfx, Ubuntu vymění textový editor]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16077</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/unikla-databaze-uzivatelu-linuxfx-ubuntu-vymeni-textovy-editor/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unikla databáze s daty více než 20 tisíc uživatelů distribuce Linuxfx. Textový editor Gedit bude v Ubuntu 22.10 nahrazen GNOME Text Editorem. NixOS má nově grafický instalátor systému.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What games do you want to see announced during the summer streams?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=324712</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/most-anticipated-games-what-do-you-want-to-see-announced-during-summer-streams-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=most-anticipated-games-what-do-you-want-to-see-announced-during-summer-streams-2022"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T21:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Destructoid names its most anticipated games of the summer 2022 news blitz
E3 was always a special event for gamers, not just because we got a whole slew of exciting new trailers, footage, and announcements for the best upcoming games, but because it was a way for us to all come together and celebrate the games that mean the most to us. While E3 may be dead for this year at least, its spirit lives on in the form of Summer Games Fest and all of the other events that are lined up in the coming months. As for us, we're back with another list of our most anticipated games, 2022 edition.
What was once a three-day event has now been stretched over nearly a dozen streams over the course of a few weeks, which means there's a whole lot of news to look forward to. Here's hoping that the streams won'…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noelle Warner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dungeons, dragons, and summer gaming tarot predictions #2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=327754</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/dungeons-dragons-summer-gaming-showcase-tarot-predictions-part-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dungeons-dragons-summer-gaming-showcase-tarot-predictions-part-2"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T19:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neutral Gud
In today's community tarot readings for summer streams, I'm going to make sure I get some PlayStation predictions out the door before the Sony presentation. If you missed the prior tarot predictions article, click here.
Let's get right to it!

Cathedral asks: Has Half-Life 3 been confirmed?
Card drawn: Queen of Strength
The Queen of Strength has many great qualities. She speaks and leads with poise. She slays. She nails it. She gets things done.
Sadly, she is not married to The Gaben and if she was she'd demand Portal 3. And ask to give Steam Decks more discreet packaging to prevent porch piracy.
It would be a triumph.

YT asks: Will we ever hear anything about Silksong ever again? Ever?
Cards drawn: The Magician, The Fool, The Empress
Oh, thank Lolth, I don't have look in the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Whispering Willow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoldenEye 007's Return Could Be Close]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-132477</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/06/goldeneye-007s-return-could-be-close"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Achievements spotted on Xbox's website.
Rare's 1997 Nintendo 64 release GoldenEye 007 is arguably one of the greatest video games of all time. The Xbox 360 version, which never saw the light of day due to licensing complications, was leaked last year, and since then, there have been ongoing rumours about this classic first-person shooter returning in some way or form.
Now, ahead of next week's Xbox and Bethesda Games Showcase, achievements for the title have appeared on the official Xbox website. As described by our sister website Pure Xbox:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardware Timestamping Engine Subsystem Merged For Linux 5.19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-HTE</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-HTE"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T17:34:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While just a day prior Linus Torvalds was questioning the proposed "HTE" subsystem, today on this final day of the Linux 5.19 merge window he decided to land this new subsystem...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Sues Leaseweb for Hosting ‘Copyright Infringing’ Sites]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219308</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/photographer-sues-leaseweb-for-hosting-copyright-infringing-sites-220605/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T17:32:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hosting provider LeaseWeb is being sued for copyright infringement at a federal court in California. The lawsuit was filed by photographer Barry Rosen who argues that Leaseweb failed to take action against "infringing" poster sites, despite receiving repeated DMCA notices. The owners of the infringing sites are unknown and listed as Doe defendants.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am charmed by the uncertain future of video games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328041</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/charmed-by-uncertain-future-of-video-games/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=charmed-by-uncertain-future-of-video-games"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T17:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Games are in a constant state of flux, and I love it
The video game industry changes a lot, and it's always looking forward. It's that time of year again when we're excited to see all the new trailers, and we're thinking about the future not in terms of days, weeks, or even months, but years. With every new title that releases, we're looking forward to seeing how the graphics, gameplay, story, art, and music are going to push games even further, showing us something that the medium has never done before. The constant clamor for new consoles has become even more prominent with the scarcity of new hardware from the ninth generation.
There's a constant force driving us forward, and while that's exciting, the sentimental side of me wants to slow down and smell the roses a little bit. I get whi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noelle Warner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dungeons, dragons, and summer gaming tarot predictions #1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=324756</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/dungeons-dragons-summer-gaming-live-stream-tarot-predictions-part-1/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dungeons-dragons-summer-gaming-live-stream-tarot-predictions-part-1"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T11:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glorious Chaos!
Well, there's no E3 this year. Again. But there are summer live streams where E3 news would go! As such, the tradition of E3 predictions lives on. In the past, one might have asked zoo animals to divine gaming predictions for the Destructoid community but I'm a night person and hate sunlight, so I use tarot cards instead.
This year I will be using the brand new Dungeons & Dragons Tarot Deck. As a small review, the deck is both beautiful and deeply flawed. The art is done by Fred Gissubel and reminds me a great deal of the tarot drawn for Dragon Age but never had a deck realized. For the gorgeous, evocative imagery alone, the deck is worth collecting.
It seems it was more geared toward DM scenario planning or tossing in a random event than a good tool for traditional divinat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Whispering Willow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Popular USB DWC3 Linux Driver Likely To "Never Be Finished" With Continued Adaptations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=USB-Thunderbolt-Linux-5.19</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=USB-Thunderbolt-Linux-5.19"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman on Friday sent in the USB/Thunderbolt updates for the Linux 5.19 kernel that is seeing its merge window end today. With the USB updates, Greg had some remarks on the DWC3 Linux driver that will likely "never be finished" given that this USB IP is appearing in lots of hardware but not consistently being implemented and thus continuing to require a lot of adaptations on the driver side...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Please help with testing the upcoming ScummVM 2.6.0 release!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.scummvm.org/news/archive/#2022-06-05</id>
        <link href="https://www.scummvm.org/news/20220605/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T09:55:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few months have passed since we released ScummVM 2.5.1.
No matter if you expect the scorching heat of the upcoming summer or freezing blizzards in winter (depending on your favorite hemisphere): it’s release time again!
Our lovely developers added support, yet again, for a bunch of new ancient games that require testing:
Sanitarium
Hades Challenge
Marvel Comics Spider-Man: The Sinister Six
The 11th Hour
Clandestiny
Tender Loving Care (CD-ROM Editions)
Uncle Henry's Playhouse
Wetlands
Chewy: Esc from F5
Besides these games, we’d appreciate it if you could check our release testing list - maybe you’ll even find your favorite game on there that has been sitting on that shelf for way too long.
And since ScummVM is about playing games in general, we’ve seen quite a bunch of changes across many, many engines - so this is the perfect time for giving your favorites another go.
The AGOS, SCI and SCUMM engine received some really extensive modifications which make all games using those engines very good testing targets as well.
All testing must be done with stable builds, not development ones. Please report any bugs or oddities on our issue tracker.
A detailed list of all exciting new features and fixes is available in our NEWS file.
Thank you very much for your support!
>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nospam@scummvm.org (The ScummVM Team)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Ships Big Update To Their CBL-Mariner 2.0 Linux Distribution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CBL-Mariner-2.0.20220527</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CBL-Mariner-2.0.20220527"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T09:19:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month Microsoft published their first production release of CBL-Mariner 2.0 as an updated version of their in-house Linux distribution used for a variety of purposes from Windows Subsystem for Linux to Azure. This week Microsoft released a rather hefty stable update to their CBL-Mariner 2.0 distribution...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whatcha been playing this week, Destructoid?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=324511</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/whatcha-been-playing-this-week-destructoid-201/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=whatcha-been-playing-this-week-destructoid-201"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T09:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Jubilee (pictured)
Morning, friends, and welcome to the first Whatcha Been Playing of June! Let me kick things off by thanking all y'all for checking into last week's 200th entry and giving us the meatiest comment section WBP has had in some time. It was awesome to see so much of the community showing out in force, as y'all do week after week. Long may it continue, long may we all continue.
As I continue to arrange the furniture (ie. Kotobukiya models) in my new homestead, I hope that your week and weekend have been/will be wicked ones. As we approach the summer months, here's hoping for some lovely weather and some great outdoor action. Go on an adventure with friends, like Stand By Me... Except without the corpse... or Keifer Sutherland flashing a switchblade... or nearly being kil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple eFuse Driver, Intel Habana Labs Driver Improvements Lead char/misc In Linux 5.19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-char-misc</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-char-misc"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T08:55:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman on Friday submitted the "char/misc" changes for the Linux 5.19 kernel. Char/misc continues to be the "catch all" area of the kernel for drivers and code not fitting formally within other kernel subsystems. Leading on this front for Linux 5.19 is the introduction of the Apple eFuse driver for M1 systems and Intel-owned Habana Labs continues improving their AI accelerator driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FEX-Emu 2206 Released For Enjoying x86/x86_64 Apps & Games On Arm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FEX-Emu-2206</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FEX-Emu-2206"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T04:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FEX-Emu 2206 has been released as the newest version of this user-space, open-source software for being able to run x86/x86_64 applications and games on AArch64 (Arm) hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asahi Linux Celebrates First Triangle On The Apple M1 With Fully Open-Source Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Asahi-Linux-First-Triangle</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Asahi-Linux-First-Triangle"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While there has been progress with the Mesa code targeting Apple M1 to run basic tests like glmark2, that has traditionally been an effort running under macOS with its kernel driver. This week the Asahi Linux crew celebrated their first rendered triangle running with a fully open-source driver stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Pi 800, počítač v klávesnici]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/orange-pi-800-pocitac-v-klavesnici</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/orange-pi-800-pocitac-v-klavesnici"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T02:07:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Pi 800 je počítač s Rockchip RK3399 SoC v klávesnici. Jedná se o alternativu k Raspberry Pi 400 [CNX Software].]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tails 5.1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/tails-5.1</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/tails-5.1"/>
        <updated>2022-06-05T01:42:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuce Tails specializující se ochranu online soukromí uživatele byla vydána ve verzi 5.1. Jde o první větší aktualizaci od vydání 5.0 založeného na Debianu 11 „Bullseye“, takže vedle pravidelných oprav webového prohlížeče Tor Browser (11.0.14) nebo e-mailového klienta Thunderbird (91.9), také ladí integraci nástrojů jako Kleopatra, průvodce připojením k Toru atd.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Dodavatelé alternativních cloudů na svou šanci teprve čekají]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-dodavatele-alternativnich-cloudu-na-svou-sanci-teprve-cekaji</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-dodavatele-alternativnich-cloudu-na-svou-sanci-teprve-cekaji"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vědci přišli na levnou výrobu nejlepšího grafenu. Umělá inteligence od Konica Minolta dokáže sledovat spokojenost zákazníků. Proč 85 % organizací do roku 2025 nasadí kontejnery? Poptávka po odbornících na kyberbezpečnost strmě roste, stejně tak i jejich platy. Dodavatelé alternativních cloudů na svou šanci teprve čekají.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telefony Murena s /e/OS jsou v prodeji, Firefox 103 možná s akcelerací videa přes VA-API]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16079</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/telefony-murena-s-e-os-jsou-v-prodeji-firefox-103-mozna-s-akceleraci-videa-pres-va-api/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Otevřený dopis za otevření kódu Intel Firmware Support Package (FSP), Wine 7.10 opravuje 17 let starou chybu-nechybu, KDE Plasma 5.25 stále ještě nehotová, Vivaldi 5.3 na bázi Chromia 102.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What will be your big summer gaming timesink?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=324544</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/cblog-recaps-summer-2022-gaming-timesink/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=cblog-recaps-summer-2022-gaming-timesink"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T21:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cblogs of 5/28 to 6/3/2022

-Black Red Gaming shares a list of their top 5 most anticipated game releases in June.
-RoomWithaMoose reviews Ghostwire: Tokyo.
-BRAV0 F1VE reviews Elden Ring.
-Necrowondo wants to talk about Fortnite seriously for a moment.
-Kerrik52 continues their Legacy of Kain retrospective through another look at Blood Omen.
-Sleeves really thinks you should give Lethal League Blaze a try.
-Eggs&Brewsterjr updates us on eight games they played recently.
-jobjoe tries to figure out what makes a good first-person dungeon crawler.
-Lord Spencer writes about Mega Man 5 as part of his Mega Man Retrospective blogging series.

-PhilsPhindings discusses the similarities between the soundtrack of Super Mario Land and Soca music.
-Titannel reviews Nitro Pepsi in the midst of giving a life update.
-ChronoLynxx opens this week's TGIF community thread for open discussions.
Look at all those lovely blogs! Thanks to Lord Spencer for providing this week’s recap and, as always, thanks to all of our dear readers for their thoughts and opinions. If you wanna join the HOT TAKE party, then simply mosey on over to the Cblogs section and have your say. You will find yourself recapped on this here front page next week.
The post What will be your big summer gaming timesink? appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Destructoid Community</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dozens of Pirate IPTV & Streaming Sites Face Potential ACE/MPA Disruption]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219193</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/dozens-of-pirate-iptv-streaming-sites-face-potential-ace-mpa-disruption-220604/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T20:32:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dozens of pirate IPTV suppliers and illegal streaming sites may be facing anti-piracy disruption in the weeks and months ahead. A fresh wave of documents filed in a US court shows that the Alliance for Creativity and Entertainment is already investigating various platforms, including one that appears to pull videos from Warner Media's official CDN, using Google as a proxy.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Witness the birth of a legend with Arcade Archives’ The Tower of Druaga]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=324741</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/tower-of-druaga-arcade-archives-hamster-namco-retro-games-ps4-switch/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tower-of-druaga-arcade-archives-hamster-namco-retro-games-ps4-switch"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T19:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tower of Power, Too Sweet to be Sour
This week's retro release from Hamster takes us back to the birth of a Namco legend — now available to download on PS4 and Nintendo Switch from the Arcade Archives, it's the legendary Tower of Druaga.
Released to Japanese arcades in 1984, before later finding its way to early home computers and consoles, The Tower of Druaga is a simple maze game with surprisingly deep lore. The game follows the adventures of the brave knight Gilgamesh, who must ascend the 60-story tower to rescue the beautiful maiden Ki from a terrifying, multi-limbed demon — the titular "Druaga."
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XCCGIP4SifE
A proto-procedurally generated title, Tower of Druaga randomizes its 60 floors on every playthrough, with players fighting off ghosts, slimes, and other nasties while gathering a sackful of special items in order to progress further and further up the increasingly challenging locale. As simplistic as the title looks in the video above, (courtesy of YouTuber Old Classic Retro Gaming), this Namco classic had a complex development, with director Masanobu Endo determined to make a deep and engaging RPG experience.
The Tower of Druaga is today considered the first entry in the "Babylonian Castle Saga," a series that has gone on to include a slew of releases including The Return of Ishtar (1986), The Destiny of Gilgamesh (1994), and Arika's 2004 release The Nightmare of Druaga. Additionally, a spin-off anime series, The Tower of Druaga: The Aegis of Uruk, was produced and released by studio Gonzo in 2008. Not a bad legacy for one of both Namco and the arcade scene's formative adventures.
The post Witness the birth of a legend with Arcade Archives’ The Tower of Druaga appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Moyse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week’s State of Play gives me hope for non-violent video games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328214</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/state-of-play-hope-for-non-violent-games/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=state-of-play-hope-for-non-violent-games"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T17:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Non-violent games are on the rise
The Sony State of Play on Wednesday had to be one of the best we've seen in a long time, because that half-hour was chalked full of some really great titles we'll be looking forward to in the coming months. From the gorgeous Resident Evil 4 remake they announced, to the immersive VR adventures, to genre-bending titles like Rollerdome and Eternights, it's easy to see why PlayStation is killing it right now, despite the chip shortage situation. Of all the announcements, though, there are two non-violent games that really stuck out to me this time around: Season and Stray.
In a mix of action games, these were the only two titles that didn't have combat mechanics on display. Gamers and developers alike have been asking for games that imagine ways for us to int…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noelle Warner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[coreboot 4.17 s Doomem]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/coreboot-4.17-s-doomem</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/coreboot-4.17-s-doomem"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T16:46:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 4.17 svobodné náhrady proprietárních BIOSů a UEFI coreboot (Wikipedie). Na vývoji se podílelo 150 vývojářů. Provedli více než 1 300 commitů. Opravena byla bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2022-29264. Podpora 12 základních desek byla přidána a 2 základních desek odebrána. SeaBIOS byl povýšen z verze 1.14.0 na verzi 1.16.0. Nově si lze na corebootu zahrát počítačovou hru Doom. Přidán byl payload coreDOOM.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[These FFVII Remake Sailor Moon mod outfits are perfect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328098</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/these-ffvii-remake-sailor-moon-mod-outfits-are-perfect/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=these-ffvii-remake-sailor-moon-mod-outfits-are-perfect"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T15:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Champions of Justice
Outfit unlocks (which eventually become free or paid DLC for the most part) rule. Every so often I'll talk about the feeling of playing through say, an action game, and picking up drastically different outfits for party members: and it's sort of indescribably fun to me. That includes this FFVII Remake Sailor Moon mod from juijub.
Thankfully, PC modding has made the practice of outfit unlocks easier than ever. As in, you literally download a file for the FFVII Remake Sailor Moon mod, and boom! You get the fan-made equivalent of a $10 DLC during the Xbox 360 era. Wild, right? This mod takes the base concept of Sailor Mars, Sailor Moon, and Tuxedo Mask, and applies them to Tifa, Aerith, and Cloud respectively. It's quite the power trio, but the combo fits Aerith perfectly, from her move set even down to her hairstyle.

So as usual, you can pick up the invisible weapon mod for Tifa from creator Narknon, which helps all Tifa costume mods sing. This hair color mod (also by juijub) lets you mix and match to fit the Sailor Moon costumes.
After this, be sure you check out the recent Final Fantasy X outfit mod!
The post These FFVII Remake Sailor Moon mod outfits are perfect appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Carter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.19's Staging Spring Cleaning: ~13k Lines Of Code Removed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-Staging</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-Staging"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T14:21:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with his other pull requests for areas of the kernel he oversees, Greg Kroah-Hartman on Friday submitted all of the staging area changes for the kernel in this "proving grounds" of sorts for the kernel. Thanks to some spring cleaning, the staging area is 13k lines of code less this cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Week In Games: Bend It Like Bowser]]></title>
        <id>1849016985</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/video-game-release-dates-this-week-mario-strikers-battl-1849016985"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s time once again to answer the age-old question: Who is the best soccer player among all the Mario characters? And thankfully on June 10 Mario Strikers: Battle League will provide us with yet another opportunity to solve one of life’s great mysteries.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine-Staging 7.10 Brings Fix For Epic Games Launcher Crash]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-7.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-7.10"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T11:45:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off yesterday's release of Wine 7.10, Wine-Staging 7.10 is now available as the newest release of that experimental/testing flavor of Wine that ships with more than 500 extra patches...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds Questions New "HTE" Subsystem Looking To Land In Linux 5.19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-HTE-Uncertain</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-HTE-Uncertain"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T09:48:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being submitted as a new subsystem for the almost wrapped up Linux 5.19 merge window is the Hardware Timestamping Engine "HTE" code. Linus Torvalds though has yet to pull in this new code and has raised concerns around some elements of it...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Fixes Many Plasma 5.25 Bugs This Week But Still Needs More Developer Help]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Starts-June-Many-Fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Starts-June-Many-Fixes"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T09:22:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE developer Nate Graham is out with his weekly report on all of the KDE development activities. In particular, for starting June the KDE developers have been very busy fixing bugs for Plasma 5.25 that is due to be released mid-June. While Plasma 5.25 is getting into good shape, they still could use more help from experienced developers in fixing more bugs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reddit Warns U.S. That Upload Filters Threaten Free Expression and Creativity]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219694</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/reddit-warns-u-s-that-upload-filters-threaten-free-expression-and-creativity-220604/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T07:28:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reddit has warned the U.S. Copyright Office that upload filters would harm free expression and creativity.  The U.S. is considering whether to make technical protection measures mandatory for certain online services but according to Reddit and other stakeholders such as Google, the EFF, Wikipedia, and the BSA, this is a bad idea.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 7.10 Brings 56 Fixes, Proton 7.0-3 RC Prepared With Support For More Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-7.10-Proton-7.0-3-RC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-7.10-Proton-7.0-3-RC"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a busy day in the space for running Windows games and applications on Linux. Wine 7.10 was released as the newest bi-weekly development feature release while Valve and CodeWeavers also issued the release candidate for Proton 7.0-3 as the newest update to that Wine-based software powering Steam Play for running Windows games on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We’re streaming Katamari Damacy tonight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328014</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/katamari-damacy-reroll-twitch-stream/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=katamari-damacy-reroll-twitch-stream"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T01:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's make the King proud
Hey guys! Prepare for trouble and make it double — you've got me for a second night in a row! Although we won't be playing Pokemon, we are continuing a highly recommended game, Katamari Damacy REROLL, on tonight's Twitch stream. It's super upbeat and cute.

We've also got some unfinished business in Pathologic. See you on stream!
Drop by Destructoid’s Twitch channel every Friday at 9:00 p.m. Eastern to hang out.
The post We’re streaming Katamari Damacy tonight appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anabela</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Premium Special To Celebrate Phoronix's 18th Birthday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Phoronix-18-Birthday-Special</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Phoronix-18-Birthday-Special"/>
        <updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Sunday, 5 June, marks the 18th birthday for Phoronix.com since I started this website to focus on Linux hardware reviews and performance testing. To mark the occasion, there will be a Phoronix Premium special if you wish to go ad-free on the site and enjoy multi-page articles on a single page while helping to hopefully ensure a successful 19th year for Phoronix...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LoongArch CPU Support Merged For Linux 5.19 - But It Won't Work For A Booting System Yet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LoongArch-Merged-Linux-5.19</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LoongArch-Merged-Linux-5.19"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T23:27:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following a mad dash this week to get the LoongArch CPU architecture support readied for Linux 5.19, Linus Torvalds successfully merged this MIPS64-inspired Chinese architecture code today into the mainline kernel. However, due to some of the code not yet passing review, while the CPU architecture code is in place some crucial drivers have yet to land and thus Linux 5.19 cannot boot on said hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hopefully Street Fighter 6's New Open World Won't Mean Capcom Skimps On The Fighting]]></title>
        <id>1849014224</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/street-fighter-6-world-tour-soul-calibur-3-pokken-capco-1849014224"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T23:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Schulkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classified military info once again leaks out on a tank game forum]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328128</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/classified-military-info-leaks-war-thunder-forum-third-time/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=classified-military-info-leaks-war-thunder-forum-third-time"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T23:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Surely this can't keep happening
The most bonkers pattern in video game leaks has happened again. Not a leak of a video game, mind you. But a leak of classified military information in order to win a fight on an internet forum for War Thunder, a game about tanks.
This is somehow the third time this has happened on the War Thunder forums. The first happened in July 2021, as a War Thunder player posted classified documents in an effort to prove a point about one of the in-game tanks.
Later that year, the same thing happened again. A player got into an argument about a French battle tank, and to win the sparring match, they posted a part of the tank manual. It led to this message from the moderators, via Kotaku: "Guys its not funny to leak classified Documents of modern equipment you put the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Van Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PS5 surpasses 20 million units sold, Sony to ramp up production]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328169</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/ps5-surpasses-20-million-units-sold-sony-to-ramp-up-production/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ps5-surpasses-20-million-units-sold-sony-to-ramp-up-production"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T22:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PS5 hits an important milestone
Even with how difficult it is to get a PS5 these days, Sony is still doing well for itself, because the PS5 just surpassed 20 million units sold. Veronica Rogers, SVP, Head of Global Sales and Business Operations at Sony Interactive Entertainment, broke the news to GamesIndustry.biz, and expressed how "thrilled" the company was to have reached this milestone for its newest console. Part of me has to wonder how many of those are currently stacked up in scalpers' houses, but it's still an impressive feat nonetheless.
Sony has struggled to keep up with demand for the PS5 since its launch in November of 2020 due to the ongoing chip shortage, but even so, it managed to reach 20 million units sold after one year, six months, and twenty-two days, only about three months later than the PS4 did. According to a tweet from games analyst Daniel Ahmad, the PS5 actually hit 10 million units faster than its predecessor, and "the issues with supply is why it's behind now."
https://twitter.com/ZhugeEX/status/1532744064516382722
Rogers continued on in her statement to GamesIndustry.biz to speak directly to players who are still waiting for their chance to purchase a console: "To those fans who have yet to get their hands on a console, please know that we are planning on a significant ramp-up in PS5 production this year and we are working endlessly to make sure that PlayStation 5 is available for everyone who wants one."
It doesn't seem like the chip shortage is letting up any time soon, but it's nice to hear that Sony has a plan to make the PS5 more accessible to those who might want one. That's a nice sentiment, but I think this is just one of those situations that I'm going to have to see to believe. Here's hoping some more consoles are coming soon, because I certainly don't want to miss out on any of the exciting new titles PlayStation has on the way.
The post PS5 surpasses 20 million units sold, Sony to ramp up production appeared first on Destructoid.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Noelle Warner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 22/2022]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-22-2022</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-22-2022"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince of Persia: Sands of Time Remake has not been canceled, just delayed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328150</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/prince-of-persia-remake-delayed-fy-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=prince-of-persia-remake-delayed-fy-2023"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T22:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It won't be arriving until after fiscal year 2023 though
Reports went around this morning that GameStop was no longer expecting the Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time remake to release. Turns out, that's not quite the case. The Prince of Persia remake is happening, though it's just as delayed as it already was.
Word of GameStop letting pre-order holders know the game wasn't expected to release was running around. The pre-order was delisted from GameStop's website. Popular games and deals Twitter account Wario64 noted the situation this morning:
https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1532767377149943808
Fanbyte spoke to an anonymous GameStop employee, who shared a message being sent around to stores:
"We have been notified that, the following product will NOT be arriving to stores. Product is …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eric Van Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Frontiers combat footage doesn’t inspire much confidence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.destructoid.com/?p=328142</id>
        <link href="https://www.destructoid.com/sonic-frontiers-combat-footage-isnt-winning-me-over/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sonic-frontiers-combat-footage-isnt-winning-me-over"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T21:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The more I see, the less I'm into it
With a month of reveals lined up, more footage of Sonic Frontiers surfaced today on IGN, and this time, combat is the focus with six minutes of drawn-out robot encounters.
If you haven't seen it yet, it's worth watching yesterday's open-world exploration and puzzle gameplay first — you kind of need to see both sides of the coin. Even then...
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q88r4mKJGoM
I'll just come right out with it: the entire vibe seems extremely weird with this open-world game, to the point where I'm struggling to picture how all of these pieces will fit together to form a satisfying, lively experience. Maybe they will, maybe they won't. But this continues to be a poor first impression for what could conceptually be a smash-hit game.
The actual comb…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Devore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vivaldi 5.3]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/vivaldi-5.3</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/vivaldi-5.3"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T20:54:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová stabilní verze 5.3 (aktuálně 5.3.2679.38) webového prohlížeče Vivaldi (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu. Nově si lze snadno přizpůsobit jednotlivé lišty. Nejnovější Vivaldi je postaven na Chromiu 102.0.5005.72.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Když zhasne datacentrum: vyjádření MasterDC k energetickému výpadku]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16076</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kdyz-zhasne-datacentrum-vyjadreni-masterdc-k-energetickemu-vypadku/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T20:18:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve čtvrtečních dopoledních hodinách došlo k velkému výpadku dodávky elektrické energie v Praze. Problém zasáhl i datacentrum MasterDC, kde se ale situace zkomplikovala natolik, že vypadly obě napájecí větve.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Y'all Morbed Too Hard, Now Morbius Is Coming Back To 1,000 Theaters]]></title>
        <id>1849016291</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/morbius-morbin-time-memes-marvel-sony-theaters-sequel-1849016291"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the past few months, a lot of people have been sharing memes connected to terrible superhero film Morbius, which stars noted method actor Jared Leto as a living vampire guy or something…look, I’ve not seen the film, okay? Anyway, all these memes, jokes, and online ha-has have been fun, but things are getting out…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Persona-Inspired JRPG Has You Fighting The Apocalypse, Holding Hands Lewdly]]></title>
        <id>1849016237</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/eternights-persona-playstation-state-of-play-jrpg-roman-1849016237"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lineup of games showcased during last night’s PlayStation State of Play was a clear W for gamers from all walks of life, whether they be VR vampire dommy mommy enthusiasts, roller derby fanatics, or fighters who’ve finally crossed the street into the open-world. However, one game’s journey joining PlayStation’s…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Letter Asks Intel To Open-Source The FSP, Google Engineer Details Interesting Plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Open-Letter-Intel-FSP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Open-Letter-Intel-FSP"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An open letter started by the Open-Source Firmware Foundation and seeking community support for this letter is calling on Intel to open-source their Firmware Support Package (FSP). The FSP binary blob has been a big limitation to the level of openness around firmware for Intel systems and has been a limiting factor in supporting the likes of Coreboot, LinuxBoot, and other technologies on Intel hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looks Like Street Fighter 6’s Entire Roster May Have Already Leaked]]></title>
        <id>1849015598</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sf6-street-fighter-6-leak-capcom-roster-ryu-marisa-camm-1849015598"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T18:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The most recent State of Play included a brief look at Street Fighter 6, which is currently set for a 2023 launch. But a new Capcom fighting game often means we’re in store for some Capcom fighting game leaks. This time around, it only took a few hours for artwork of what appears to be a sizable chunk of the Street…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Kernel Driver Enabling Peer-To-Peer Multi-GPU Compute For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Multi-GPU-Compute-P2P</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Multi-GPU-Compute-P2P"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T18:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new patch series posted today by AMD is enabling peer-to-peer support within their AMDKFD kernel compute driver for allowing communication between multiple AMD GPUs over the PCIe bus without needing intermediate copies through system memory. In turn this should help with the multi-GPU compute performance for the Radeon ROCm stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great Queer Games Bundle Nets You 500+ Games For $60]]></title>
        <id>1849015576</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/queer-games-bundle-itchio-pride-visual-novels-1849015576"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T18:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Huge bundles of games on the itch.io store are frequently used as a means of raising money for charitable causes. Typically, they let you set your own price (above an extremely reasonable minimum), and the proceeds go to various charities and organizations. The new Queer Games Bundle is a little different. Each…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.19 Adding Support For The PolarBerry RISC-V FPGA Board]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-PolarBerry-RISC-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-PolarBerry-RISC-V"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T17:43:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago the RISC-V pull request landed in Linux 5.19 with support for RISC-V 32-bit (RV32) binaries on RV64, enabling the new Svpbmt extension, and other improvements. On Friday a secondary set of RISC-V changes were sent in for Linux 5.19 that includes adding the DeviceTree files for another new RISC-V board...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Witch Strandings is moving Hideo Kojima’s Strand game ideals into new, slightly cursed territory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-witch-strandings-is-moving-hideo-kojimas-strand-game-ideals-into-new-slightly-cursed-territory</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-witch-strandings-is-moving-hideo-kojimas-strand-game-ideals-into-new-slightly-cursed-territory"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T16:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xalavier Nelson Jr has a bit of a love hate relationship with screens right now. As development on his studio’s gutsy market game Space Warlord Organ Trading Simulator was wrapping up at the end of last year, he tells me he remembers “just being really angry at the concept of the borders of the screen”. He was, by his own admission, in “a vague fugue state” at the time, having spent months immersed in Space Warlord’s black and green trading interfaces. But the feeling of having his game “chained to these walls” at the edge of his monitor proved to be a surprisingly powerful one - so much so that it spurred Nelson Jr and his team at Strange Scaffold to create an entirely new kind of game in the months leading up to Warlord’s release: Witch Strandings.

That's right. Taking cues from Hideo Kojima’s hiking postal sim Death Stranding, Witch Strandings is a game that not only asks what Sam Bridges’ cross-country cargo routes might look like if they were made with a fraction of Kojima’s development budget, but also how games can create experiences that are “larger than my screen,” says Nelson Jr. And the answer, it turns out, lies in your PC’s humble mouse.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Survival horror game The Callisto Protocol is coming in December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/survival-horror-game-the-callisto-protocol-is-coming-in-december</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/survival-horror-game-the-callisto-protocol-is-coming-in-december"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T15:45:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The developers of survival horror game The Callisto Protocol have announced that it'll be coming out in December, and revealed a new gameplay trailer to watch with the sound off through your fingers.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cat simulator Stray will wander out into its cybercity in July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cat-simulator-stray-will-wander-out-into-its-cybercity-in-july</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cat-simulator-stray-will-wander-out-into-its-cybercity-in-july"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T14:31:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stray, the game about being a little cat exploring around a big cybercity, has a release date - and it's soon! July, in fact. That's next month! Time flies when you're excited about getting to be a ginger tabby kitty.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zstd Compressed Firmware Submitted For Linux 5.19, Other Driver Core Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-Zstd-Firmware</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-Zstd-Firmware"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T13:50:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman has gotten onto submitting his feature pull requests to Linux 5.19 for various areas of the kernel he oversees. With the driver core changes with this new kernel is now the ability to compress firmware files using the popular Zstd...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Fighter 6 will bring an open-world mode when it launches next year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/street-fighter-6-will-bring-an-open-world-mode-when-it-launches-next-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/street-fighter-6-will-bring-an-open-world-mode-when-it-launches-next-year"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T13:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom have released a new trailer for Street Fighter 6, showcasing an open-world mode that sees characters exploring and brawling alike on the between the neon signs of the city.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telefony Murena s /e/OS 1.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/telefony-murena-s-e-os-1.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/telefony-murena-s-e-os-1.0"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T13:10:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V prodeji jsou telefony Murena s operačním systémem /e/OS (Wikipedie) 1.0. Představení startupu Murena na YouTube nebo Vimeo. Za startupem i operačním systémem stojí nadace e.foundation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Na starých Apple iPadech s procesory A7 a A8 běží Linux]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43707</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/na-starych-apple-ipadech-s-procesory-a7-a-a8-bezi-linux/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T12:02:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Staré Apple iPady s procesory A7 a A8 z let 2013–2014 již nedostávají žádné aktualizace od Apple, ale dva nadšenci Konrad Dybcio a quaack723 dokázali na nich spustit jádro 5.18. Použitá byla distribuce postmarketOS, která je odvozena od Alpine Linuxu a je používána hlavně na zařízeních s Androidem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SiFive RISC-V Sees Some Performance Improvements On Ubuntu 22.04]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=31170</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=31170"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T12:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While SiFive has sadly shutdown production on the current HiFive Unmatched development board in order to focus on new products expected later this year, those with a SiFive HiFive Unmatched RISC-V developer board can enjoy seeing continued performance improvements with newer Linux distributions. Here is a look at the SiFive FU740 SoC performance under the recently released Ubuntu 22.04 LTS compared to the prior 21.10 and 20.04 releases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NTFS3 Kernel Driver Sees Fixes Sent In For Linux 5.19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-NTFS3-Fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.19-NTFS3-Fixes"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T11:37:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the recent concerns around maintenance for the NTFS3 kernel driver and other developers stepping up to maintain the "NTFS3" kernel driver contributed by Paragon Software, there is now a batch of fixes ready to go for Linux 5.19...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI gets a new trailer, summer 2023 release window]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-xvi-gets-a-new-trailer-summer-2023-release-window</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-xvi-gets-a-new-trailer-summer-2023-release-window"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T11:14:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI has released another trailer. This one's for showing off the summons and giving it a release window of summer next year. Summons for the summer!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel’s Spider-Man Remastered and Marvel’s Spider-Man: Miles Morales are heading to PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-spider-man-remastered-and-marvels-spider-man-miles-morales-are-heading-to-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-spider-man-remastered-and-marvels-spider-man-miles-morales-are-heading-to-pc"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T10:19:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Both of Insomniac Games' web-slingin', super villain kickin' games are coming to PC this year. Marvel’s Spider-Man Remastered will be out this August, while Marvel’s Spider-Man: Miles Morales is scheduled for the autumn.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.10 Looking At Replacing WPA With IWD For Linux Wireless]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.10-IWD-Wireless</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.10-IWD-Wireless"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T10:08:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adding to the list of planned changes for the Ubuntu 22.10 release this October is transitioning from WPA_Supplicant to Intel's IWD daemon for Linux wireless needs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom announce Resident Evil 4 remake, due March 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/capcom-announce-resident-evil-4-remake-due-march-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/capcom-announce-resident-evil-4-remake-due-march-2023"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T09:33:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom have confirmed that Resident Evil 4 is getting a remake. It's due out in March of next year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pozvánka na přednášky Java After Eight a Java at Speed]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43706</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/pozvanka-na-prednasky-java-after-eight-a-java-at-speed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T09:24:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V polovině června navštíví Prahu Gil Tene – spoluzakladatel a CTO firmy Azul, která vyvíjí vlastní implementaci platformy Java. V Praze se zúčastní dvou meetupů, na kterých přednese přednášky]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Preparing To Finally  Support Virtual NMI With Their CPUs (VNMI)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Virtual-NMI-VNMI</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Virtual-NMI-VNMI"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T09:21:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It appears that with upcoming AMD Zen 4 processors there will finally be Virtual NMI (VNMI) support for virtualization, a feature Intel CPUs have supported for well more than the past decade...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NoiseTorch 0.12.0, audit nic špatného neobjevil]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43705</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/noisetorch-0-12-0-audit-nic-spatneho-neobjevil/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T08:48:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před dvěma týdny jsme informovali, že vývojář software pro odstranění šumu z mikrofonu NoiseTorch měl podezření, že s kódem mohlo být manipulováno. Komunita zdrojový kód podrobila auditu a nic nebezpečného nenašla.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon Age's next entry will be called Dragon Age: Dreadwolf]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-ages-next-entry-will-be-called-dragon-age-dreadwolf</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-ages-next-entry-will-be-called-dragon-age-dreadwolf"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T08:44:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BioWare have given a new tease for Dragon Age 4, announcing that its official title will be Dragon Age: Dreadwolf. It'll follow up that plot about Solas wanting to destroy the entire world - fantastic news for fans and haters alike.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vydán nástroj pro offline překlad Bergamot od Mozilly]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43704</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vydan-nastroj-pro-offline-preklad-bergamot-od-mozilly/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T08:22:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla pracuje na offline překladači Bergamot již od roku 2019 spolu s univerzitami v Edinburku, Sheffieldu, Tartu a Karlovou univerzitou v Praze. Projekt byl podporován EU. Včera byla oznámena dostupnost rozšíření pro Firefox s názvem Firefox Translation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New VPN Crackdown Underway in Russia, Government Confirms]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219681</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/new-vpn-crackdown-underway-in-russia-government-confirms-220603/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T07:38:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Authorities in Russia have confirmed a that a new crackdown to prevent citizens from accessing VPN services is underway. Telecoms regulator Roscomnadzor says that "measures" are being taken to limit access to VPN services that violate Russian law, which can simply mean providing access to content previously deemed illegal by the government.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Server 37 Looking At Providing A KVM-Optimized Image]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-Server-37-Optimized-KVM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-Server-37-Optimized-KVM"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Server working group stakeholders are looking at offering an optimized KVM VM disk image as part of their offerings with the F37 release later this year...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Python Akademie: začněte s programováním v oblíbeném jazyce (online kurz)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41123</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/online-python-akademie-zacnete-s-programovanim-v-oblibenem-jazyce-kurz/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T06:59:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chceš začít s programováním? Python je oblíbený programovací jazyk mezi vývojáři i zaměstnavateli a zároveň super vstupenka do světa programování. Nauč se přemýšlet jako programátor a efektivně využívat Python na řešení nejrůznějších problémů. Online Python Akademie znamená celkem 12 týdnů, vždy jedna lekce týdně, večer od 18:00 do 21:00. Následující kurz začíná 16. června.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Motion Blur]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2628/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2628/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Zpřesnili hodnotu Hubbleovy konstanty, problém ale trvá]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-zpresnili-hodnotu-hubbleovy-konstanty-problem-ale-trva</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-zpresnili-hodnotu-hubbleovy-konstanty-problem-ale-trva"/>
        <updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Za kolik antihmoty může běžná hmota? Zbývá něco na temnou? Nejsilnější marsotřesení. Ceres měl vzniknout až za Saturnem. Z atomů uhlíku sestavili Möbiovu pásku. Diamantová zrcadla pro výkonné lasery.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stavíme počítač pro příštích 10 let: nadčasové komponenty za rozumnou cenu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16075</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/stavime-pocitac-pro-pristich-10-let-nadcasove-komponenty-za-rozumnou-cenu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[O počítačích zhruba od roku 2011 lze říci, že morálně zastarávají velmi pomalu. Většina komponentů nám vydrží mnoho let a můžeme je postupně obměňovat. Lze ale sestavit stroj, který bude plně použitelný i za 10 let?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube and Uploaded Could be Liable For Pirating Users, Court Rules]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219662</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/youtube-and-uploaded-could-be-liable-for-pirating-users-court-rules-220602/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T17:34:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Platforms such as YouTube and Uploaded could be directly liable for the copyright-infringing uploads of their users. The German Federal Court of Justice came to this conclusion based on advice from the EU's top court. Several liability lawsuits will now besent back to the lower court to decide whether damages are indeed warranted.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Impish Indri končí s podporou 14. června]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43703</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-21-10-impish-indri-konci-s-podporou-14-cervna/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T16:11:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Impish Indri vyšlo už před devíti měsíci (článek na Rootu) a jelikož jde o běžné vydání s krátkou životností, blíží se nyní konec jeho podpory. Ten byl ohlášen na 14. června a po tomto datu přestanou vycházet bezpečnostní aktualizace. Uživatelé by tedy měli brzy aktualizovat, podporovaná je cesta přes Ubuntu 22.04 LTS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Itch.io's Queer Games Bundle is back, offering hundreds of games for Pride month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchios-queer-games-bundle-is-back-offering-hundreds-of-games-for-pride-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/itchios-queer-games-bundle-is-back-offering-hundreds-of-games-for-pride-month"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T16:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A very merry Pride month to all, and what better way to celebrate than by putting some money in queer developers' pockets and getting more than 500 games (and zines and other such goodies) in return? There's a bit of everything in here, from a bird-run grocery store to a meditation on the decay and connection both inherent to today's internet.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Electronic Wireless Show episode 189: the best thing from a game you want in real life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-episode-189-the-best-thing-from-a-game-you-want-in-real-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-episode-189-the-best-thing-from-a-game-you-want-in-real-life"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on the Electronic Wireless Show podcast we clear up an initial misunderstanding but eventually get in sync and talk about the game things we'd want in real life: health packs, tetris, inventory management. By their powers combined we manage to create an absolutely nightmarish dystopian society where people live forever but cannot put more than four of the same thing in a line. It's bleak. Games should stay in games.
Matthew continues the Wolfe Carlton saga, Nate is making a crayfish into a mini-model, and I have a cold. A regular cold! No funny business. Matthew also does a very hard Cavern Of Lies this week that honestly nearly has us.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck's docking station has been delayed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-steam-decks-docking-station-has-been-delayed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-steam-decks-docking-station-has-been-delayed"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T14:21:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck's docking station has been delayed, says Valve. Unfortunately, there's currently no way to tell when the issue might be resolved.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Výpadek v datacentru Master Internet vyřadil spoustu služeb včetně Root.cz]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43702</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vypadek-v-datacentru-master-internet-vyradil-spoustu-sluzeb-vcetne-root-cz/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T13:54:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V dopoledních hodinách proběhl v Praze rozsáhlý výpadek dodávek elektřiny způsobený výpadkem páteřního zařízení ČEPS na Chodově. Výpadek trval asi dvě hodiny, během kterých byl například částečně omezen provoz tramvají a pražského metra. Zároveň však došlo k poruše na jedné napájecí větvi v datacentru Master Internet, kde běží například také servery společnosti Internet Info včetně Root.cz.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V Rising dev talks success, surprises, and future plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-dev-talks-success-surprises-and-future-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-dev-talks-success-surprises-and-future-plans"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T13:46:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I haven’t really had time to let it sink in yet, I don’t think,” says Jeremy Fielding, community manager for Stunlock Studios. When we spoke on Tuesday, their early access vampire sim survival game V Rising had just passed 1.5 million players, far beyond the team’s wildest expectations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wadjet Eye announce time travelling adventure Old Skies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wadjet-eye-announce-time-travelling-adventure-old-skies</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wadjet-eye-announce-time-travelling-adventure-old-skies"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T10:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's not good to dwell too much on the past. Unless, of course, you're playing Old Skies, the newly announced point and click adventure game from Wadjet Eye studios. In that case, you'll need to cast your mind back, because cross-temporal puzzling is what it's all about. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Frontiers shows off seven minutes of open world gameplay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-frontiers-shows-off-seven-minutes-of-open-world-gameplay</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-frontiers-shows-off-seven-minutes-of-open-world-gameplay"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T09:27:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sega have released a look at the world and exploration of Sonic Frontiers, giving us a glimpse of just what it might be like to go fast, open world style.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shueisha & VIZ Media Target Massive Manga Piracy Site ‘Manganato’]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219609</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/shueisha-viz-media-target-massive-manga-piracy-site-manganato-220602/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T08:08:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manga publishing giants Shueisha & VIZ Media are preparing legal action against two large manga piracy platforms. The primary target is Manganato.com, a massive site pulling in 167 million visits per month, more than The Pirate Bay and Fmovies combined. The second target, Manganelo.com, is a comparatively smaller player with 'just' 24 million visits per month. 
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Jubilee street party in Minecraft is the least worst version of the actual Jubilee, I guess]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-jubilee-street-party-in-minecraft-is-the-least-worst-version-of-the-actual-jubilee-i-guess</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-jubilee-street-party-in-minecraft-is-the-least-worst-version-of-the-actual-jubilee-i-guess"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Because I now live in a country that isn't the UK, I get different bank holidays to staff in the UK, which it turns out is almost everyone else. This means I'm at work today and Friday. For other people outside the UK who don't know, this weekend it is celebrating the Queen's Platinum Jubilee. She's the first UK monarch to manage 70 years on the throne, most of the other ones having killed each other or somesuch. The country, specifically England, has responded to this by going absolutely off the boil, represented even in digi-form with a virtual street party map in Minecraft. I wouldn't normally write about it, but it gives me an excuse to republican-post on main when nobody is looking.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this long weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-long-weekend-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-long-weekend-1"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The benefits of monarchy are few and far between, but you do sometimes get a bonus public holiday to 'celebrate' them clinging onto the cushy job their dad gave them. Here in the UK, the four-day Platinum Jubilee weekend has just begun, meaning we here at RPS will be mostly quiet from Thursday until Monday. What are you playing this long weekend? Here's what we're clicking on!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak is a tough yet accessible expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-sunbreak-is-a-tough-yet-accessible-expansion</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-sunbreak-is-a-tough-yet-accessible-expansion"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seregios can get stuffed. I recently faced off against the massive golden dragon during a hands-on session for Sunbreak, the upcoming expansion pack for Monster Hunter Rise, and it battered me repeatedly for the best part of an hour. It has become the flying white whale to my dual blade wielding Ahab, and I left the preview event determined to chop it to bits when the DLC finally arrives later this month.


Sunbreak’s new master rank quests aren’t messing around, basically. It seems Capcom have taken criticisms that the base version of Monster Hunter Rise didn’t provide challenging enough end-game content to heart, and have loaded the expansion with some truly agonising encounters purpose-built for returning veterans.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Více než 3,6 milionů serverů MySQL je dostupných z internetu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43701</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vice-nez-3-6-milionu-serveru-mysql-je-dostupnych-z-internetu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T05:43:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Odborníci z nadace Shadow Server proskenovali internet a hledali přitom otevřené TCP porty 3306, na kterých může poslouchat MySQL server. Objevili přitom více než 3,6 milionů instalací, které odpovídaly na jejich dotazy. Takto otevřený přístup k serveru může vytvářet potenciální prostor pro útočníky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 34 bude od příštího týdne bez podpory]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43700</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/fedora-34-bude-od-pristiho-tydne-bez-podpory/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-02T05:32:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Příští týden, konkrétně v úterý 7. června, končí podpora pro Fedoru 34. Po tomto datu už nebudou k dispozici žádné aktualizace, včetně těch bezpečnostních. Pokud tuto verzi stále ještě používáte, měli byste brzy aktualizovat na některé z novějších vydání.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kouzlo minimalismu: vývoj her a demo programů pro herní konzoli NES]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16074</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kouzlo-minimalismu-vyvoj-her-a-demo-programu-pro-herni-konzoli-nes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na sérii článků o vývoji her (či spíše hříček) pro osmibitovou herní konzoli Atari 2600 s využitím Batari Basicu dnes nepřímo navážeme. Řekneme si totiž, jak vyvíjet hry a dema pro slavnou a přelomovou herní konzoli NES.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kotlin Multiplatform: jednotná platforma pro aplikace určené pro iOS a Android]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16072</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kotlin-multiplatform-jednotna-platforma-pro-aplikace-urcene-pro-ios-a-android/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývoj mobilních aplikací pro chytré telefony je obor mladý a stále prochází dynamickým vývojem. Na počátku bylo v této oblasti více hráčů a téměř každá vývojářská společnost měla své želízko v ohni.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Milan Mitošinka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mega Reports Surge in Copyright Takedown Requests]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219602</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/mega-reports-surge-in-copyright-takedown-requests-220601/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T20:36:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mega is one of the leading file storage platforms on the Internet with more than 117 billion files stored on its servers. Given this scale, it is no surprise that these files include some infringing content. During the first quarter of 2022, Mega reported a significant increase in copyright takedown requests, targeting more than a million links. 
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Elden Ring locations, ranked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-elden-ring-locations-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-elden-ring-locations-ranked"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T18:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever have an idea that you regret the instant you commit to realising it? That's how I feel about my decision to rank all of Elden Ring's major locations. It turns out that, not only are there a lot of locations in Elden Ring, but the definition of a distinct location is largely up for debate. The opening area of Limgrave, for example, could be as many as four separate regions (East Limgrave, West Limgrave, Stormhill and Weeping Peninsula) depending on how you interpret it. That's not to mention all of the dungeons, caves, chapels, and other landmarks scattered throughout the Lands Between.
Yet like a newly minted Wretch squaring up to Margit the Fell Omen for the first time, I am prepared to plough on despite the pain that awaits. Below you'll find a comprehensive ranking of Elden Ring's major regions and legacy dungeons, based on the admittedly woolly criteria of how fun and interesting each location is to explore. So grab your map, put on your boots, and update your life insurance policy as we embark upon a grand tour of From Software's magnificent fantasy realm.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rick Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything shown at the Warhammer Skulls showcase, including three new games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everything-shown-at-the-warhammer-skulls-showcase-including-three-new-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everything-shown-at-the-warhammer-skulls-showcase-including-three-new-games"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The week-long Warhammer Skulls event has kicked off with an avalanche of announcements. Leading the pack are three new games: CRPG Warhammer 40,000 Rogue Trader, digital card game Warhammer 40,000: Warpforge, and retro FPS Warhammer 40,000: Boltgun. Warhammer 40,000: Shootas, Blood & Teef, the 2D action platformer, also got a release date. It’ll be out on the 20th of October.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a 6600MB/s Crucial P5 Plus SSD for £81, nearly £20 cheaper than it was last week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-6600mbs-crucial-p5-plus-ssd-for-81-nearly-20-cheaper-than-it-was-last-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-6600mbs-crucial-p5-plus-ssd-for-81-nearly-20-cheaper-than-it-was-last-week"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T17:11:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Crucial P5 Plus is one of my favourite SSDs, as you might know from me writing about it last week. . Then, I was happy to announce that this rapid 1TB PCIe 4.0 drive had made it to £100 - a price it's gotten near a few times before but not stayed at with any regularity. You can imagine my surprise, therefore, when I discovered that Crucial are now selling the same drive at their site for £80.69 - a genuine bargain and the lowest price we've ever seen by some margin. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 best games coming to PC in June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-10-best-games-coming-to-pc-in-june</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-10-best-games-coming-to-pc-in-june"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T16:56:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s officially summer, although you wouldn’t think it based on the amount of rain we’ve had up here in Newcastle this week. Still, that vague hint of warmth that lingers between the raindrops has got me dreaming of all those lovely things that make summer so appealing. Al fresco dining, excluding that bit where a wasp crawls into your glass of Fanta, which seems to happen to me a lot. Music festivals, minus the part where you queue for half an hour to have a wee. Oh, and obviously spending time on a beach somewhere hot, purposefully ignoring that horrible bit where you try to get your socks back on after taking a dip in the ocean and the sand scrapes against your skin.


OK, so maybe summer isn’t all it’s cracked up to be. Why do we even bother leaving the house, when we can stay indoors and play video games on PC instead? June is a little sparse when it comes to new releases (as is so often the case during these warmer seasons) but there’s still plenty on the horizon to keep you occupied.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pick up an Intel 12th-gen B660 motherboard for £86 (£110 off)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-an-intel-12th-gen-b660-motherboard-for-86-110-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pick-up-an-intel-12th-gen-b660-motherboard-for-86-110-off"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T16:17:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's 12th-gen motherboards are getting cheaper, which is handy if you're planning a new build around one of Intel's excellent 12100, 12400F or 12600F CPUs for gaming. One of the best deals we've spotted is for the Asus Prime B660M-A WiFi D4, which launched at £197 and is now down to £86 at CCL in the UK.
This motherboard uses better value DDR4 memory, two M.2 PCIe 4.0 slots and WiFi 6 on board, so it ticks a lot of boxes in terms of the essentials. You're missing some things from higher-end Z690 boards - like PCIe 5.0, USB-C ports and 2.5-gig networking - but nothing that affects gaming performance, at least in the here and now. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speedy Eggbert's level editor made it the best game to ever score 4%]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/speedy-eggberts-level-editor-made-it-the-best-game-to-ever-score-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/speedy-eggberts-level-editor-made-it-the-best-game-to-ever-score-4"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I used to draw Abe’s Oddysee levels. Then Abe’s Exoddus, when that came out. Also, before them, every other platform game I ever got my hands on. Take a sheet of plain paper, turn it horizontal, draw two long lines across it, dividing it into three strips. That’s a level; that’s a side-scrolling environment. That’s what I’d do, basically all the time, basically every day. You could call me a budding game designer, only I had no knowledge of how to transfer my genius creations into digital form. I’d tried before, with Doom, but the editor was incomprehensible. Sectors? Vectors? Call me a particularly stupid child, but I just wanted to draw two long lines on a piece of paper.


Enter Speedy Eggbert, a budget-priced platform game that scored “the world’s first generous 4% review” in PC Gamer magazine. But I wasn’t aware of that yet. I was, though, aware of its big, shiny box on the shelves of Game, with its gorgeously embossed Eggbert and a reverse emblazoned with screenshots and features, including the most enticing few words I’d ever seen – “MAKE YOUR OWN LEVELS!”

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Gipp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[God of War now has AMD FSR 2.0 support on PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/god-of-war-now-has-amd-fsr-20-support-on-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/god-of-war-now-has-amd-fsr-20-support-on-pc"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T10:23:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A surprise God of War PC update has made it one of just three games to support AMD FidelityFX Super Resolution (FSR) 2.0. This significantly improved upscaling option, introduced a few weeks back in Deathloop (and more recently making it to Farming Simulator 22), completely replaces God of War’s FSR 1.0 setting, giving Radeon GPU owners a performance booster that comes much closer to Nvidia DLSS on quality. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doživotní licence na Windows 10 za € 11, Office za € 23, v červnu s námi ušetříte až 91 %!]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/dozivotni-licence-na-windows-10-za-11-office-za-23-v-cervnu-s-nami-usetrite-az-91</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/dozivotni-licence-na-windows-10-za-11-office-za-23-v-cervnu-s-nami-usetrite-az-91"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supernabídka od Goodoffer24 pokračuje i v červnu! Nejzajímavější z nabídek je bezpochyby doživotní licence na Windows 10 za pouhých € 11, u které připomínáme, že vám dovoluje upgradovat na Windows 11 zdarma! Hovoříme přitom o doživotní licenci, u které vám garantujeme výměnu 30 dní od nákupu v případě, že by se vyskytl nějaký problém. Také potvrzujeme excelentní nabídky na balíky Office ve verzi 2016, které můžete koupit za € 23 s doživotní licencí.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Silt review: there are plenty of fish in the sea but they're all trying to kill you]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/silt-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/silt-review"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Has anyone coined the term Limbolike yet? 2D side-scrolling platformers that are a bit Tim Burton-y, and possibly in monochrome. Y'know the ones? Silt is a Limbolike, only it's Limbo under the sea. Other free-wheeling associations I have made include Minute Of Islands and, most weirdly, Gormenghast. But having mentioned the later, and because people who like Gormenghast really bloody like Gormenghast (a reasonable position), and respond to its evocation like Chekhov's dogs let loose at the eleventh annual Ringing World National Youth Championship competition, I'm now going to have to temper expectations back down.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LVFS v roce 2021: přes 52 miliónů instalovaných firmwarů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43699</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/lvfs-v-roce-2021-pres-52-milionu-instalovanych-firmwaru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T08:29:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt Linux Vendor Firmware Service (LVFS) běží něco přes pět let. V roce předposledním skrze něj bylo instalováno zhruba 25 miliónů nových firmwarů a Richard Hughes z Red Hatu, který vývoj LVFS vede, hlásí z konference Embedded Recipes 2022, že loňský rok zvýšil celkový počet instalovaných firmwarů skrze LVFS na 52,1 miliónů. Úspěšnost instalací pak přesahuje 99 %]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtuální Bastlírna vol. 15: předinstallfestová]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43698</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/virtualni-bastlirna-vol-15-predinstallfestova/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T07:29:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Měsíc utekl lusknutím prstu a krom konference InstallFest se nám přiblížila i další Virtuální Bastlírna. Chcete vědět, co za zajímavé novinky a zvláštní témata pro vás organizátoři našli tentokrát?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: bkralik)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Přijďte na školení MikroTik od základů po velkou síť a odnesete si router]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-39043</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/prijdte-na-skoleni-mikrotik-od-zakladu-po-velkou-sit-a-odnesete-si-router/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T06:57:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Máte spravovat síťové prvky společnosti MikroTik, ale chybí vám potřebné znalosti a zkušenosti? Přijďte na naše školení MikroTik od základů po velkou síť a kromě všech důležitých informací si domů odnesete i vlastní router MikroTik.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piracy, It’s a Crime: UK Govt. Ignored Warnings, Now Families Pay The Price]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219420</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/piracy-its-a-crime-uk-govt-ignored-warnings-now-families-pay-the-price-220601/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T06:42:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before the UK passed the Digital Economy Act in 2017, critics warned that categorizing file-sharers as criminals would encourage "copyright trolls" to demand cash settlements while implying a criminal conviction might be an alternative. The government didn't listen and it is now happening. One of the parties involved is FACT, the company behind the infamous 'Piracy, It's a Crime' campaign.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Types of Scopes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2627/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2627/"/>
        <updated>2022-06-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt C64: rozebrání a renovace celého počítače]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-16055</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/projekt-c64-rozebrani-a-renovace-celeho-pocitace/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ke slovu přichází samotný počítač. Kromě úvodního slova zmíníme nezbytné příslušenství k jeho zprovoznění a podrobíme celý počítač renovaci, byť v tomto případě se jedná pouze o jeho důkladné vyčištění.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Tauchman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME záměrně zcela bez X11 / Xwaylandu: experiment již běží]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43697</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gnome-zamerne-zcela-bez-x11-xwaylandu-experiment-jiz-bezi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME bylo první velké desktopové prostředí, které přešlo na Wayland. A pokud bychom si měli vsadit, které jako první jednoho dne zcela přestane podporovat X11 a také XWayland, bude to opět GNOME. První krok už nastal, vedle existující vývojové větve kompozitoru GNOME Mutter „without-xwayland“ probíhá restrukturalizace kódu, která mimo jiné umožní sestavit Mutter zcela bez závislostí rodiny X11.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[eFootball's Master League paid DLC won't be available until 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/efootballs-master-league-paid-dlc-wont-be-available-until-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/efootballs-master-league-paid-dlc-wont-be-available-until-2023"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T20:31:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[eFootball 2022's Master League will launch as paid DLC in 2023, Konami say. In a Twitter thread, Konami clarified their future update plans, including the free content to come this summer and new teams to be added as paid DLC before the end of the year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Record Labels Want to Know if Piracy Trial Jurors are Hip-Hop Fans]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219524</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/record-labels-want-to-know-if-piracy-trial-jurors-are-hip-hop-fans-220531/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T20:12:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mixtape platform Spinrilla is being sued by several major record labels. It faces hundreds of millions of dollars in potential damages in the upcoming jury trial. To rule out bias, Spinrilla wants to ask potential jury members if they have ever worked in the music industry. The labels, meanwhile, want to know whether the jurors have DJ experience, are hip-hop fans, or support EFF.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Frontiers gets first trailer showing open world combat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-frontiers-gets-first-trailer-showing-open-world-combat</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sonic-frontiers-gets-first-trailer-showing-open-world-combat"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T19:37:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Frontiers is the next attempt to make Sonic work in a 3D world, with Sega referring to it as the blue hedgehog's "first ever open zone" game. Now there's a first teaser trailer of it in action, showing Sonic zipping around a seemingly vast world and bashing giant robots to bits.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Harvest getting new World Map campaign in next free update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/iron-harvest-getting-new-world-map-campaign-in-next-free-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/iron-harvest-getting-new-world-map-campaign-in-next-free-update"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T19:18:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our Iron Harvest review referred to the real-time strategy game as "Company Of Heroes with mechs", which is a strong pitch. A future update is planning on borrowing yet more ideas from mid-00s strategy games, with the addition of a campaign world map.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro Truck Simulator 2's Russia DLC has been indefinitely postponed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/euro-truck-simulator-2s-russia-dlc-has-been-indefinitely-postponed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/euro-truck-simulator-2s-russia-dlc-has-been-indefinitely-postponed"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T18:56:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Euro Truck Simulator 2's next DLC was going to be headed to Russia, with signifcant work on creating the vast country already finished. Now developers SCS Software say that they've decided not to release the expansion, "so that it is not perceived in any way as being in support of or tolerance of the aggression."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Porsche Design AOC Agon Pro PD32M review: not very Porsche-y, but a fine gaming monitor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/porsche-design-aoc-agon-pro-pd32m-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/porsche-design-aoc-agon-pro-pd32m-review"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T15:58:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here we have another AOC gaming monitor, except it’s not just by AOC, but by posh car makers Porsche? It’s the Porsche Design AOC Agon Pro PD32M, a premium 4K / 144Hz beast of a display, and is in fact the second hardware collaboration between these unlikely bedfellows.


It’s also far more ambitious (and expensive) than 2020's AOC Agon PD27. It’s flat rather than curved, but goes for both a higher resolution and a larger 31.5in IPS panel. Its DisplayHDR certification also rises from 400 to 1400, fuelled largely by a switch to more advanced Mini LED backlighting: the same sort as the Asus ROG Swift PG32UQX, one of the best 4K gaming monitors. As a gaming screen, then, it’s got all the right tools, but what exactly about it is Porsche-like?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Monument Valley games are coming to PC in July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-monument-valley-games-are-coming-to-pc-in-july</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-monument-valley-games-are-coming-to-pc-in-july"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T14:48:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Perspective puzzlers Monument Valley and Monument Valley 2 are heading to PC this summer. They'll be expanded - not just for bigger screens, but also "with more intriguing impossibilities than ever before."
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steelrising's robotic revolutionary Paris could be in line for the Soulslike throne]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steelrising-preview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steelrising-preview"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's a bold play, releasing a Soulslike in the year of Elden Ring. Let me rephrase that, actually. It's a bold play releasing a Soulslike in any year, let alone the year of Elden Ring. You could snap open any twelve month span like a bulrush and watch many thousands of little Soulslikes disperse into the atmosphere, with only a select few really making an impact.
Steelrising is one of these Soulslike seeds hoping to sink into our screens, sprout, and take root not only in the innards of our Panasonics, but our minds too. From what I've seen, it stands a chance of survival in a saturated land.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smartphone Motorola s 200Mpix fotoaparátem už příští měsíc]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43696</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/smartphone-motorola-s-200mpix-fotoaparatem-uz-pristi-mesic/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T14:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Už příští měsíc bude představen první telefon s 200Mpix snímačem hlavního foťáčků. Čínská pobočka Motoroly neudržela pokličku na místě.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nouveau vylepšuje podporu GeForce RTX 3xxx Ampere]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43695</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nouveau-vylepsuje-podporu-geforce-rtx-3xxx-ampere/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T13:28:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před několika týdny Nvidia konečně po dlouhé době od uvedení karet samotných vydala i jim příslušné binární firmwary a umožnila tak start prací na podpoře v open-source ovladači nouveau pro generaci Ampere. Vývojáři od té doby nelenili a Ben Skeggs a Karol Herbst z Red Hatu hlásí pokrok.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 101 s několika drobnostmi]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43694</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-101-s-nekolika-drobnostmi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T11:50:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla týden po vydání Chrome / Chromium 102 zveřejnila verzi 101 webového prohlížeče Firefox. Novinek je poskrovnu, spíše jde o věci pro vývojáře, od vylepšení CSS až po korektní parsování parametrů kodeku AV1. Androidí verze přidává podporu lupy pro Android 9 a výš.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo Immortal won't launch in Belgium and the Netherlands]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-immortal-wont-launch-in-belgium-and-the-netherlands</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-immortal-wont-launch-in-belgium-and-the-netherlands"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T09:35:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Devilish MMOARPG Diablo Immortal is set to launch later this week - but not everywhere. Players in Belgium and the Netherlands won't get a release, likely because the game's microtransactions clash with their gambling laws.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espressif Systems pracuje na novém čipu podporujícím standard Wi-Fi 6]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43692</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/espressif-systems-pracuje-na-novem-cipu-podporujici-standard-wi-fi-6/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T08:32:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web chiptron.cz upozornil na novinku z dílny Espressif Systems, na které se momentálně pracuje. Jedná se o novinku nazvanou ESP32-C5 a čip by měl být založen na jádře RISC-V a má podporovat standard Wi-Fi 6 v pásmech jak 2,4 GHz, tak i 5 GHz. Kromě Wi-Fi bude disponovat i Bluetooth Low Energy 5.0.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Šrámek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piracy: Disney Files Police Complaint Against Tamilrockers & Pikashow]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219395</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/piracy-disney-files-police-complaint-against-tamilrockers-pikashow-220531/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T07:38:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disney Star, a wholly-owned subsidiary of The Walt Disney Company, has filed a complaint with police in India. The report targets well-known piracy sites Tamil Rockers, Tamil MV, and Tamil Blasters, plus popular streaming application Pikashow. The registered First Information Report names two local men as suspects.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red žaluje Nikon za porušení patentů na kompresi videa]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43693</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/red-zaluje-nikon-za-poruseni-patentu-na-kompresi-videa/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-31T07:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Výrobce profi kamer RED podal žalobu na japonskou centrálu a americkou pobočku společnosti Nikon. Viní jí z porušení patentů na kompresní technologii používanou v kamerách RED pro video. Nikon se porušení měl dopustit s uvedením své vlajkové lodi, bezrzcadlovky Z 9 loni v říjnu s následnými aktualizacemi firmwaru.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a 500GB Crucial NVMe SSD for £36 after a 34% discount]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-500gb-crucial-nvme-ssd-for-36-after-a-34-discount</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-500gb-crucial-nvme-ssd-for-36-after-a-34-discount"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T20:19:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After discussing a good deal on an incredibly rapid NVMe SSD, I thought I should let you know about something on the other side of the spectrum: a 500GB NVMe SSD going for just £36. This is the Crucial P2, a drive that's been reviewed warmly here at RPS, and it's a 34% reduction from the drive's UK RRP. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a 1TB Samsung 980 Pro PCIe 4.0 SSD for £120, £50 cheaper than it was last month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-1tb-samsung-980-pro-pcie-40-ssd-for-120-50-cheaper-than-it-was-last-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-1tb-samsung-980-pro-pcie-40-ssd-for-120-50-cheaper-than-it-was-last-month"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T19:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung's excellent 980 Pro PCIe 4.0 NVMe SSD has been reduced on Amazon UK, where a 1TB model with heatsink is down to £120 from £170. This makes it only a touch higher than the cheapest drives in this category, for one of the best performing models. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ni no Kuni: Cross Worlds has blockchain integration, NFT plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ni-no-kuni-cross-worlds-has-blockchain-integration-nft-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ni-no-kuni-cross-worlds-has-blockchain-integration-nft-plans"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T15:37:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It turns out that free-to-play MMO Ni no Kuni: Cross Worlds, which recently launched worldwide, is tied up with the blockchain. Developers Netmarble have also said that they're looking to implement NFTs in to the game by the end of the year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘App Stores Should Screen Developers and Apps to Prevent Piracy’]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219429</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/app-stores-should-screen-developers-and-apps-to-prevent-piracy-220530/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T15:17:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The U.S. Government wants to know what challenges and barriers exist in the mobile app ecosystem. While piracy is not at the center of this inquiry, the Copyright Alliance suggests that screening apps and developers will be helpful. Apple, meanwhile, stresses that "piracy" is one of the reasons why sideloading isn't allowed; a notion that's disputed by Cydia creator "saurik".
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V Rising developers post update on their next steps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-developers-post-update-on-their-next-steps</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-developers-post-update-on-their-next-steps"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T15:06:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vampiric survival crafting game V Rising has been a runaway hit since it entered early access a couple of weeks ago. The developers over at Stunlock Studios have now laid out their current priorities for the game's progress, emphasising that it still has a "journey" before its full release.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moderní alternativy terminálových příkazů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-43691</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/moderni-alternativy-terminalovych-prikazu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T14:39:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na serveru LinuxOPsys dnes vyšel článek probírající 13 moderních alternativ klasických terminálových příkazů. Najdete zde alternativy k find  a grep jako ripgrep a fd. To stejné, ale s interaktivním vyhledáváním zvládá fzf (Fuzzy Finder) a skim.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 of the most cutest things in Little Witch In The Woods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/7-of-the-most-cutest-things-in-little-witch-in-the-woods</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/7-of-the-most-cutest-things-in-little-witch-in-the-woods"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers may remember my delight over the demo for Little Witch In The Woods, and I'm happy to report that game is now out in early access. It's already much more polished than the demo, with more yet to come. It's a life sim with a bit of a Stardew Valley or Animal Crossing vibe, except instead of farming you are a witch called Ellie (size: small) living in a biome (type: forest).
In the story you start to free the nearby village from cursed vines, and this requires that you catalogue and collect ingredients for spells, and thence expand your repertoire of witchy recipes. At the same time you can trade spells and magical candy with locals for currency, which you can use to improve your little machines - a roaster, a caldron, a press for ingredients - to make even better things, more efficiently. It's a satisfying process of mastery and exploration. But that is not the important bit. The important bit is that Little Witch In The Woods is disgustingly adorable.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computex 2022 highlights: all the best PC gaming bits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/computex-2022-highlights-all-the-best-pc-gaming-bits</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/computex-2022-highlights-all-the-best-pc-gaming-bits"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T14:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To be honest, I found Computex 2022 kind of underwhelming; this is usually the biggest event in the PC gaming hardware calendar, and had returned to Taipei after an all-remote 2021 show, but ended with only a smattering of major announcements in the bag. We got nothing on Intel’s Arc graphics cards, and Nvidia’s keynote revealed some new DLSS games but otherwise went light on GeForce deets.


That said, this year’s show wasn’t a bust either: there was fresh AMD Ryzen 7000 info, Corsair’s first crack at a gaming laptop and, at long last, some PCIe 5.0 SSDs you can actually buy. One day. In the future. That’s in addition to the wackier, moon-shooting tech on display, without which it just wouldn’t be Computex. So, in descending order - from the interesting and sensible to the blinking ludicrous – here are the PC gaming highlights from Computex 2022.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossfire: Legion early access review: a well-made RTS that's in too much of a rush]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crossfire-legion-early-access-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crossfire-legion-early-access-review"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I feel a bit sorry for Crossfire: Legion, which appears to have suffered the worst launch imaginable for a fast-paced competitive RTS game. Since releasing last week, its all time peak of concurrent players is less than 400, and the average daily concurrents have slid down to around 100 people in only a few days. Worse, a fair chunk of this already dwindling community has been sorely narked off due to an apparent misunderstanding over how one of Legion's key features work.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rick Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embracer Group is creating an archive to preserve games history]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embracer-group-is-creating-an-archive-to-preserve-games-history</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embracer-group-is-creating-an-archive-to-preserve-games-history"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T11:37:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Megacorp Embracer Group has announced that they are building a games archive, to preserve games culture and save it for the future. The project is in the early stages, but they've already got 50,000 games and consoles stored up waiting to be catalogued.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Piracy Company Targets Sites That Shut Down a Decade Ago]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219208</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/anti-piracy-company-targets-sites-that-shut-down-a-decade-ago-220530/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T08:40:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten years ago Google launched its DMCA takedown transparency report. The piracy ecosystem has changed dramatically since then but it appears that not everyone received that memo. Even today, some companies are still requesting the removal of "infringing" links to sites that have long since gone.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[d65536]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2626/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2626/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-30T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[6,500 IPTV Pirates Identified After Accessing Police-Controlled Service]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219398</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/6500-iptv-pirates-identified-after-accessing-police-controlled-service-220529/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-29T18:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police in Italy have revealed details of an operation against pirate IPTV services and subscribers. In addition to targeting around 500 'pirate' sites, servers, and Telegram channels, police say IT specialists were able to identify 6,500 people who accessed a pirate IPTV platform under police control.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-642</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-642"/>
        <updated>2022-05-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for watching a delivery van reverse into a bollard. Before you hear the crunch, let's read this week's best writing about games (and game related things).
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Four Words is a Wordle-like race to think of as many words as you can]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fast-four-words-is-a-wordle-like-race-to-think-of-as-many-words-as-you-can</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fast-four-words-is-a-wordle-like-race-to-think-of-as-many-words-as-you-can"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T23:03:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Four Word is a clever idea. It's a Wordle-like in which you begin with a four-letter starting word and must enter a new word which changes just a single letter. So if the starting word is AHEM, as it was yesterday, you could change the first letter and enter THEM. 

From there, you have 44 seconds to chain together as many new words as you can, with plenty of other twists to make it more challenging.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foretales is a lush narrative card game about a thieving bird]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foretales-is-a-lush-narrative-card-game-about-a-thieving-bird</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foretales-is-a-lush-narrative-card-game-about-a-thieving-bird"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T22:27:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm always interested in card games that stretch beyond pure combat and are used to convey narrative. That's what Foretales does. It's a card game filled with anthropomorphic animals in medieval garb in which you can sneak and barter before or instead of scrapping. Find the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Zdokonalovat lze i kvantové simulátory]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-zdokonalovat-lze-i-kvantove-simulatory</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-zdokonalovat-lze-i-kvantove-simulatory"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jak jsme na tom s řízením kybernetické bezpečnosti. Broadcom převezme VMware za 61 miliard dolarů. Nový IT normál? Cloudové služby, edge computing a automatizace. Téměř polovina finančních ředitelů považuje samoobslužná data a analytiku za hnací sílu produktivity zaměstnanců. Elektroniku čeká další zdražování, zejména kvůli růstu cen čipů. Zdokonalovat lze i kvantové simulátory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elden Ring Seamless Co-Op mod lets you play the entire game with a friend]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-seamless-co-op-mod-lets-you-play-the-entire-game-with-a-friend</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-seamless-co-op-mod-lets-you-play-the-entire-game-with-a-friend"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T21:12:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elden Ring is too intimidating for a coward like me, but that only makes the idea of playing it with mates more appealing. The Elden Ring Seamless Co-Op mod enables just that: the ability to team up with a friend, ride your weird horses, and go muck up some bosses together. It's out now in early beta.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Wars Jedi: Survivor finally has a first teaser trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-wars-jedi-survivor-finally-has-a-first-teaser-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-wars-jedi-survivor-finally-has-a-first-teaser-trailer"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T20:11:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like teaser trailers for Star Wars projects more than I like most Star Wars projects, so this has been a good week for me. It was capped off with the release yesterday of the first teaser trailer for Star Wars Jedi: Survivor, Respawn's sequel to Fallen Order. You can watch it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sued IPTV Operator is Curious About MPA’s “Involvement” With TorrentFreak]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219099</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/sued-iptv-operator-is-curious-about-mpas-involvement-with-torrentfreak-220528/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T14:33:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, several Hollywood studios plus Netflix, Amazon, and Apple sued the alleged operator of IPTV services AllAccessTV and Quality Restreams. According to a joint report filed with the court, it appears the parties are still open to settlement but something else piqued our interest. As part of discovery, the defendant wants details of the MPA's "relationship and involvement" with TorrentFreak.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-193</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-193"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've less than one week left until the Queen's Platinum Jubilee long weekend, so please do remember to book your pets in to be dyed red, white, and blue before it's too late. All the grooming parlours will be heaving with patriotic pups and pusses. Don't forget to brew a giant pot of coronation chicken (or, like me, coronation tofu) to keep you going during the coming week of endless festivity and forced celebration. If you grow tired and that flag-waving arm starts to sag, you'll be in for it. But first, what are you playing this weekend? Here's what we're clicking on!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 21/2022]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-21-2022</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-21-2022"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a Former Radio DJ Became a ‘VIP’ Music Uploader on The Pirate Bay]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=218924</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/how-a-former-radio-dj-became-a-vip-music-uploader-on-the-pirate-bay-220527/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T20:50:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are millions of people consuming pirated content but the supply side is much more limited. A lot of content originates from The Scene and organized P2P release groups. In addition, there are also solo 'hobbyist' uploaders. Today we speak with a Pirate Bay VIP music uploader with more than 3,000 releases under his belt.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ernesto Van der Sar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines Humble Bundle contains six years of DLC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cities-skylines-humble-bundle-contains-six-years-of-dlc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cities-skylines-humble-bundle-contains-six-years-of-dlc"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T20:20:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My favourite kind of Humble Bundle isn't a collection of games, most of which I'll never get round to playing. It's a bundle of a single game I like with lots and lots of discounted DLC. 

Enter the Cities Skylines Colossal Collection, which offers up Cities: Skylines, 9 expansions and 21 add-ons for £16.22/$20/€18.95.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clanfolk looks like RimWorld set in the medieval Scottish highlands]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clanfolk-looks-like-rimworld-set-in-the-medieval-scottish-highlands</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clanfolk-looks-like-rimworld-set-in-the-medieval-scottish-highlands"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T19:52:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clanfolk is colony sim set in medieval Scotland, in which you manage generations of Archibalds and Duncans and attempt to survive each harsh winter. It looks a lot like RimWorld, and it's aiming for an early access release this July. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mafia developers Hangar 13 have undergone a new round of layoffs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mafia-developers-hangar-13-have-undergone-a-new-round-of-layoffs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mafia-developers-hangar-13-have-undergone-a-new-round-of-layoffs"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T19:01:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hangar 13, the studio behind Mafia 3 and Mafia: Definitive Edition, have undergone a round of layoffs according to a report on Bloomberg. The layoffs are the likely consequence of several of the studios projects being cancelled in the past year, including an unannounced superhero game.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077's expansion dialogue and missions details have allegedly leaked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-expansion-dialogue-and-missions-details-have-allegedly-leaked</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-expansion-dialogue-and-missions-details-have-allegedly-leaked"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T17:43:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Details of Cyberpunk 2077's first expansion have apparently leaked, including the dialogue for all its main quests. The leak apparently comes via files accidentally included with the Cyberpunk 1.5 patch released back in February, which were removed by CDPR hours later but discovered and saved by dataminers.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World’s May update introduces combat arenas for 3v3 PvP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-may-update-introduces-combat-arenas-for-3v3-pvp</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-may-update-introduces-combat-arenas-for-3v3-pvp"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T15:43:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Games’ fantasy MMORPG New World has received its latest update, ‘Arenas’, which means you can now smack other players upside the head in teams of three. The update brings PvP arena combat in best-of-five contests that Amazon say are for “glory and riches”, but then quickly qualifies that they're actually for unique stuff to decorate your in-game house with. The trailer makes the whole thing seem pretty wacky, see for yourself below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardspace: Shipbreaker review: moreish sci-fi work sim sticks the landing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hardspace-shipbreaker-review-moreish-sci-fi-work-sim-sticks-the-landing</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hardspace-shipbreaker-review-moreish-sci-fi-work-sim-sticks-the-landing"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Friends and loved ones will agree, I have big “background character” energy. If I lived in the Star Wars universe, I wouldn’t be a Jedi or a Sith inquisitor. I wouldn’t even be one of those rebels who wear the long funny bike helmets. There would be no “Liam: A Star Wars Story” premiering on Disney+. Instead, I'd be the guy who changes the bedding at a grungy BnB on Tatooine. I would spend my days just sort of vibing on the fringes of all the excitement, blissfully unaware of the very important adventures occurring in a galaxy very-very-close-actually.


Maybe this is why Hardspace: Shipbreaker appeals to me so much. As a cutter, a nameless employee of the LYNX Corporation, you’re about as important to this particular vision of the future as the lad who polishes the floors on the Death Star. You are a nobody. But Shipbreaker relishes in how much that still makes you somebody. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo Immortal pre-load begins on PC today ahead of its launch on June 2nd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-immortal-pre-load-begins-on-pc-today-ahead-of-its-launch-on-june-2nd</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-immortal-pre-load-begins-on-pc-today-ahead-of-its-launch-on-june-2nd"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T15:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard Entertainment and NetEast Games have announced that the upcoming devilish MMOARPG Diablo Immortal is available for pre-load on PC today. As in, right now. It won't launch in full until next June 2nd, but Blizzard have provided a handy ‘roadmap’ for accessing the game here. Scurry forth ye demons.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Adrenalin driver 22.5.2 tested: big promises, but no GPU miracle worker]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-adrenalin-driver-2252-tested-big-promises-but-no-gpu-miracle-worker</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-adrenalin-driver-2252-tested-big-promises-but-no-gpu-miracle-worker"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T14:58:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been keeping a curious eye on AMD’s Software Preview Driver for May 2022; GPU drivers often promise “optimisations” that are rarely felt in practice, but this one genuinely sounded like a performance enhancing drug for Radeon graphics cards. In a community post, AMD asserted this particular Preview Driver could provide double-digit percentage gains in games running DirectX 11; claims that were backed up by early independent testing, like the creator of benchmarking tool CapFrameX getting an extra 24% out of Crysis Remastered.


This week, AMD Software Adrenaline Edition 22.5.2 released, making that new Radeon driver available to anyone who didn’t fancy switching to preview builds. Armed with an RX 6500 XT (a low-end card that desperately needs a performance kick), I gave the new software a whirl – and found that, for all those big numbers, Radeon owners should probably lower their expectations.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drainus isn't quite special, but sure is swish]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/drainus-isnt-quite-special-but-sure-is-swish</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/drainus-isnt-quite-special-but-sure-is-swish"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The word that comes to mind is "slick". In a genre defined by busy screens and showy light spectacles, Drainus does well to distinguish itself with such excellent animation. The enemies, and particularly the way they spill from levels like the battleship one, demonstrate some of the best sprite work I've seen for ages.
It's more than just stylish, too. As I've mentioned before, I'm bad enough at scrolling shooters, and outright averse to bullet hell, to make me less than an authority on which are the best. But Drainus held my attention for long enough that you should definitely give it a chance.
I'm not going to do a pun about the name. I'm not. I'm definitely not.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I've bought Lost Judgment with no intention of playing it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ive-bought-lost-judgment-with-no-intention-of-playing-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ive-bought-lost-judgment-with-no-intention-of-playing-it"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while back I finished Yakuza: Like A Dragon and felt a little bit lost. You know the feeling, right? When you snap shut a piece of fiction you’ve been reading for days, or months even, it can be difficult severing those relationships you’ve built with its characters. Unless there’s a direct sequel, you must pull your pants up and shelve those emotions and move on.
Not that I struggle with letting go of characters and stories particularly, but my brain makes an exception for the Yakuza games. More specifically, Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio's games. I’ve reached a point where I’m ordering Lost Judgment with no intention of playing it for months - maybe even a year? It’s all a ploy to hang onto RGG’s characters and worlds for as long as I can; a sort of buffer to keep the unease at bay. Having nowhere to turn to next isn’t an option.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve finally respond to Team Fortress 2’s bot problem]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-finally-respond-to-team-fortress-2s-bot-problem</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-finally-respond-to-team-fortress-2s-bot-problem"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T12:22:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For about a week earlier this month, my inbox was absolutely rammed with emails from Team Fortress 2 players complaining about the game’s bot problem. I’d only just started this job and was still setting up my email signature at the time (sorry, TF2 community), but thankfully all that shouting has finally been heard by the people who matter most. For the first time in two years, Valve tweeted through the official TF2 account today that they’re finally going to do something about the bots. My inbox is thankful.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solve a mystery with new character Yelan in Genshin Impact's latest web event]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/solve-a-mystery-with-new-character-yelan-in-genshin-impacts-latest-web-event</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/solve-a-mystery-with-new-character-yelan-in-genshin-impacts-latest-web-event"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T11:34:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact will be back next week with its Version 2.7 update, which hit a three-week delay earlier this month. Among the headline new features anticipated in Phase I of the update is the addition of a new 5-star event-exclusive character, Hydro bow wielder Yelan. You'll be able to wish for her in the gacha from May 31st, but in the meantime, MiHoYo have set up a web event to let players get to know this mysterious newcomer a little bit better. Naturally, you'll be rewarded with in-game goodies (including Primogems) for taking part.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frogs are hopping aboard Minecraft in June with The Wild update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frogs-are-hopping-aboard-minecraft-in-june-with-the-wild-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frogs-are-hopping-aboard-minecraft-in-june-with-the-wild-update"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T10:34:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mojang have revealed that Minecraft’s first major update of 2022, 1.19 The Wild, will arrive on June 7th to zhuzh up the game’s wildlife and biomes. There’ll also be some new aggressive mobs to contend with if you choose to venture down into the dark underground.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clash: Artifacts Of Chaos is a mind-bending brawler pulling no punches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clash-artifacts-of-chaos-is-a-mind-bending-brawler-pulling-no-punches</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clash-artifacts-of-chaos-is-a-mind-bending-brawler-pulling-no-punches"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not long ago I attended a journo event in Paris, where game devs and their demo booths lined the walls. But none stood out quite like Clash: Artifacts Of Chaos, a third-person fighting adventure set in a punk-fantasy universe. Despite only the briefest of hands-on sessions cut short by sod's law, I simply can't shake the game from my short back and sides-furnished skull. I think I need someone to roundhouse kick me into reality, before I fall asleep and wake up in the fantastical reams of Zenozoik for good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck’s fan quietening, refresh rate customising OS update is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-steam-decks-fan-quietening-refresh-rate-customising-os-update-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-steam-decks-fan-quietening-refresh-rate-customising-os-update-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T09:26:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve have wheeled out another major Steam Deck software update, featuring some tasty changes that have been available to try on the SteamOS beta branch for a few weeks. Namely, SteamOS 3.2 tweaks the Deck’s fan curve to make it quieter (especially under light load), and adds the option to set the screen’s refresh rate anywhere between 40Hz and 60Hz – potentially saving battery life in exchange for a lower frames-per-second ceiling.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tor Project Unblocked But Russia Demands Censorship, Embroils Google]]></title>
        <id>https://torrentfreak.com/?p=219009</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/tor-project-unblocked-but-russia-redemands-censorship-embroils-google-220527/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T07:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After the main domain of privacy-focused anti-censorship tool Tor was blocked by Russian authorities last December, digital rights activists stepped in with a successful legal challenge. TorProject.org is now unblocked but as part of a new legal process, prosecutors are restating and broadening their case. Tor Browser must be banned and deleted from Google Play, they insist.
From: TF, for the latest news on copyright battles, piracy and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Maxwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field Topology]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2625/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2625/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Týden na ScienceMag.cz: V CERNu změřili hmotnost kvarku c]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-v-cernu-zmerili-hmotnost-kvarku-c</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-v-cernu-zmerili-hmotnost-kvarku-c"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vznik života a kvantové tečky. Hledání Dysonových sfér u bílých trpaslíků. Poprvé syntetizovali materiál při tlaku, jaký panuje v jádru Uranu. Drony mohou rozsypávat bezdrátové senzory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compete to solve Wordle puzzles against others in WeWordle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/compete-to-solve-wordle-puzzles-against-others-in-wewordle</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/compete-to-solve-wordle-puzzles-against-others-in-wewordle"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T21:03:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wordle is a puzzle game I play for a few minutes each day in order to relax. WeWordle, by comparison, isn't relaxing at all. It's a multiplayer variant where both players take it in turns to guess words on the same board, which means that each helpful guess you make is also helping your opponent.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BioShock: The Collection is free to keep from Epic right now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bioshock-the-collection-is-free-to-keep-from-epic-right-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bioshock-the-collection-is-free-to-keep-from-epic-right-now"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T20:14:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BioShock: The Collection is the latest freebie on the Epic Games Store. Grab it anytime between now and June 2nd and BioShocks 1, 2 and Infinite are free to keep forever, including all the add-ons such as Minerva's Den and Burial At Sea.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Survarium, spiritual successor to S.T.A.L.K.E.R., will shut down this month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/survarium-spiritual-successor-to-stalker-will-shut-down-this-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/survarium-spiritual-successor-to-stalker-will-shut-down-this-month"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T19:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Survarium was one of several games that hoped to claim S.T.A.L.K.E.R's stalking hood after GSC Game World burst. Ten years after it was first announced and seven after it was released, developers Vostok Games say that Survarium's servers will go offline for the final time on May 31st.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returnal might be headed to PC, a new SteamDB listing suggests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/returnal-might-be-headed-to-pc-a-new-steamdb-listing-suggests</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/returnal-might-be-headed-to-pc-a-new-steamdb-listing-suggests"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T18:38:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sony mentioned in an investor call this week that a third of their first-party games would be on PC by 2025. Well, it looks like Returnal could be next in line to be ported across based on details in a new listing on SteamDB. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unexplored 2: The Wayfarer's Legacy review: a special, chunky roguesomething]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/unexplored-2-the-wayfarers-legacy-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/unexplored-2-the-wayfarers-legacy-review"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gather round the fire, rogue likers and roguelike likers. In a moment of high folly, perhaps hubris, Unexplored 2 has arrived to these lands to preach the benefits of novelty and moreish dungeon delving. This is a chonker of a roguelike RPG, in which long-held assumptions about how the genre ought to be designed are thrown away, while others are strictly obeyed. The designers of this colourful 'splorer have rubbed their chins and decided to see what our beloved randomly generated death tales would look like without two sacred cows: money and meters. Folks, it looks kinda good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This cool roguelike mockup looks like screenshots printed in an old magazine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-cool-roguelike-concept-looks-like-screenshots-printed-in-an-old-magazine</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-cool-roguelike-concept-looks-like-screenshots-printed-in-an-old-magazine"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:56:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A digital artist has created a stylish mockup of a roguelike (maybe even a Roguelike) which looks like printed screenshots in a magazine. It's a pretty little thing, though I should stress it is only a mockup to demonstrate a shader, not an actual game. But still, come, watch.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Quarry's online multiplayer has been delayed to July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-quarrys-online-multiplayer-has-been-delayed-to-july</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-quarrys-online-multiplayer-has-been-delayed-to-july"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:50:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The launch of Supermassive Games' upcoming teen horror The Quarry is just over two weeks away now, but its online multiplayer component won't be arriving on day one, the studio confirmed today. The announcement was tweeted by Supermassive this afternoon, saying the mode will now added "by July 8th" at the latest. No reason was given other than wanting to "deliver the best possible experience" for players. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V Rising players are calling for an arachnophobia mode to deal with its horrible spiders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-players-are-calling-for-an-arachnophobia-mode-to-deal-with-its-horrible-spiders</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-players-are-calling-for-an-arachnophobia-mode-to-deal-with-its-horrible-spiders"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:06:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Players of hit vamp ‘em up V Rising have taken to the game’s Discord server to request an anti-phobia mode to make some of its creatures easier on the eyes. It seems the offending boss in this particular instance is Ungora the Spider Queen, a high-level giant arachnid (the worst kind) who’s set up a fetching gothic domicile in the Cursed Forest’s Spider Cave. According to the mission summary for Ungola: “No living creature save for her children has ever entered and lived to tell the tale.” That’s enough to put anyone off.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Electronic Wireless Show podcast episode 188: the best noble failures in video games special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-188-the-best-noble-failures-in-video-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-188-the-best-noble-failures-in-video-games-special"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T15:05:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on the Electronic Wireless Show PC gaming podcast we're talking about the best our favourite noble failures, like the time I tried to make feta and red onion breakfast muffins. Ne'er touch the muffin pan since. No, of course it's our favourite video games that made big swings but didn't quite hit, a Nate Crowley-backed themed - and he kicks us off with a bid discussion about the infamous Jurassic Park tie-in game Trespasser. Try spelling "jurassic" properly first time; I've never been able too. 
Diversions this week are discussing classic UK subterranean tourist attractions Wookey Hole and Cheddar Gorge, and how Matthew's life could have been different if only he'd been Wookey Hole's witch mascot. Nate has bought a model kit for one of those massive excavation machines, which he says is "about as big as an Alsatian" and "basically a bin-bag full of girders". So he is turning it into an Orc sewage treatment plant. Standard week to be honest.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Point Campus' students are as weird, wonderful and w-fun as you'd expect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/two-point-campus-students-are-as-weird-wonderful-and-fun-as-youd-expect</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/two-point-campus-students-are-as-weird-wonderful-and-fun-as-youd-expect"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's tempting to make a bunch of jokes about Two Point Campus in the vein of, "A nudist knight and a wizard studying the dark arts? Sounds like my freshman year!" and then chortle at the open mic night audience. It's also tempting to say something like, "You know Two Point Hospital? It's like that, but at a university," but that would also be the lazy way out. In reality, the weirdest person I knew at uni only wore a top hat and an opera cape to campus once as a joke (and now has a proper job), and Two Point Campus is actually a way more complex and weird management sim than Two Point Studios' previous - and indeed, ongoing - hospital effort.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Quarry is giving 80s slasher screams to 2022 teens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-quarry-is-preview-80s-slasher-screams-to-2022-teens</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-quarry-is-preview-80s-slasher-screams-to-2022-teens"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I saw the new Scream film earlier this year, the audience was a mix of zoomers sitting at the back giggling at how rubbish it was, and people my age and older fighting the urge to go, "No, see, it's actually really cool and good how they say what the plot is and then that actually is the plot!" There were just too many layers to peel off the metafictional onion for a generation who didn't love the original Scream from 1996. Heck, Scream 5 even opens with a joke about how kids today only like 'prestige' horror like The Babadook.
I'm convinced that there's a middle ground, where you can have a slasher horror that loves the tropes and knows how to work them, but still feels smart and fresh in 2022. And, preferably, stars pro-wrestler and part-time actor David Arquette. This week I played some of The Quarry.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky’s Leviathan update will trap you in a roguelike time loop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-leviathan-update-will-trap-you-in-a-roguelike-time-loop</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-leviathan-update-will-trap-you-in-a-roguelike-time-loop"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T11:58:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Games’ intergalactic wandering simulator No Man’s Sky has gone roguelike for its seventh free expedition update, Leviathan. With a name like that you’d expect something pretty big and, lo, the space whales have arrived. You’ll be able to recruit these leviathans for your capital ship’s frigate fleet, and even keep a baby version as a pet inside your base. Witness them in the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help make EGX better by taking this survey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/help-make-egx-better-by-taking-this-survey</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/help-make-egx-better-by-taking-this-survey"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T11:49:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the worldwide events machine begins to whir back up again, we and our corporate uncles at Reedpop need your help. In order to make sure the return of events such as EGX are the best that they can possibly be, we'd be very grateful if you could fill out a survey for us. The aim is to get an idea of what you're most interested in, and the things you'd like to see most at an in-person event. You'll be doing RPS a favour as well, as your answers will also help to shape the kind of EGX panels and streams we organise for it, too. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A third of PlayStation’s first-party releases will be on PC by 2025, say Sony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-third-of-playstations-first-party-releases-will-be-on-pc-by-2025-say-sony</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-third-of-playstations-first-party-releases-will-be-on-pc-by-2025-say-sony"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T11:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sony Interactive Entertainment boss Jim Ryan has revealed that the company expects around 30% of their PlayStation games to be released on PC by 2025. The comments were made during an annual business briefing today, which also revealed performance figures for core PlayStation games released on PC in the past two years. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Marvel MMORPG from the DC Universe Online devs has been cancelled]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-marvel-mmorpg-from-the-dc-universe-online-devs-has-been-cancelled</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-marvel-mmorpg-from-the-dc-universe-online-devs-has-been-cancelled"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T10:07:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Remember when it emerged that the folks behind DC Universe Online were working on a Marvel MMORPG back in November? You know, the one that was being led by Jack Emmert, co-founder of Cryptic Studios and designer of City Of Heroes? Well, hope you weren’t too excited because it’s been cancelled by parent company Enad Global 7.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SteelSeries mice and headsets are discounted at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steelseries-mice-and-headsets-are-discounted-at-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steelseries-mice-and-headsets-are-discounted-at-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T04:18:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news, everyone! Our pick for the best lightweight wireless mouse, the Aerox 5 Wireless, is discounted by 35% on Amazon UK. That's not all either, as the wired version of the same mouse and a host of other SteelSeries mice and headsets are also discounted. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back up everything with this discounted 16TB external HDD from WD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-up-everything-with-this-discounted-16tb-external-hdd-from-wd</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-up-everything-with-this-discounted-16tb-external-hdd-from-wd"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T03:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right now, a pair of massive 16TB external hard drives are going 'cheap' on Amazon UK. Despite RRPs of over £400, you can get a basic model for £245 or a slightly fancier box for £270. Either way, you'll have a ton of storage space for backups, video projects, game install directories and other media. 
My colleagues at Digital Foundry pick these drives up regularly for their video production work, as capturing game footage and creating YouTube videos quickly causes standard hard drive sizes to fill up. You never want to be in a situation where you're forced to delete your old work to save the new stuff, so having a capacious backup like this is perfect. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Crucial P5 Plus 1TB is down to £100 at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-crucial-p5-plus-1tb-is-down-to-100-at-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-crucial-p5-plus-1tb-is-down-to-100-at-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T03:42:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crucial's P5 Plus is one of the best value SSDs for gaming, thanks to its impressive 6600MB/s read speeds and high-speed PCIe 4.0 NVMe connection. Normally it costs £110, but today it's on Amazon for £100.79, making it a good time to upgrade your PC with a DirectStorage-compatible SSD. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The PS5 DualSense controller is 25% off at Amazon UK this week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-ps5-dualsense-controller-is-20-off-at-amazon-uk-this-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-ps5-dualsense-controller-is-20-off-at-amazon-uk-this-week"/>
        <updated>2022-05-26T03:21:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sony's PS5 DualSense controller is one of the best gamepads for PC too, and now it's 25% off at Amazon UK. This makes it the perfect time to pick up one of these comfortable, long-lasting and very haptic controllers for your very own - or double-up if you're enjoying split-screen games. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creditas: Jak začít investovat a na co si dát pozor?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/creditas-jak-zacit-investovat-a-na-co-si-dat-pozor</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/creditas-jak-zacit-investovat-a-na-co-si-dat-pozor"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mezi základní návyky lidí s pokročilou úrovní finanční gramotnosti patří investování přebytečných financí do výnosných aktiv. Jak ale s investováním začít a na jaká rizika si dát pozor? Poradíme vám v dnešním článku.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Codename: Wandering Sword is a Wuxia RPG with a blend of real-time and turn-based battles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chinese-rpg-codename-wandering-sword-merges-pixel-art-with-3d-graphics</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chinese-rpg-codename-wandering-sword-merges-pixel-art-with-3d-graphics"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T16:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese indie studio Xiameng are bringing a Wuxia martial arts RPG to the West with Codename: Wandering Sword, which looks like a pixel art version of Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon. The game's graphics riff on the ‘HD-2D’ style of RPG that Square Enix introduced with Octopath Traveler. Have a watch of the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghibli-esque MMO Ni No Kuni: Cross Worlds has launched on PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ghibli-esque-mmo-ni-no-kuni-cross-worlds-has-launched-on-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ghibli-esque-mmo-ni-no-kuni-cross-worlds-has-launched-on-pc"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T14:29:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Level 5 and Netmarble’s free-to-play massively multiplayer JRPG Ni No Kuni: Cross Worlds has finally arrived outside of Japan today. The Studio Ghibli-tinged MMO originally launched in June last year, making $100 million (£80 million) in the first 11 days after launch. That’s more than Pokémon GO and Genshin Impact managed.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Cycle: Frontier touches down on Steam and Epic Games Store in June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-cycle-frontier-touches-down-on-steam-and-epic-games-store-in-june</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-cycle-frontier-touches-down-on-steam-and-epic-games-store-in-june"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T13:50:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Free-to-play science fiction PvPvE shooter The Cycle: Frontier will begin its ‘pre-season’ phase on June 8th, developers Yager have revealed today. Season one will then launch on June 22nd, bringing the extraction shooter’s full complement of ‘Fortuna’ season pass rewards along with it. Check out the launch trailer below. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roller Champions is a wheely good time but may stumble at the start line]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roller-champions-is-a-wheely-good-time-but-may-stumble-at-the-start-line</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roller-champions-is-a-wheely-good-time-but-may-stumble-at-the-start-line"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T12:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roller Champions is a free-to-play rollerbasketderbyball mash-up that's been a long time coming. I mean, Matt Cox (RPS in peace) said it was the best game at E3 2019 when it was due out in early 2020. Then it got delayed to early 2021. And now the game's first season has - *double checks* - finally arrived.
So, Ollie, Liam, and I strapped on our skates and jumped into a few games to see how it's getting on. Ollie had some experience with the game before, while Liam and I went in totally blind. We all emerged from our play sesh glowing with praise albeit with a tinge of worry. Would it get any traction, or quickly succumb to the cheery sports game curse?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're finally ready to ESCape from F5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.scummvm.org/news/archive/#2022-05-25</id>
        <link href="https://www.scummvm.org/news/20220524/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After an extended period of time, we're finally ready to announce that the game Chewy: ESC From F5 is ready for testing. This quirky game features the protagonist Chewy as he tries to outwit the evil Borks. Escaping from their high security zone, F5, will just be the start of his adventure.
If any of you have the game and are willing to test it out, we'll welcome any feedback. You will need a daily development build. As always, please submit the bug reports to our issue tracker. 
Please note that the ScummVM version does have one major outstanding issue: the music used by the game is in a custom format we've been unable to properly support yet. So only sound effects and speech currently work at this time.
>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nospam@scummvm.org (DreamMaster)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V Rising sinks its teeth into offline mode with a hotfix today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-sinks-its-teeth-into-offline-mode-with-a-hotfix-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/v-rising-sinks-its-teeth-into-offline-mode-with-a-hotfix-today"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T11:08:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Offline servers are finally arriving for vampiric Steam sensation V Rising as part of a hotfix today. Developers Stunlock announced the changes on the V Rising Discord and Twitter this morning. It looks fairly straightforward to enable the new mode so I’ll run through that for you.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sniper Elite 5 review: too much sprinting, not enough sharpshooting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sniper-elite-5-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sniper-elite-5-review"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T11:01:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Karl Fairburne, the titular Sniper Elite, is a pro at pinging baddies in the distance. The master of shooting Nazis in the balls across hundreds of metres. It’s a mystery, then, why the French Resistance constantly hand him objectives that require close-quarters combat. “Sneak into this chateau,” or “blow up that radar,” they say, probably with a smirk assuming that he won’t be able to pull it off. He can, of course, but it’s a monotonous series of missions that rarely asks you to get inventive with your trusty rifle.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitman 3 ray tracing arrives, kills performance, escapes in nice suit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-3-ray-tracing-performance</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-3-ray-tracing-performance"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T10:36:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As promised, Hitman 3 now has ray tracing support, added in a new patch alongside Nvidia DLSS and AMD FSR 1.0 upscaling capabilities. It’s no lightweight implementation either, combining both ray traced reflections and sun shadows that can really spruce up the game’s already-gleaming murder sandboxes. It’ll please shiny floor enthusiast Katharine, put it that way.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Grumps are overseeing Homebody, a psychological horror game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-grumps-are-overseeing-homebody-a-psychological-horror-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-grumps-are-overseeing-homebody-a-psychological-horror-game"/>
        <updated>2022-05-25T10:07:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not content with just a foothold in the world of dad-dating visual novels, Game Grumps have decided to team up with Rogue Games to develop a psychological horror game. Homebody will channel the slasher film aesthetic of the 1980s, a stark tonal shift from the hand-drawn cheesecake colourfulness of Game Grumps and Rogue Games' first collaboration, Dream Daddy. Some of the same team are back for this one though. Watch the eerie trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>CJ Wheeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 will launch in October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-will-launch-in-october</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-will-launch-in-october"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T22:41:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a while since I've seen a developer or publisher blow a bunch of money on a big, dumb videogame announcement, but then here comes Call Of Duty: Modern Warfare 2. The remake of Infinity Ward's famous (and infamous?) first-person shooter will release on October 28th, and Activision Blizzard decided to reveal some of its character art via the medium of a real world cargo ship.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Melatonin looks like the Rhythm Heaven game of your dreams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/melatonin-looks-like-the-rhythm-heaven-game-of-your-dreams</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/melatonin-looks-like-the-rhythm-heaven-game-of-your-dreams"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T22:04:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are a handful of rhythm games on PC, but a lot of them are ultra-hard, anime-drenched tests of reflexes and memorisation. I like my rhythm games on the other end of the scale, containing playful minigames with silly concepts and stories. Think Rhythm Heaven. Think Osu! Tatakae! Ouendan.

Think, perhaps, Melatonin. It's an in-development rhythm game about dreams merging with reality, and looks like exactly my thing. Watch the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer's excellent Basilisk Ultimate wireless mouse is £86 off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razers-excellent-basilisk-ultimate-wireless-mouse-is-86-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razers-excellent-basilisk-ultimate-wireless-mouse-is-86-off-today"/>
        <updated>2022-05-24T22:04:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There's a rather fetching deal on the Razer Basilisk Ultimate going at Amazon UK today, where you can pick up a mouse with 11 programmable buttons, high-end components, RGB lighting throughout and a handy charging dock for £84, down from a UK RRP of £170. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: O financování většiny podnikového IT se rozhoduje (i) mimo IT oddělení]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-o-financovani-vetsiny-podnikoveho-it-se-rozhoduje-i-mimo-it-oddeleni</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-o-financovani-vetsiny-podnikoveho-it-se-rozhoduje-i-mimo-it-oddeleni"/>
        <updated>2022-05-22T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Teams zvládá automatický zápis schůzek. Hewlett Packard Enterprise v Česku staví nový výrobní závod na superpočítače. Acer omladí pracovní notebooky TravelMate P4, TravelMate Spin P4 a TravelMate P2. Pure dále zpřístupňuje podnikům Kubernetes. Zasuneš a jedeš. Kubernetes: obliba roste, problém zůstává bezpečnost a know-how. O financování většiny podnikového IT se rozhoduje (i) mimo IT oddělení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Summer of Code 2022 – please welcome our students!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.scummvm.org/news/archive/#2022-05-22</id>
        <link href="https://www.scummvm.org/news/20220522/"/>
        <updated>2022-05-22T03:57:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago, Google announced the list of students accepted for this year's Google Summer of Code.
We are very proud to welcome 4 students this year who will be working on various parts of the project during the upcoming months.
Pragyansh Chaturvedi (aka Raikou) will work on improving our DIRECTOR engine. His effort will help us to allow support for many 90s-era adventure games made with the Macromedia Director authoring tools. By implementing more internal functions used by DIRECTOR, Pragyansh's main objective is to extend support for Meet Mediaband and The Journeyman Project (Win and Mac), making them fully playable without any glitches.
Michael Hayman (aka Quote58) is about to implement support for The Immortal. The game (released in 1990) can be described as a mix of genres involving RPG elements with action and puzzles. Many changes across different game variants (written in pure assembly code!) will make this an interesting challenge. This project is a continuation of a GSoC task initially started by a former student back in 2018.
Emanuele Grisenti (aka grisenti) will be working on a new engine, HPL1. The original sources for this engine got recently released by the original developer Frictional Games under GPLv3. The purpose of this project is to achieve a full port of this engine to ScummVM, with the goal of supporting the 2007 survival game Penumbra: Overture.
Avijeet Maurya (aka StableSteady) will pick up several incomplete engines: MacVenture, Avalanche, Glk-Scott, Pink and WAGE. Some of these engines are very close to completion, but not quite there yet. The main objective of Avijeet's task is to identify all missing features and fix existing bugs. The goal for his project is to bring the above engines to a stable state.
The team is very excited about the upcoming weeks – and we hope you are as well.
Please give a warm welcome to our new students! Let's make GSoC 2022 a huge success – together!
>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nospam@scummvm.org (sev, lotharsm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: 2D materiál dokáže uchovávat qubity při pokojové teplotě]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-2d-material-dokaze-uchovavat-qubity-pri-pokojove-teplote</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-2d-material-dokaze-uchovavat-qubity-pri-pokojove-teplote"/>
        <updated>2022-05-21T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetické pole si může převrátit i černá díra. V atmosféře přibývá helia, je tam víc i izotopu 3He. Další teorie postuluje neexistenci času. Simulace NASA ukazují, že sopky mohou klima i oteplovat. Účinný vodíkový palivový článek se obejde bez drahých kovů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>