<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-18T20:14:36.836Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-18T20:14:36.836Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foreman 3.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/foreman-3.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/foreman-3.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T18:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Foreman (Wikipedie), nástroj pro kompletní správu životního cyklu fyzických i virtuálních serverů, byl vydán ve verzi 3.0. Přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toby Fox: Deltarune Chapter 2 Is Free Because It's Been 'Really Tough For Everybody Recently']]></title>
        <id>1847702225</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/toby-fox-deltarune-chapter-2-is-free-because-the-world-1847702225"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After waiting three years for any kind of news about the next chapter in the Deltarune series, indie dev Toby Fox surprise announced earlier this week that it would be out on September 17. When it finally became available the game was free and the rush of players trying to download it was so large that it temporarily…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DRM Driver Posted For AI Processing Unit - Initially Focused On Mediatek SoCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DRM-AI-APU-RFC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DRM-AI-APU-RFC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T17:12:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BayLibre developer Alexandre Bailon has posted a "request for comments" of a new open-source Direct Rendering Manager (DRM) driver for AI Processing Unit (APU) functionality. Initially the driver is catering to Mediatek SoCs with an AI co-processor but this DRM "APU" driver could be adapted to other hardware too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feature: 30 Years Of Sonic The Hedgehog - The Many Faces Of Mario's Biggest Rival]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120908</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/feature_30_years_of_sonic_the_hedgehog_-_the_many_faces_of_marios_biggest_rival"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The personal recap of the fastest thing alive.
Over the last three decades, many types of Sonic fan have emerged and evolved. The type of fan you are often depends on where you jumped aboard the platforming franchise. You've got your 2D purists, your handheld advocates, your 3D defenders, your Werehog worriers, your people who say the 8-bit games were better than the 16-bit ones... and that's just the tip of the Green Hill.
Today self-described 'long-suffering Sonic veteran' Stuart Gipp takes a chronological look back over the entire series 'til now...
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-Order Mario Party Superstars From My Nintendo And Get Some Free Goodies (UK)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121108</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pre-order_mario_party_superstars_from_my_nintendo_and_get_some_free_goodies_uk"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T16:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Existing orders will be upgraded.
Metroid Dread isn't the only first-party Nintendo title arriving in the month of October. At the very end of it is the launch of Mario Party Superstars - first announced in June this year during Nintendo's E3 Direct.
If you are planning on adding a physical copy of the game to your Switch library and happen to be located in the UK, then you might be interested in this special offer from Nintendo. If you pre-order the game now on My Nintendo, you'll receive a free coaster set and a Birdo keyring.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Gaming Console That's Become A Giant Car Crash, Explained]]></title>
        <id>1847699027</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-new-gaming-console-thats-become-a-giant-car-crash-1847699027"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On October 22, 2018, Intellivision unveiled the Amico, a family-friendly retro console. The pitch: The games would be simple to play and cost no more than $8. The console itself would retail at about $180 with all games being exclusive to the console. In that initial trailer, the Amico was given a release date of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardware Review: Can You Really "Make Your Own Switch Pro" With This $100 Dongle?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121050</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/hardware_review_can_you_really_make_your_own_switch_pro_with_this_usd100_dongle"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We go hands-on with the Marseille mClassic.
The debate about the existence of a 'Switch Pro' rages on, with reports suggesting it would be announced this year seemingly being disproven by the arrival of the more modest Switch OLED Model. However, the promise of 4K gaming has clearly struck a chord with the general public, and in an effort to fill the void, Marseille, Inc. has given its mClassic a fresh marketing push, boldly claiming that it can transform your standard Switch into a 'Switch Pro' for just $100.
"The eternal disappointment of Nintendo fans continues," reads the press release we were sent back in August. "While we were all anticipating the Switch Pro, we instead got an OLED screen with the exact same resolution and the same Joy-Con drifts. It’s the 3DS XL saga all over again. However, not all hope is lost. While we don’t know when or if we will get a Switch Pro, gamers can create their own with Marseille’s mClassic."
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talonflame Might Be Running A Whole Arson Crime Ring]]></title>
        <id>1847700698</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/talonflame-might-be-running-a-whole-arson-crime-ring-1847700698"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Pokemon is interesting and worth talking about. I don’t play a ton of Pokemon, but I do enjoy the universe and I love learning more about the creatures in it. So, Here’s Another Pokemon! It’s Talonflame!

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple M1 USB Type-C Linux Support Code Sent Out For Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-USB-Type-C-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-USB-Type-C-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T13:05:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest patches sent out for review/testing on the long mission for enabling Apple M1 support on Linux is the USB Type-C connectivity...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Active Life Outdoor Challenge / Family Trainer - Fit Enough For Purpose]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120340</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/active_life_outdoor_challenge"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wii think we've seen this before.
There used to be a time during the Wii era where you couldn't move for fitness games. The enormous success of Wii Fit led to a steady stream of imitators, from well-known established publishers all the way down to the shovelware merchants looking to cash in on the latest fad. One of the more unique offerings was Active Life Outdoor Challenge (known in Europe as Family Trainer)
Released by Bandai Namco in 2008, it opted not to use the Wii Remote or even Wii Fit’s Balance Board, and instead came with a giant floor mat. This was a nod to Bandai’s original 1986 Famicom game Family Trainer, which also used a mat (which would eventually be known in the West as the NES Power Pad).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story Of Seasons: Pioneers Of Olive Town has sprouted on Steam]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/story-of-seasons-pioneers-of-olive-town-has-sprouted-on-steam</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/story-of-seasons-pioneers-of-olive-town-has-sprouted-on-steam"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T12:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Story Of Seasons game starts the same way, with a young person fleeing the big city for a more relaxing and simple life. Good luck to them, sez I, but personally I find takeaway delivery services much more relaxing and simple than growing my own beets. 

Story Of Seasons: Pioneers Of Olive Town repeats the myth, though I admit its pastoral greens and funny hats make a strong argument for country living. It's out on Steam now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo's Switch OLED Model Makes Its First Public Appearance In Japan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121107</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/nintendos_switch_oled_model_makes_its_first_public_appearance_in_japan"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Launching worldwide October 8th.
We're just over halfway through September and that means we're getting closer to the Switch OLED's release on October 8th.
We've seen trailers from Nintendo, read "hands-on" first impressions from the media about it and now we've got a first look at the device in the wild. As highlighted by our friends at VGC, the new model priced at $349.99 / £309.99 has just gone on display at various retailers around Japan - including Nintendo's very own Tokyo store.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 2.10.28]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/gimp-2.10.28</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/gimp-2.10.28"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T12:11:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová stabilní verze 2.10.28 svobodné aplikace pro úpravu a vytváření rastrové grafiky GIMP (GNU Image Manipulation Program). Verze 2.10.26 byla přeskočena. Přehled novinek v oznámení o vydání a v souboru NEWS na GitLabu. Vývojáři zdůrazňují opravu několika chyb ve verzi pro Windows. Nový GIMP je již k dispozici také na Flathubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Český překlad příručky LibreOffice Impress 7.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/cesky-preklad-prirucky-libreoffice-impress-7.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/cesky-preklad-prirucky-libreoffice-impress-7.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T11:57:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Český LibreOffice tým vydává překlad příručky LibreOffice Impress 7.0. Tato příručka je určena pro začátečníky i pokročilé uživatele aplikace Impress, prezentační komponenty v LibreOffice. S její pomocí můžete vytvářet snímky, které obsahují text, číslované a odrážkové seznamy, tabulky, grafy, videoklipy, kliparty a další objekty. Impress přichází s předdefinovanými textovými styly a předlohami snímků; můžete si také vytvořit vlastní.  Příručka je ke stažení na stránce dokumentace. Tým nyní pracuje na překladu příruček Draw a Base.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zdeněk Crhonek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD + Valve Focusing On P-State / CPPC Driver With Schedutil For Better Linux Efficiency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-P-State-XDC2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-P-State-XDC2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T11:26:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As reported at the start of August, AMD and Valve have been working on Linux CPU performance/frequency scaling improvements with the Steam Deck being one of the leading motivators. As speculated at that time, their work would likely revolve around use of ACPI CPPC found with Zen 2 CPUs and newer. Published last week was that AMD P-State driver for Linux systems indeed now leveraging CPPC information. AMD formally presented this new driver yesterday at XDC2021...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dicey spaceship crisis sim Tharsis is the latest Epic Games Store freebie]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dicey-spaceship-crisis-sim-tharsis-is-the-latest-epic-games-store-freebie</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dicey-spaceship-crisis-sim-tharsis-is-the-latest-epic-games-store-freebie"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T11:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tharsis is a turn-based spaceship management game where your ability to deal with a Sandra Bullock of disasters is determined by a dice roll. Alec once sung its praises while calling it "cruel as hell" - and it's one of this week's free games from the Epic Games Store.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online konference LibreOffice 2021]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42829</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/online-konference-libreoffice-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T10:47:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Od 23. do 25. září bude probíhat online konference LibreOffice 2021. Během tří dnů je připraveno okolo padesáti přednášek, workshopů a komunitních setkání s tématy týkající se kancelářského balíku, komunity a open source.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FIFA 22 Ultimate Team will let you see inside loot boxes from launch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fifa-22-ultimate-team-will-let-you-see-inside-loot-boxes-from-launch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fifa-22-ultimate-team-will-let-you-see-inside-loot-boxes-from-launch"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[EA have detailed how FIFA Ultimate Team is changing for FIFA 22 when it launches on September 26th. Chief among the new features is the adoption of Preview Packs, which let you see the contents of one of Ultimate Team's lucrative loot boxes before you decide whether to buy it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 2.10.28 Released With More Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GIMP-2.10.28-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GIMP-2.10.28-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T09:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There's still some time to go before seeing the long-awaited GIMP 3.0 release for this open-source image manipulation program but at least out this weekend is GIMP 2.10.28 for bettering the current stable series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Sees Another Big Batch Of Plasma Wayland Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=More-Plasma-Wayland-Sep-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=More-Plasma-Wayland-Sep-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T09:42:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with releasing Plasma 5.23 Beta this week, KDE developers have been busy on driving in a bunch of Plasma Wayland fixes and other refinements to their stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Victoria III details its approach to slavery in new dev diary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/victoria-iii-details-its-approach-to-slavery-in-new-dev-diary</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/victoria-iii-details-its-approach-to-slavery-in-new-dev-diary"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T09:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest development diary post for Victoria III talks in detail about how Paradox's empire builder will deal with the topic of slavery. Extremely carefully, is the answer.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Are You Playing This Weekend? (September 18th)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120781</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/talking_point_what_are_you_playing_this_weekend_september_18th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Got gaming plans?
Another busy week in the world of Nintendo has flown by. We've seen the return of a famed arcade racing series, a price 'adjustment' for Switch in Europe, the 20th anniversary of a treasured console, and a surprise Switch firmware update that included a much-requested feature: Bluetooth audio support.
After all that it's time to chill out and discuss our weekend gaming plans. A few members of the Nintendo Life team have done just that below, so feel free to give our entries a read and then join in with your own via our comment section. Enjoy!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-162</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-162"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hold tight, it's still summer! Four more days and then you can put on as many jumps as you want and chug pumpkin spice lattes until you hurl but for now please, don't deny me the dregs of summer. I need this. You're probably indoors playing video games anyway, so what does it matter to you? Tell me: what are you playing this weekend?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Český překlad příručky LibreOffice Impress 7.0]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42828</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/cesky-preklad-prirucky-libreoffice-impress-7-0/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T06:12:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Český LibreOffice tým vydává překlad příručky LibreOffice Impress 7.0. Tato příručka je určena pro začátečníky i pokročilé uživatele aplikace Impress, prezentační komponenty v LibreOffice. S její pomocí můžete vytvářet snímky, které obsahují text, číslované a odrážkové seznamy, tabulky, grafy, videoklipy, kliparty a další objekty. Impress přichází s předdefinovanými textovými styly a předlohami snímků; můžete si také vytvořit vlastní. Příručka je ke stažení na stránce dokumentace. Tým nyní pracuje na překladu příruček Draw a Base.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Kart Tour Teases New Event Ahead Of Its 2nd Year Anniversary Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121105</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/mario_kart_tour_teases_new_event_ahead_of_its_2nd_year_anniversary_next_week"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Start your engines.
The Sydney tour has almost come to an end in Mario Kart Tour, and next up is a very special event to celebrate the two-year anniversary of the mobile racer.
Yes, that's right - MKT is almost two years old and Nintendo is planning on an eight-city race. Here's the promo artwork, which shows off previous character unlocks and some of the cities that can be expected.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Undertale's 6th Anniversary Broadcast Locks In A Release Date For Deltarune Chapter 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120989</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/undertales_6th_anniversary_broadcast_locks_in_a_release_date_for_deltarune_chapter_2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Out now (and free) on PC, but Switch owners will have to wait.
Update : Deltarune Chapter 2 is now available on PC. It seems Nintendo Switch owners will have to wait a little bit longer. On the plus side, creator Toby Fox has confirmed the second chapter has been released for free:

Original article : It seems like ages since we got an update on the progress of Deltarune Chapter 2, and now we've finally got some new information to share.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic And Balan Wonderworld Creator Yuji Naka Is Now Making Smartphone Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121104</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/sonic_and_balan_wonderworld_creator_yuji_naka_is_now_making_smartphone_games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Retirement can wait.

One of the most underwhelming releases in 2021 has been Balan Wonderworld - by Sonic the Hedgehog creator, Yuji Naka.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every TV Moment I Recognized In The Cool New SpongeBob Game Reveal]]></title>
        <id>1847699681</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/every-tv-moment-i-recognized-in-the-cool-new-spongebob-1847699681"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[THQ Nordic revealed a new SpongeBob SquarePants game during its 10th anniversary showcase livestream today, and while the trailer lacked any actual gameplay, it was bursting at the seams with iconic references to the series. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 37/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-37-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-37-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retro Shooter ExZeus Has Been Polished Up For A September Switch Re-Release]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121091</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/retro_shooter_exzeus_has_been_polished_up_for_a_september_switch_re-release"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Go ahead, mech my day.
Ziggurat are on a roll with resurrecting games from decades ago — yesterday, we had the news that cult vampire classic Bloodrayne was getting "ReVamped" for the Switch, and today, Ziggurat have announced a September 30th release date for ExZeus: The Complete Collection on consoles and PC.
ExZeus (AKA Counter Force) was an arcade game from the early 2000s, which was later ported to the PS2, PC, and Wii. It's a rail shooter in the vein of Star Fox, only with a lot more mechs and a lot less Slippy.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[D&D 5th Edition Is Deeply Flawed, So Why Not Play Something Better?]]></title>
        <id>1847698975</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/d-d-5th-edition-is-deeply-flawed-so-why-not-play-somet-1847698975"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dungeons & Dragons 5th Edition is known for being two things above all else, depending on who you talk to: really approachable and easy to play, or a total mess that dilutes a lot of the distinctive factors of previous editions of D&D. Both things are true. It is also true that other games exist, and execute on most…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grindstone's Monsters And Mamas update adds new playable character]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grindstones-monsters-and-mamas-update-adds-new-playable-character</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grindstones-monsters-and-mamas-update-adds-new-playable-character"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T20:24:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beloved puzzle battler Grindstone has received another free content update. "Monsters And Mamas" adds the game's first alternate playable character, letting you choose to ascend the mountain as vetern stonegrinder Jorja, pictured above. There's also a new Boss Blitz mode, new rewards, and a high-contrast accessibility feature for the colourblind.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crysis Remastered is available on Steam now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-remastered-is-available-on-steam-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-remastered-is-available-on-steam-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T20:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crysis Remastered landed on the Epic Games Store last year, and the Crysis Trilogy Remastered will similarly don its freshly dry-cleaned nanosuits for Epic's store on October 15th. But as of today, you can also grab Crysis Remastered from Steam.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Outcast is getting a sequel 20 years after the original]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/outcast-is-getting-a-sequel-20-years-after-the-original</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/outcast-is-getting-a-sequel-20-years-after-the-original"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, the 90s are calling and they'd like to offer you sequels to games you've probably forgotten about. Outcast 2: A New Beginning is the newly announced follow-up to 1999's Outcast. It's an open-world third-person shooter that takes place right after the events of the original, where Cutter Slade (the best-named man in the world) has been stuck in time for 20 years after trying to get home to Earth from the alien planet Adelpha. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jagged Alliance 3 is coming from the developers of Surviving Mars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jagged-alliance-3-is-coming-from-the-developers-of-surviving-mars</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jagged-alliance-3-is-coming-from-the-developers-of-surviving-mars"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jagged Aliance 3 has been announced during this evening's THQ Nordic 10th anniversary showcase. The turn-based tactics sequel is the first numbered game in the series since 1999's Jagged Alliance 2. It's being developed by Haemimont Games, who are best known for several Tropico games or most recently citybuilder Surviving Mars.

There's a cinematic and gameplay trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Destroy All Humans! 2: Reprobed is in development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destroy-all-humans-2-reprobed-is-in-development</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destroy-all-humans-2-reprobed-is-in-development"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Destroy All Humans 2: Reprobed has been announced. It's a ground-up remake of the 2006 third-person action game in which you go on a globe-trotting adventure to, uh, destroy all humans. Reprobed follows  last year's remake of the first Destroy All Humans, and comes from the same developer, Black Forest Games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SpongeBob SquarePants: The Cosmic Shake Heads To Switch Soon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121097</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/spongebob_squarepants_the_cosmic_shake_heads_to_switch_soon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T19:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That's a whole lot of SpongeBob.
THQ Nordic has wrapped up its 10th Anniversary Showcase, and thankfully it included a Switch announcement among a number of PC and PS5 / Xbox Series titles. Unsurprisingly Nintendo's system will be getting SpongeBob SquarePants: The Cosmic Shake, the latest game for the iconic IP that is 'coming soon'.
As you'd expect it looks fun in the trailer, and digging into the game description makes us think it could be a rather clever adventure game. Check out some details below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Is Hiring So Linux Can Finally Have Good HDR Display Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-Hiring-For-Linux-HDR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-Hiring-For-Linux-HDR"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T19:15:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the areas where Linux has struggled on the desktop has been around HDR (high dynamic range) display support while that will hopefully be addressed in the coming months with Red Hat hiring an engineer to focus on that problem...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's Why Folks Think Nintendo Might Be Bringing N64 To Switch]]></title>
        <id>1847697687</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/heres-why-folks-think-nintendo-might-be-bringing-n64-to-1847697687"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been on Twitter lately, you may have noticed that folks are spinning their gears contemplating the nature of a mysterious “game controller” application that Nintendo just filed with the Federal Communications Commission. Most seem to think it’s related to a rumored, upcoming expansion of the Nintendo Switch…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Silicon / M1 Port Planned For GCC 12]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-Apple-M1-Port-Plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-Apple-M1-Port-Plan"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T18:41:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developers are hoping for next year's GCC 12 release they will have Apple AArch64 support on Darwin in place for being able to support Apple Silicon -- initially the M1 SoC -- on macOS with GCC...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lovecraft-Inspired Horror Game Explores The Cost Of Creation]]></title>
        <id>1847696873</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/lovecraft-inspired-horror-game-explores-the-cost-of-cre-1847696873"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T18:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Well is the latest microscopic horror game from Yames, the dev behind other unnerving fare like Water Womb World and Discover My Body. It takes about 20-30 minutes to see through to the end (maybe a little longer if you, like me, struggle with getting the game to run full screen). Yames releases these small games…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch: THQ Nordic 10th Anniversary Showcase - Live!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121088</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/watch_thq_nordic_10th_anniversary_showcase_-_live"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T18:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geoff Keighley and 'legendary franchises' promised.
The season for showcases, and Geoff Keighley gracing our screens, never ends. This time around it's THQ Nordic's 10th Anniversary Showcase, in which the publisher promises "the return of legendary franchises and sequels to beloved games" with six new reveals.
The show kicks off at noon PT / 3pm ET / 8pm BST / 9pm CEST, so find a comfy seat and a tasty beverage and join us for the festivities.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-18.04.6-lts</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-18.04.6-lts"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T18:14:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bylo vydáno Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS, tj. šesté opravné vydání Ubuntu 18.04 LTS s kódovým názvem Bionic Beaver (poznámky k vydání). Řešen je především problém s bootovaním předchozích instalačních obrazů se zapnutým Secure Bootem z důvodu revokace klíčů kvůli BootHole a dalším bezpečnostním chybám v zavaděči GRUB 2.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard Reduces Titty In World Of Warcraft, But Not Sexism At The Company]]></title>
        <id>1847697184</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/blizzard-reduces-titty-in-world-of-warcraft-but-not-se-1847697184"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The newest World of Warcraft update reduces the amount of titty that can be seen in the game. Unfortunately, no restitution for its gender-marginalized developers is in sight. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Players Are Mad Bungie's Gonna Enforce Fair Multiplayer Matchmaking]]></title>
        <id>1847696997</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-players-are-mad-bungies-gonna-enforce-fair-mu-1847696997"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T17:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Friday, Bungie will roll out matchmaking assistance for Destiny 2’s hardcore mode, Trials of Osiris. The intent, basically, is to make the multiplayer gauntlet a bit more fair for Guardians who continuously get thrashed. You’ll never believe this, I know, but some players are pissed about the prospect of being…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimenting Is Underway For Rust Code Within Mesa]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-Rust-2021-Experiment</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-Rust-2021-Experiment"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T17:39:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Longtime Mesa developer Karol Herbst who has worked extensively on the open-source NVIDIA "Nouveau" driver as well as the OpenCL/compute stack while being employed by Red Hat is now toying with the idea of Rust code inside Mesa...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS Released To Correct Broken Install Media]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-18.04.6-LTS-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-18.04.6-LTS-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T17:06:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The unplanned Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS release is available today that was made on short notice for addressing unbootable media with Ubuntu 18.04.5...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gas Station Simulator Is One Of Steam's Biggest Games Right Now, With Good Reason]]></title>
        <id>1847696557</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/gas-station-simulator-is-one-of-steams-biggest-games-ri-1847696557"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T17:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I first booted up Gas Station Simulator, a game that’s spent the last week tearing up the Steam charts, my first thought was “Christ, this place is a dump!” At the start of the game, you inherit a derelict gas station from your uncle, who I’m pretty sure is gang affiliated. Your goal is simple: pay back your…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallery: Is The Panasonic Q The Most Goshdarn Beautiful Nintendo Console Of All Time?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121064</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/gallery_is_the_panasonic_q_the_most_goshdarn_beautiful_nintendo_console_of_all_time"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shine get.
This week, the Nintendo GameCube turns 20. This eye-catching system may have struggled against the incredible might of the PlayStation 2, but few would argue that Sony's machine was more attractive on a purely physical level. The boxy GameCube, complete with its unusual travel handle, is a true design icon and its appealing aesthetics are perhaps one of the key reasons it remains so beloved, even after two decades.
However, it's easy to forget that an even more attractive variant of the GameCube exists – although, with reported sales of just 100,000 units, you can't be blamed for having never seen one in the flesh. The Panasonic Q follows on from Sharp's Twin Famicom – a Nintendo system that wasn't actually manufactured by Nintendo itself, but another company under licence – and for many collectors, is the crown jewel of Nintendo fandom.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Dead Cells update makes it more approachable to newcomers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-dead-cells-update-makes-it-more-approachable-to-newcomers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-dead-cells-update-makes-it-more-approachable-to-newcomers"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T16:31:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dead Cells has received yet another update, named Practice Makes Perfect, which adds a training area, powerful buffs called Aspects, and other more. The devs say the patch is focused "on improving the ease-of-use and learning curve for everyone (paticularly newcomers & occasional players), without altering the overall difficulty of the game." To facilitate this goal, all the new features are optional – allowing players to execute their sweet dodge rolls with the challenge they prefer.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skatebird Puts Cinnamon Roll Birds In A Bleh Skateboarding Game]]></title>
        <id>1847696269</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/skatebird-puts-cinnamon-roll-birds-in-a-bleh-skateboard-1847696269"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skatebird is a great idea. A skateboarding game starring adorable, puffy birds! Wonderful. But sadly, while the bird part of Skatebird is perfect, the skate part is a janky and frustrating mess. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The making of Dishonored: Death Of The Outsider, and how Arkane killed a god]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-making-of-dishonored-death-of-the-outsider-and-how-arkane-killed-a-god</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-making-of-dishonored-death-of-the-outsider-and-how-arkane-killed-a-god"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dishonored: Death Of The Outsider is a revenge and redemption tale, only here the target of your revenge is god. 'We're going to kill a god’ might seem like a well-trodden path in JRPG country, but Death Of The Outsider brings something new to the table. Here, the god is a trickster, a victim, and the source of the player's power. He's a figure that has come to define the Dishonored series as a whole, and is both revered and pitied by its players. So how, exactly, do you go about killing a god like this? I spoke to the developers at Arkane to find out. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hirun Cryer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 10 pouze za 12 €, super slevy až 91%!]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pořiďte si doživotní aktivační klíč k Windows 10 za 12,52 EUR na prodejním portálu GoodOffer24.com. Kromě toho nástrojů produktivity od Microsoftu zde lze získat i hry a další software. Nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód  AX30.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ČTÚ má nový certifikovaný měřič rychlosti NetTest]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42827</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ctu-ma-novy-certifikovany-meric-rychlosti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ČTÚ má nový měřič rychlosti připojení k internetu NetTest. Starý NetMetr bude dál fungovat pod CZ.NIC. NetTest nabízí testování jen přes webové rozhraní, NetMetr měl i mobilní aplikace. NetTest je stejně jako NetMetr založen na open-source řešení rakouského telekomunikačního regulátora RTR. Licence NetTestu by měla být Apache 2.0, ale kód zatím zveřejněn nebyl.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop’s Villain Group Chat Is A Perfect Mess]]></title>
        <id>1847695907</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/deathloop-s-villain-group-chat-is-a-perfect-mess-1847695907"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop does a lot of things right. One of those things is chat logs. When you’re not going on a murder spree, you’re reading through the private DMs of those you just killed. Arkane has done a superb job of imbuing its villains with flair and personality from beyond the grave, thanks to one of the best in-game…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There's A Hidden Secret Inside The LEGO Super Mario Question Block Set]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121086</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/theres_a_hidden_secret_inside_the_lego_super_mario_question_block_set"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And a lovely Easter Egg, too.
It's weird to give a spoiler warning for a LEGO set, but this article will obviously spoil elements of the secrets and surprises in the Question Block. If you want to go in fresh, stop reading already.
Ever since the LEGO Super Mario Question Block set was announced, we've been wondering... what's up with that little flap at the front? This one:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop codes: safe, door, and machine code locations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-safe-codes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-safe-codes"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:18:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where are all of the codes to open safes and doors and unlock machine terminals in Deathloop? In true Arkane tradition, Deathloop is full of safes and locked doors that can only be accessed with three- and four-digit codes. Some of the secrets hidden within are essential to progressing the story, while others just contain some good loot. Some of the Visionaries have also used codes to protect some of their machines, which you'll need to override in order to bypass their security.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultimate Audio Bang #14: big meaty guns slapping meat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-14-big-meaty-guns-slapping-meat</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-14-big-meaty-guns-slapping-meat"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:10:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Predictably, Imogen and I begin this week's episode of Ultimate Audio Bang by getting excited about Deathloop before realising that there's plenty of other newsy bits to cover. Listen to get our hot thoughts on the Call Of Duty: Vanguard reveal, Battlefield 2042's delay, the Overwatch League using an early build of Overwatch 2 in 2022, and plenty more shootery things.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wuchang: Fallen Feathers looks like a Chinese take on Bloodborne]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-looks-like-a-chinese-take-on-bloodborne</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-looks-like-a-chinese-take-on-bloodborne"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:09:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following fawning over the Monkey King violence of Black Myth: Wukong, the latest upcoming Chinese game to turn heads with Souls-inspired action and shiny graphics might be Wuchang: Fallen Feathers. A new gameplay trailer released today gives a long look at a sexy babe fighting against plague-mutated people using her melee weapons, firearms, and gut-gouging counters. Yeah, feeling a lot of Bloodborne inspiration here. Have a look below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arctic CPU coolers to get free mounting kit upgrades for Intel LGA 1700 socket]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arctic-cpu-coolers-to-get-free-mounting-kit-upgrades-for-intel-lga-1700-socket</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arctic-cpu-coolers-to-get-free-mounting-kit-upgrades-for-intel-lga-1700-socket"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:09:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We haven’t seen much of Intel Alder Lake so far, despite being set for release in a matter of weeks.  One thing we do know is that like the majority of Intel’s last few chip family releases, the desktop contingent of these 12th-gen processors will need a brand-new motherboard socket: LGA 1700. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Benchmarking has completely ruined my Steam play time profile]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/benchmarking-has-completely-ruined-my-steam-play-time-profile</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/benchmarking-has-completely-ruined-my-steam-play-time-profile"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:09:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don't know if you know this about me, but I love a good list. For the past ten years, I've kept a detailed spreadsheet of all the games I've ever played. The bulk of it catalogues games by platform, but I've also kept a list of all the games I play per year since 2010. Call me crazy, but this document is a great source of joy for me. I love being able to look back and see when I last played a certain game, and it's also interesting to me to see just how many of them I manage to play each year. I also keep similar lists for films I see at the cinema, the books I read, as well as the plays and musicals I see at the theatre. I'm not kidding. I really do love a good list. 
Perhaps unsurprisingly, I'm also fascinated by the amount of time I spend playing games, too (and yes, I do have a list for this as well - albeit only for my Nintendo Wii games at the moment). Steam, of course, keeps excellent track of your play time - and because it's always open on my PC, there's no need to keep my own version of it. I can just load up my Steam profile and gaze lovingly at the hours and minutes in my All Games tab. Except I can't anymore, because four years' worth of professional benchmarking has absolutely ruined my play time figures. It upsets me. Because I haven't really spent 130 hours playing Shadow Of The Tomb Raider. Or 38 hours playing Doom. It's all benchmarking, and I wish there was a way to scrub these games clean again so everything can be nice and neat and orderly again, and most of all, accurate. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jackbox Party Pack 8 Is Coming To Switch This Autumn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121083</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/jackbox_party_pack_8_is_coming_to_switch_this_autumn"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Including a new take on Drawful.
The Jackbox Party Pack 8 is almost here, and what do you mean you didn't know there were already eight of them?
The super-successful minigame collections have been a mainstay of game-savvy friend groups ever since Jackbox branched out from their "You Don't Know Jack" trivia games into a broader range of offerings, and JPP8 follows on from the crowdpleasing Party Pack 7.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Give yourself a good day by playing Webbed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/give-yourself-a-good-day-by-playing-webbed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/give-yourself-a-good-day-by-playing-webbed"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T14:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was 3am and Hucks the cellar spider was finally surrounded by, instead of carrying, her wee hatchlings. Clarice, her slightly dim neighbour, was resting after another hour spent fruitlessly stumbling around after an even dafter flying thingy that would eventually blunder right into her face.

Playing Webbed seemed inevitable for someone who watches her ceiling spiders when she can't sleep or finish an article. But within about a minute of playing, it became clear that it's the kind of game that will bring joy to almost anyone. Webbed is immediately brilliant.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ni No Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom - Prince’s Edition Is Out Now On Switch, Here's The Launch Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121076</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/ni_no_kuni_ii_revenant_kingdom_-_princers_edition_is_out_now_on_switch_heres_the_launch_trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DLC included.
It's been quite the wait for Switch fans – Ni No Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom first released on PS4 back in March 2018 – but the chance to see Level 5's acclaimed RPG on Nintendo's system has finally arrived.
Technically released as the 'Prince's Edition' on Switch, the game tells the story of Evan Pettwhisker Tildrum, a kid who lost his promised throne in the kingdom of Ding Dong Dell and sets himself on a quest to establish a new kingdom.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SUDA51 Would Love To Revive A Lesser-Known Nintendo Classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121061</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/suda51_would_love_to_revive_a_lesser-known_nintendo_classic"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T14:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["I  know deep down inside me it’s not okay for me to make a Zelda game".
As you may have already seen, we've recently shared a video interview (and the full transcript if you prefer) with the one and only SUDA51, a hugely influential developer that recently brought us No More Heroes III on the Switch. We delve into the series, in terms of its history and future, and also ask the question plenty of fans have had for a while - how about Travis in Smash?
We also asked what Nintendo franchise, given the numerous choices, SUDA51 would like to work on. He shows some notable self awareness before identifying an IP that could actually be a rather good fit.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: SUDA51 On No More Heroes And The Future Of Travis Touchdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120873</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/video_suda51_on_no_more_heroes_and_the_future_of_travis_touchdown"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grasshopper has bigger plans.
The recent launch of No More Heroes III completed the journey of series protagonist Travis Touchdown, capping off a trilogy of games (plus a spin-off) that began back on the Wii. Fans of iconic game director SUDA51 had waited a while for this one, and apparently this game will be his final outing with Travis.
With the entire Travis 'saga' now available on Switch, we recently sat down with the director to discuss the future of Mr Touchdown, saying goodbye to the series, and the Nintendo IP he'd enjoy remaking given the chance. We recommend you watch the video of our interview with SUDA above, but if you prefer the written word, we can accommodate you there, too. We're generous like that. Enjoy!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poetic Adventure The Lightbringer Arrives Soon On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121071</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/poetic_adventure_the_lightbringer_arrives_soon_on_switch"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demo out now on the eShop.
Back in the Spring we highlighted The Lightbringer, which has been developed by Rock Square Thunder and will be released by Zordix Publishing. It's an adventure puzzle-platformer that looks rather promising, and an interesting touch is that story narration comes from the protagonist's sister and is fully voiced in verse.
The Lightbringer pitches itself as featuring an old-school adventure, a heartfelt story, and a mix of combat and puzzles to solve. The poem from the trailer has also been transcribed and shared.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Current State Of Intel Discrete Graphics On Linux: Almost "Fully Functional"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-DG1-Status-XDC2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-DG1-Status-XDC2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T13:25:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with bringing up DG2/Alchemist graphics card support on Linux, Intel engineers have been working to square away their support for the DG1 developer graphics card. This week thanks to XDC2021 is a fresh status update about what is working with this initial Intel graphics card on their open-source driver and what remains in the works...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck dev kit screenshots show a likely Big Picture replacement, SteamOS 3 allegedly leaks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-dev-kit-screenshots-show-a-likely-big-picture-replacement-steamos-3-allegedly-leaks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-dev-kit-screenshots-show-a-likely-big-picture-replacement-steamos-3-allegedly-leaks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T13:03:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whelp, that didn’t take long. Steam Deck dev kits were only sent out to game developers this week, and it looks like Valve’s handheld PC is already getting picked apart. That’s according to SteamDB creator Pavel Djundik, who tweeted screenshots of the Steam Deck UI before claiming the entire SteamOS 3 operating system has been leaked.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Eastward - A Creative Zelda-Like Adventure With Absolutely Killer Art]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120829</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/eastward"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[East? I thought you said Weast.
The line between an homage and a copycat can often be a blurry one, and it feels like all too often that new games borrowing ideas from old games fall on the wrong side of it. Instead of offering creative new takes on favored concepts, these games are more content to prod you with a sharp elbow as they say “’member?” over and over. Eastward is not one of those games. The inaugural release from Shanghai-based Pixpil smartly integrates gameplay and story ideas from beloved classics while still managing to feel like an original and well-executed adventure.
Eastward follows the story of John, a gruff man of action not words, and his companion, Sam, an energetic and white-haired little girl who he found underground. The two live happily together in a small subterranean village and enjoy a quasi father/daughter relationship, but things quickly take a turn when certain events lead to them arriving at the surface that they were told is such a dangerous and awful place. It turns out that things aren’t quite as bad up there as they were led to believe, although there’s a mysterious force called miasma that’s slowly rolling over the land and destroying everything in its path.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Increasing Importance Of ACPI Platform Profiles With Today's Throttle-Happy Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Platform-Profiles-Axboe</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Platform-Profiles-Axboe"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T12:58:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As covered several times going back to the end of last year, ACPI Platform Profile support has materialized in recent versions of the Linux kernel for the core infrastructure and implementations that work with the latest laptops from the likes of Dell, Lenovo, ASUS, and HP. This platform profile support is becoming increasingly important with expressing your power/cooling/performance preference so that your laptop behaves as one would expect...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: IKEA's Gaming Range Has The Essentials, Like A Mug Holder And Neck Pillow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121068</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/random_ikeas_gaming_range_has_the_essentials_like_a_mug_holder_and_neck_pillow"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Batman-chic.

While the term 'gamer' is becoming increasingly vague, which is a positive sign that everyone from small children to retirees can love video games as a perfectly normal part of life, the conventional use of the phrase is still a segment of the market relentlessly targeted by companies. IKEA is another joining in, creating a range of gaming furniture that seems to be focused on competitive PC-centric gaming, and of course streamers.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clive Sinclair, who brought us the ZX Spectrum, has died]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clive-sinclair-who-brought-us-the-zx-spectrum-has-died</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/clive-sinclair-who-brought-us-the-zx-spectrum-has-died"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T12:09:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clive Sinclair, the founder of the company which brought us the ZX Spectrum computer, has died. The first encounter with PC gaming for many of a certain age in the UK wasn't through any beige box MS-DOS or Windows, it was on that futuristic wee black keyboard with rubbery keys and a colourful stripe, which loaded software from cassette tapes. I'm too young to have seen its glory days but I think the first PC game I played was a Speccy shoot 'em up, a magical experience I didn't believe would actually work when I first saw my pal plug a tape deck into a keyboard.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tails Of Iron review: a fun 2D Soulslike with a bit too much padding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tails-of-iron-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tails-of-iron-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T12:04:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As enquiring minds already know, rats are very cute. I've not had pet rats myself, but a bunch of my friends have. Rats have lovely little pin-prick hands and feet, and they will give you wiffly-nose kisses while they assess whether your hair is worth exploring or not.
The rats in Tails Of Iron are cute. Little 2D inhabitants of a feudal rat kingdom, where they get milk from insects that look like cows, and royal succession is determined in trial by combat - which you, Prince Redgi, win, and shortly thereafter become King Redgi when your dad is murdered by frogs right in front of you. Let the amphibian bodies hit the floor. Time to kick this RPG into a side-on soulslike experience. Slice open a frog belly and see the guts spill out. These rats are cute, but also u wot? U wot? Say that again m8. Say that to my face. I'll 'ave you.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LVFS Serves Up 2+ Million Firmware Downloads In The Past Month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LVFS-2-Million-Downloads</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LVFS-2-Million-Downloads"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T11:54:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux Vendor Firmware Service (LVFS) in conjunction with FWUPD for offering easy-to-deploy firmware updates on Linux continues its meteoric rise...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead Cells 'Practice Makes Perfect' Update Makes The Game Easier, But Only If You Want That]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121058</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/dead_cells_practice_makes_perfect_update_makes_the_game_easier_but_only_if_you_want_that"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Aspects feature adds "incredibly strong powers".
Motion Twin and Evil Empire have released the 25th – yes, twenty-fifth – update for Dead Cells. Called 'Practice Makes Perfect', the update intends to make things a little easier for new players or those who want to have a gentler time exploring everything the game has to offer.
One new addition is the training room, a space where players can practice their gameplay by taking on all the mobs and bosses you've encountered in-game. There are presets available which can artificially reflect the bestiary of each biome, and you can also practice against all of the bosses in their own environments.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox bude v Ubuntu 21.10 jako snap]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42826</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-bude-v-ubuntu-21-10-jako-snap/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T10:50:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla a Canonical se dohodly, že Firefox bude v příštím vydání Ubuntu 21.10 dostupný jen jako balíček snap a ne jako doposud balíček deb. Výhodou je, že snap bude vytvářet přímo Mozilla a aktualizovaný Firefox bude tedy dostupný hned v den vydání. V současnosti Canonicalu trvá několik dní vyrobit deb balíček. Snap bude dostupný pro architektury amd64, arm64 a armhf.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zedd Just Showed The Unfairness Of Japan's Travel Ban]]></title>
        <id>1847694183</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/zedd-just-showed-how-unfair-japans-travel-ban-is-1847694183"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right now, nineteen prefectures in Japan are under a state of emergency until September 30. But one of them, Chiba Prefecture, will host the Supersonic music festival at a baseball stadium this weekend. Zedd, along with Alan Walker and Steve Aoki, are among the international DJs flown in for the event.  
“Finally made…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Father Of Home Computing Sir Clive Sinclair Dies Aged 81]]></title>
        <id>1847694156</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sir-clive-sinclair-father-of-home-computing-dies-aged-1847694156"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s hard to overstate the importance of Sir Clive Sinclair’s role in the world of computing. His inventing the ZX Spectrum home computer in 1980 radically changed the masses’ perception of, and access to, computers. His work created the path to not only gaming, but also the creation of games, by regular people. He…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japan's Getting A Stunning Zelda: Skyward Sword Soundtrack With An Adorable Music Box]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121055</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/japans_getting_a_stunning_zelda_skyward_sword_soundtrack_with_an_adorable_music_box"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We need it.
For the 500th time this year, we're here to express our excruciating jealousy over the amazing things Nintendo fans in Japan get treated to. This time, it's a stunning Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword soundtrack collection.
From Nippon Columbia, the new soundtrack will be available to Japanese fans in either a Regular or First Press Limited edition. Both come with five discs of music from the game, with 187 songs featured in total, but the Limited edition also includes a "luxury" outer box and a truly beautiful music box which plays 'Ballad of the Goddess'.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KWinFT Continues Working On WLROOTS Render, Library Split]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KWinFT-2021-WLROOTS-Continues</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KWinFT-2021-WLROOTS-Continues"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T09:55:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KWinFT as a fork of KDE's KWin X11/Wayland compositor code continues making progress on driving fundamental display improvements and ironing out the Wayland support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple Games Are Now Working With RADV's Ray-Tracing Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Ray-Tracing-Multi-Games</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Ray-Tracing-Multi-Games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T09:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not only is Intel progressing with its open-source ray-tracing driver support but the Mesa Radeon Vulkan driver "RADV" has been rounding out its RT code too and now has multiple games correctly rendering...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Diamond And Pearl Remake Pre-Orders Include ﻿Shiny Zacian/Zamazenta Bonus In South ﻿Korea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121054</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pokemon_diamond_and_pearl_remake_pre-orders_include_shiny_zacianzamazenta_bonus_in_south_korea"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's hoping for a worldwide release.
South Korean fans who pre-order the upcoming Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl games for Nintendo Switch will receive a shiny version of either Zacian or Zamazenta, it's been announced.
As reported by Serebii, the shiny Pokémon will be distributed via a code given to any players who pre-order either of the two new games or the Brilliant Diamond & Shining Pearl Double Pack. The codes are valid for use with Pokémon Sword and Shield and will be sent to qualifying buyers from 19th November through to 31st December.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise Adds Mega Man's Rush In New Collab]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121051</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/monster_hunter_rise_adds_mega_mans_rush_in_new_collab"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And you don't have long to wait.
Capcom has announced that Monster Hunter Rise is about to be treated to an exciting collaboration, teaming up with none other than Mega Man.
From 24th September, you'll find that Mega Man's faithful robotic sidekick Rush arrives in-game as a Palamute layered armour set. As you can see from the trailer above, Rush comes with all sorts of tricks that Mega Man players will already be familiar with, including the ability to throw you up into the air to reach higher ground.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox ve formátu snap v Ubuntu Desktopu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/firefox-ve-formatu-snap-v-ubuntu-desktopu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/firefox-ve-formatu-snap-v-ubuntu-desktopu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T07:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři Ubuntu oznámili, že v Ubuntu Desktopu bude Firefox ve formátu deb nahrazen Firefoxem ve formátu snap vydávaným přímo Mozillou. Pravděpodobně již ve verzi 21.10.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vytvořte si bezpečnou VPN pomocí OpenVPN (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41285</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vytvorte-si-bezpecnou-vpn-pomoci-openvpn-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T07:26:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VPN umožňuje bezpečně propojit různá zařízení pomocí šifrovaných tunelů. Umožňuje také zapojit uživatele do vnitřní sítě přes zabezpečený přístupový bod. Na našem školení VPN a bezpečné připojení k síti s OpenVPN si prakticky ukážeme, jak to celé nastavit a zprovoznit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V kinech AMC bude možné platit kryptoměnami]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42825</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/v-kinech-amc-bude-mozne-platit-cryptomenami/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T06:40:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMC Theaters je největším řetězcem kin na světě, má v Evropě 358 kin a v USA 620. Novinka se však týká jen kin v USA. Před měsícem bylo oznámeno, že do konce tohoto roku bude možné online platit lístky a předplatné pomocí Bitcoinu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zemřel Sir Clive Sinclair, tvůrci ZX Spectra bylo 81 let]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42824</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/zemrel-sir-clive-sinclair-tvurci-zx-spectra-bylo-81-let/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T06:04:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V Londýně včera ve věku 81 let zemřel Sir Clive Sinclair, britský vynálezce a podnikatel. Známý je především jako tvůrce domácích počítačů ZX Spectrum. O jeho odchodu informoval britský deník The Guardian, s odkazem na informace od dcery Belindy. Příčinou jeho smrti byla dlouhodobá nemoc.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's PSH ISHTP Driver Readied On Linux For Systems Wanting To Forego A Traditional EC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-PSH-ISHTP-ECLite</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-PSH-ISHTP-ECLite"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It looks like Intel's ISHTP_ECLITE driver will be ready for mainlining in Linux 5.16 as a driver for newer systems skipping out on a traditional embedded control (EC) and instead using this EC-like IP as part of their Programmable Service Engine subsystem...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rover Replies]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2517/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2517/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ikea's New Gaming Collection Looks Pretty Good]]></title>
        <id>1847692859</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/ikeas-new-gaming-collection-looks-pretty-good-1847692859"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T00:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While people have been using Ikea stuff in the gaming space forever—right now I’m sitting on an Ikea office chair and using an Ikea desk—the Swedish company has never gone to the trouble of releasing dedicated gaming furniture before. That’s about to change

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New WipEout Game Announced, Only It's Not On Console]]></title>
        <id>1847692615</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-wipeout-game-announced-only-its-not-on-console-1847692615"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T23:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WipeOut is, very quietly, one of the most important video game series to have ever lived, thanks to its role in selling the original PlayStation as something genuinely “cool.” But it’s a franchise that has fallen on hard times of late.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tales Of Arise is the fastest selling game in the series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tales-of-arise-is-the-fastest-selling-game-in-the-series</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tales-of-arise-is-the-fastest-selling-game-in-the-series"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T22:36:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tales games stretch back to 1995's Tales Of Phantasia, but the latest entry, Tales Of Arise, is now the fastest selling in the series. In less than a week, it has sold a million copies, Bandai Namco say.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 15 Best Games on PC]]></title>
        <id>5878852</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-12-best-games-on-pc-5878852"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T22:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PC gamers have got a pretty great thing going. Interesting, experimental indie games? Yup. Complex strategy simulations? Totally. The shiniest, prettiest versions of big-budget console games? They get a lot of those, too. Let’s say you’ve recently joined the ranks of the PC elite. Which games should you install? Start…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kotaku Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Mint má nové webové stránky]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-mint-ma-nove-webove-stranky</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-mint-ma-nove-webove-stranky"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T22:01:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Mint má nové webové stránky. Pro porovnání stránky z minulého týdne.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kanón na vrabce: recenze herního notebooku Tuxedo Stellaris 15]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15653</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kanon-na-vrabce-recenze-herniho-notebooku-tuxedo-stellaris-15/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Se značkou Tuxedo jsme se zde již párkrát setkali. Recenzí prošly dvě generace ultrabooků řady Infinity Book. Nyní ale na redakční stůl zamířil stroj ze zcela opačného spektra, a to herní Tuxedo Stellaris 15. Jak dopadl?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Škuta)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Titan Quest and Jagged Alliance are free to keep right now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/titan-quest-and-jagged-alliance-are-free-to-keep-right-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/titan-quest-and-jagged-alliance-are-free-to-keep-right-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T21:41:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[THQ Nordic are celebrating their 10th anniversary by giving away free games via Steam. Surprisingly enduring action RPG Titan Quest is currently free-to-keep, and so is the ancient turn-based tactics of Jagged Alliance. 

Then, if you want something a little more modern, the real-time tactical stealth of Desperados 3 is free-to-try for the next three days.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Konami Rolls Out Loot Box Pre-Orders]]></title>
        <id>1847691729</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/konami-rolls-out-loot-box-pre-orders-1847691729"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T21:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the summer, Konami announced its killing of the Pro Evolution Soccer brand (known as Winning Eleven in Japan) by morphing the popular franchise into the free-to-play eFootball.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deno 1.14]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/deno-1.14</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/deno-1.14"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T21:19:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deno (Wikipedie), běhové prostředí (runtime) pro JavaScript a TypeScript, bylo vydáno ve verzi 1.14. Přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Please Ikea, make me some grownup gaming furniture]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-ikea-make-me-some-grownup-gaming-furniture</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-ikea-make-me-some-grownup-gaming-furniture"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T21:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ikea, makers of large, boring Lego projects for adults, are launching a range of gaming furniture. The set, created in collaboration with Republic Of Gamers, includes desks, chairs, streaming accessories and what The Guardian describes as a "multi-functional cushion/blanket."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zemřel Clive Sinclair, tvůrce počítače ZX Spectrum]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/zemrel-clive-sinclair-tvurce-pocitace-zx-spectrum</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/zemrel-clive-sinclair-tvurce-pocitace-zx-spectrum"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T20:59:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes ve věku 81 let zemřel Clive Sinclair, známý především jako tvůrce počítače ZX Spectrum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Could Use More Help Improving & Addressing Its Security]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Security-Help-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Security-Help-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T20:10:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those reading Phoronix over the years likely know the X.Org Server has had an increasing number of vulnerabilities come to light in recent times and statements by security researchers like the security being even worse than it looks. Given the age of the X.Org/X11 codebase and many components being rather unmaintained these days, the security situation isn't that great combined with a lack of manpower. The security topic was under the spotlight today at the XDC2021 conference...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[God Of War Ragnarök Will Wrap Story Because Trilogies Take Too Long]]></title>
        <id>1847691005</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-will-wrap-story-because-trilogies-t-1847691005"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T20:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developer Sony Santa Monica has confirmed that God of War Ragnarök will complete the series’ Norse story when it launches next year, wrapping up Kratos’ bout with deities like Freya and Thor in just two games.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard's beta opens to all this weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-beta-opens-to-all-this-weekend</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-beta-opens-to-all-this-weekend"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T20:07:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard has already had a beta on PlayStation, and if you've pre-ordered the game you can play it right now on PC. On Saturday however, the beta will open up to everyone with a Battle.net account. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprising No One, Pathfinder Still Incredibly Confusing In Video Game Form]]></title>
        <id>1847690732</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/surprising-no-one-pathfinder-still-incredibly-confusin-1847690732"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous, the recently released character RPG developed by Owlcat Games, seems really neat. I like the writing so far and the character work seems solid. But holy shit, it has possibly the most overwhelming character creator I’ve ever touched. If your game asks me to process 25 different…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Fan Says They're Suing Devs For Changing A Character]]></title>
        <id>1847690358</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/genshin-impact-fan-says-theyre-suing-devs-for-changing-1847690358"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact got a strong new character in September, Raiden Shogun, and she’s already sending waves through the player community. While most of the reception has been positive, a vocal minority believe that developer miHoYo misled fans expecting Raiden to work well with an existing playable character.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube Duo Find $100,000 Of Vintage Games In Hoarder’s Abandoned House]]></title>
        <id>1847690206</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/youtube-duo-find-100-000-of-vintage-games-in-hoarder-s-1847690206"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like a real-life Tomb Raider run sans picturesque vistas from an ancient civilization, a pair of YouTuber game hunters found themselves in an extremely messy room that had been locked for close to 20 years. But amid the filth, they found a treasure trove of factory-sealed video games, including mainstream hits like …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Saga Behind The New PS5's Heatsink, Explained]]></title>
        <id>1847689679</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-saga-behind-the-new-ps5s-heatsink-explained-1847689679"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T18:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last few weeks, much hay has been made about the PlayStation 5, specifically a new revision of the Sony console that includes a smaller heatsink. Early reports criticized this change for leading to increased temperatures during operation, but fears that this would impact performance have mostly been put to…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenZFS 2.1.1 Arrives As A Big Point Release]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-2.1.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-2.1.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T18:17:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the big OpenZFS 2.1 release from July that brought Distributed SPARE RAID, a compatibility property for pools, and other new features, OpenZFS 2.1.1 is available today as a follow-up release for this open-source ZFS file-system implementation for Linux and FreeBSD systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Returnal’s ‘Tentacle Tech’ Is So Real—And So Scary]]></title>
        <id>1847689743</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/why-returnal-s-tentacle-tech-is-so-real-and-so-scary-1847689743"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Returnal, the PlayStation 5 time loop game that isn’t the one everyone’s talking about this week, might seem like it’s about escaping a temporally out-of-whack exoplanet. But really, it’s about getting your lunch money repeatedly stolen by malevolent tentacle monsters. Much of the game’s unsettling vibe comes from…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Talks More About Their Open-Source Vulkan Ray-Tracing Bring-Up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Vulkan-RT-XDC2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Vulkan-RT-XDC2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T17:42:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prominent Intel open-source Vulkan Linux driver developer Jason Ekstrand presented at today's X.Org Developers Conference (XDC2021) about their work on enabling Vulkan ray-tracing support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop Players All Agree: The Dedicated Kick Button Rules]]></title>
        <id>1847688695</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/deathloop-players-all-agree-the-dedicated-kick-button-1847688695"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T16:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There I was, creeping along a cliff on the outside of a big castle-like structure when I saw a single enemy, completely alone. He was standing on the edge of the cliff with his back to me. This setup ranked high on my “kickable moment meter,” a situation which routinely leads to disappointment. How often have games…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to overclock your GPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-overclock-gpu</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-overclock-gpu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T16:26:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learning how to overclock your GPU sounds like it should be one of gaming PC ownership’s essential skills, like knowing how to clean your PC or how to check CPU temperature. And why not? Coaxing extra performance out of a component will get you more frames-per-second at no additional charge, and you can do it with just about every gaming card under the sun. Even the best graphics cards that come with factory overclocks will leave headroom for additional gains to unlock yourself.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim has added a hot tub for Vikings to unwind]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-has-added-a-hot-tub-for-vikings-to-unwind</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-has-added-a-hot-tub-for-vikings-to-unwind"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T16:22:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trying to survive in purgatory isn't easy, having to hunt and build and craft everything you need to slay mighty mythical beasts. Thankfully, the Vikings of Valheim can now relax with their pals in a hot tub, one of many fancy household items added in the 'Home & Hearth' early access update today. Sure sure it brings new weapons and new creatures and balance changes and things too, but: hot tub!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Yervha: how to beat Deathloop's fiendish trivia machine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-how-to-beat-yervha</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-how-to-beat-yervha"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T15:02:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are the correct answers to the Yervha's questions in Deathloop? The Yervha, a.k.a. Queen of Riddles, is a trivia machine in Deathloop. If you can answer all 10 of its questions correctly you'll win a prize! A very modest prize, but a prize nonetheless. And who doesn't love a good trivia challenge? You certainly seem to, since you're here!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 156: the best doctors special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-156-the-best-doctors-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-156-the-best-doctors-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The recording of this episode of The Electronic Wireless Show podcast turned out to be unfortunately cursed with technical issues, which means I am (probably noticeably) tired and grumpy, and don't let Matthew and Nate reproduce their witty banter from the first time we tried to record. No cold open! Still, nothing to cheer me up like some good bedside manner from a doctor. Oh no, it turns out all game doctors are awful!
We discuss our favourite game medical types, and also discuss why doctors in games are so often evil baddies. The saga of Matthew and his teeth continues, as well as envisioning Matthew as a clown who just turns up to your kids birthday party smeared in his wife's lipstick, drinks all your Fanta, and leaves again. Now that's malpractice.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gamedec review: a great cyberpunk concept undone by a bloated script]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gamedec-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gamedec-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the stealth-oriented Foreclosed to the twin-sticky The Ascent, there has been a bumper crop of cyberpunk shooters this year, their endless gun fests typically set amidst a gaudy onslaught of neon-tinged billboards, metallic skyscrapers and indiscriminately-placed Asian motifs.
In spite of its roots, Gamedec initially seems like a reprieve from this recent blitz of cyberpunk games. It sticks steadfastly to its self-imposed, zero-combat rule, instead leaning heavily towards the genre’s crime fiction elements. That’s because in Gamedec, you’re a detective actually carrying out proper investigative work, rather than simply pointing the smokey end of a gun towards your problems. You’ll sleuth around for clues, make deductions based on your discoveries, and draw conclusions that will shape the outcome of your cases.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khee Hoon Chan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Deathloop trinkets: what every trinket does and which are best for your loadout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-trinkets</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-trinkets"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T13:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are the best trinkets in Deathloop? Trinkets might sound frivolous, but they are in fact Deathloop's answer to mods: applying them provides potentially very powerful combat buffs, and therefore they're actually very important. Deathloop's Trinkets come in two varieties: Character Trinkets (personal mods applied to your player character) and Weapon Trinkets (mods which can be applied individually to every gun in your possession).
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.23 Beta Released As The 25th Anniversary Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-5.23-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-5.23-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T13:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was in October of 1996 that the KDE desktop environment was founded and as such with marking twenty-five years since its creation, the forthcoming Plasma 5.23 is being advertised as the "25th Anniversary Edition" for the desktop...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MechWarrior 5: Mercenaries gets marriage, melee and mech-switching with its next DLC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mechwarrior-5-mercenaries-gets-marriage-melee-and-mech-switching-with-its-next-dlc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mechwarrior-5-mercenaries-gets-marriage-melee-and-mech-switching-with-its-next-dlc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don't you just hate it when you're getting married to secure an alliance with a certain faction, but another faction insists on existing in-between your borders? Don't worry, it's a simple fix: send in an army of mechs to conquer them, then you and your betrothed get even more space to share! 


This is pretty much the plot of the next MechWarrior 5: Mercenaries DLC, Legend Of The Kestrel Lancers. It's arriving on September 23rd alongside a free update that will finally let players punch other mechs in the face. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache HTTP Server (httpd) 2.4.49]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/apache-http-server-httpd-2.4.49</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/apache-http-server-httpd-2.4.49"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T12:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 2.4.49 svobodného multiplatformního webového serveru Apache (httpd). Řešeno je také 5 bezpečnostních chyb (CVE-2021-40438, CVE-2021-39275, CVE-2021-36160, CVE-2021-34798 a CVE-2021-33193). Více o CVE-2021-33193 s CVSS 7.5 v článku HTTP/2: The Sequel is Always Worse.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nový typ kybernetického útoku: zneužitím platforem proxyware]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42821</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/novy-typ-kybernetickeho-utoku-zneuzitim-platforem-proxyware/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T12:28:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Útočníci na internetu vytrvale hledají nové způsoby, jak nelegálně vydělat peníze. Poznatky Cisco Talos ukazují, že stále častěji se tak děje na platformách, které umožňují sdílení síťového provozu, zvaných proxyware, jako jsou Honeygain, IPRoyal Pawns, Nanowire, Peer2Profit nebo PacketStream. Ty ve špatných rukou umožňují využívat konektivitu uživatelů bez jejich vědomí, protože běží na pozadí na infikovaném zařízení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unicode 14.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/unicode-14.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/unicode-14.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T12:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Standard Unicode 14.0 byl finalizován. Přibylo 838 znaků: podpora několika jazyků, zápis znamenného zpěvu a 37 nových emoji. Doplněny byly také doprovodné specifikace, např. dělení znaků a zalamování řádků.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deltarune Chapter 2 continues the Undertale follow-up tomorrow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deltarune-chapter-2-continues-the-undertale-follow-up-tomorrow</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deltarune-chapter-2-continues-the-undertale-follow-up-tomorrow"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:54:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week we'll get to play the second chapter of Deltarune, the neither-sequel-nor-prequel-but-maybe-related follow-up to Undertale, creator Toby Fox has announced. Surprise!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 best battle royale games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-battle-royale-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-battle-royale-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:06:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Outlast the rest of the competition and emerge the last person standing, that's the motto for the best battle royale games out there. Often there's a big circle of poison gas pushing people closer together, or like, everyone parachutes in for some reason. Some don't feature any of these things, and opt for obstacle courses, or zany community creations instead. You may have thought battle royale games were quite one-note, but they're actually quite varied. So below I've rounded up some of the best ways to prove you're the fittest survivor of them all.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skatebird review: tiny hawks win the day in this wonky skating game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skatebird-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skatebird-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:02:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skatebird is simultaneously a homage to the Tony Hawk games of old and a celebration of just how stupid birds can be. It's the arcadey kind of kickflipper, handling more like THUG than a Skate game. But don't expect the truly smooth flow of the Hawkster's outings. There's plenty of wobbly physics on show here, much of it intentional and jokey (as you'd expect from a game that seems to have resulted entirely from a single pun). But some of it perhaps not. Still, it's hard to hate on these feathery ones when they squawk so pure, and when their taste in music is im-peck-able.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Linux 5.15-rc1 Causing A New Slowdown... Here's A Look]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30531</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30531"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As usual when the Linux 5.15 merge window began wrapping up, I set out to dive into its performance to see what is in store for this next version of the kernel and whether there was any regressions or other performance changes worth noting. Linux 5.15 overall has been in good shape for the "-rc1" state except noticing that code compilation workloads were taking longer on multiple Linux 5.15-rc1-running systems than Linux 5.14 or prior. Seeing it across multiple systems and a very real-world regression, it was worth bisecting and looking closer so here are the details.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 To Add Quirk For The Steam Deck, Other DRM-Misc-Next Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=First-DRM-Misc-Next-For-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=First-DRM-Misc-Next-For-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T09:22:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the Linux 5.15 merge window out of the way, the first drm-misc-next pull request has been sent in to DRM-Next for staging until the Linux 5.16 merge window opens up about two months from now...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa's LLVMpipe + Lavapipe Land FP16 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LLVMpipe-Lavapipe-FP16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LLVMpipe-Lavapipe-FP16"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest work landing for Mesa 21.3 is supporting FP16 within the LLVM-based software driver code namely for the LLVMpipe Gallium3D OpenGL and Lavapipe Vulkan drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ITWorkshop v Plzni: PHP FFI aneb proč (ne)volat C kód z vašich webovek]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42820</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/itworkshop-v-plzni-php-ffi-aneb-proc-ne-volat-c-kod-z-vasich-webovek/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T08:31:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dne 29. září 2021 od 18:00 společnost PeoplePath pořádá IT workshop s názvem PHP FFI aneb proč (ne)volat C kód z vašich webovek. Akce se koná v salonku v restauraci U Salzmannů v Plzni. Drobné občerstvení a pivo jsou samozřejmostí a vstupné je zdarma.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: PeoplePath)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Amazing American Circus review: I hate to say it, but there are better shows in town]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-amazing-american-circus-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-amazing-american-circus-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By the time Henry Ford rolled up to see my show, I was ready to pack my trunk and say goodbye to the circus. I’d been ready a long time ago, truth be told, some time between inciting industrial action amongst JP Morgan’s workers and nabbing an automaton from Tesla. My troupe spread delight wherever we roamed, but the crowds weren’t to know we’d been plying the same tricks for hour after hour - nor that it had hardly taken one to hone my act to the point where failure was inconceivable. Every meagre juggling trick brought whoops from the crowd and impatience to my heart. With every high-wire act, my spirit sank lower still. 


There’s no turn around coming, I’m afraid. The Amazing American Circus is a deckbuilder with some nice ideas, but it’s far more clown than strongman. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Is Successfully Using The Open-Source Qualcomm GL/VLK Drivers On Chromebooks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chromebooks-Mesa-QLCM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chromebooks-Mesa-QLCM"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been known that Google has been using the open-source "MSM" DRM/KMS driver on Qualcomm-powered devices that originally started out as a reverse-engineered driver project separate from the company. Now it's also been confirmed how Google is successfully using the open-source Mesa Freedreno OpenGL and TURNIP Vulkan drivers on Qualcomm-powered Chromebooks too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early Patches Bring BPF To The Linux Scheduler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-BPF-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-BPF-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest area where BPF is looking to expand within the Linux kernel is its CFS scheduler...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Adds An EGL Implementation To Mesa For Windows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Microsoft-Mesa-EGL-Windows</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Microsoft-Mesa-EGL-Windows"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T22:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Microsoft has long had WGL as an API analogous to EGL for residing between OpenGL and the Windows interfaces, Microsoft has now wired up an EGL implementation for Mesa that works on Windows...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kompresní algoritmy v souborech ZIP: Deflate, Implode a srovnání]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15617</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kompresni-algoritmy-v-souborech-zip-deflate-implode-a-srovnani/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kompresní formát ZIP je přes třicet let starý, přesto by mohl být i v současnosti pro někoho zajímavý. Podporuje několik kompresních algoritmů, které si zde postupně rozebereme a na závěr všechny srovnáme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jazyk Go a vyhodnocování výrazů v době běhu aplikace]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15665</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/jazyk-go-a-vyhodnocovani-vyrazu-v-dobe-behu-aplikace/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Často se setkáme s požadavkem na umožnění zápisu výrazů do vstupních formulářových polí, pro použití výrazů v konfiguračních souborech atd. Lze to řešit vložením interpretru plnohodnotného jazyka, ale mnohdy stačí doménově specifický jazyk (DSL).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's pretty 240mm AiO cooler is going cheap on Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-pretty-240mm-aio-cooler-is-going-cheap-on-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-pretty-240mm-aio-cooler-is-going-cheap-on-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T20:56:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liquid CPU coolers are all the rage these days, as they look neat and provide the sort of excellent cooling performance you'd normally only get out of an oversized air cooler. Corsair make some of the best AiOs in the business, and today their (draws breath) iCue H100i Pro XT RGB 240mm CPU cooler (phew) is going cheap. It debuted at £115 and normally costs £90, but today you can pick it up for the relative bargain price of £72. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crucial MX500 1TB SSD for $85 headlines a host of Newegg deals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-crucial-mx500-1tb-ssd-for-85-headlines-a-host-of-newegg-deals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-crucial-mx500-1tb-ssd-for-85-headlines-a-host-of-newegg-deals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T20:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newegg in the US is discounting a host of PC peripherals and components today, so we thought we'd highlight our favourite three deals especially for you. They include a full-size hot-swappable mechanical keyboard for $50, 16 gigabytes of 3600MHz RAM for $73 and a 1TB SSD for just $85. Here are all the details!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 delayed until November 19th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-rumoured-to-be-delayed-by-several-weeks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-rumoured-to-be-delayed-by-several-weeks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T20:18:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 has been delayed until November 19th. EA Dice's futuristic shooter was originally due to release on October 11th, but a day of rumours was concluded by official confirmation of the new release date by EA.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nidhogg and Nidhogg 2 free updates add new levels and cats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nidhogg-and-nidhogg-2-free-updates-add-new-levels-and-cats</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nidhogg-and-nidhogg-2-free-updates-add-new-levels-and-cats"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T19:35:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news! Chaotic multiplayer brawler Nidhogg 2 just received a free update adding new costumes and two new levels, including one set upon a train. Even better news: the original Nidhogg also received a free update, adding a new battleground and some new animated cats.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beaver city-builder Timberborn is out in early access now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/beaver-city-builder-timberborn-is-out-in-early-access-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/beaver-city-builder-timberborn-is-out-in-early-access-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T18:47:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It feels as if the past couple of years have seen a quiet resurgence of Settlers-style town building games, and often those where you're prepping to survive a terrible winter. Timberborn looks like it would sit in that genre but with a distinct twist: all the humans are long dead, and your town is instead inhabited by beavers.

It's out in early access now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reverse Engineering, Open-Source Driver Writing Continues For Apple's M1 GPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-AGX-XDC2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-AGX-XDC2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T18:11:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alyssa Rosenzweig spoke today at the virtual X.Org Developers Conference about the ongoing work for bringing up Linux display and graphics support on the Apple M1 graphics processor...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kerbal Space Program developer's Balsa Model Flight Simulator is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kerbal-space-program-developers-balsa-model-flight-simulator-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kerbal-space-program-developers-balsa-model-flight-simulator-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T18:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building balsa models doesn't have the same immediate appeal as constructing space rockets, and yet Balsa Model Flight Simulator still seems extremely appealing. That's partly because it's from the original developer of Kerbal Space Program, and offers a similar physics construction toolset even if on a more terrestrial scale. It's available now in early access.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon Pro Software for Enterprise 21.Q3 Released For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-Pro-Software-21.Q3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-Pro-Software-21.Q3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T17:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD today released their quarterly update to the Radeon Pro Software for Enterprise graphics driver package, which includes an updated Linux build as well...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solar Ash has a very different take on Mario's Mushroom Kingdom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/solar-ash-has-a-very-different-take-on-marios-mushroom-kingdom</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/solar-ash-has-a-very-different-take-on-marios-mushroom-kingdom"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, remember Hyper Light Drifter, your favourite action-RPG of five years ago? The devs Heart Machine are soon to be back with their new game Solar Ash, which is coming out at the end of next month. It is not like Hyper Light Drifer. For starters, Solar Ash is full 3D. Creative director Alx Preston described the elevator pitch to me as "Super Mario Galaxy meets Shadow Of The Colossus, and sprinkle in a bit of Jet Set Radio" during a hands off preview event last week, and on the face of it, it looks fantastic - something that you, too, may have gleaned from one of its recent trailers. 
But Solar Ash is a game about motion, something that's very difficult to convey during a remote hands-off demo. I cannot tell you how Solar Ash feels, but I'm also a toddler with a marshmallow: put something that looks fuckin' sweet in front of me and I want to consume it, and snatch it up with my grabby little fingers. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aragami 2 review: a breezy ninja stealth 'em up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/aragami-2-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/aragami-2-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Breezy’ seems like an odd word to slap on a stealth game - a measured, sometimes plodding genre - but it fits ninj-em-up Aragami 2 perfectly. Flow like water, it says; stabby water, with wings. Flow, then, like an irresponsibly sharp ice-sculpture of a hummingbird. Flow imperfectly and playfully, for the same tools that allow you to strike masterfully silent also let you mitigate sloppiness with improvisational glee. If Tenchu was an armoury to select from, and Shadow Tactics a map to study, Aragami 2 is a toybox. Let’s play ninjas, shall we?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bethesda "actively investigating" Deathloop PC stuttering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesda-say-theyre-actively-investigating-deathloop-pc-stuttering</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesda-say-theyre-actively-investigating-deathloop-pc-stuttering"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T15:58:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Arkane's time-looping supernatural shooter Deathloop is a good'un, the PC release has not gone down well, with many players reporting suffering framerates—the worst type of timejank. The problem still stands, a day-and-a-half after launch, but there is some comfort to be found in at least an official acknowledgment from publishers Bethesda that yes, they know it's a problem. Not nearly as much comfort as a fix would be. Maybe you'll find some meagre comfort in the unlikely source for this acknowledgement: a nice picture of some burgers.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shashingo helps you learn Japanese through photography and I'd like it now please]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shashingo-helps-you-learn-japanese-through-photography-and-id-like-it-now-please</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shashingo-helps-you-learn-japanese-through-photography-and-id-like-it-now-please"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T15:25:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite being half Japanese, I know very, very little of the language. It pains me, it really does. Occasionally I get this urge to learn it, and lately it's bubbled up because I'm planning on jetting over there next year [laughs in covid]. Unfortunately, all my efforts at self-study have gone down the pan.
I've tried learning Japanese using audio courses and textbooks, but my discipline wanes only a couple of months in. There are many reasons why I suck at self-study, but flashcards are one of them. Sorry, but they suck and they are tedious. This is where I hope the upcoming 'edutainment' game Shashingo will change my relationship with them.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now a union have filed charges against Activision Blizzard too]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/now-a-union-have-filed-charges-against-activision-blizzard-too</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/now-a-union-have-filed-charges-against-activision-blizzard-too"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T15:09:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group of Activision Blizzard workers have teamed up with a union to file charges of unfair labour practices, accusing the company of "intimidation and union busting". This comes less than two months after a California state agency sued the company for alleged discrimination, harrassment, and retaliation. The new charges filed with the labour board claim that Actiblizzard have attempted to stop employees from discussing working conditions or working together to improve them, in violation of labour law.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch the I Am Dead devs explain the lovely real world inspirations behind the game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-the-i-am-dead-devs-explain-the-lovely-real-world-inspirations-behind-the-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/watch-the-i-am-dead-devs-explain-the-lovely-real-world-inspirations-behind-the-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T15:04:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hollow Ponds have released a video detailing the real-world inspirations behind their 2020 puzzle game I Am Dead, a game about a ghost returning to their hometown and view it through new (dead) eyes. The cultural specificity in I Am Dead becomes clear as the two lead developers, Richard Hogg and Ricky Haggett, discuss how the British seaside town of Hastings influenced the creation of the game’s fictional setting Shelmerston. It's 25 minutes long, but it's a lovely watch.
Hogg and Haggett give insights on the various buildings, objects, and jokes from Hastings that infiltrated their way into the game. The video shows off previously unseen concept art, photography, diagrams, maps and mood boards that were used in the development of I Am Dead. You will also learn a lot about the town Hastings.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop infusion: how to carry over weapons and powers between loops with Residuum]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-infusion-residuum</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-infusion-residuum"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T15:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How can you carry over weapons and powers in Deathloop? Deathloop is a darkly comedic action-adventure game which sees assassins Colt and Julianna attempting to kill each other time and time again over the course of a single looping day. The titular loop resets itself if the day ends before Colt can kill all eight Visionaries (including Julianna), or if Colt dies three times in a single mission. When this happens, Colt wakes up at the beginning of the day with everything reset — including any weapons, powers, and trinkets he managed to pick up during his last trip through the loop.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How water-resistant is this water-resistant mouse? A scientific investigation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-water-resistant-is-this-water-resistant-mouse-a-scientific-investigation</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-water-resistant-is-this-water-resistant-mouse-a-scientific-investigation"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T14:56:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are lots of spill-resistant keyboards, including some in our best gaming keyboard rankings, but you hardly ever see mice with similar protection. Despite the fact that they’re always right next to the keyboard, and thus just at risk from low-flying beverages. There are at least two, though: The SteelSeries Aerox 3 and Aerox 3 Wireless. According to SteelSeries, these were the first gaming mice on the market to receive IP54 certification, effectively guaranteeing protection against dust ingress and water splashes.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This new Doom mod will let you send Thatcher back to Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-new-doom-mod-will-let-you-send-thatcher-back-to-hell</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-new-doom-mod-will-let-you-send-thatcher-back-to-hell"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next week, reviled former British prime minister Margaret Thatcher will rise from her grave to bring Hell back to Earth, and only one space marine can stop her. Announced today, Thatcher's Techbase is an upcoming mod for classic Doom which ventures in the tenth circle of Hell (aka the United Kingdom) to battle the demonic forces of the Iron Lady. Modding politicians into games is a vintage jape but Thatcher's Techbase makes a real effort with custom art, its own campaign, music from Paradise Killer's composer, and apparently even the voice behind Demeter and Persephone in Hades. Watch this trailer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Publishes Initial Firmware For Yellow Carp APUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Yellow-Carp-FW</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Yellow-Carp-FW"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:25:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A small but important step forward is seeing AMD recently publishing their binary firmware files in advance of new GPU/APU launches for rounding out their Linux driver support stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Fish review: a physics platformer with sole]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-am-fish-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-am-fish-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like a splash of cold water to the face, I Am Fish is a wonderfully refreshing physics platformer. This isn't a grim tale wrapped in layers of metaphor, or a walking simulator that guides you slowly through a field of feelings. Here, you are simply a fish. The bowl is your prison. The ocean is your freedom. Now imagine Ian Mckellen with the same gravitas as he had playing Gandalf in Lord Of The Rings, except with a farmer's cap on. He is peering into your googly, goldfish eyes. In a west country accent, he bellows, "Swim, you fool!"
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi V3DV Driver Still Working On Vulkan 1.1 Conformance, More Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-2021-Status</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-2021-Status"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T12:07:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iago Toral of Igalia kicked off the first day of the virtual XDC2021 developer conference today by sharing a status update on V3DV as the open-source Mesa Vulkan driver most notably used for Raspberry Pi 4 and newer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Deathloop weapons: every weapon in Deathloop explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-weapons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-weapons"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T11:27:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many weapons are there in Deathloop and how do you get the best ones? Deathloop is about two assassins locked in a time-looping duel to the death, so naturally, there are weapons aplenty in this game. Thanks to the titular loop, you aren't always going to be able to hang on to every weapon you pick up, so knowing where and how to get your favourite weapons back is going to be important.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death Trash and others want to know how the sausage is made]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/death-trash-and-others-want-to-know-how-the-sausage-is-made</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/death-trash-and-others-want-to-know-how-the-sausage-is-made"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“What’s with all the meat everywhere, anyway?” my Death Trash alter ego Mildred asks. “It’s just there. Grows.” the meat merchant replies. “Maybe we’re living on a planet full of flesh and right now we’re standing on a crust of stone and dirt. So, do you want a piece of meat now?” I really don’t. But Mildred does. After all, this mystery meat is the main healing item in the game. It’s what keeps you and the world around you alive. It’s harvested from the ground like precious stones, the literal blood flowing in this grotesque world’s barebones economy, eaten raw and served in meat bars.
But where does the meat come from? Whence the amorphous flesh blobs and pools of blood? From another planet, another dimension? There are no animals in this strange ecosystem apart from Fleshworms. The strange meat seems to be linked to another mystery, the advent of the flesh titans (which are exactly what the name suggests). Soon we discover that we are able to commune with the meat and, through it, speak to a enigmatic being called The Oracle. The meat is a kind of universal consciousness, a flesh and blood information highway, into which those who are attuned to it can plug in. Whether the meat and the flesh titans are good or bad for humanity is up for debate, and there are factions that deify and others that hate them, vying for power. The clot thickens.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Publishes An In-Kernel eBPF-Powered Cache - Can Speed Up Memcached By ~18x]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Orange-BPF-Memory-Cache-BMC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Orange-BPF-Memory-Cache-BMC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French telecommunications giant Orange has published "BMC" as the (e)BPF Memory Cache providing a cache focused on memcached usage within the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HP OMEN Laptops To Be Better Supported With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=HP-OMEN-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=HP-OMEN-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:08:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HP's higher-end "OMEN" laptop series is set to see better support with the next kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boyfriend Dungeon broke my heart, and I'm glad it did]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/boyfriend-dungeon-broke-my-heart-and-im-glad-it-did</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/boyfriend-dungeon-broke-my-heart-and-im-glad-it-did"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:03:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitfox’s recently released dating sim Boyfriend Dungeon has a novel premise. In Boyfriend Dungeon you date sword people: humans who transform into weapons that you can take dungeon crawling. And no, not sex dungeons. Classic video game dungeons with loot and monsters. On paper, Boyfriend Dungeon sounds like the best six-ish hours you could have in a game, combining the endorphin rush of monster-slaying with a cast of hotties that’ll make your heart flutter. Sounds like a great time… except one of these hotties slid a sword right through my heart.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve posts Steam Deck dev kits, on blog and in mail]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-posts-steam-deck-dev-kits-on-blog-and-in-mail</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-posts-steam-deck-dev-kits-on-blog-and-in-mail"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T09:34:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck, Valve’s attempt at a fully portable handheld PC, has taken another step towards being an actual product. In a Steam blog post, Valve have shown off the Steam Deck dev kits that are leaving the roost to provide game developers with some hands-on time, ahead of the planned launch this December. They grow up so fast, eh?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone's invited to play Age Of Empires 4 this weekend in a stress test]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everyones-invited-to-play-age-of-empires-4-this-weekend-in-a-stress-test</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everyones-invited-to-play-age-of-empires-4-this-weekend-in-a-stress-test"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T09:15:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After running an Age Of Empires 4 closed beta test for lucky ticketholders, the makers now want absolutely everyone to pile in and click men as hard as you can to see if the game explodes. The historical RTS is holding an open "technical stress test" this weekend, from Friday to Monday, to give the multiplayer backend a sound kicking and see if it stays stands. In short, hey, you can play AO4's multiplayer for free this weekend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Seamless Update: aktualizace UEFI bez restartu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42819</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-seamless-update-aktualizace-uefi-bez-restartu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Intel připravuje do Linuxu zajímavou inovaci pro své platformy. První patche už do jádra zamířily a až se vše podaří dotáhnout do konce, bude možné na strojích Intel aktualizovat firmwary (zejména UEFI) bez nutnosti restartu stroje. Vše proběhne v rámci aktuálního běhu operačního systému.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gitlab CI: automatizujte přímo v Gitlabu (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-38836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gitlab-ci-automatizujte-primo-v-gitlabu-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T06:39:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automatizace pomocí continuous integration přímo v Gitlabu. CI vám pomůže automatizovat rutinní procesy a ušetří vám hromadu času. Pomůže vám od automatického testování, buildy po nasazování. Chcete vědět víc? Přijďte na naše školení, které se uskuteční 29. září a proběhne plně online. Školí Ondřej Sika.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Java 17 a OpenJDK 17 s hotovým Vector API a plánovaným koncem Applet API]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42818</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/java-17-a-openjdk-17-s-hotovym-maturing-vector-api-a-planovanym-koncem-applet-api/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová hlavní verze Javy, resp. číselně stejná verze balíku OpenJDK. Sedmnáctka přináší několik novinek, například novou renderovací pipeline pro macOS (používá API Metal, OpenGL končí), podporu portu pro Apple M1, vylepšené pseudo-náhodné generátory čísel, označení Java Applet API za zastralé (naplánováno je odstranění), podpory sealed classes, odstranění experimentální kompilace ahead-of-time (AOT) a just-in-time (JIT), o další krok posunutých prací na Java Vector API či práce na context-specific deserializačních filtrech.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hubble Tension]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2516/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2516/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how to remove Deathloop's intro logos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-to-remove-deathloops-intro-logos</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-to-remove-deathloops-intro-logos"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:46:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If there's one thing I hate in this life, it's having to lift my hand onto the Esc key so I can press it to skip logos. Ideally I only lift my arms to deliver food to my maw, or to express my lack of care. So it's nice that someone has already identified which files to delete to remove the logos at the start of Arkane's new shooter Deathloop.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellaris 3.1 is out and adds new content to old DLC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellaris-31-is-out-and-adds-new-content-to-old-dlc-alongside-many-balance-tweaks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellaris-31-is-out-and-adds-new-content-to-old-dlc-alongside-many-balance-tweaks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scifi grand strategy Stellaris's free 3.1 update, titled "Lem", is out now. This is the first update created by "The Custodians", a new team formed within developers PDS Green focused on free, quarterly updates which tweak game balance, add new content to old DLC and fix bugs.

The "Lem" update does all three, changing how tradition trees work, adding new features to old species packs such as 2016's Planetoids, and rebalancing some Civics and Origins.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Faire Prague 2021 obrazem: setkání bastlířů, vynálezců a inovátorů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15664</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/maker-faire-prague-2021-obrazem-setkani-bastliru-vynalezcu-a-inovatoru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Největší setkání bastlířů, vynálezců a inovátorů v Česku se konalo v Průmyslovém paláci pražského Výstaviště. Představilo 150 makerských expozic, workshopů a přednášek, včetně zahraničních hostů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (15. 9. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15663</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-15-9-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si řekneme o svobodné alternativě k Discordu, vyzkoušíme si aplikaci pro ovládání ITUSB1 USB Test Switch, dáme si dohromady knihovnu obrázků a stáhneme si do počítače instalační balíčky pro Android.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 už nezkompilujete s GCC 4.9 a starším]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42817</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-5-15-uz-nezkompilujete-s-gcc-4-9-a-starsim/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jedna z posledních změn v rámci vývoje příští verze jádra Linux 5.15 povyšuje minimální verzi GCC pro kompilaci. Až dosud stačilo GCC 4.9, nyní bude pro sestavení jádra potřeba minimálně GCC 5.1. Jde současně o verzi, která je už delší dobu potřebná pro build na architektuře Aarch64 (64bit ARM).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD's SN850 1TB SSD is down to £145 with a free heatsink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-sn850-1tb-ssd-is-down-to-145-with-a-free-heatsink</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-sn850-1tb-ssd-is-down-to-145-with-a-free-heatsink"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Black SN850 is a tremendously fast PCIe 4.0 SSD, capable of hitting some outrageous speeds - up to 7000MB/s reads and 5300MB/s writes. That makes it a great choice for any PC that can handle it (as well as the PS5, which gets external SSD support tomorrow). It's been discounted on Scan to £145 today, where you'll also get a free Akasa NVMe heatsink in the bargain. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Rock Galactic now has official mod support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-now-has-official-mod-support-and-a-mod-that-gives-spiders-beards</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-now-has-official-mod-support-and-a-mod-that-gives-spiders-beards"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:14:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mods are amazing and can never get enough love, so I'm glad to see that co-operative cave-diving FPS Deep Rock Galactic now has official mod support. It includes mod.io integration for browsing and installing mods, an in-game mod manager, and clearer communication for players joining modded servers, among a lot of other changes.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The top-rated Dell S2721DGFA Fast IPS monitor is 20% off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-top-rated-dell-s2721dgfa-fast-ips-monitor-is-20-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-top-rated-dell-s2721dgfa-fast-ips-monitor-is-20-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dell's S2721DGFA has had a storied history, starting out as a critically acclaimed 27-in gaming monitor that no one could actually buy, to slowly becoming available over the months and finally now to being a great value option in the wake of several big price cuts. 
Today, the S2721DGFA has hit a historic low thanks to a code at the Dell UK site: using the phrase DAE40S at the checkout will knock the price from its usual £329 to just £265.94, a £63 savings and more than £100 cheaper than the same monitor at Amazon. That's an incredible price for one of the best gaming monitors on the planet. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funcom acquires the Conan and Mutant Year Zero IP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/funcom-acquires-the-conan-and-mutant-year-zero-ip</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/funcom-acquires-the-conan-and-mutant-year-zero-ip"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:46:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Funcom have acquired the Cabinet Group, the company which owns the intellectual properties Conan The Barbarian and Mutant Year Zero. Funcom have already developed several Conan games by licensing the IP, including the MMO Age Of Conan and more recently the survival game Conan Exiles. 

The announcement also mentioned that a new game is currently in development which will star Conan and "many of the characters in the Robert E. Howard universe."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077's 1.31 update is small but has substantial fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-131-update-is-small-but-has-substantial-fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-131-update-is-small-but-has-substantial-fixes"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Cyberpunk 2077 patch is small, but the bugs it fixes aren't. 1.31 addresses issues that only affected some users, but they include issues that would halt progress on critical quests if they happened. The patch is live now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hopes for God Of War on PC stoked by leaked Nvidia list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hopes-for-god-of-war-on-pc-stoked-by-leaked-nvidia-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hopes-for-god-of-war-on-pc-stoked-by-leaked-nvidia-list"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:25:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since Sony began releasing PlayStation-exclusive games on PC too, many have been clamouring for more of the big'uns: God Of War, Spider-Man, chuffing Bloodborne for god's sake please Bloodborne. While Sony are still being coy about which games are coming our way, hopes were raised by a recent leaked list of games pulled from the digital guts of GeForce Now, which included a mention of God Of War for Steam. I wouldn't get too excited just yet. While Nvidia have confirmed the list itself was real, they say some games on the list were "speculative".
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weekspot podcast #053: in the loop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-053-deathloop</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-053-deathloop"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, we all know the game has a very cool look, and all of us enjoy playing a good time loop game, but what actually is Deathloop? Thankfully, Matthew's played the first few hours and is here to enlighten both you and I.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to install an SSD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-an-ssd</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-an-ssd"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:52:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the RPS guide on how to install an SSD, which you’ll note is not titled “How to install an SSD or hard drive”. Yes yes, old-timey mechanical drives are cheaper, and better if you need terrabytes upon terabytes of space, but when you can buy a good-quality NVMe SSD like the WD Blue SN550 at £70 for 1TB…I mean, you should probably do that instead.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Met Gala 2021 outfits remind me of video game heroes and villains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/met-gala-2021-outfits-remind-me-of-video-game-heroes-and-villains</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/met-gala-2021-outfits-remind-me-of-video-game-heroes-and-villains"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:21:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual Met Gala event took place last night as some of the world's most famous people gathered to celebrate fashion. This year's theme was "In America: A Lexicon of Fashion", which is wildly inaccurate since most of the attendees decided to dress as video game heroes and villains. Fashion brands like Balenciaga and Versace designed outfits that wouldn't be out of place on a JRPG antagonist or in a Platinum game. Let's look at which celebrities decided to take the Paragon route and dress as a hero and who decided to go full Renegade, dressing as a video game boss.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Otevřený telefon Librem 5 zdraží na 1199 USD]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42816</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/otevreny-telefon-librem-5-zdrazi-na-1199-usd/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:48:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová cenovka telefonu Librem 5 bude od listopadu tohoto roku 1199 dolarů. Telefon přitom v rámci kampaně šlo v roce 2017 předplatit za 599 dolarů, tedy poloviční částku. Dnes ještě stojí 899 dolarů, plus existuje verze vyráběná v USA s cenovkou 1999 dolarů. Hlavním důvodem dalšího výrazného růstu ceny je samozřejmě situace na trhu s komponentami a materiály.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 reveals Grand Cathay's army, created for the game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-reveals-grand-cathays-army-created-for-the-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-reveals-grand-cathays-army-created-for-the-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The mysterious army of Grand Cathay have finally been revealed for Total War: Warhammer 3, wearing their Chinese influences plainly. Grand Cathay have existed in the world of Warhammer (Warlore? Lorehammer?) for almost 30 years but not fielded a full plastic army, so one had to be created for Creative Assembly's fantasy strategy game. Led by dragons in human form, they field forces including Jade Warriors, towering Terracotta Sentinels, and the Celestial Dragon Guard. Come meet 'em in the new trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dying Light 2 delayed again, shambling into February 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-2-delayed-again-shambling-into-february-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-2-delayed-again-shambling-into-february-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:17:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parkour enthusiasts will need to wait two months longer to prance around an open-world city full of zombies (and zombies-to-be), because Dying Light 2 has been delayed again. Previously due December 7th, and spring 2020 before that, Dying Light 2 is now scheduled to launch on February 4th, 2022. The developers, Techland say they need extra time to make it good, yeah?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Come and gawp at Clash: Artifacts Of Chaos' gorgeous, sketchy planet in this new dev diary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-and-gawp-at-clash-artifacts-of-chaos-gorgeous-sketchy-planet-in-this-new-dev-diary</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-and-gawp-at-clash-artifacts-of-chaos-gorgeous-sketchy-planet-in-this-new-dev-diary"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first-person brawler Zeno Clash games have been long-time favourites here at RPS, and when Chilean developers ACE Team announced they were making a new game set in their weird and wonderful Clash universe back in July, we were over the moon. Admittedly, Clash: Artifact Of Chaos' reveal trailer left a lot of unanswered questions at the time, but the good news is that we've got an early sneak peak at a new developer diary that tells us all about the game's story and what to expect when it eventually releases next year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop slabs and abilities: how to obtain and fully upgrade all paranormal powers in Deathloop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-slabs-abilities</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-slabs-abilities"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:14:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to collect and fully upgrade all the slabs in Deathloop? Slab abilities are the paranormal powers in Deathloop, the game's take on Dishonored's Void Powers and Prey's Neuromods. When playing as Colt or Julianna there are five of these slabs to pick up, as well as several levels of upgrades for each.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA RTX 30 Series Resizable BAR Support Continues Helping Performance On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30523</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30523"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:09:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While NVIDIA has been supporting Resizable BAR for a while now with their GeForce RTX 30 series graphics cards, for those exclusively using Linux it remains more of a challenge due to AIB partners generally not releasing any vBIOS updates for ReBAR support that can be easily applied under Linux. But if you do carry out an update -- such as under Windows -- the performance uplift can be worthwhile if using a game that can benefit from the support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastward review: a stunning, but slow burning post-apocalypse adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/eastward-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/eastward-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling flying pigs, saving a nerdy kid from the school bullies, cooking up exquisite dishes to appease a local casino boss whose slot machines you accidentally rinsed with your trusted lucky coin... These are the stories most adventure RPGs would stuff into their ever-growing sidequest menus - distractions meant to provide extra flavour to the world you're meant to be saving, or which hold bountiful supplies of EXP to level up your skills and weapons. Not so in Eastward.
In this impressive debut from Shanghai developers Pixpil, these humdrum slices of life are placed front and centre, forming much of the narrative backbone that drives the game forward. This is still a game that's ultimately about saving the world from a mysterious and all-consuming miasma, but it's also one that makes damn sure you know what you're doing it all for - and that's its striking cast of NPCs. As you busy yourself with the minutiae of their everyday lives, Eastward makes every person (and robot) count in this deadly post-apocalypse, and the result is an affecting, detail-rich tale that owes as much to the action of top-down Zelda games as it does to the role-playing intimacy of Earthbound. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2 remaster cutscenes look like how I remember the originals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-remaster-cutscenes-look-like-how-i-remember-the-originals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-remaster-cutscenes-look-like-how-i-remember-the-originals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T11:19:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I appreciate when a remaster of an old game looks like my memories of the original, a rose-tinted vision which would crumble if I looked at even one screenshot. Blizzard and Vicarious Visions have managed that with Diablo 2: Resurrected, from what I've seen, and a new trailer focuses on the redone cutscenes. And yeah, this is how I remember D2 cutscenes looking? They were dead fancy and high-tech, yeah? Must have looked like this?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World's open beta hasn't convinced me to drop Final Fantasy XIV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-open-beta-hasnt-convinced-me-to-drop-final-fantasy-xiv</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-open-beta-hasnt-convinced-me-to-drop-final-fantasy-xiv"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The last time I got some brief hands-on time with Amazon's upcoming MMO New World, I emerged from Aeternum feeling pretty positive about this new kid on the massively multiplayer block. Crafting, in particular, had me pretty excited. But having spent a big chunk of time in its open beta, I've come away feeling a bit, I don't know, bleh? If anything, I just wanted to go back to my beloved Final Fantasy XIV.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Organizace IETF schválila nový internetový standard, spoluautorem je Ladislav Lhotka z CZ.NIC]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42815</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/organizace-ietf-schvalila-novy-internetovy-standard-spoluautorem-je-ladislav-lhotka-z-cz-nic/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:43:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ladislav Lhotka, vedoucí Laboratoří CZ.NIC, je spoluautorem nového internetového standardu (RFC 9108), který v září vydala organizace IETF. Toto RFC převádí dva IANA registry do podoby vhodné pro datové modelování v jazyku YANG. Jde o dva důležité parametry služby DNS – třídy a typy zdrojových záznamů (resource records).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends will keep tap-strafing, at least for now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-will-keep-tap-strafing-at-least-for-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-will-keep-tap-strafing-at-least-for-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:11:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago, Respawn Entertainment said they were going to get rid of tap-strafing in Apex Legends, but now it seems they've changed their minds. Tap-strafing is a movement exploit that allows players to keep their momentum after slide-jumping, letting them make speedier turns than they should. Unfortunately for Respawn, they say getting rid of this tech has some "unexpected side effects", so tap-strafing gets to stay in the game, for now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Radeon Software update simplifies overclocking, brings Smart Access Memory to older GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-software-update-simplifies-overclocking-brings-smart-access-memory-to-older-gpus</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-software-update-simplifies-overclocking-brings-smart-access-memory-to-older-gpus"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:05:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD have launched a big update for their Radeon Software app and Adrenalin drivers, unlocking a clutch of potentially frame rate-boosting features for those with recent AMD graphics cards and CPUs. The new version, 21.9.1, also includes a Windows 11 driver that gets Radeon Boost, Radeon Anti-Lag and Radeon Image Sharpening ready for Microsoft’s next big OS launch.



In the meantime, those with both a Ryzen 5000 series CPU and a Radeon RX 6000 series graphics card – those lucky enough to have found one in stock, I should say –  can take advantage of Radeon Software 21.9.1’s updated overclocking feature. In previous versions, it was possible to instantly overclock your graphics card with a single click; now you can do the same with both the GPU and CPU at once. Provided they’re from these specific product lines, mind.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neočekávané vydání Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS řeší revokaci klíčů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42814</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/neocekavane-vydani-ubuntu-18-04-6-lts-resi-revokaci-klicu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:59:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S dalším vydáním v rámci LTS řady 18.04 se už po loňské verzi 18.04.5 nepočítalo, nicméně revokace klíčů si vyžaduje vydání aktualizovaných instalačních obrazů této stále podporované LTS verze Ubuntu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop is out now, but some PC players report stuttering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-is-out-now-but-some-pc-players-report-stuttering</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-is-out-now-but-some-pc-players-report-stuttering"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dishonored and Prey devs Arkane have released their latest superpowered sneak-o-shooter, the time-looping Deathloop. It's good, everyone tells me. However, one word of warning: a fair number of PC players are complaining about stuttering framerates, enough to bring it down to a 'Mixed' review rating on Steam. That's the sort of wonky time you don't want. If you want your initial loop o' death to be as slick as blood, maybe wait a bit in the hope of a fix?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 34-35/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Závěr letních prázdnin a začátek školního roku přinesly několik významných vydání, LibreELEC s novým Kodi, příručky Linux From Scratch nebo novou stabilní větev OpenWrt, a také aktualizace Clonezilly, Ubuntu LTS, EndeavourOS či EasyOS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Craftopia, the everything game, is on Xbox Game Pass now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/craftopia-the-everything-game-is-on-xbox-game-pass-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/craftopia-the-everything-game-is-on-xbox-game-pass-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:38:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The description under the latest trailer for Craftopia explains that its developers "combined many features we find enjoyable, such as hunting, farming, hack-and-slash, building, [and] automation" in making the game. It does not explain whether catching giraffes in Pokéball-like traps counts as "hunting", or whether blasting cows into space with a baseball bat is "hack-and-slash."

Craftopia remains every game that has ever existed, from Zelda to Factorio, just as it was last year - only now it's available via Xbox Game Pass.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrobrighting: vraťte starému počítači původní vzhled]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15641</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/projekt-retrobrighting/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Některé z mnou napsaných článků o legendárních počítačích končily zmínkou o nutnosti vrácení jejich původního vzhledu pomocí metody zvané retrobrighting. Výsledky svého letošního snažení bych rád krátce představil.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Tauchman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Křivky v přírodě i v počítačové grafice – svět spirál]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15659</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/krivky-v-prirode-i-v-pocitacove-grafice-svet-spiral/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spirály se v různé podobě objevují na mnoha místech v přírodě, a to jak v malých škálách (ulity, popínavé rostliny), tak i na škálách odpovídajících planetám (víry v atmosféře) či dokonce celým galaxiím (spirální galaxie).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 2.6.1 přináší vylepšení ořezu a opravy chyb]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42813</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/openshot-2-6-1-prinasi-vylepseni-orezu-a-opravy-chyb/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Thomas informuje o nové verzi střižny OpenShot. Ta slouží primárně jako vydání opravující nahlášené chyby předchozí verze 2.6.0 z doby před pár týdny. Najdeme zde ale také automatickou migraci klíčových snímků u ořezu z projektů verze 2.5.1. Zpětná kompatibilita je zde 100%. Opraveny jsou také chyby v některých překladech (včetně slovenštiny) a mnoho překladů bylo vylepšeno.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 will launch in early access on October 26th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-26th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-26th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T21:39:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 will launch in early access via the Epic Games Store on October 26th. Developers Red Hook announced the date via Twitter earlier today, after first announcing a 2021 release date in October of last year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch are suing two users for leading "hate raids"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-suing-two-users-for-leading-hate-raids</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-suing-two-users-for-leading-hate-raids"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T21:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch, the livestreaming platform, are suing two users for allegedly organising "hate raids" against streamers. According to the complaint, these users began in August 2021 to "attack these streamers by flooding their chats with bot-powered Twitch accounts that spew racist, sexist, and homophobic language and content" in violation of the Twitch terms of service.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The winner of the US Open did the best FIFA celebration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-winner-of-the-us-open-did-the-best-fifa-celebration</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-winner-of-the-us-open-did-the-best-fifa-celebration"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T20:16:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The winner of the men's US Open tennis final called me a legend yesterday during post-match interviews. Daniil Medvedev was explaining the strange celebration he did immediately after his victory. "Only legends will understand what I did after the match is 'L2 + Left'."

And I did understand. L2 + Left is the best celebration from the FIFA series.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Samsung 980 Pro PCIe 4.0 1TB SSD is £36 off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-samsung-980-pro-pcie-40-1tb-ssd-is-36-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-samsung-980-pro-pcie-40-1tb-ssd-is-36-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T18:40:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Samsung 980 Pro SSD is one of the very fastest drives on the market, thanks to its PCIe 4.0 connection and 7000MB/s flash memory, and today it's been heavily discounted... on Amazon Germany. I know what you're thinking, but with a bare minimum of effort you can get the 1TB drive for £136, way below the current UK price of £172. Here's how it works. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nvidia RTX 3080 Ti graphics card is shockingly available to purchase in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-nvidia-rtx-3080-ti-graphics-card-is-shockingly-available-to-purchase-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-nvidia-rtx-3080-ti-graphics-card-is-shockingly-available-to-purchase-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T18:06:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nvidia RTX 3080 Ti is currently available for purchase at its recommended retail price, a headline that would have ludicrous to write a few years ago but now constitutes major news. Scan in the UK have stock of the high-end card at its £1049 RRP, stock that has seemingly persisted for a few hours - one of only a handful of times that an Nvidia RTX graphics card at RRP hasn't sold out immediately. If you're building a high-end rig, I'd say this is a great option - as long as you can't find an RTX 3080, at least. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox CEO admits "inappropriate behaviour" towards employee in 2018]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-ceo-admits-inappropriate-behaviour-towards-employee-in-2018</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-ceo-admits-inappropriate-behaviour-towards-employee-in-2018"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T17:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fredrik Wester, the CEO of Paradox Interactive, has publicly expressed regret for "inappropriate behaviour" towards an employee at a company event in 2018. This comes shortly after someone leaked the results of a union survey which revealed many employees felt they'd been mistreated at the company behind games including Crusader Kings and Hearts Of Iron. "Accountability starts from the top," said Wester.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Střídání času ještě minimálně pět let, na zrušení není shoda]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42812</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/stridani-casu-jeste-minimalne-pet-let-na-zruseni-neni-shoda/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T16:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Střídání času se mělo podle Evropského parlamentu zastavit již letos. Jenže plány překřížila pandemie COVID-19. Dnes naše vláda schválila nařízení, že střídání času bude probíhat dalších pět let.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop: PC performance guide and the best settings to use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-pc-performance-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-pc-performance-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:51:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve read Brendan’s Deathloop review, you’ll know Arkane Lyon’s latest is a frequently hilarious time-loop shooter that’s worth getting trapped in. And if you’ve seen its official PC system requirements, you’ll also know it makes some big asks of your hardware. At least, in theory. After a few hours of testing it appears the minimum requirements aren’t quite so minimum, and it’s possible to get slick frame rates in Deathloop even on older graphics hardware – especially if you make a few choice settings adjustments. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 delayed into 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-delayed-into-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-delayed-into-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, someone has to apologise to the neighbours and round up the dogs of war, because Total War: Warhammer 3 has been delayed. Previously expected late this year, the trilogy-concluding strategy game based on Games Workshop's fantasy plastic world is now due in 2022. The developers, Creative Assembly say they want to make sure it's good, yeah?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games appealing the Apple app store battle ruling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-appealing-the-apple-app-store-battle-ruling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-appealing-the-apple-app-store-battle-ruling"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:03:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though a judge largely ruled against Epic Games on Friday in their App Store legal battle with Apple sparked by Fortnite in-app purchases on iOS, clearly that wouldn't be the end. It isn't. On Sunday, Epic filed a notice that yes, they're appealing the ruling. At this point they haven't said precisely what they object to and why but, y'know, they want it to go their way.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things left on my office desk after 18 months of working from home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/things-left-on-my-office-desk-after-18-months-of-working-from-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/things-left-on-my-office-desk-after-18-months-of-working-from-home"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently I am one of about six people in the entire world who hates working from home. I can't do it. At home I am lazy, unproductive, and I accidentally do hours of overtime despite this, because I have no place where work ends and home begins. In March 2020, we were all officially sent home for a temporary office closure, the definition of "temporary" soon being stretched as far as I allow my credulity to when I watch The Prestige. It's magical! David Bowie makes thousands of hats!
Anyway, at the tail end of last week I returned to the office, which it turns out is still almost entirely empty. It's like working from home except I have to wear trousers (also Graham is here too so I can kick his chair and throw stuff at him). I spent a few hours on the first day creeping about looking at everything that had been left here for 18 months, and concluded that if our office were a level in a post-apocalyptic game, or a scene in 28 Days later, it would be pretty embarrassing.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Among Us mods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-among-us-mods</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-among-us-mods"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among Us made a hit out of some very basic minigames and complex social interaction. Surviving against the Imposters as they stab and lie their way through a game might rely more on the players than on the game, but you can craft a more complex base game with a few mod additions - the best of which we've rounded up right here. While you can’t mod your friends, you can mod the game, building on the anxiety-ridden camaraderie crusher by adding new roles and new modes to the basic format. Below, you’ll find out how to fall in love or enact the rule of law (by killing) with our guide to the best Among Us mods. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Craig Pearson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple musí otevřít platby v AppStore]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42811</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/apple-musi-otevrit-platby-v-appstore/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T13:54:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V již rok trvajícím sporu Epic vs. Apple kvůli hře Fortnite byl v pátek vynesen 185 stránkový rozsudek kalifornským soudem. Ten dává většinou za pravdu Apple a Epic tak bude muset platit náhradu za platby Fortnite, které šly mimo AppStore. To dělá přes 3,6 milionů dolarů. A k tomu další náhrady.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toem review: a modern, yet nostalgic photography adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/toem-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/toem-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Remember that brief period in the 00s where everyone had a mobile phone, but none of them could take decent photos, so at least one girl per friendship group also had to have a small digital camera? Laboriously uploading and tagging. These are the photos that come up on your Facebook Memories, reminding you that for a brief period during your final year of school you started wearing 50s-ish neck scarves, for some reason. 
The little black-and-white puzzle adventure game Toem, in which all problems are solved with a camera, reminds me of that. Not because you are able to make disasterous or whimisical fashion choices - you very much are, mostly in the hat department - but because you just take photos of everything, for the fun of it, to remember this thing you saw. Wonky-focused snaps of a flower, or a ladybird, or a nice building (poorly framed because you can't get all of it in shot). This isn't really photography for the camera nerds interested in lenses or different exposures. This is photography as a joyful insta-record of your life. I was here, I did this thing, it was good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšel GNU Wget2, rychlejší Wget]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42810</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vysel-gnu-wget2-rychlejsi-wget/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T12:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Všichni jistě znáte GNU Wget, jednoduchý stahovač pro HTTPS, HTTP a FTP do příkazové řádky. Včera vyšel GNU Wget2 ve verzi 2.0.0 Jde o nové přepsání nástroje okolo knihovny libwget. Wget2 by měl být rychlejší než Wget, protože podporuje více vláken, HTTP/2, HTTP kompresi, TCP fast open a hlavičky If-Modified-Since.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop review: this is not your daddy's Dishonored]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T12:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[William Blake once wrote: "Hold Infinity in the palm of your hand, and Eternity in an hour." Shut up, Blake. This is Deathloop. It is a full-blown action-comedy with a double jump. You get a sideways dash and a gun that splits to become two, smaller guns. If I see anyone trying to be too smart about this game, in which a time-looping assassin tries to break free of hilarious eternity by murdering many people who deserve it, I will look at them with hollow eyes and say: "In Deathloop you regularly snap necks by 270 degrees." Turn away, poets and stealth likers. This is not your daddy's Dishonored.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Destiny 2's revamped Trials Of Osiris is great, and hugely popular]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-2s-revamped-trials-of-osiris-is-great-and-hugely-popular</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-2s-revamped-trials-of-osiris-is-great-and-hugely-popular"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T11:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Bungie announced last year that they were reviving Destiny 2's serious PvP weekend event mode, Trials, they said "It's important that this doesn't go out half-baked." Reader dear, it went out half-baked. But! Seventeen months and one revamp later, Trials Of Osiris is good now. Really good. With generous new reward systems, the option to queue solo, and a few anti-cheater measures, the return of Trials this weekend has seen a huge surge in player numbers and been, like, actually fun.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxenfree 2's villains are sending spooky signals to the original game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oxenfree-2s-villains-are-sending-spooky-signals-to-the-original-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oxenfree-2s-villains-are-sending-spooky-signals-to-the-original-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T11:31:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The makers of Oxenfree have started teasing the upcoming sequel via audio transmissions in the original game. Oxenfree 2: Lost Signals is set to arrive sometime next year, and it'll feature villains who're causing mysterious radio signals that mess with electronics. But it seems they're already up to no good, because an update to the original Oxenfree has introduced these spooky transmissions, which you can hear in several different areas in the supernatural thriller. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to fish in Genshin Impact]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-fish-in-genshin-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-fish-in-genshin-impact"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T11:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to learn how to fish in Genshin Impact? Genshin Impact’s 2.1 update is finally here, and it introduces an entirely new mechanic that will gives you something else to procrastinate searching for your missing sibling with: fishing! Before you can become Teyvat’s most accomplished angler, though, you’ll need to complete a short quest and become familiar with the fishing mechanic. Here’s everything you’ll need to know about fishing in Genshin Impact.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyhledávač Google má tmavý vzhled, zatím ale ne pro všechny]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42809</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyhledavac-google-ma-tmavy-vzhled-zatim-ale-ne-pro-vsechny/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T08:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vyhledávací stránku Google.com je možné nyní přepnout do tmavého vzhledu. Je potřeba být přihlášen a na stránce s výsledky zmáčknout ozubené kolečko vpravo nahoře. V nastavení vyhledávání se vám možná objeví nová položka vzhled. Tam je možné přepnout na tmavý, světlý a výchozí podle zařízení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux mírně rozvolní opatření proti Spectre]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42808</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-mirne-rozvolni-opatreni-proti-spectre/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T08:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxové jádro mírně „rozvolní“ opatření proti Spectre V2 a  V4 (Speculative Store Bypass) pro uživatelské úlohy. Od jádra 4.20 je výchozím chováním spec_store_bypass_disable=seccomp a spectre_v2_user=seccomp  , tedy jen pro úlohy používající SECCOMP (secure computing mode). Nově by mělo být nastaveno prctl, tedy jen pro procesy, které to mají nastaveno.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se používat Linux správně a bezpečně (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40574</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-pouzivat-linux-spravne-a-bezpecne-online-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T06:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxových systémů přibývá, každý den se spouštějí nové servery a někdo se o ně musí starat. To znamená spoustu různých dovedností specifických právě pro linuxové prostředí. Jak to zprovoznit, kudy bezpečně dovnitř, co tam najdeme, jak se o to postaráme a jak to nastavíme nebo rozšíříme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine Research]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2515/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2515/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo představuje hybridní tablety budoucnosti. Canon rozšiřuje nabídku A3 multifunkcí pro hybridní pracovní prostředí. Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: FortiGate pod palbou]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15661</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-fortigate-pod-palbou/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes postřehneme zranitelnou VPN od Fortinetu, návrat starých a příchod nových známých, vykradené OSN i nového člena advisory boardu ProtonMailu. V rychlosti pak nové zranitelnosti Microsoft nástrojů či zamyšlení nad biometrickými údaji.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CESNET CERTS)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin oživuje PalmOS, Linux Mint pracuje na vzhledu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15658</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/pumpkin-ozivuje-palmos-linux-mint-pracuje-na-vzhledu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt Pumpkin má za cíl oživit ukončený systém PalmOS na moderních strojích. Linux Mint se hodlá zaměřit na přepracování témat vzhledu. Na serveru OSNews vyšla obsáhlá recenze KDE Slimbooku. Program unzip na openSUSE poškozuje soubory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-610</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-610"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for staring at Mr Muscle, debating for a second whether you could take him, then coming to the conclusion that you absolutely couldn't. Before you consider things, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Dokázali přepnout vodivost z 2D na 1D]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-dokazali-prepnout-vodivost-z-2d-na-1d</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-dokazali-prepnout-vodivost-z-2d-na-1d"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Topologické izolátory. Janusovský grafen a baterie. Zachycen nový typ gravitačních vln. Dvojvrstvý borofen. Hledání mimozemských civilizací. Dysonovy sféry u černých děr. Planeta Devět. Oblečení z umělých svalových vláken.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple nabírá experty na RISC-V, IBM uvedla první servery s POWER10]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15660</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/apple-nabira-experty-na-risc-v-ibm-uvedla-prvni-servery-s-power10/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LG představila River OS, nový operační systém pro TV protkaný reklamou, VESA přidává certifikaci DisplayHDR True Black 600, vychází Wine 6.17 a také GNOME 41 Release Candidate s řadou vylepšení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Dynasties aka 'Crusader Kings in space' is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-dynasties-aka-crusader-kings-in-space-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-dynasties-aka-crusader-kings-in-space-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T20:47:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's always been a surprise that more games haven't followed in the footsteps of Crusader Kings, but Star Dynasties looks to give it a go. It's a space strategy game about growing your space empire, getting space married, and having space affairs. It left early access at the beginning of the month.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Eternal Cylinder will roll onto hard drives on September 30th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-eternal-cylinder-will-roll-onto-hard-drives-on-september-30th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-eternal-cylinder-will-roll-onto-hard-drives-on-september-30th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T19:02:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Eternal Cylinder was first shown as a prototype six years ago. Back then, Adam described it as "Billy Hatcher and the Giant Egg by way of Philip José Farmer, Icepick Lodge and Hieronymus Bosch, all set in the shadow of a hungry horizon." The prototype was a personal project of ACE Team co-founder Carlos Bordeu, who said that he wasn't yet sure what you would do in the game moment to moment.

Now the game is reaching the end of its journey. ACE Team have announced you'll be able to flee the planetary rolling pin on September 30th.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Epic vs. Apple court has a great definition of video games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-epic-vs-apple-court-has-a-great-definition-of-video-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-epic-vs-apple-court-has-a-great-definition-of-video-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T18:34:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Epic's court case against Apple reached a conclusion yesterday, at least temporarily, but the judge's ruling didn't only address the big issues of app stores and payment systems. Judge Yvonne Gonzalez also offered an answer to a question raised during the trial: what is a game? Most surprisingly, Gonzalez's definition is pretty great.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic vs. Apple: US court rules Apple must allow third-party payment systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-vs-apple-us-court-rules-apple-must-allow-third-party-payment-systems</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-vs-apple-us-court-rules-apple-must-allow-third-party-payment-systems"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T17:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[iOS app developers must be allowed to direct users towards payment options other than those provided by Apple, a US judge has ruled in the Epic v. Apple case. Apple have 90 days, until December 9th, to comply. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 36/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-36-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-36-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Originální doživotní aktivační klíč Windows 10 Pro za pouhých 12,52 EUR od Goodoffer24.com]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/originalni-dozivotni-aktivacni-klic-windows-10-pro-za-pouhych-12-52-eur-odgoodoffer24.com</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/originalni-dozivotni-aktivacni-klic-windows-10-pro-za-pouhych-12-52-eur-odgoodoffer24.com"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Získejte doživotní aktivační klíč k Windows 10 za 12,52 EUR na prodejním portálu GoodOffer24.com. Kromě toho zde můžete získat mnohem více, od dalších nástrojů produktivity od Microsoftu, až po hry. Nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód  AX30.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oprava uspávání notebooků s AMD bude v jádře 5.15]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42807</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/oprava-uspavani-notebooku-s-amd-bude-v-jadre-5-15/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T12:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Některé notebooky s novými procesory AMD mají problémy s probuzením ze spánku s2idle. Mezi nimi například HP Envy x360. Po probuzení například nesvítí dioda napájení, nefunguje ovládání jasnosti displeje či dokonce nefunguje ventilátor.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD bude mít ovladač frekvencí procesoru amd_pstate, o 11 % lepší výkon na Watt]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42806</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-bude-mit-ovladac-frekvenci-procesoru-amd-pstate-o-11-lepsi-vykon-na-watt/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T11:33:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Procesory AMD Zen 2 a 3 budou mít lepší ovladač frekvencí amd_pstate místo doposud používaného acpi_cpufreq. Nový ovladač bude lépe využívat možností procesoru podobně jako u Intelu intel_pstate. Používat bude rozhraní ACPI CPPC (Collaborative Processor Performance Controls), které umožňuje jemnější řízení než staré ACPI. Z počátku bude podpora pouze pro Zen 3, později bude přidána podpora Zen 2.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lab Equipment]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2514/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2514/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jaderné noviny – přehled za srpen 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-srpen-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-srpen-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Přehled srpnových vydání Jaderných novin: stav vydání jádra, citáty týdne a seznam článků týkajících se jádra.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Co prozradí myš]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-co-prozradi-mys</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-co-prozradi-mys"/>
        <updated>2021-09-05T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grafen vrací do hry pevné disky, hustota dat může vzrůst až 10krát. Hlavní chyby digitální transformace. Kontejnery jsou klíčová technologie při vývoji podnikových aplikací. Co prozradí myš.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Zachytili rozpad elektronu na chargon a spinon]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-zachytili-rozpad-elektronu-na-chargon-a-spinon</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-zachytili-rozpad-elektronu-na-chargon-a-spinon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kvantové spinové kapaliny. Delší dolet dronů díky palivovým článkům. Po 12 letech ukončuje provoz český tokamak COMPASS. Odhady hmotností černých děr. Pozornost si zaslouží i měsíce Uranu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 35/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-35-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-35-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>