<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-10-24T06:17:22.167Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-24T06:17:22.167Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switch OLED Model Scores 2 Out Of 10 On Screen Durability Scratch Test]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122682</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/switch-oled-model-scores-2-out-of-10-on-screen-durability-scratch-test"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T03:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might want to get a screen protector.
The Nintendo Switch OLED has been out for a handful of weeks now, and if you haven't already applied a screen protector - you really should.
While Nintendo claims the screen is made out of glass, YouTube channel JerryRigEverything has now put the new screen to the test and it's only got 2/10 screen protection - which makes it as vulnerable as plastic.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sociální síť Truth Social porušuje licenci AGPLv3]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/socialni-sit-truth-social-porusuje-licenci-agplv3</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/socialni-sit-truth-social-porusuje-licenci-agplv3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T23:33:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Trump Media & Technology Group (TMTG) založena bývalým prezidentem USA Donaldem Trumpem spouští sociální síť Truth Social. Ta je založena na open source sociální síti Mastodon, jejíž zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici pod licencí AGPLv3 (GNU Affero General Public License). Zdrojové kódy Truth Social ale k dispozici nejsou a tím pádem je licence AGPLv3 porušována. Dle organizace Software Freedom Conservancy má TMTG 30 dnů na nápravu, tj. zveřejnění zdrojových kódů Truth Social. Pokud se tak nestane, přijde o práva ke zdrojovým kódům sítě Mastodon.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Distributions Timeline 21.10]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-distributions-timeline-21.10</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-distributions-timeline-21.10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T22:14:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fabio Loli vydal verzi 21.10 časové osy linuxových distribucí Linux Distributions Timeline. Ke stažení je png i svg. Jedná se o fork již neaktualizovaného GLDT (GNU/Linux Distribution Timeline).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Panasonic končí s výrobou TV v ČR, SiFive má o polovinu rychlejší jádro RISC-V]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15729</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/panasonic-konci-s-vyrobou-tv-v-cr-sifive-ma-o-polovinu-rychlejsi-jadro-risc-v/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšel MX Linux 21 “Wildflower” přechází na Debian 11, GIMP 2.99.8, XWayland 21.1.3 přidá podporu ovladače Nvidia 495.xx, Wine 6.20 opravuje 29 chyb, PipeWire 0.3.39 vylepšuje Libcamera i podporu JACK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mediatek Posts 8k Lines Of New Linux Kernel Driver Code For AI Processing Unit Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mediatek-MT8192-APU-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mediatek-MT8192-APU-Driver"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T21:24:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a number of months Mediatek engineers have been posting some Linux kernel driver code for bringing up the AI Processing Unit (APU) within the MT8192 SoC while out this weekend is the complete patch series at more than eight thousand lines of code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Destroy All Humans! 2 Remake Skipping Old Consoles So Devs Can Create Bigger, More Detailed Maps]]></title>
        <id>1847923778</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/destroy-all-humans-2-remake-skipping-old-consoles-so-d-1847923778"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T18:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The devs behind THQ Nordic’s Destroy All Humans! 2 remake, out sometime next year, explained recently in an interview why the remake of the cult classic game is avoiding PS4, Xbox One, and Switch. The team decided to go for bigger, more detailed open world levels on next-gen consoles instead of sacrificing quality or…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crysis 2 & 3 Remastered Have Received A Switch Patch, Here Are Full Details]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122679</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/crysis-2-and-3-remastered-have-received-a-switch-patch-here-are-full-details"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crisis averted.
Crytek's Crysis Remastered Trilogy arrived on the Nintendo Switch recently and while we thought it was pretty impressive, there's definitely some issues present.
Fortunately, the developer has heard players' feedback and has now resolved a lot of the reported problems (specifically tied to the remastered version of Crysis 2 and Crysis 3) in the latest patch for the game - Version 1.1.0.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone Put OLED Switch’s Durability To The Test]]></title>
        <id>1847923622</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/someone-put-oled-switch-s-durability-to-the-test-1847923622"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo’s new, updated Switch is selling well and looks great. But if you are lucky enough to find one this year, you might want to buy a screen protector for it as one YouTuber has discovered the Switch OLED screen is very soft and easily damaged by objects like coins or keys.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex86 Processor Detection Landing For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Detection-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Detection-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T16:47:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I wrote about Vortex86 processors seeing detection work under Linux for improving the state of these aging x86 32-bit SoCs. That work is now slated to be introduced in the upcoming Linux 5.16 cycle for those running these aging SoCs/processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every Far Cry Game, Ranked From Worst To Best]]></title>
        <id>1847920434</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/every-far-cry-game-ranked-from-worst-to-best-1847920434"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Way back in 2004 a then-unknown developer called Crytek released the first game in what would become the Far Cry series, wowing players with its impressive visuals and sprawling, outdoor maps. Crytek moved on to creating the Crysis series, Ubisoft bought up Far Cry and continues to make new entries to this day. Some…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Now That Smash Is Complete, Sakurai Doesn't Have To Worry About What He Shares On Social Media]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122678</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/random-now-that-smash-is-complete-sakurai-doesnt-have-to-worry-about-what-he-shares-on-social-media"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An Among Us photo would have been sus a month ago.
Super Smash Bros. Ultimate might be the greatest crossover video game of all time, but it's been far from easy for the game's director Masahiro Sakurai over the years.
Apart from health issues and struggles when adding certain fighters - whenever he appeared on a show, did an interview, or posted something on social media, he had to be extremely careful as some fans would speculate about anything he said and link it back to the next fighter or collab coming to Nintendo's all-star brawler on the Switch. Obviously, as of this week, it's the end of an era - with the final DLC fighter, Sora from Kingdom Hearts, now available.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Litwick Is Cute, But Can't Be Trusted]]></title>
        <id>1847923275</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/litwick-is-cute-but-cant-be-trusted-1847923275"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Pokemon is interesting and worth talking about. I don’t play a ton of Pokemon, but I do enjoy the universe and I love learning more about the creatures in it. So, Here’s Another Pokemon! It’s Litwick!
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Best Nintendo Switch FPS Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-90667</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-nintendo-switch-fps-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lock and load.
Nintendo Switch's bulging catalogue of games covers practically every genre, and First-Person Shooters are no exception. It's a welcome change because Nintendo systems have historically lagged a little behind other consoles in the FPS field despite hosting some classics. After all, GoldenEye 007 and Perfect Dark helped define the FPS on consoles, and the Metroid Prime series shifted the exploration of the 2D Metroids into a first-person perspective to great effect. Still, Nintendo consoles have often missed out on the best multiplatform shooters.
The success of Switch is changing all that, though, and we've seen a raft of FPS games arrive on the handheld hybrid. From remade classics to seemingly 'impossible' ports, there's now plenty to chose from, and with Metroid Prime 4 lingering stubbornly over the horizon, there's never been a better time to gear up like John Matrix, light a cigar and blast through the demonic hordes on your handheld.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poll: The Hype For Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy Is High, Is It In Your Switch Plans?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122664</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-the-hype-for-grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-is-high-is-it-in-your-switch-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And can it live up to that hype?
Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition getting official release details, along with a trailer and lots of screens, was certainly the standout and dominant news item at the end of the week. Perhaps counter to expectations the visual overhaul is a bit more than a simple upscale, with the footage looking rather familiar but undoubtedly fresh. That's not to say it would be mistaken for footage of games developed from scratch in the 2020s, as characters in particular still have that angular look familiar from past generations.
The official information does point to key gameplay changes, such as controls more in tune with what players know from GTA V. Yet we'd suggest those control updates will need to be good; you may have fond memories of the original '3D' GTA trilogy, but they're of their time and don't necessarily feel particularly smooth to play now. Perhaps The Trilogy will fix that, it's certainly one of the big tests it'll face.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma Readies Its NVIDIA GBM Support, Fingerprint Authentication Added]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-GBM-NVIDIA-Ready</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-GBM-NVIDIA-Ready"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T09:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been an exciting week for KDE developers with preparing their formal support for handling NVIDIA's driver with GBM support as well as getting fingerprint authentication finally in place, among other improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Are You Playing This Weekend? (October 23rd)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122069</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-october-23rd"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us your weekend gaming plans.
We made it through another week, well done everyone! There was a varied slate of news this week, with one of the slightly disappointing stories being allegations of poor management practices at Metroid Dread developer MercurySteam, but in happier news we also had the arrival of Sora in Smash, we confirmed that Crysis Remastered Trilogy does indeed run on Switch, Nintendo gave us Vampire Waluigi, and GTA Trilogy was dated and detailed for Switch. In slightly disappointing news, though, Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp was delayed to Spring 2022.
After all that, it's time to chill out and discuss our weekend gaming plans. A few members of the Nintendo Life team have done just that below, so feel free to give our entries a read and then join in with your own via our comment section. Enjoy!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 12.3 Prepares For New Release Ahead Of Christmas, Beta Starts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FreeBSD-12.3-BETA1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FreeBSD-12.3-BETA1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T08:52:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The FreeBSD team has begun preparations for their next release process with an aim to ship FreeBSD 12.3 in early December...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-166</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-166"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I ate my first mince pie this week, which feels like a betrayal of my belief that Christmastime should not start before Halloween is over. That said, it wasn't a mince puff, so does it really count? Please, tell me about your festive eating. And may as well mention what you're playing this weekend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flame In The Flood Developer Acquired By CD Projekt Group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122674</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/flame-in-the-flood-developer-acquired-by-cd-projekt-group"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T05:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Studio already working on "ambitious project" based on CDP IP.
The Polish video game company CD Projekt Group - known for titles such as The Witcher III and Cyberpunk 2077 - has acquired the US-based developer The Molasses Flood.
This studio is perhaps best known for the survival-building base games The Flame in the Flood, and more recently Drake Hollow.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: 20 Secrets Of Kingdom Hearts' Sora In Super Smash Bros. Ultimate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122673</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/video-20-secrets-of-kingdom-hearts-sora-in-super-smash-bros-ultimate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T04:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Did you spot any?
It's been quite an exciting week in the world of Super Smash Bros. Ultimate with the arrival of the final fighter Sora from the Kingdom Hearts series.
Now that we've had some time to see what this new and final addition to the game's roster is all about, our American-based video producer, Zion Grassl, has put on his Kingdom Hearts hat and assessed all the cool secrets and references in this latest DLC drop.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkanised Fall 2021 Material Available - Autodesk Has Begun Using MoltenVK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkanised-Fall-2021-Materials</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkanised-Fall-2021-Materials"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week was the virtual Vulkanised Fall 2021 event hosted by The Khronos Group. The two-day event was focused on all things Vulkan and for those that missed it all of the slide decks and other material are now available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flipnote Studio Creations Find New Life On Crank-y Playdate Handheld]]></title>
        <id>1847921468</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/flipnote-studio-creations-find-new-life-on-crank-y-play-1847921468"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T00:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although it won’t officially be in our hands until later this year (if you got in on the first wave of pre-orders, that is), Panic’s unique Playdate handheld is already being poked and prodded by folks lucky enough to score a dev unit. One such developer recently shared a neat little project that revives Flipnote…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard Has Officially Renamed Overwatch's McCree]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122671</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/blizzard-has-officially-renamed-overwatchs-mccree"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T00:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Say hello to Cole Cassidy.
As you might recall, Blizzard announced it would be changing the name McCree - the popular cowboy gunslinger in its team-based first-person shooter, Overwatch.
In case you missed the original announcement, the character was named after one of the now ex-employees linked to the recent harassment and discrimination lawsuit - brought against Activision Blizzard by the state of California.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XIV Has Many Mounts, But Only One Sneezes]]></title>
        <id>1847920301</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-xiv-has-many-mounts-but-only-one-sneezes-1847920301"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hype for Endwalker’s impending launch recently pushed me back into the arms of Final Fantasy XIV. Instead of doing the smart thing and working my way through the massively multiplayer role-playing game’s litany of main story quests so I’d be caught up in time for the expansion’s November 23 release, however, I’ve…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GTA Trilogy Remasters Look Great, But Shouldn’t Replace The Originals]]></title>
        <id>1847920893</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-gta-trilogy-remasters-look-great-but-shouldn-t-rep-1847920893"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T22:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today Rockstar finally showed footage of the Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy remasters and they look surprisingly good, but also very different from the original games. This has raised concerns about erasing the series’ past, and also called to mind the fragmented state of game preservation.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 16 Best Cards In Back 4 Blood]]></title>
        <id>1847920257</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-16-best-cards-in-back-4-blood-1847920257"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the most part, Left 4 Dead 3– wait, no, that’s not what it’s called...for the most part, Back 4 Blood is a first-person shooter about teaming up with your friends to mow down hordes of zombies. But Back 4 Blood flips the script by including a decidedly non-shooting mechanic: a deck-building system.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis and Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.20 Released With More Modules Switching To The PE Format]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.20-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.20-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:57:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.20 was released today as the latest bi-weekly development release of this open-source software for enjoying Windows games and applications on Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch's McCree Is Now Cole Cassidy]]></title>
        <id>1847919311</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/overwatchs-mccree-is-now-cole-cassidy-1847919311"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch’s McCree will now be known as Cole Cassidy, the developers announced today, further distancing the character from former designer Jesse McCree, one of the men who took part in the controversial, recently exposed “Cosby Suite” meet-ups.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[System76 Laptops To See Some Useful Improvements With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=System76-ACPI-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=System76-ACPI-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patches queued this week into the platform-drivers-x86 "for-next" branch ahead of the Linux 5.16 merge window will provide some useful improvements to System76 laptop owners...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTuber Valkyrae Under Fire Over Skin Care Line]]></title>
        <id>1847918855</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/youtuber-valkyrae-under-fire-over-skin-care-line-1847918855"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After streamer Valkyrae’s skincare line RFLCT drew criticism for its promises to help offset the negative effects of computer light,” the YouTube has issued a statement. Yesterday, Valkyrae posted a voice note acknowledging the pushback and promised to answer questions in a future stream.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy Gets A Meaty File Size, By Switch Standards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122666</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-gets-a-meaty-file-size-by-switch-standards"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inevitable questions pop up over the physical edition.
Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy – The Definitive Edition, if you want to use its full name, has made headlines today with the unveiling of its debut trailer and release details. Naturally some questions for big GTA fans and indeed Switch collectors have revolved around the file size and what we can expect from the Switch physical version.
Well, it's certainly in the top list of sizeable Switch games, with the North American eShop page listing it as 25.4GB. That's pretty small fry if you happen to download a lot of games on systems like PS5 and Xbox Series X, but is relatively high end on Nintendo's hybrid. Only select titles like Doom (2016) and the NBA 2K games come in with larger file sizes.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You’re Probably Not Actually Stuck In Metroid Dread]]></title>
        <id>1847918773</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/you-re-probably-not-actually-stuck-in-metroid-dread-1847918773"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe you’ve been playing Metroid Dread since it hit Nintendo Switch on October 8, but put it down out of frustration from being stuck in the dang game. Or is that just me? Good news: you’re not actually stuck. It’s just easy to not realize what blocks are destroyable while you’re exploring.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's What Will Improve After Battlefield 2042's Chaotic, Buggy Beta]]></title>
        <id>1847918644</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/heres-what-will-improve-after-battlefield-2042s-chaotic-1847918644"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T18:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open beta for Battlefield 2042 was chaotic, buggy, and pretty limited given the scope of the latest game in the long-running shooter series. For developer DICE the beta was one more thing: a learning experience. In an article posted yesterday Battlefield 2042 devs introduce five new specialists and a host of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix Is Removing The Hated Denuvo DRM From A Bunch Of Games]]></title>
        <id>1847918583</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/square-enix-is-removing-the-hated-denuvo-drm-from-a-bun-1847918583"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T18:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix patched the controversial digital rights management and anti-cheat software Denuvo out of Nier Replicant, Rise of the Tomb Raider, and Shadow of the Tomb Raider earlier this week. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games Faces Staff Uproar Over Ending Popular Time-Off Policy]]></title>
        <id>1847918205</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/epic-games-faces-backlash-after-ending-popular-time-off-1847918205"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games, creator of the massively popular and lucrative battle royale Fortnite, decided to end a popular policy of allowing staff every other Friday off earlier this week. According to a new report by Bloomberg, which a source corroborated for Kotaku, the move angered staff who were caught off guard by the sudden…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 19 Best Games For The Nintendo Switch]]></title>
        <id>1794881447</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-best-games-for-the-nintendo-switch-1794881447"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How’s this for a fun fact? In November 2020, the same month Sony and Microsoft released much-anticipated next-gen consoles, the Switch outsold every other console in the United States. Those who’ve recently hopped on board the Nintendo bandwagon might be faced with a question as old as the universe: “What should I…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kotaku Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire 0.3.39 Brings Libcamera Plugin Improvements, Better Compatibility For JACK Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PipeWire-0.3.39-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PipeWire-0.3.39-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T17:43:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire 0.3.39 was released on Thursday as the newest update to this audio/video stream solution for Linux systems that continues proving itself capable of replacing the roles of JACK and PulseAudio, among other use-cases...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření Visual Studio Code "Language Support for Java(TM) by Red Hat" dospělo do verze 1.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/rozsireni-visual-studio-code-language-support-for-java-tm-by-red-hat-dospelo-do-verze-1.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/rozsireni-visual-studio-code-language-support-for-java-tm-by-red-hat-dospelo-do-verze-1.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T17:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření Visual Studio Code "Language Support for Java(TM) by Red Hat" dospělo do verze 1.0. Přehled novinek s náhledy a videi v příspěvku na blogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Lost In Random, 2021’s Most Innovative Game, Shares With Star Wars]]></title>
        <id>1847917323</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/what-lost-in-random-2021-s-most-innovative-game-share-1847917323"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Random rules! Random rules!”

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Rare Games Confirms Limited Edition Of '1-Bit' Action Platformer Dogworld]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122659</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/super-rare-games-confirms-limited-edition-of-1-bit-action-platformer-dogworld"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manual, sticker and trading cards included, as always.
Dogworld arrived relatively recently (during the Summer) on the eShop, a retro-styled '1-Bit' action platformer in which you "shoot, jump, and slide your way through a ruined, mysterious, dog-filled world". It's now the latest download title to get the limited release treatment from Super Rare Games, with details now available on the package and orders.
You can take a look below; it's due to go on sale with a 3000 copy run on 28th October at 10am PT / 1pm ET / 6pm BST / 7pm CEST, via the Super Rare Games website.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CD Projekt have bought the studio behind The Flame In The Flood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-have-bought-the-studio-behind-the-flame-in-the-flood</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-have-bought-the-studio-behind-the-flame-in-the-flood"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T16:35:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk and Witcher crew CD Projekt have acquired The Molasses Flood, the American studio behind post-apocalyptic raft ride The Flame In The Flood and base-building game Drake Hollow. Huh! The studio will be making a game set in one of CD Projekt's world, which warrants a second: huh! It's all secret for now.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soapbox: 8 Times I Ugly Cried At Kingdom Hearts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122541</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/soapbox-8-times-i-ugly-cried-at-kingdom-hearts"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gawrsh!
SPOILER WARNING! In the following article Stuart discusses some rather whopping spoilers as he takes us on an emotional and tearful Kingdom Hearts journey. If you haven't played the games and you're sensitive to spoilers, we recommend coming back in a year or so once you've played the lot. Otherwise, be warned that certain unfortunate events are discussed in detail.
Of course, if you haven't played the games, none of this will make a lick of sense anyway, but you have been warned!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Happens When AI Tries To Review A Video Game]]></title>
        <id>1847917110</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/what-happens-when-ai-tries-to-review-a-video-game-1847917110"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a comment I’ve seen hundreds of times, or variations of throughout my time here at Kotaku: internet complaints about the quality of reviews. “A bot can do better than this,” some would cry. So let’s put that to the test.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My hunger for games like Warcraft 2 is slowly being sated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-hunger-for-games-like-warcraft-2-is-slowly-being-sated</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-hunger-for-games-like-warcraft-2-is-slowly-being-sated"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:38:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I think back to the games of my childhood, nothing puts a warm, fuzzy smile on my face like Warcraft 2. As one of the few PC games I had growing up, I ended up playing the campaign over and over again - or at least starting it over and over again - for what felt like actual years. I loved building up my fort and endlessly poking the peasants and peons until they shouted back at me in annoyance, and man alive, there is nothing sweeter than ordering a tooled-up army across the map and absolutely wrecking the enemy in one fell swoop of doom and destruction. 
It is something I wish I could play again now with all my heart. I know there's version of it on GOG, but I'd also just quite like, you know, a newer, shinier version with a more up to date UI and all that jazz, and one whose map didn't whizz over to the other side of the screen with a single tap of the arrow key. I'd also like a version that isn't, somehow, made by Activision Blizzard because... *gestures to all their ongoing harassment lawsuits*. Fortunately, I've happened upon a couple of games in recent weeks that have really scratched that old Warcraft 2 itch of mine. I've already written about one of them - Diplomacy Is Not An Option - and the other is Age Of Darkness: Final Stand, a game with the most boring name imaginable, but is secretly very good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to uninstall Windows 11 and go back to Windows 10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-uninstall-windows-11-and-go-back-to-windows-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-uninstall-windows-11-and-go-back-to-windows-10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:33:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Change isn’t for everyone: just ask the 5% of Steam Hardware Survey respondents still using Windows 7. Sadly, even the most eager of early adopters might be looking to find out how to uninstall Windows 11, the very latest of Microsoft’s operating systems. It could be the newly centralised Start menu; it could be the lack of DirectStorage support among games making the best SSDs perform below their full capability; it could just be a single unsquished bug, which remains a risk with the infant OS. Fortunately, if you decide to want to switch back to Windows 10 within 10 days of installing its successor, it’s possible to roll back in just a few, mildly regretful clicks.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to upgrade to Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-11"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:32:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, fine, here’s how to upgrade to Windows 11 from Windows 10. The current stance of this hardware ed is that Windows 11 has some cool features but is yet to fulfil its potential, largely owing to the missing DirectStorage capability – which, to be fair, could be a very big deal when games start supporting it. For now, then, it’s a free but absolutely not an essential upgrade, and you can think of this post as the RPS equivalent of that video where Valve tore down a Steam Deck: we’re not saying you should do this, just that you can do this. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby bude mít just-in-time compiler YJIT]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42935</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ruby-bude-mit-just-in-time-compiler-yjit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maxime Chevalier-Boisvertová představila v úterý just-in-time compiler pro Ruby s názvem YJIT, který používá Lazy Basic Block Versioning (LBBV). YJIT je průměrně o 23 % rychlejší než CRuby. Podle plánu by YJIT měl být v Ruby 3.1, jen nebude ve výchozím stavu zapnut.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon GO And JD Team Up For Gyms And Pokéstops In UK And Europe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122663</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/pokemon-go-and-jd-team-up-for-gyms-and-pokestops-in-uk-and-europe"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ticks boxes with Nike apparel and in-game items.
Pokémon GO isn't quite the behemoth it once was, in fact recently nearly 20,000 Pokéstops were confirmed to be closing down at 7-Eleven stores in Japan, but it still has some partnerships and activities drawing in players.
In the UK and Europe the game is hoping to tempt in fans of sporty apparel after confirming a partnership with retail chain JD. There'll be small number of Gyms but a much larger group of Pokéstops, with some special virtual clothes available alongside actual real-life Nike gear in the stores.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remastered GTA San Andreas Is Coming To Xbox Game Pass]]></title>
        <id>1847916194</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/remastered-gta-san-andreas-is-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-1847916194"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alongside news that Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy—a remastered bundle of the first three 3D GTA games—drops on November 11, Rockstar stealthily revealed that GTA: San Andreas will also hit Xbox Game Pass the same day. Oh, and GTA III is making its way to PlayStation Now soon, too.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Truck Simulator now supports mods in multiplayer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/truck-simulator-now-supports-mods-in-multiplayer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/truck-simulator-now-supports-mods-in-multiplayer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T14:06:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After adding official multiplayer modes to American Truck Simulator and Euro Truck Simulator 2, developers SCS Software have now made both support mods in multiplayer too. They're games many truckers mod with the trucks and decor of their dreams, so it'll be nice to show everyone your true truck self. I'd call this your drivatar but Forza has already claimed that.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Delays Advance Wars Switch Remakes Until 2022]]></title>
        <id>1847915827</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-delays-advance-wars-switch-remakes-until-2022-1847915827"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hottest Nintendo Switch game of the season is the latest to get hit with a delay. Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp won’t be out until spring 2022, Nintendo revealed this morning, completely upending my holiday plans in the process.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto remastered trilogy's first trailer looks shiny yet cartoony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-remastered-trilogys-first-trailer-looks-shiny-yet-cartoony</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-remastered-trilogys-first-trailer-looks-shiny-yet-cartoony"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:32:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a stretch of teasing and leaking, Rockstar today revealed how they've renovated the GTA 3 trilogy for the upcoming horribly named collection, Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition. A new trailer and screenshots reveal that GTA 3, Vice City, and San Andreas still have distinctly cartoon vibes, now paired with fancy reflections and effects. Rockstar also announced a release date of November 11th and a price of... £55? Gosh. See the new look for yourself in the trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Posts The "Last Part" To Their AMX Bring-Up For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-Linux-Part-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-Linux-Part-4"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:07:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While for many years we have been accustomed to seeing Intel land their new hardware feature enablement work in the Linux kernel and related components well ahead of products shipping, occasionally there are lapses due to various internal and external timings. The launch of Sapphire Rapids is quickly approaching and one of the major additions is Advanced Matrix Extensions with its Linux support still being in the works...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh No, Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp Has Been Delayed On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122658</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/oh-no-advance-wars-1plus2-re-boot-camp-has-been-delayed-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Thanks for your patience".
Sad news, folks. Nintendo has announced that Advance Wars 1+2: Re-Boot Camp has been delayed.
The game, which serves as a remake of both Advance Wars and Advance Wars 2: Black Hole Rising, will no longer launch on 3rd December as planned. Instead, you can expect to see it on the eShop in "spring 2022".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doom Eternal's Horde mode arrives next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-eternals-horde-mode-arrives-next-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-eternals-horde-mode-arrives-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday the 26th of October, Doom Eternal players will be able to rip and tear through the hellish shooter's new horde mode. If you're not quite satisfied with murdering demons in a linear fashion, you'll be able to jump into a match to fight off waves of the beasties instead. It's arriving in the game's 6.66 update, along with two new master levels and Battlemode 2.0.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy Gets Confirmed Release Date, First Trailer And Screenshots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122654</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-gets-confirmed-release-date-first-trailer-and-screenshots"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And there's not long to wait.
Today, Rockstar has shared more details on Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy – The Definitive Edition which was recently confirmed to be heading to Nintendo Switch.
The collection will let you play Grand Theft Auto III, Grand Theft Auto: Vice City, and Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas with "across-the-board enhancements", including new lighting and environmental upgrades, high-resolution textures, increased draw distances, Grand Theft Auto V-style controls and targeting, and "much more".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FOSDEM 2022 proběhne online]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fosdem-2022-probehne-online</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fosdem-2022-probehne-online"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T12:35:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bylo oznámeno, že konference FOSDEM 2022 (Free and Open source Software Developers’ European Meeting) proběhne online o víkendu 5. a 6. února 2022.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone Has Fainted In Pokémon's Next Merchandise Range]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122651</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/everyone-has-fainted-in-pokemons-next-merchandise-range"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cute, but kinda sad.
The Pokémon Company has revealed a new line of merchandise that's sure to be a hit with fans, partly because it's all so darn adorable.
Interestingly enough, the range's theme is 'Pokémon who lost in battle', with each piece depicting a 'mon or two that appears to have fainted. It's a cute idea – just don't think about the fact that the poor things have just fought for you, lost, and have now been transformed into a pencil case.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy Priced, Dated And First Footage Revealed]]></title>
        <id>1847915306</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/grand-theft-auto-the-trilogy-priced-dated-and-rated-1847915306"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Kotaku was the first to tell you Rockstar was remastering the first three 3D Grand Theft Auto games, all manner of leaks and rumors have flown around until the developer finally officially confirmed their existence two weeks ago. Today, they’ve announced a release date—November 11 for the digital version—and an…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man Arrested For Allegedly Stealing Four Copies Of Tokyo Revengers Manga Worth $18]]></title>
        <id>1847915371</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/man-arrested-for-allegedly-stealing-four-copies-of-toky-1847915371"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A 48-year-old man has been arrested on suspicion of stealing four volumes of Tokyo Revengers, a popular manga about hoodlum high school kids. 
Illustrated and written by Ken Wakui, the award-winning Tokyo Revengers is serialized in Kodansha’s Weekly Shonen Magazine. (Full disclosure: My first two books were published…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Different Among Us Collector's Editions Are Now Available For Pre-Order]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122647</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/three-different-among-us-collectors-editions-are-now-available-for-pre-order"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ranging from $30 to $90.
Consider yourself a huge Among Us fan or looking to get into the game for the first time? Well, these fancy physical Collector's Editions could be just the thing.
Three different Collector's Editions are now available to pre-order; the cheapest of the bunch will be shipped out this winter (December in Europe, January in North America), while the larger sets arrive in both territories next March.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite will let you host a cross-platform LAN party on a PC dedicated server]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-let-you-host-a-cross-platform-lan-party-on-a-pc-dedicated-server</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-let-you-host-a-cross-platform-lan-party-on-a-pc-dedicated-server"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:25:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After decades of Halo being primarily an Xbox series [settle down, disgruntled elderly Mac fanatics -ed.], Halo Infinite will buck that with a simultaneous launch on PC too. With that December launch drawing near, a new trailer focuses on the PC edition, detailing various graphics settings and multiplayer options and noting the interesting detail that you'll be able to use a PC to host a dedicated server for a cross-platform LAN party. Watch on for lots of shots of scrolling through options menus.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nová sociální síť TRUTH Social bývalého prezidenta Donalda Trumpa porušuje AGPL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42934</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nova-socialni-sit-truth-social-byvaleho-prezidenta-donalda-trumpa-porusuje-agpl/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:16:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bývalému prezidentovi USA Donaldu Trumpovi byl na konci volebního období zablokován účet na Twitteru i Facebooku kvůli útoku jeho příznivců na Kapitol. Donald si však vytvořil vlastní sociální síť TRUTH Social, která je v současné době pouze na pozvání a měla by být volně dostupná od příštího roku.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Friend Peppa Pig Releases Today On Switch, Here's The Launch Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122644</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/my-friend-peppa-pig-releases-today-on-switch-heres-the-launch-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["﻿Just like being in an episode of the TV show".
Today sees the release of the latest game set in the Peppa Pig universe, as My Friend Peppa Pig launches on Nintendo Switch.
From publisher Outright Games, the game is said to be a fun-filled adventure that's "just like being in an episode of the TV show". Players get to choose and dress up their own character, before meeting up with fan-favourite characters from the hit show and checking out plenty of familiar locations.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World character transfers paused due to gold duping glitch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-character-transfers-paused-due-to-gold-duping-glitch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-character-transfers-paused-due-to-gold-duping-glitch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World's long-awaited character transfers have been taken away almost as soon as they arrived, because they've caused a glitch that allows players to duplicate gold. The bug came about after the MMORPG's 1.0.3 update this week. It makes it so characters don't save properly after transferring, letting them trade gold and items to others while magically keeping it in their own pockets. Amazon have paused server transfers for the time being to work on a fix, and have warned players that those caught exploiting the glitch will be banned.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Early Look At The GCC 12 Compiler Performance On AMD Zen 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12.0-October-Zen-3-Perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12.0-October-Zen-3-Perf"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12 isn't seeing its stable release until around March~April as usual, but with feature development slowly wrapping up as approaching the next stage of development next month to focus on fixes, recently I wrapped up some preliminary benchmarks for how GCC 12.0 is currently performing against GCC 11.2 on an AMD Ryzen 9 5950X (Zen 3) system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardware Review: Evercade VS - A Low-Cost Gateway To Past Nintendo Classics And Much More Besides]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122404</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/hardware-review-evercade-vs-a-low-cost-gateway-to-past-nintendo-classics-and-much-more-besides"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hands-on with Blaze's latest retro hardware.
Blaze's Evercade handheld was one of 2020's more pleasant surprises; a new piece of hardware that offered an alternative for retro enthusiasts and offered a wide range of physical cartridges packed with classic titles (many of which were originally found on Nintendo consoles) – all for a very reasonable price. Now, its creator is taking the concept in a new direction with the Evercade VS, a system that retains compatibility with (almost) all of the existing Evercade cartridges but is more focused on offering the best possible experience on your TV – and, as the name suggests, the prospect of good, old-fashioned competitive play.
The Evercade VS retains much of the same design language as its handheld counterpart, using white and red as the two main colours. It takes a leaf out of Nintendo's book, too; the cartridge bay (which actually has two slots – more on that shortly) is hidden behind a NES-style flap at the front of the machine. Below this, there are four USB ports for controllers, while the power button is found on the right-hand side of the machine. On the back, there's the HDMI port and Micro USB port (both of which are upside-down, confusingly), as well as a reset button, used in the event of the system crashing (something that mercifully didn't happen during our review period). There's no HDMI cable included in the box, with Blaze claiming that it helps keep down the cost of the unit (most households have at least one spare HDMI cable lying around, so it's no biggie). There's also no power supply unit, but most modern TV sets offer the 5V USB port required to power the Evercade VS.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Psychonauts 2 turns the mind inside out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-psychonauts-2-turns-the-mind-inside-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-psychonauts-2-turns-the-mind-inside-out"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“It’s all in your head.” It’s a response that encapsulates all the condescension and ignorance surrounding mental health issues. And yet, in a way, it’s true. Subjective experience is an objective reality – that just so happens to be located and locked away in your head. 
These individual realities can only be conveyed through language and other subjective means of communication, and more and more games are grasping this fact, turning inward to explore and map the inland empires of the mind. They have all the tools of the medium at their disposal to turn the invisible workings of the mind into landscapes of audio-visual and mechanical metaphors that can be explored and interacted with. At their best, they convey the dynamic and complex mechanisms of the psyche in a way that only this medium can.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NetEase Games Acquires Goichi Suda's Grasshopper Manufacture]]></title>
        <id>1847914966</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/netease-games-acquires-goichi-sudas-grasshopper-manufac-1847914966"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Founded in 1998 by Goichi Suda, Grasshopper Manufacture is best known for games like Killer 7, Lollipop Chainsaw, and No More Heroes. Today, the studio announced it is being acquired by Chinese conglomerate, NetEase Games. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Sword And Shield Shiny Zacian/Zamazenta Distribution Now Live In Europe, US And More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122642</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/pokemon-sword-and-shield-shiny-zacianzamazenta-distribution-now-live-in-europe-us-and-more"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are all the details you need.
The Pokémon Sword and Shield distribution allowing fans to pick up Shiny versions of both Zacian and Zamazenta is now live across Europe, the US, Canada, and select parts of Asia.
We have all the currently-known details for you below, with thanks to Serebii for compiling parts of the list, and will make sure to update this page if we hear of any more.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK-Native 1.9.2a Released For Direct3D-Over-Vulkan With Native Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-Native-1.9.2a</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-Native-1.9.2a"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:16:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve continues embracing DXVK-Native for allowing more of their older games to target Vulkan by using this Direct3D-to-Vulkan translation layer for native games. DXVK-Native 1.9.2a is out with the latest fixes and improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proxmox: moderní virtualizační platforma schopná nahradit VMware (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40445</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/proxmox-moderni-virtualizacni-platforma-schopna-nahradit-vmware-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:13:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proxmox je moderní virtualizační platforma, která v mnoha případech může nahradit VMware. Je open-source, zdarma a je postaven na otevřených technologiích jako KVM, LXC, CEPH a dalších. Pokud potřebujete provozovat virtualizaci, Proxmox je pro vás ideální stack a na našem workshopu se dozvíte, jak na něj.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GBA's Unreleased 'Dune' Game Is Being Revived, Minus The IP Rights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122636</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/the-gbas-unreleased-dune-game-is-being-revived-minus-the-ip-rights"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little less spice.
If you happen to have Nintendo's retro handhelds in your collection, there are still multiple interesting releases and projects emerging. The latest to pop up is Elland: The Crystal Wars for Game Boy Advance, a game that publisher The Retro Room Games is reviving minus a famous IP.
Originally, way back in 2002, it was a GBA game that was pretty much finished but got cancelled due to the financial issues of its publisher Cryo Interactive, which was no doubt a source of huge disappointment for developer Soft Brigade (hat-tip to Unseen64). At that point it was called Frank Herbert’s Dune: Ornithopter Assault, licensed to use characters and settings from the iconic novel; no doubt you've seen a lot about the latest film version in the media, too. It was a flying / shooter with over 20 stages, and even had some multiplayer modes for use with the portable's link cable.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buy Smash Bros. Ultimate Or Any Of Its DLC And Earn Double My Nintendo Gold Points]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121892</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/buy-smash-bros-ultimate-or-any-of-its-dlc-and-earn-double-my-nintendo-gold-points"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Offer ends soon!
Update: As a friendly reminder, Nintendo's current promotion in which you can earn double My Nintendo Gold Points when buying any digital Super Smash Bros. Ultimate product is about to come to an end. If you were thinking of grabbing that second DLC pass or perhaps even the game itself, it wouldn't be a bad idea to snap it up by Sunday 24th October.
Full details can be found in our original article below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oprava pomalejších procesorů Ryzen ve Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42933</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/oprava-pomalejsich-procesoru-ryzen-ve-windows-11/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T08:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před dvěma týdny jsme psali, že Windows 11 je až o 15 % pomalejší na procesorech AMD Ryzen. Včera Microsoft vydal opravu problému s časováním vyrovnávací paměti L3 u procesorů AMD Ryzen, která je součástí kumulativní preview opravy KB5006746.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Graphics Driver's New Parallel Submission uAPI Landing For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Linux-5.16-Multi-LRC-Exec</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Linux-5.16-Multi-LRC-Exec"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's "parallel submission" user-space API for their i915 kernel graphics driver has been queued into DRM-Next today ahead of the Linux 5.16 kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chyba v GPSD vás může o víkendu přenést do března 2002]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42932</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chyba-v-gpsd-vas-muze-o-vikendu-prenest-do-brezna-2002/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T05:40:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Program GPSD se používá k obsluze GPS přijímačů v Linuxu a to nejen ke zjištění polohy, ale také k velmi přesné synchronizaci času. GPS formát data však má jen 10 bitů pro kódování týdne. To stačí jen na zhruba 20 let.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft Is Bringing A New Monopoly Game To The Nintendo Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122633</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/ubisoft-is-bringing-a-new-monopoly-game-to-the-nintendo-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The madness begins this December.
Who needs Watch Dogs, Assassin's Creed and Far Cry when you have the all-time classic board game Monopoly.
Ubisoft has announced a new take on Hasbro's property trading game called Monopoly Madness - a title that "reinvents" the iconic board game and is launching on the Nintendo Switch and multiple other platforms on 9th December this year. Here's the rundown, courtesy of the PR:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Continues Improving Its Shader Pre-Caching Support, Other Beta Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Continues-Mesa-Cache</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Continues-Mesa-Cache"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new Steam client beta is out with a few Linux enhancements worth noting...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Censored Vaccine Card]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2532/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2532/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: It Has Now Been 1,000 Days Since Metroid Prime 4's Development Was Restarted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122632</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/random-it-has-now-been-1000-days-since-metroid-prime-4s-development-was-restarted"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're ready for an update, Nintendo.
Where were you approximately 1,000 days ago? While it might not seem long ago, it actually dates back to 25th January 2019 and you know what that day was, right? Yep, on this particular day in Nintendo history, development on the highly anticipated release Metroid Prime 4 was restarted.
Nintendo's Senior Managing Executive Officer, Shinya Takahashi, delivered the news in an "open and honest" video message - admitting development progress at the time had not reached the standard Nintendo expected from the Metroid Prime series.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grasshopper Manufacture Joins Chinese Video Game Giant NetEase]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122631</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/grasshopper-manufacture-joins-chinese-video-game-giant-netease"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T01:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Suda51 says his company "is now reborn".
Just a day after we heard how the famous video game creator Goichi "Suda51" Suda would love to reboot or remake Nintendo's older IP, he's now announced his development studio will be working under the Chinese video game giant NetEase.
Yes, that's right - Grasshopper Manufacturer is ending its partnership with the Japanese publisher and developer GungHo Online Entertainment to join the NetEase Group - one of the biggest internet and video game companies in the world that also partners with western companies like Blizzard.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft Brings Back Might and Magic Game They Shut Down In June]]></title>
        <id>1847912970</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-brings-back-might-and-magic-game-they-shut-down-1847912970"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T00:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In May, Ubisoft took down some DRM servers that accidentally broke Might & Magic X - Legacy, to the point where the game had to be removed from shopfronts. A few months later, and probably after some folks had long assumed the game was simply dead, it’s back.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022's early access beta is available now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022s-early-access-beta-is-available-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022s-early-access-beta-is-available-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T23:22:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022 pre-launch beta is live now. If you buy the kicking sim on Steam or Epic, you can immediately start playing a nearly-finished version of the game. If you're really committed you can probably be sacked at least once before the sun comes up.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust 1.56.0 a Rust 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/rust-1.56.0-a-rust-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/rust-1.56.0-a-rust-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:57:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze 1.56.0 programovacího jazyka Rust (Wikipedie). Současně byla edice Rust 2021 prohlášena za stabilní. Podrobnosti v poznámkách k vydání. Vyzkoušet Rust lze například na stránce Rust by Example.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SiFive Has A New RISC-V Core To Improve Performance By 50%, Outperform Cortex-A78]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SiFive-P550-Successor</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SiFive-P550-Successor"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:42:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SiFive just shared word that at today's Linley Conference they teased their Performance P550 successor that will "set a new standard for the highest efficiency RISC-V processor available."..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big NFT Project Cancelled After Just Five Hours]]></title>
        <id>1847906380</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/big-nft-project-cancelled-after-just-five-hours-1847906380"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, a group of respected young adult novelists thought it would be a good idea to launch a new project spearheaded by NFT purchases. Sadly/hilariously, their big plans went from “let’s do this” to “we’re not doing this” in a matter of hours.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Man's Sky's new update lets you ride on flying worms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-new-update-lets-you-ride-on-flying-worms</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-new-update-lets-you-ride-on-flying-worms"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:07:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At this point, it has become a cliché to say that space sim No Man's Sky has come a long way since its initial release. And yet, is there any better example of its long development journey than the sandworms? Initially shown in pre-release trailers only to be cut from the release version, they were finally added in some recent updates. Now the most recent update and seasonal event adds new sandworm varieties, including rideable sandworms. The worm has indeed turned.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence a signály odměn]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problém zpětnovazebného učení u skutečné umělé inteligence. Primordiální černé díry. Záhadné rádiové vlny. Nejchytřejší psi. Drony jako hasiči.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 „Impish Indri“: poslední verze před velkým dubnovým LTS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15725</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/ubuntu-21-10-impish-indri-posledni-verze-pred-velkym-dubnovym-lts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nové Ubuntu přináší jednu významnou evoluční změnu, GNOME 40. Jinak jde z velké části o poklidné vody připravující půdu pro příští vydání s dlouhou podporou. Současné novinky napovídají, kam se vývoj ubírá.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's flagship Virtuoso RGB Wireless XT headset is 26% off in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-flagship-virtuoso-rgb-wireless-xt-headset-is-26-off-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-flagship-virtuoso-rgb-wireless-xt-headset-is-26-off-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's Virtuoso RGB Wireless XT is just as fancy as its long-ass name implies, and today it's £65 off as part of Corsair's autumn sale. That drops the price from £250 to £185, considerably less than even the going price on Amazon of £230. I think this is a great deal if you've got a hefty budget for an all-in-one wireless headset, so let me share a little on why I'm so convinced!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haunted Chocolatier is the Stardew Valley developer's next RPG]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:38:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The developer of Stardew Valley has revealed their next game: Haunted Chocolatier. It's again a game about moving to a new town to "try your hand at a new way of living", but instead of a farm, you're opening a chocolate shop staffed by ghosts. There's an adorable trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a high-spec 1TB NVMe SSD for £139 after a 21% off voucher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-high-spec-1tb-nvme-ssd-for-139-after-a-21-off-voucher</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-high-spec-1tb-nvme-ssd-for-139-after-a-21-off-voucher"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:34:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The XPG S70 Blade is one of the few 'second-gen' PCIe 4.0 SSDs on the market, offering incredible speeds on PC and even full compatibility with PS5. Today the 1TB model is heavily discounted at Amazon UK, with the NVMe drive dropping from £176 all the way to £139. To get the reduced price, tick the box where it says 'Apply 21% voucher'; the reduced price will be visible at the checkout. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Klávesnice Dactyl-Manuform s tvrdými ohebnými PCB]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/klavesnice-dactyl-manuform-s-tvrdymi-ohebnymi-pcb</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/klavesnice-dactyl-manuform-s-tvrdymi-ohebnymi-pcb"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:26:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dactyl-Manuform (kombinace Dactyl a Manuform) je svého druhu populární typ ergonomické klávesnice. Existuje několik parametrických generátorů variant šasi pro 3D tisk, řada forků a dokonce několik drobných výrobců nabízí sady nebo již sestavené klávesnice: patří mezi ně např. Bastard Keyboards (dříve HID Technologies), jenž nyní zveřejnil schémata tvrdých ohebných PCB ([1] [2]) pod licencí Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0. Oproti původnímu ručnímu drátování je to krok k více funkcím (podsvícené či hotswap spínače) a příp. sériové výrobě.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 will tweak maps, UI and more in response to beta feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-will-tweak-maps-ui-and-more-in-response-to-beta-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-will-tweak-maps-ui-and-more-in-response-to-beta-feedback"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:11:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 has been and gone, and now its developers have written about what they learned based on player feedback. There are some straight fixes, some explanations, and lot more in a post on the Battlefield blog. 

Also: a look at the five previously unrevealed specialists you'll be able to play as when the game launches.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Next Game Pass Pick Is An RPG That Combines Stranger Things and EarthBound]]></title>
        <id>1847912195</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/your-next-game-pass-pick-is-an-rpg-that-combines-strang-1847912195"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m not normally a fan of turn-based RPGs, but Echo Generation’s voxel-based visuals caught my attention, so I decided to give it a shot. I’m very glad I did. While it’s a sometimes frustrating game, it has enough charm and style that I enjoyed it even when I got stuck. It also doesn’t overstay its welcome, offering…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Uncharted movie finally has a trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-uncharted-movie-finally-has-a-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-uncharted-movie-finally-has-a-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T20:52:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Uncharted series will arrive on PC early next year with Uncharted 4: A Thief's End. That game features a retired Nathan Drake being coaxed into another adventure, but you therefore might want to experience some of the Indylike's earlier treasure hunts first. There is literally only one way I can think of to do that: watching the Uncharted movie, which is also due to release in cinemas early next year.

The first trailer just released, starring Tom Holland and Mark Wahlberg.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying Out Ubuntu's New Flutter+Curtin-Powered Desktop Installer Was Disappointing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-New-Install-Try</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-New-Install-Try"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T19:15:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An effort going on for a while at Canonical has been to develop a new desktop installer for Ubuntu. With the recent Ubuntu 21.10 release they are still using their classic Ubiquity installer by default but have published a new preview build of Ubuntu 21.10 with their new desktop installer option. Here is a look at Ubuntu's forthcoming new installer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 96 Beta Begins Preparing For Chrome 100, Adds Priority Hints Feature]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-96-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-96-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T18:37:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following this week's release of Chrome 95, Google has now promoted Chrome 96 to beta status...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer cap RazerCon announcements with first PSU and liquid cooler components]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-cap-razercon-announcements-with-first-psu-and-liquid-cooler-components</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-cap-razercon-announcements-with-first-psu-and-liquid-cooler-components"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T18:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Razer, purveyors of green and black gaming peripherals, have announced they’re having a proper go at PC components as well. The Razer Hanbo AIO liquid CPU cooler series, Razer Katana PSUs, Razer Kunai case fans and Razer Pulse Width Modulator (PWM) Fan Controller all debuted during this year's RazerCon showcase.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XWayland 21.1.3 Nears With Support For NVIDIA 495 Driver's GBM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-21.1.3-RC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-21.1.3-RC"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T17:57:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The release candidate to XWayland 21.1.3 is out today with just a few changes but made significant by support for the NVIDIA 495 series driver GBM code path...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dwarf Fortress Steam edition video demonstrates convenience of seeing what's happening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-edition-video-demonstrates-convenience-of-seeing-whats-happening</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-edition-video-demonstrates-convenience-of-seeing-whats-happening"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T16:45:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["You will not believe what the hell just happened in Dwarf Fortress!" my pal will tell me, proceeding to share a screenshot which, to me, is indistinguishable from e.g.:

██,.,,;lz,zl;L:@gjse,.gm.,,.m.zm,.m,x.zm.amL:m3jp5jkmToiHy*
████()ht23htuhqIJg.......UG.uos\kjk:███/,,p,c.xz/,c./z,c;\/.
██'z,c./xz,c./zx,cpaswf/w.qfw.,/f,aa███,g.ew/t,3wq./t,,2..@|
█3/.6t,.esg,f.e/sg,./ewt,./w4t4..,1t6,m42ijpnz\kuiys8fun/.|█
█|?|..../\/\..|@@@%%$|"(((|..FHzFhLlk@A}||||....*|JGH,.3████
zZ./@Z@@'Z'@@LSXCl;a,sl;FLZL;@'A:@,;'F":%T@:H^OQHOh8^£$.\/.█

"That's wild!" I will reply, not wanting to hurt their feelings. But how delightful, then, to watch the latest video from the upcoming premium edition, where co-creator Zach Adams demonstrates defending against a goblin attack and you can actually see it's a goblin attack.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amanita's unhappy Happy Game is coming in time for Halloween]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amanitas-unhappy-happy-game-is-coming-in-time-for-halloween</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amanitas-unhappy-happy-game-is-coming-in-time-for-halloween"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T16:12:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amanita Design are known for their cheery and charming adventure games, wonders like Samorost, Machinarium, Botanicula, and Chuchel. Their next game sounds like it should be their cheeriest yet, given that it's named Happy Game. Reader dear, this is a trick. Happy Game is blood and death and horror. You will see this soon, as Amanita today announced plans to release Happy Game on the 28th of October. Or you can try a demo now!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim will add aquariums in its Anniversary Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrim-will-add-aquariums-in-its-anniversary-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrim-will-add-aquariums-in-its-anniversary-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T15:56:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim: Anniversary Edition comes out next month, and it's quickly becoming the fishiest version of the RPG yet. Bethesda have announced it will let you add aquariums to your Skyrim homes. We already know this edition will let us go fishing too, so I'm hoping we'll be able to yank those suckers straight out of the sea to put on display in our homes. Can't believe I'm going to buy yet another version of Skyrim just to have pet fish.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 161: the best songs special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-161-the-best-songs-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-161-the-best-songs-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It occurs to me now that "best songs" is probably not a great topic for the podcast, given that we do not perform any of the songs, or put them in the show. But on this week's episode of The Electronic Wireless show, we talk about them songs real good. Plus, we are joined by Randy Newman, who sounds a surprising amount like Matthew Castle.
Matthew himself has a new awkward food related story to share, Nate has been watching Squid Game, and a listener has sent in a very special musical theme for Sweeten The Deal!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2021-21703 v PHP]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bezpecnostni-chyba-cve-2021-21703-v-php</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bezpecnostni-chyba-cve-2021-21703-v-php"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:52:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V PHP byla nalezena bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2021-21703 zneužitelná k lokální eskalaci práv. Opravena je v upstream verzi 8.0.12.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can’t buy an RTX 3080? GeForce Now will let you play with one in the cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cant-buy-an-rtx-3080-geforce-now-will-let-you-play-with-one-in-the-cloud</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cant-buy-an-rtx-3080-geforce-now-will-let-you-play-with-one-in-the-cloud"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:24:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service is getting a new, ultra-premium subscription tier powered by its GeForce RTX 3080 GPU. While one of the best graphics cards around, especially for higher resolutions, the RTX 3080 has remained frustratingly hard to find in stock since it launched last year – for many, this GeForce Now tier could be the best chance of seeing what it’s like to play with one, even if is simply streaming from a server rather than a dedicated gaming PC.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter From The Editor #03: EGX Rezzed is dead, long live EGX Rezzed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/letter-from-the-editor-03</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/letter-from-the-editor-03"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:12:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello folks. Sorry to be writing this letter so late into October. This time two weeks ago I was walking the halls of London's ExCel on my way to host the first RPS Presents panel at EGX 2021, and all the planning and organising I had to do for it rather cut back on my available writing time. I then took some time off to recuperate a bit, and here we are, three weeks into October and I'm only just getting round to doing my monthly editor's letter. I do apologise. But! We are here now and there's plenty to talk about. A lot of it is EGX-related, but you'll hopefully have noticed some new site features being introduced these last few weeks as well, which I'll explain below. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charming tower defence Toy Soldiers has an HD remaster now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/charming-tower-defence-toy-soldiers-has-an-hd-remaster-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/charming-tower-defence-toy-soldiers-has-an-hd-remaster-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:07:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2010 tower defence game Toy Soldiers has two big neat ideas: it looks like a toybox upended onto battlefield dioramas built on bedroom tables; and you can take to the battlefield yourself to control units and vehicles. It's a good'un, and today it relaunched with an 'HD' version. I liked the original enough to buy it on both Xbox 360 and PC, but wasn't interested in getting it again until I heard Toy Soldiers: HD offers more than the usual high-res texture overhaul.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dark Pictures Anthology: House Of Ashes review: very nearly a fun horror romp]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-house-of-ashes-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-house-of-ashes-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a real soft spot for Supermassive Games. Until Dawn was a knowingly schlocky teen slasher horror film made into an interactive adventure game, and it was great for at least two thirds of its runtime. I've also felt the same about their more recent project, The Dark Pictures Anthology, which began with Man Of Medan in 2019. Every time a new instalment comes out I believe it's in with a shot of being well good - although each one has since made me doubt the "knowing" part of my interpretation of Until Dawn. The latest entry, House Of Ashes, comes the closest yet to recapturing the daft thrills of Until Dawn, with a classic survival-horror setup that's half The Descent and half Aliens.
The five playable protagonists you flit between are trapped in an ancient Sumerian temple that leads into an even deeper cavern, and then an even deeperer, ancienter ruin. The turducken of potholing. But instead of delicious stuffing, the surprise in these layers is a race of vampiric monsters whose vision is based on sound, and whose spit is LSD. Your job is to get your goons out alive, and the main problem is that the goons in question are - instead of a busload of teens on a field trip gone wrong - a small team of US marines searching for WMDs in 2003 Iraq. Wakka wakka.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Austin Powers spliced into Mass Effect makes a disturbingly good Shepard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/austin-powers-spliced-into-mass-effect-makes-a-disturbingly-good-shepard</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/austin-powers-spliced-into-mass-effect-makes-a-disturbingly-good-shepard"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T13:04:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The geth have begun launching seemingly random attacks on human colonies. Rumours are circling that ancient machines will soon emerge from darkspace. There is only one man equipped to deal with these threats: Intergalactic Man Of Mystery, Austin Powers. Someone has made a video editing Mike Myers' 60s spy into Mass Effect and I'm astounded at how well it works. I don't know what else to say. This is Mass Effect in its ultimate form. Please watch it, it's the best minute I've spent all week.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 7003 "Milan" Performance On Ubuntu Linux Six Months After Launch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30634</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30634"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a half-year already since AMD introduced the EPYC 7003 "Milan" processors that continue performing well and gaining marketshare. While the recently released Ubuntu 21.10 is not a long-term support (LTS) release, for those wondering what this latest Linux distribution means for EPYC 7003 series performance, here is a look at its performance across many benchmarks against that of Ubuntu 21.04 that was released right after the Milan launch and then Ubuntu 20.04 as the current LTS stable series.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KrakenSDR]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/krakensdr</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/krakensdr"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T12:05:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na Crowd Supply běží kampaň na podporu zařízení KrakenSDR s pěti přijímači RTL-SDR. Lze je používat nezávisle nebo současně jako radiozaměřovač nebo pasivní radar.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit was inspired by Devil Daggers and a Nicolas Cage film]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-was-inspired-by-devil-daggers-and-a-nicolas-cage-film</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-was-inspired-by-devil-daggers-and-a-nicolas-cage-film"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit is a fast-paced roguelike shooter with hints of Doom, and excellent hands that shoot magical bullets. It's not the first occult-themed game to turn hands into guns (and I sure hope it won't be the last), but is inspired by one. I spoke to Into The Pit's creator, Tom Betts, who told me about the game's Devil Daggers influences, from weaponry to aesthetics, and why the occult setting works so well for the roguelike genre. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 4 s 2 GB paměti dočasně zvyšuje cenu z 35 na 45 dolarů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42931</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-4-s-2-gb-pameti-docasne-zvysuje-cenu-z-35-na-45-dolaru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T10:45:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dodavatelské řetězce jsou nestabilní a projevuje se to dlouhými lhůtami na dodávku součástek a narůstajícími cenami. Zasáhlo to také výrobce jednodeskových počítačů Raspberry Pi, který musel poprvé v historii zvýšit cenu modelu RPi 4 zpět z 35 na 45 dolarů. Eben Upton zdůrazňuje, že jde o dočasné zdražení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD "Smart Trace Buffer" Feature Being Wired Up For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Smart-Trace-Buffer-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Smart-Trace-Buffer-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T10:15:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD patches this month have begun preparing support for a new CPU feature called Smart Trace Buffer (STB)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bethesda's new Starfield trailer introduces mercenary and pirate factions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesdas-new-starfield-trailer-introduces-mercenary-and-pirate-factions</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesdas-new-starfield-trailer-introduces-mercenary-and-pirate-factions"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T10:08:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm fighting off a real Bethesda itch right now. I know I'll hate myself if I start yet another Skyrim playthrough, and I'm too fussy to decide on a Fallout to sink another fifty hours into. But now there's a new Starfield trailer, and it's making me pine for those damned RPGs all the more. The developers have dived into Starfield's history, and revealed a handful of factions we'll come across on our space travels. It's mostly concept art, but hey, it's very nice concept art.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World now lets you transfer your character to another server]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-now-lets-you-transfer-your-character-to-another-server</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-now-lets-you-transfer-your-character-to-another-server"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T09:46:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server transfers opened up in New World overnight, letting players shunt their explorers from one world to another. This is a desirable feature in many MMOs, and particularly in this one because servers were so overloaded at launch that Amazon recommended players join any old server then transfer to their desired home later once things settled. All players get one transfer for free, but only one, with Amazon planning to start selling that service later.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V3DV Raspberry Pi Driver Now Exposes Vulkan 1.1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-Vulkan-1.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-Vulkan-1.1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T09:19:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa's V3DV driver for supporting newer Broadcom VideoCore graphics hardware with Vulkan now is advertising v1.1 support. This Vulkan 1.1 support in V3DV is notable as the Raspberry Pi 4 and newer are the most notable beneficiaries of this driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sequoia PGP přelicencována z GPL 2+ na LGPL 2+]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/sequoia-pgp-prelicencovana-z-gpl-2plus-na-lgpl-2plus</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/sequoia-pgp-prelicencovana-z-gpl-2plus-na-lgpl-2plus"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T08:48:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Implementace OpenPGP Sequoia PGP byla přelicencována z GPL 2+ na LGPL 2+. Vývojáři to zdůvodňují na dvou příkladech: Apple nepovoluje GPL software ve svém App Storu a problém s GPL má také Thunderbird.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 4 s 2 GB RAM dočasně zdražilo z 35 na 45 dolarů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-4-s-2-gb-ram-docasne-zdrazilo-z-35-na-45-dolaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-4-s-2-gb-ram-docasne-zdrazilo-z-35-na-45-dolaru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T08:15:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problémy s výrobou a dodáváním má také Raspberry Pi. Raspberry Pi 4 s 2 GB RAM proto dočasně zdražilo z 35 na 45 dolarů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evertried review: a rough-hewn roguelike that fails to stand out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/evertried-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/evertried-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is no mouse cursor in Evertried. You control everything with the keyboard, from the hops and scythe attacks of your cute otherworldly hero, to the settings in the pause menu. It's a strange omission but one that is representative of the feeling this roguelike evokes throughout your time climbing its purgatorial tower of baddies. That is to say, a feeling that there's something important missing. In fact, there seems to be a lot missing from this tile-based timewaster, small touches that could have given its solid foundation the polish it needed to excel. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Sees Their First Price Increase Due To Supply Chain issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-Supply-Chain</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-Supply-Chain"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ongoing supply chain issues across the semiconductor industry (and more broadly) are now impacting the Raspberry Pi operations for end-users/customers when it comes to pricing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby Lands "YJIT" As A Speedy, In-Process JIT Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ruby-YJIT</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ruby-YJIT"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Ruby programming language implementation has merged YJIT, its new just-in-time (JIT) compiler...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CUDA-Python Reaches "GA" With NVIDIA CUDA 11.5 Release, __int128 Preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-CUDA-11.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-CUDA-11.5"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T23:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA has made available CUDA 11.5 today as the latest version of their popular but proprietary compute stack/platform. Notable with CUDA 11.5 is that CUDA-Python has reached general availability status...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Základy práce s grafickou plochou v jazyku Basic-256]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15722</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/zaklady-prace-s-grafickou-plochou-v-jazyku-basic-256/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T22:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pro výuku programování se velmi často používají jazyky s grafickým výstupem. Výjimkou není ani Basic-256, který obsahuje grafickou plochu s podporou vykreslení běžných 2D entit, jednotlivých pixelů, ale i zobrazení pohyblivých spritů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matematické měření rozlišení softwarově korigovaného dalekohledu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15553</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/matematicke-mereni-rozliseni-softwarove-korigovaneho-dalekohledu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarově změříme ostrost obrazu, abychom zjistili skutečné zvýšení rozlišení díky jeho použití. Matematiky možná potěší vlastní funkce Fourierovy transformace a centrální limitní věta.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Karel Kulhavý)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get the outstanding Razer Viper ultralight mouse for 50% off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-outstanding-razer-viper-ultralight-mouse-for-50-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-outstanding-razer-viper-ultralight-mouse-for-50-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T20:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Razer Viper is one of my favourite mice of all time, whether we're talking about the wireless Ultimate version, the compact Mini model or the vanilla Viper. It's this OG model that is on sale today at Amazon, who have marked it down from £80 to just £40 - an incredible bargain for an ultralight mouse with a high-end optical sensor, optical mouse buttons, flexible cable and low weight of just 69 grams. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get an RTX 3070 gaming laptop for £1250 after a £150 discount]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3070-gaming-laptop-for-1250-after-a-150-discount</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3070-gaming-laptop-for-1250-after-a-150-discount"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T20:05:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Asus Tuf Gaming A15 is a great value gaming laptop that attracted warm reviews for its design and performance, and today it's also the cheapest RTX 3070 gaming laptop we can find*. The A15 FA506QR-HN006T specification, which includes a Ryzen 7 5800H processor, 16GB of RAM and 512GB SSD, is down to just £1250 at Overclockers after a £150 reduction. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CD Projekt Red delay The Witcher 3's next-gen update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-red-delay-the-witcher-3s-next-gen-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-red-delay-the-witcher-3s-next-gen-update"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T19:17:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The update adding raytracing and other mod cons to The Witcher 3 will not launch this year, developers CD Projekt Red announced today. They've been fancying up their fantasy RPG for the latest console generation, and those 'next-gen' additions are headed to PC in a patch too. But not this year. Instead, look to be blinded by the light in spring 2022. They've also delayed the next-gen version of Cyberpunk 2077 for consoles.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 2.99.8 Released As Another Step Toward The Long Overdue GIMP 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GIMP-2.99.8-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GIMP-2.99.8-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T19:06:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 3.0 as the GTK3 port of this open-source Adobe Photoshop alternative has been talked about for nearly a decade now and the work remains ongoing. However, out today is GIMP 2.99.8 as the newest development snapshot...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Makes ControlFlag Open-Source For Helping To Detect Bugs In Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-ControlFlag-Open-Source</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-ControlFlag-Open-Source"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T18:29:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year Intel announced ControlFlag as a machine learning tool for helping to uncover bugs within code. ControlFlag promised impressive results after being trained on more than one billion lines of code and at the end of 2020 was already being used internally on Intel's code-bases from firmware to software applications. We hadn't heard anything more about ControlFlag this year... Until today. Intel has now made ControlFlag open-source for helping to autonomously detect more programming bugs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse OpenJ9 0.29 Released With Full AArch64 Linux Support, More Mature JITServer Tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Eclipse-OpenJ9-v0.29</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Eclipse-OpenJ9-v0.29"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T18:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The newest feature release to Eclipse OpenJ9 is now available, the high performance Java Virtual Machine originating from IBM J9...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[God Of War is coming to PC in January 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/god-of-war-is-coming-to-pc-in-january-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/god-of-war-is-coming-to-pc-in-january-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T16:32:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As was rumoured, the dadtastic godstabber God Of War is indeed coming to PC. Sony today announced that the PlayStation-exclusive action-adventure game will launch for PC on the 14th of January, 2022. Good game, that. It'll have support for assorted PC technical fanciness too.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Subnautica mods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-subnautica-mods</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-subnautica-mods"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:36:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subnautica was a game I spent a lot of time just living in. It was a rare combination of survival and relaxation. I loved the base building, crafting what amounted to a reverse aquarium clinging to an underwater sea cliff. It grew from a small bulb of oxygen into a proper little sanctuary. When I picked it up, it was fairly late into its life, and a number of mods were already waiting to be installed. I quickly dialed down the game’s frustrations and made my time under the sea all the more enjoyable, so here are our picks for the best Subnautica mods available today.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Craig Pearson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave 1.31 s Brave Search jako výchozím vyhledávačem]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42930</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/brave-1-31-s-brave-search-jako-vychozim-vyhledavacem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:33:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová verze webového prohlížeče Brave 1.31 je spojena s přechodem na vlastní vyhledávač jako výchozí – v USA, Kanadě a UK nahrazuje Google, ve Francii střídá Qwant, v Německu zase v Brave přecházejí z DuckDuckGo. Další země se budou přidávat postupně. Uživatelé samozřejmě mohou změnit na jakýkoli jiný a stávajícím uživatelům samozřejmě zůstává jejich nastavení. Brave Search má vlastní nezávislý index i engine, nesleduje uživatele ani jejich vyhledávání a kliknutí. V tuto chvíli nezobrazuje reklamy, ale v budoucnu bude reklamami podporován (plus bude možné používat Premium službu bez reklam).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 20 people reported for behaviour now gone from Activision Blizzard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-20-people-reported-for-behaviour-now-gone-from-activision-blizzard</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-20-people-reported-for-behaviour-now-gone-from-activision-blizzard"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard's initial response to allegations of workplace harrassment and discrimination was disappointing enough that thousands of current and former employees signed an open letter condemning it then hundreds staged a walkout in July. With several legal cases against the Warcraft and Call Of Duty owners underway, they've now admitted they haven't done enough. Yesterday, Along with laying out their next steps, they confirmed that over 20 people have "exited" Activision Blizzard in connection with reports against them.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD Blue SN570 review: The best cheap SSD grows up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wd-blue-sn570-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wd-blue-sn570-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a time, not so long ago, when the WD Blue line exemplified that “good but boring” quality that sees many a budget SSD damned by faint praise. Fast enough yet rarely eye-catchingly rapid, even when the WD Blue SN500 ditched SATA for the much quicker NVMe interface, they’ve always been sensible purchases that nonetheless lived in the shadow of the WD Black lineup. That all changes with the latest WD Blue SN570: it’s not just an excellent M.2 drive for the money, but quite possibly the single most compelling SSD for anyone sticking with PCIe 3.0.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The zombies in Back 4 Blood are more fashionable than me]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-zombies-in-back-4-blood-are-more-fashionable-than-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-zombies-in-back-4-blood-are-more-fashionable-than-me"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T14:41:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don't know what I was expecting to take away from co-op FPS Back 4 Blood. A greater sense of comradery between myself and my friends? An appreciation of the weighty guns and how magazines snap into place with each reload? The sheer amount of blood that splashes on your person with each wave of zombies you cut down? Yes, all of these things.
But none more so than what the zombies wear. They favour comfortable clothing, but mainly the gilet. They love gilets. And they now have me questioning my fashion choices. Should I also join them as a wearer of gilets?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that we know about Fireflies in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-fireflies</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-fireflies"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T14:40:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about Fireflies in Minecraft? Whether you call them Fireflies, glowbugs, or lightning bugs, they’ll all occupy the same two pixels when they come to Minecraft and it’s time to get fired up for their arrival. Fireflies were announced at Minecraft Live 2021, which also shared more details on the upcoming Caves and Cliffs part 2 update.
This guide will explain everything that you need to know about Fireflies in Minecraft, including when you can expect Fireflies to come to Minecraft, where Fireflies will appear, and what they do.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon RX 6600 Linux Performance Rising Even Higher With Newest Open-Source Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30628</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30628"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T13:09:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just one week ago was the public launch of the Radeon RX 6600 as the newest offering in the RDNA2 GPU line-up. While in our Radeon RX 6600 Linux review the performance was good on AMD's well regarded open-source driver stack and standing ground against the likes of the GeForce RTX 3060 with NVIDIA's proprietary Linux driver, it turns out the RX 6600 Linux performance can be even better already. Here are benchmarks of the Radeon RX 6600 on Linux across six different driver configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 To Support The 2021 Apple Magic Keyboard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Apple-Magic-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Apple-Magic-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T13:03:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Separate from all the ongoing Apple Silicon/M1 bring-up work for the Linux kernel, the Linux 5.16 cycle is set to support this year's Apple Magic Keyboard...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about mangrove swamps in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-mangrove-swamp</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-mangrove-swamp"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T11:42:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about mangrove swamps in Minecraft? At Minecraft Live 2021, Mojang revealed that mangrove swamps - one of the options in the biome vote way back in 2019 - are finally coming to Minecraft. Many of the ideas mentioned back then, including mangrove trees and frogs, will be key features of the mangrove swamp biome.
This guide will explain everything that you need to know about mangrove swamps in Minecraft, including when mangrove swamps will be released, what you will find in the new biome, and how to grow your own mangrove trees with propagules.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard want harassment lawsuit paused over conflict of interest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-want-harassment-lawsuit-paused-over-conflict-of-interest</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-want-harassment-lawsuit-paused-over-conflict-of-interest"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T10:58:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard have filed an application to halt the harassment and discrimination lawsuit from the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH). This follows an update on the suit last week, which revealed that two DFEH lawyers previously worked for the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), who're also going through legal proceedings with Actiblizzard, creating a conflict of interest. Now the Call Of Duty and World Of Warcraft publishers want the DFEH's case to be paused so they can investigate, and decide whether they want to try and get the case disqualified, or find "other appropriate remedies". 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomhaven review: a loving adaptation that nails the ambition and detail of the tabletop original]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gloomhaven-pc-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gloomhaven-pc-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomhaven’s scoundrel has a custom animation for her flintlock pistol, and I am still jazzed about it. Releasing today in full after lurking in early access for the last two years, there are 17 classes in this digital adaptation of Cephalofair’s tabletop legacy dungeon crawler, hereafter referred to as ‘Tablehaven’. Each class, from psychic rodent Mindthief to basalt shithouse Cragheart, has around 30 ability cards each. And Flaming Fowl, alongside offering Tablehaven’s entire branching campaign, map editors, and a digi-only ‘Guildmaster’ campaign, have animated this single flintlock shot. It’s almost opulent. 
All right, so I probably won’t use it much. Five damage at range four is a belter, but that burn hurts for a single target ability. I’ll be smiling when I do, though. Grinning as the scoundrel whips the silver pistol from her hip and deletes a cultist just before he summons a skeleton. Just as I’ve been grinning at these detailed, cel-shaded dungeons and grimy sewers, or the spoken narration before each quest. All Gloomhaven needed to do was not get in Tablehaven’s way too much. Accuracy and usability would have been just fine. But there’s enough passion and pizzaz in this wonderful package that a part of me wishes I was new here, just so I could be surprised all over again.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Silicon PCIe Driver Queued For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-PCIe-For-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-PCIe-For-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:54:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Queued this week into the Linux PCI subsystem's "next" branch is the Apple PCIe driver needed to enable PCI Express support for Apple SoCs such as the M1...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything we know about frogs in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-frogs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-frogs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about frogs in Minecraft? If you’ve always looked at lakes and rivers in Minecraft and thought ‘those need some slimy little amphibians that leap on lily pads and whip fireflies out of the sky with their tongues’, then you’re in luck! At Minecraft Live 2021, the team shared that we are getting frogs in Minecraft, and they’ll actually have a lot more depth than you might expect.
This guide will explain everything that we currently know about frogs in Minecraft, including how to get the different frog variants and how they act.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Genshin Impact Hu Tao build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-hu-tao-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-hu-tao-build"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:53:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Hu Tao build in Genshin Impact? As the 77th Director of the Wangsheng Funeral Parlor, Hu Tao has the help of ghosts in battle, where she’ll stir up a fright as she absolutely demolishes enemies. Despite being a bit of a prankster, the Pyro Polearm wielder will make a great DPS addition to your team.
This guide will show you how to create the best Hu Tao build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Hu Tao, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google představil telefony Pixel 6 a Pixel 6 Pro s vlastním 5nm čipem Tensor]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42929</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/google-predstavil-telefony-pixel-6-a-pixel-6-pro-s-vlastnim-5nm-cipem-tensor/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový 5nm procesor Google Tensor, displej s 90Hz a HDR10+, sklo Gorilla Glass Victus, nová baterie foťáků s podporou 4k/60p videa či 30W nabíjení s USB PD a samozřejmě Android 12, to jsou v základu nové Pixely od Googlu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that we know about the Allay in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-allay</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-allay"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T08:52:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about the Allay in Minecraft? For the past few years, Minecraft Live has included lots of announcements about new updates, as well as a fan vote for a new Minecraft mob. For Minecraft Live 2021, the options were the Glare, the Copper Golem, and the Allay. Ultimately, the Allay came out on top, and will be added to Minecraft in 2022.
Here’s everything that you need to know about the adorable Allay, including when it will arrive in Minecraft and what the Allay will do.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se pracovat s Dockerem a kontejnery (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-39529</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-pracovat-s-dockerem-a-kontejnery-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T08:13:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Docker je dnes technologie, která proces vývoje, testování a provozování softwaru velmi zjednodušuje. Provozujte cokoliv a kdekoliv. Už nečekejte na nastavení svého serveru nebo na aktualizaci nějaké knihovny. Mějte prostředí jako součást vaší aplikace.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[24. stretnutie komunity Cloud Native – Kubernetes online]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42927</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/24-stretnutie-komunity-cloud-native-kubernetes-online-1/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T08:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nosná téma meetupu: CI/CD & DevOps culture, 20.10.2021 od 18:00 do 20:00.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD GPU Driver Looks To Make Use Of Intel's New Buddy Allocator Code In The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Intel-Buddy-Allocator</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Intel-Buddy-Allocator"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to the nature of open-source, AMD engineers for the "AMDGPU" kernel graphics driver are looking to make use of Intel's new i915 buddy allocator code they introduced as part of all their video memory management changes as part of their discrete graphics bring-up...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 95 přináší URLPattern či API Eye Dropper]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42928</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chrome-95-prinasi-urlpattern-ci-api-eye-dropper/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T06:38:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová verze webového prohlížeče Google Chrome (a též Chromium). Mezi novinkami přináší jednodušší routování pomocí URLPattern přímo v prohlížeči, dále API Eye Dropper poskytující zabudovaný nástroj pro výběr barev. Další novinky nalezneme v origin trials (například user-agent reduction).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Wii U Gamepad Linux Driver Support Still Pursuing Mainline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wii-U-Gamepad-Driver-v4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wii-U-Gamepad-Driver-v4"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a half-year since talking about the Wii U gamepad driver that's been in development with mainline ambitions for supporting this wireless gamepad in conjunction with the Nintendo Wii U console. The driver has just been revised to address earlier code review comments, again renewing interest in the effort and possible mainlining in a future kernel version...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Arts]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2531/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2531/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle Releases GraalVM 21.3 With Java 17 Support, Other Enhancements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GraalVM-21.3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GraalVM-21.3-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T23:17:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle has published its latest quarterly update to GraalVM, the  open-source Java JVM/JDK implemented in Java that also supports other execution modes and programming languages from Python to R to Ruby...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riders Republic will offer a free trial week before launch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-will-offer-a-free-trial-week-before-launch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-will-offer-a-free-trial-week-before-launch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T23:11:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm exhausted at the mere thought of most Ubisoft games now, but I do want to fall down mountains in Riders Republic. To make that easier for me, Ubisoft are offering a trial week for their bigly multiplayer extreme sports 'em up. From October 21st until the 27th, you'll be able to play four hours of Riders Republic for free, with progress carrying over to the full game should you buy it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator is getting more free updates with GOTY edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-is-getting-more-free-updates-with-goty-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-is-getting-more-free-updates-with-goty-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T22:18:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator is getting a 'Game Of The Year' edition. The skybound sim has received regular free updates since launch, each adding new cities and points of interest. The GOTY edition will bring even more, including new potogrammetry cities, 8 new airpirts, and 5 new aircraft. It'll launch on November 18th and be free to all existing players.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logování v PHP: různé možnosti výsledného formátování výstupů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15674</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/logovani-v-php-ruzne-moznosti-vysledneho-formatovani-vystupu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V poslední třetí části budou popisovány různé možnosti výsledného formátování výstupů, které dokáží výrazně ovlivnit logovanou informaci. Na závěr bude uveden realističtější příklad použití, ze které vyplynou možné kombinace.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Herout)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (20. 10. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15719</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-20-10-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes si představíme platformu pro ladění mobilních aplikací, vyzkoušíme Visual Studio Code bez telemetrie, začneme používat Signal i mimo mobilní zařízení a nakonec navrhneme větrnou turbínu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jiří Sluka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo and Disintegration's Marcus Lehto founding new studio with EA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-and-disintegrations-marcus-lehto-founding-new-studio-with-ea</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-and-disintegrations-marcus-lehto-founding-new-studio-with-ea"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T21:55:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marcus Lehto, former creative director at Bungie and the artist responsible for Master Chief, has joined EA to found a new studio that will make first-person games. Lehto's last company was V1 Interactive, who released the short-lived Disintegration last year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead By Daylight's Hellraiser models are now an NFT]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-models-are-now-an-nft</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-models-are-now-an-nft"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T21:33:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you enjoy the feeling of having pins hammered into your head? Then allow me to introduce you to: our modern reality. 

Today's pin to the brow is that you can now buy NFTs based on Dead By Daylight's in-game models of Hellraiser's Pinhead. I can tell the difference between pleasure and pain, and this is pain.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked 'do not ban' list reveals how Twitch dealt with rule breakers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leaked-do-not-ban-list-reveals-how-twitch-dealt-with-rule-breakers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leaked-do-not-ban-list-reveals-how-twitch-dealt-with-rule-breakers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T20:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among the many discoveries of this month's Twitch source code and data leak was a file called "do_not_ban_list." While not as black and white as the name suggest, the file sheds light on the otherwise opaque way Twitch has enforced its rules when streamers break them.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get an RTX 3060 gaming laptop for $850 in an early Black Friday deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3060-gaming-laptop-for-850-in-an-early-black-friday-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3060-gaming-laptop-for-850-in-an-early-black-friday-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T19:16:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MSI GF65 Thin is the first Black Friday gaming laptop deal we've spotted, around a month before the shopping holiday traditionally begins. At Best Buy, you can pick up this RTX 3060 equipped machine for $850, a cool $250 below its usual price of $1100. That's a fantastic value for a laptop that's seen strong reviews since its release earlier this year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade your PC with two sticks of 8GB 3200MHz RAM for £55]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/upgrade-your-pc-with-two-sticks-of-8gb-3200mhz-ram-for-55</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/upgrade-your-pc-with-two-sticks-of-8gb-3200mhz-ram-for-55"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T18:01:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adata is one of the best brands for budget RAM, and their long-standing Gammix D10 series offers a good balance of low price and high performance. Right now you can pick up two 8GB sticks of DDR4-3200 CL16 memory from Ebuyer for £56, around £10 cheaper than you'd pay for RAM with the same specs on Amazon. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grotto review: a grim, mystical tale about the limitations of language]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grotto-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grotto-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's a hard life, being a soothsayer in Grotto. You live in a dingy little cave, the locals look at you with varying levels of distrust and suspicion, and occasionally your campfire will perk up and talk to you when no one's looking, its yellow flames turning an ominous shade of blue as it whispers dread-filled words about failure and the beating heart of the mountain into your ear. It's unclear how you ended up like this, but day after day you're tasked with consulting the handful of stars visible through a crack in the cave's ceiling to dole out advice to the local tribespeople, a group of anthropomorphic animals known only as The Brutes. 
Said advice comes in the form of 24 constellations you can discover by looking up and drawing shapes in the sky with your mouse. You'll need to give one of them to each Brute that asks you a question, but when every constellation has its own fortune-cookie-like meaning attached to it, finding the right one to answer their question successfully can be a challenge. As the toad man Ouuch tells you at the start, if you ask three separate people what the word 'blue' means to them, you'll get three separate answers. Sometimes, your intentions will be misinterpreted, while others will willfully ignore you. But one thing Grotto always manages to do is to keep you coming back for more. Once you've set this car crash of consequences in motion, it's very hard to tear your eyes away.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crysis Remastered Trilogy: new and old versions compared]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-remastered-trilogy-new-and-old-versions-compared</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-remastered-trilogy-new-and-old-versions-compared"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T16:11:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Crysis Remastered Trilogy is out, complete with all the angry nanosuit men, angry alien squids, and solitary angry Cockney bloke of the originals – now with 8K support. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft 1.19 release date: The Wild Update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-1-19-the-wild-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-1-19-the-wild-update"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T15:17:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about the Minecraft 1.19 update? The Wild Update was revealed at Minecraft Live 2021, where we got details about all of the new additions, including frogs, fireflies, and mangrove swamps. This will be the first Minecraft update in 2022, and will be the next major update after Caves and Cliffs part 2.
This guide will explain everything that you can expect with Minecraft 1.19, so that you don’t go wild looking for details all over.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 trailer shows Grand Cathay and Tzeentch rumbling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-trailer-shows-grand-cathay-and-tzeentch-rumbling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-trailer-shows-grand-cathay-and-tzeentch-rumbling"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T14:04:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a lot of explaining how the factions of Grand Cathay and Tzeentch will work in Total War: Warhammer 3, Creative Assembly today demonstrated with a nine-minute video dramatically recapping a battle between the two. The third game in their fantasy real-time strategy series has needed to invent and fill out a lot of armies not present in the tabletop game, so it's interesting to see them in action. Got some nice colours and weird warmen, at the very least.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple prodává hadřík za 590 Kč]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42923</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/apple-prodava-hadrik-za-590-kc/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Apple má mezi svými produkty v nabídce čisticí hadřík. Koupí získá zákazník produkt vhodný k očištění jakýchkoli displejů Apple, včetně těch s nanotexturou. Seznam kompatibilních produktů je velmi dlouhý a logo Apple na hadříku Apple velmi povedené a dojem dokonalého výrobku podtrhuje cenovka 590 Kč.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Build HAT propojí malinu s LEGO Technics / Mindstorms]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42922</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-build-hat-propoji-malinu-s-lego-technics-mindstorms/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T12:54:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi představuje novou rozšiřující desku pro své minipočítače. Raspberry Pi Build HAT umožní připojit k Raspberry Pi snímače či motory systému LEGO Technics / LEGO Education SPIKE, resp. oblíbené stavebnice LEGO Mindstorms (a další s konektorem LPF2). Raspberry Pi navíc mezi produkty přidává potřebné příslušenství jak na poli hardwaru (napájecí 48W zdroj, který se postará i o napájení samotného Raspberry Pi), tak na poli softwaru (Python Build HAT).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Games investigating New World invulnerability exploit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazon-games-investigating-new-world-invulnerability-exploit</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazon-games-investigating-new-world-invulnerability-exploit"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T12:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World players have found an exploit that lets you turn invincible, which is certainly not the sort of exploit you want in your PvP-focused MMORPG. According to players who've encountered the bug, it's pretty easy to replicate, and folks are calling for wars to be disabled until there's a fix. Amazon Games say they're aware of the problem and are investigating, so hopefully they'll patch the game soon to make sure everyone's staying vincible.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Valhalla's educational Discovery Tour is out today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-valhallas-educational-discovery-tour-is-out-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-valhallas-educational-discovery-tour-is-out-today"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T12:31:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best part of primary school in the UK is learning about Vikings: getting to make and decorate cardboard swords and jewellery, write stories about legends, and maybe even escape school with a visit to a historical site. Well, Assassin's Creed Valhalla might not offer the same crafting opportunities, but you can learn a lot about the game's history with the new Discovery Tour mode. It hits Valhalla today in a free update, and will also be sold separately for folks who don't want Valhalla.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck Verified: hodnocení bezproblémovosti chodu her]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42921</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/steam-deck-verified-hodnoceni-bezproblemovosti-chodu-her/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T11:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve v rámci zkonzolovatění Linuxu na Decku spustilo hodnocení her, jak zákazníkům na Decku poběží. Hodnocení zahrnuje následující varianty:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Smrž)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new character is a familiar face from Titanfall 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-character-is-a-familiar-face-from-titanfall-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-character-is-a-familiar-face-from-titanfall-2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T11:17:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends is adding a second spooky murderbot to its roster, one that both Apex and Titanfall 2 fans might recognise. Ash is a simulacrum (human consciousness in a freaky robot) who was previously a baddie in Titanfall 2. Since May this year, she's been overseeing Apex's new 3v3 Arenas mode - you know, that ominous voice that tells you to crush your enemies. But in the battle royale's next season, Escape, she'll be joining the fight herself.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm sorry to say it New World, but you need mounts, mate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-to-say-it-new-world-but-you-need-mounts-mate</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-to-say-it-new-world-but-you-need-mounts-mate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My heart sinks every time I accept a quest in MMORPG New World, which isn't ideal. These are tickets to adventure, to discovery, to that sweet, sweet EXP. But the more time I spend with the game, the more I'm beginning to loathe them. It's got nothing to do with what you actually do in them, it's the getting there that's the problem. I have to run my little legs ragged and I'm tired. I'm so very tired of it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ActRaiser Renaissance review: raise one for a great remake of a 16-bit classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actraiser-renaissance-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actraiser-renaissance-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[1990's ActRaiser is special. Most video games released in the late '80s tasked you with saving a princess from a dragon. ActRaiser says, “Hey, would you mind playing God with the people living on the demon-scarred land you just liberated? They're really squishy and helpless. Thanks, you’re a peach."
The game's developer, Quintet, was pretty special, too. Once a branch of Enix before the latter joined with Squaresoft in 2003, Quintet was behind a lot of SNES-era RPGs that are still fondly remembered today, such Illusion of Gaia and Terranigma. They’re all solid adventures that share a canon, albeit vaguely, and tackle some pretty heavy subject matter, including colonialism, poverty, and the slave trade. Alas, Quintet disbanded when Square Enix was born, and most of its team scattered to the winds. There’s been a Q-shaped hole in my heart ever since, so I hope I can be excused for yelling like a madwoman when ActRaiser Renaissance made a surprise debut at the September 2021 Nintendo Direct presentation.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Oxford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RPS Asks: you to please take our 2021 readership survey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-you-to-please-take-our-2021-readership-survey</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-you-to-please-take-our-2021-readership-survey"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:40:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's that time of year again where we come to you with a single question: would you fill out our RPS Readership Survey, please? It should only take around 5-10 minutes of your time to complete, and it will be a big help to us going forward - particularly when it comes to shaping the future of the RPS supporter program.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Childe build (Tartaglia)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-childe-build-tartaglia</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-childe-build-tartaglia"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:06:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Childe build in Genshin Impact? Thanks to his unique ability set that enables both close-range and long-range combat, Hydro Bow user Childe (also known as Tartaglia) is especially powerful in almost any situation and is great as a main or sub DPS. As the 11th Harbinger of the Fatui, he’s an incredibly fierce warrior who also cares deeply for those he loves.
This guide will show you how to create the best Childe build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Childe, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CZ.NIC zkušebně vypne tunelovací technologie Teredo a 6to4 pro IPv6]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15717</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/cz-nic-zkusebne-vypne-tunelovaci-technologie-teredo-a-6to4-pro-ipv6/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CZ.NIC se rozhodl, že obě IPv6 tunelovací technologie na zkoušku vypne 25. října 2021 na dobu 24 hodin. Pokud se nestane nic neočekávaného, budou servery definitivně vypnuty už 1. listopadu 2021. Proč k tomu dojde?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Václav Steiner)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic-256: další moderní reinkarnace BASICu určená pro výuku programování]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15718</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/basic-256-dalsi-moderni-reinkarnace-basicu-urcena-pro-vyuku-programovani/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prozatím poslední moderní reinkarnací programovacího jazyka BASIC, s níž se seznámíme, je Basic-256. Opět se jedná o jazyk (a vývojové prostředí) určené primárně pro výuku programování, které navíc podporuje i práci s grafikou.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple představil až 10jádrová SoC M1 Pro a M1 Max]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42920</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/apple-predstavil-az-10jadrova-soc-m1-pro-a-m1-max/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dva nové čipy pro své počítače představil Apple v souvislosti s novými Macbooky Pro. Firma navyšuje počet CPU i GPU jader a hovoří až o 70 % vyšším CPU výkonu oproti M1 a o 2× rychlejším GPU v M1 Pro, resp. 4× rychlejším v M1 Max. Jinými slovy: už tak rychlé a úsporné řešení jménem Apple M1 v nových Macboocích Pro bude značně rychlejší a nikdo nemůže ani vzdáleně hovořit o tom, že by bylo (z hlediska výkonu) lepší, kdyby s Apple vrátil k Intelu (což je mimochodem plán Pata Gelsingera).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell's 1440p 240Hz Alienware monitor is back to £550]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dells-1440p-240hz-alienware-monitor-is-back-to-550</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dells-1440p-240hz-alienware-monitor-is-back-to-550"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T19:58:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Dell Alienware AW2721D is one of our top recommended monitors, sitting right in the emerging 1440p 240Hz sweet spot preferred by players of fast-paced shooters and racing titles. Right now, the monitor has returned to the lowest price we've ever seen for it, £550, down from a nominal RRP of over £800. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Here's how you'll know which games will run on Valve's Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve have always maintained that the Steam Deck is closer to a conventional PC than a handheld console, and as such should be able to run your existing library of games on Steam. But while the official Steam Deck Twitter is full of videos showing games performing well on dev kits, the compatibility status of many more games remains up in the air. That could just be through a lack of confirmation, or it could be deep-lying technical issues relating to hardware requirements or anti-cheat services that needed tweaks to work on the Deck’s Proton-based OS. Ahead of the planned December launch, Valve have unveiled their plan to bring clarity on whether specific games will be able to run (and run effectively) on the Steam Deck.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a WD Blue 4TB SSD for just $339 at Newegg - $50 off its normal price]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wd-blue-4tb-ssd-for-just-339-at-newegg-50-off-its-normal-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wd-blue-4tb-ssd-for-just-339-at-newegg-50-off-its-normal-price"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T17:20:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Blue SATA SSD is a great choice if you want a lot of fast storage at a cheap price, and today Newegg are offering $50 off the giant 4TB size when you use the code EMC2AAZA827. This knocks the price to $339, the cheapest we've seen a 4TB drive in some time and $40 below the current Amazon price. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit review: a gorgeous roguelike shooter that sadly descends into comfortable familiarity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know how some games, like, throb? I mean your Thumpers, your Devil Daggers, your Dooms. Games you disappear into, but not in that namby pamby, prancing around fulfilling all your desires sense. I mean games that will eat you alive unless you stop them. Games set in pulsating, hostile dimensions in which you don’t belong; games that fling their menageries at the battered windows of your soul, where survival teeters on a combo of hair-trigger reflexes and total concentration.


Into The Pit is one of those, until it isn’t. You know you’re in trouble when the demonic eldritch hell portal starts feeling too comfortable. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise PC vs Switch: how the demo compares]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-pc-vs-switch-how-the-demo-compares</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-pc-vs-switch-how-the-demo-compares"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:45:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The recent launch of the Monster Hunter Rise demo on PC has given us a free look at how this soon-to-be-former Nintendo Switch exclusive will run and play when it releases in full in January 2022. This calls, naturally, for some screenshot comparisons.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Žaloba na Canon: není možné skenovat bez inkoustu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42919</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/zaloba-na-canon-protoze-nejde-skenovat-bez-inkoustu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:40:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canon USA je žalován kvůli multifunkčním all-in-one tiskárnám PIXMA MG6320, MG5420 a MX860, které s prázdnými zásobníky inkoustu odmítají skenovat i když k tomu žádný inkoust potřeba není. Na problém si stěžovalo přes dva tisíce uživatelů, ale Canon jim odpověděl, že je potřeba vyměnit zásobník s inkoustem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[With mage hunts and talking trees, Salt And Sacrifice is looking like a worthy successor to Salt And Sanctuary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/salt-and-sacrifice-preview-a-worthy-successor-to-salt-and-sanctuary</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/salt-and-sacrifice-preview-a-worthy-successor-to-salt-and-sanctuary"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:35:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you liked Dark Soulsy side-scroller Salt And Sanctuary, I have some great news. I got hands-on with an early portion of its sequel Salt And Sacrifice, and it seems set to deliver all the things that made its predecessor tick. The punishing enemies, the smooth combat, the vast skill trees, and the interconnected world are all still doing good things, but this time around they've just been joined by a few new additions, or seen some tweaks to keep things fresher, but no less difficult.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machinarium is selling the best merch: a bronze statuette of its adorable star]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/machinarium-is-selling-the-best-merch-a-bronze-statuette-of-its-adorable-star</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/machinarium-is-selling-the-best-merch-a-bronze-statuette-of-its-adorable-star"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:29:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don't buy video game merch, and if I did buy video game merch I wouldn't buy statues, and yet... my heart melts looking at Machinarium's hot new merch drop. Amanita are selling a limited run of bronze statuettes of the adventure game's adorable scrap robot star, Josef, and I love him. 405 grams of bronze might sound cold to hold but I know he'd warm my heart.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption review: a sinister and excellently crafted card game with a darkly comic underbelly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Be afraid. Inscryption is both a love letter to card games and a twisted, jocular caricature of their numerical excess. It had me grinning ear to ear, sometimes nervously, sometimes with the joy of someone who simply loves thumbing through new cards, even when a rustic antagonist with big hands is reaching for my throat. This is not your average deckbuilder. It's a card game with an escape room built on top, and other sinister secrets buried beneath. The depth of its rabbit hole isn't apparent at first. It starts off as a familiar card battler, if a little darkly themed. You are in a cabin, playing cards against a face shrouded in darkness. It seems like Slay The Spire or Hand Of Fate. 
Then the cards start talking.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elden Ring delayed to February 25th, 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-delayed-to-february-25th-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-delayed-to-february-25th-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:51:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In game development, the flow of time itself is convoluted, with projects centuries old phasing in and out, so we shouldn't be surprised that Bandai Namco have delayed the launch of Elden Ring. The long-awaited new game from the makers of Dark Souls was expected to launch on January 21st, but now it's due on February 25th. Sounds like the usual reason: they want more time to make it good, yeah? Oh, and supposed leaked gameplay footage is doing the rounds, though I warn you that it's a bad and disappointing clip.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Succubus has censorship on by default, and it's unintentionally the most hilarious thing I've ever seen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/succubus-censorship-on-by-default</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/succubus-censorship-on-by-default"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes a game is so clearly desperate for attention that you are loathe to give it any. Like that one guy whose entire brand is getting in loud quote-tweet arguments on Twitter every eight to ten weeks, you know both exactly what it wants, and that you shouldn't go there. For months now I have been getting regular emails from the Succubus devs, all of which contain 112% of my daily recommended nipple allowance, and I know - I know - I shouldn't be writing about it. It is an action-adventure-hell-titty game that is, on every level, very bad. But I am breaking my silence now because the censored version of it is, quite possibly, the funniest thing I have encountered in my recent memory, and accidentally better than anything the devs could have made on purpose. You win, Madmind Studio. You win.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say hello to RPS' new guides writers, Rebecca Jones and Hayden Hefford]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/say-hello-to-rps-new-guides-writers-rebecca-jones-and-hayden-hefford</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/say-hello-to-rps-new-guides-writers-rebecca-jones-and-hayden-hefford"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:08:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After months of searching, I'm pleased to announce that the RPS guides team has finally added two fresh faces to its ranks. Please say hello to Rebecca Jones and Hayden Hefford.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay aktualizoval spoustu klasických her, aby fungovaly v Linuxu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42918</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/interplay-aktualizoval-spoustu-klasickych-her-aby-fungovaly-v-linuxu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T13:43:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve čtvrtek Interplay Entertainment oznámil, že aktualizoval spoustu klasických her na Steamu, aby fungovaly v Linuxu a macOS. Většinou půjde o přidání DOSBoxu. V seznamu her od Inteplay uvidíte nově velké množství her spustitelných v Linuxu (logo Steam). Jde třeba o Battle Chess, Battle Chess II: Chinese Chess, Battle Chess 4000, Descent a Descent 2.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh, nope, Microsoft's big hint at Fable news today was nothing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-nope-microsofts-big-hint-at-fable-news-today-was-nothing</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-nope-microsofts-big-hint-at-fable-news-today-was-nothing"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T11:46:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, Microsoft's Xbox Game Studios Publishing Twitter account offered what sure sounded like tantalising hints that Monday would bring big news on the mysterious upcoming new Fable game. Like, really sounded like. Like, totally sounded like the sort of obvious hint marketing campaigns drop when they're pretending it's a surprise but want you to know full well what's up. Nope. They've now deleted those tweets and apologised, saying no, no Fable news today. Oh.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telegram dosáhl miliardy stažení v Google Play]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42917</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/telegram-dosahl-miliardy-stazeni-v-google-play/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T11:31:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obchod Google Play hlásí, že si oficiálního klienta Telegram stáhla více než miliarda uživatelů. Pavel Durov, zakladatel tohoto komunikačního nástroje, přitom na začátku letošního roku tvrdil, že jej měsíčně použije asi půl miliardy uživatelů. Překročení miliardového milníku bylo urychleno také nedávnými velkými výpadky Facebooku, které postihly také WhatsApp a Messenger a přivedly Telegramu desítky milionů nových uživatelů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back 4 Blood jukebox music list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-jukebox</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-jukebox"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want a list of songs that play on the Back 4 Blood jukebox? A few missions into Act 1, you’ll come across the Bar Room Blitz mission. Sure, there are some story points about distracting zombies and saving people, but this mission is a smash-hit for one reason. There’s a jukebox that plays some very cool tunes in the background whilst you shoot, slash, and slaughter zombies from every angle. If you really like that one scene in Shaun Of The Dead, then this will be your fever dream.
This guide will show you all of the songs that you can hear on the Back 4 Blood jukebox, so that you can repeatedly replay Bar Room Blitz whilst waiting for someone to inevitably get Simon Pegg and Nick Frost to play the mission on Youtube.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kódové jméno Ubuntu 22.04 LTS odhaleno, vyšlo OpenBSD 7.0]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15714</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kodove-jmeno-ubuntu-22-04-lts-odhaleno-vyslo-openbsd-7-0/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:44:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kódové jméno Ubuntu 22.04 LTS odhaleno. Vyšlo OpenBSD 7.0. Vznikl alternativní klient pro Snap, který umí pracovat i s repozitáři mimo Canonical. Společnost Pine64 zahájila předobjednávky pro svůj telefon PinePhone Pro.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gotham Knights trailer introduces its baddies, the Court of Owls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gotham-knights-trailer-introduces-its-baddies-the-court-of-owls</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gotham-knights-trailer-introduces-its-baddies-the-court-of-owls"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T09:46:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your reaction to hearing that the villains of Batman 'em up Gotham Knights are the Court of Owls is "Hoo?", 1) wow, good grief 2) you might want to watch these new trailers. Released over the weekend during the DC FanDome pow-o-rama, they introduce the secret society who pull Gotham's strings, as well as giving us a peek at the game's version of Penguin.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WhatsApp přestane od 1. listopadu fungovat na Androidu 4.0.4 a starším]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42916</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/whatsapp-prestane-od-1-listopadu-fungovat-na-androidu-4-04-a-starsim/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T08:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WhatsApp přestane od 1. listopadu fungovat na Androidu 4.0.4 a starším. Ke svému běhu bude potřebovat alespoň Android 4.1.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Měsíc bude mít svůj internet LunaNet]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42915</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mesic-bude-mit-svuj-internet-lunanet/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T06:11:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V rámci programu Artemis plánuje NASA návrat astronautů na Měsíc v roce 2024. Předtím bude na Měsíci vybudována síť LunaNet, která bude podobná jako WiFi s velkým počtem vysílačů. To umožní využívat také přesnou polohu a čas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical Trials]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2530/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2530/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podzimní smršť novinek od Aceru. SentinelOne v ČR nabere 300 lidí a investuje miliardu. Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci. Dodávky a ceny osobních počítačů z pohledu výrobce. VMworld: Zabezpečení na principu nulové důvěry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: co odhalil phishing na CoinBase]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15715</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-co-odhalil-phishing-na-coinbase/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes se podíváme na jemnou hodinářskou práci útočníků při získávání OTP hesel, koukneme se na nové povinnost provozovatelů informačních systémů a také na to, co můžeme čekat v oblasti kybernetické bezpečnosti od nové vlády.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CSIRT.CZ)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-614</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-614"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for inhaling the smell of a new book. Before you lean in, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GTA: The Trilogy system requirements and details allegedly leak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-the-trilogy-system-requirements-and-details-allegedly-leak</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-the-trilogy-system-requirements-and-details-allegedly-leak"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T23:26:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rockstar finally announced their long-rumoured Grand Theft Auto remasters a little over a week ago. Official confirmation that they were on the way hasn't stopped the leaks, however. A user of GTAForums has seemingly leaked a more detailed description of the games and their system requirements.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dota 2's next hero is Marci from the Dota: Dragon's Blood anime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dota-2s-next-hero-is-marci-from-the-dota-dragons-blood-anime</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dota-2s-next-hero-is-marci-from-the-dota-dragons-blood-anime"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:42:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dota 2 is getting a new hero this autumn. It's Marci, the mute bodyguard from Netflix's Dota anime, Dota: Dragon's Blood. She'll join the game in an update "coming soon."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tweet2Doom lets you play Doom via Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tweet2doom-lets-you-play-doom-via-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tweet2doom-lets-you-play-doom-via-twitter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:06:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doom is now playable on Twitter - sort of. Thanks to Tweet2Doom bot, you can send replies to the account with a list of actions - move, turn, shoot, etc. - and get a video clip of Doom showing the results sent back to you. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence v kooperativních hrách]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový typ magnetismu nezpůsobují spiny. Beethovenovu slavnou 10. symfonii dokončila umělá inteligence  Studium neuronových sítí může pomoci při zkoumání toho, jak se do mozku ukládají konspirační teorie. Minirobot se pohybuje díky gradientům teploty. Splynutí obřích černých děr provázejí nejen gravitační vlny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rocksteady's Suicide Squad gets a new story trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rocksteadys-suicide-squad-gets-a-new-story-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rocksteadys-suicide-squad-gets-a-new-story-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T21:27:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's DC FanDome event brought another trailer for Rocksteady's Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League. There's still no gameplay, but the story trailer filled out the world, its cast, and heck, it's good fun. Watch it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games Store will "welcome games that make use of blockchain tech"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-store-will-welcome-games-that-make-use-of-blockchain-tech</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-store-will-welcome-games-that-make-use-of-blockchain-tech"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T20:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday Valve told developers that they wouldn't allow games featuring NFTs or cryptocurrency on their digital storefront, Steam. Since then, Epic have followed up by telling The Verge that the Epic Games Store would be "open to games that support cryptocurrency or blockchain-based assets."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft Dungeons adds roguelikelike singleplayer mode this December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-dungeons-adds-roguelikelike-singleplayer-mode-this-december</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-dungeons-adds-roguelikelike-singleplayer-mode-this-december"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft Dungeons has finished telling its story through a number of DLCs that have released over the last year, but Mojang isn't done with the blocky Diablo-like just yet. They're introducing seasonal updates that they're calling Seasonal Adventures, adding progression systems, challenges and more - similar to the new Sea Of Thieves' Seasons. Season 1 will be called The Cloudy Climb, and it's coming this December. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft's The Wild Update will add excellent frogs after Caves & Cliffs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecrafts-the-wild-update-will-add-excellent-frogs-after-caves-cliffs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecrafts-the-wild-update-will-add-excellent-frogs-after-caves-cliffs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Minecraft's Caves & Cliffs part 2 nearly upon us, Mojang have revealed the next big update that will follow it. Named The Wild Update, it'll focus on enhancing some of the existing areas we can explore and, importantly, adding colourful frogs! They'll arrive with the new Mangrove Swamp biome, along with tadpoles, fireflies and more. The Wild Update will also introduce the Deep Dark biome, which was supposed to arrive with Caves & Cliffs, but needed a little more time in the oven. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft will soon bundle Java and Bedrock editions together]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-will-soon-bundle-java-and-bedrock-editions-together</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-will-soon-bundle-java-and-bedrock-editions-together"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years and years, Minecraft's Java and Bedrock editions have lived apart, but Mojang finally have plans to unite them. They plan to package the two together next year as the Minecraft PC Bundle, so if you own one you'll get the other too. Ahead of this, both Java and Bedrock are coming to Xbox Game Pass for PC on November 2nd, which is lovely news. I've only ever owned Java, so it'll be nice to have the option to jump into Bedrock too.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxový telefon PinePhone Pro]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42914</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linuxovy-telefon-pinephone-pro/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T11:25:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost PINE64 včera představila linuxový telefon PinePhone Pro, který je vylepšením původního PinePhone. Obsahuje SoC Rockchip RK3399S (2× A72 + 4× A53 na 1,5 GHz) a 4 GB RAM. Interní úložiště má 128 GB eMMC a je možné připojit SDCX kartu až do velikosti 2 TB.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 LTS bude Jammy Jellyfish]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42913</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-22-04-lts-bude-jammy-jellyfish/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T10:57:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Následující vydání oblíbené distribuce Ubuntu 22.04 LTS bude mít označení Jammy Jellyfish. Tedy šťastná medúza nebo také medúza marmeládové konzistence.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-165</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-165"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A week of goodbyes. Vid bud Colm waved goodbye on Monday, and Friday was the final shift at the news face for longtime evening freelancer Lauren Morton. She leaves us to join cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer and they'll be lucky to have her, as we were. Say goodbye, gang.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portal speedrunner explains their wild tricks to Valve developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/portal-speedrunner-explains-their-wild-tricks-to-valve-developers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/portal-speedrunner-explains-their-wild-tricks-to-valve-developers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:48:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm constantly in awe of the wild tricks that speedrunners discover in just about any game they set their collective minds to. It's always a treat to hear developers being equally astounded though, and Valve's developers are no exception. Three of them recently got to have a chat with Portal speedrunner "CantEven" to ask about extremely calculated trick shots, weird save glitches, and all the other things that game developers don't always know about their own games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch are "confident" no passwords or credit cards were exposed in leak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-confident-no-passwords-or-credit-cards-were-exposed-in-leak</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-confident-no-passwords-or-credit-cards-were-exposed-in-leak"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:07:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch were hit by a rather big source code and data breach earlier this month, which they say they've since been investigating. They've updated users again today, reiterating that the breach was made possible by a server configuration change and that they're confident no passwords, login credentials, or credit card numbers were exposed.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 41/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retro sci-fi thriller The Invincible now has a proper trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/retro-sci-fi-thriller-the-invincible-now-has-a-proper-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/retro-sci-fi-thriller-the-invincible-now-has-a-proper-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T21:05:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Retro-future sci-fi romp The Invincible is the upcoming thriller from some folks formerly of The Witcher, Cyberpunk, Dying Light, and others. It's based on the sci-fi novel of the same title from the 60s by Polish author Stanisław Lem. The first we saw of The Invincible last year was mostly a teaser set to some nice tunes, but now there's a full cutscene-style trailer to check out and it sure does look like some classic space stuff.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam is banning games with NFTs and cryptocurrency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-is-banning-games-with-nfts-and-cryptocurrency</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-is-banning-games-with-nfts-and-cryptocurrency"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T20:14:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve appear to be laying down some new rules for games on Steam, specifically games that involve trading or receiving cryptocurrancy and NFTs. The change has been shared by SpacePirate Games, developers of Age Of Rust, who say they were notified this week about the new prohibition. Over in the Steamworks portal, a new type of content that cannot be published on Steam has been added. "Applications built on blockchain technology that issue or allow exchange of cryptocurrencies or NFTs."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lo-fi adventure Chasing Static is now out with some classic horror puzzling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-adventure-chasing-static-is-now-out-with-some-classic-horror-puzzling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-adventure-chasing-static-is-now-out-with-some-classic-horror-puzzling"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:56:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chasing Static is both the name of this lo-fi Welsh horror story and also an accurate description of me attempting to track down a post about it on RPS. Someone's written about it. I just know it. Oh no, we've just mentioned it several times in a roundabout way. Well, I've finally pinned it down—chased the clues and cornered it now that it's launched and I can tell you a thing or two about it. Chasing Static is a swell and spooky story so far with a good chunk of classic horror game puzzling and just a bit of sudden scares. Come on and have a quick look.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultimate Audio Bang #16: all things FPS merch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-16-all-things-fps-merch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-16-all-things-fps-merch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:24:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've returned from my trip to the Lake District, with aching calves and a desire to talk about online shooters with Imogen. On this week's episode of the Ultimate Audio Bang, we don't chat sore muscles, instead, we focus on various Halloween events in games like Apex Legends and Rainbow Six: Siege, our thoughts on the Battlefield 2042 beta, Destiny 2 vaulting yet more stuff, and Call Of Duty: Vanguard finally introducing anti-cheat.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TFI Friday: three indie puzzle games with slightly melancholy vibe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-three-indie-puzzle-games-with-slightly-melancholy-vibe</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-three-indie-puzzle-games-with-slightly-melancholy-vibe"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year has finally turned, reader. I am having discussions at home about putting the heating on. When I leave the office it isn't dark, but it's fuzzy around the edges. My knuckles are cold. It's the time of year, before the Skeleton War memes begin in earnest, to luxuriate in feeling a bit melancholy. It's healthy to feel sad sometimes, you know. Didn't you watch Inside Out? I did, and in my screening at the cinema a child called out "Where's Bing Bong?" when the heroic Bing Bong disappeared...
This week, I have collected three different puzzle games with very different vibes. I know I'm biased in favour of puzzle games more than the usual reader, but these ones are very good and worth a punt, and at least one should pique the old interest. And they all gave me that happy-sad feeling. Like, I want to wrap up in a blanket and play these games and maybe think about my granny a bit. That sort of feeling.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Roblox horror games: great scary games in Roblox]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roblox-horror-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roblox-horror-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:42:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are the best horror games in Roblox? It's October once again, so naturally our minds are turning to Halloween. There are so, so many horror games in the world to choose from, especially since it's a genre that lends itself so well to short indie offerings. What I'm getting at here is that there are tons of scary games on Roblox, and if you fancy giving some a go this spooky season, we've put together a list of all-time favourites and current big trends.
You might have seen "scary corn game" trending in Roblox circles recently, and if you're wondering why that is, it's because no-one can spell or pronounce Kalampokiphobia — the technical name for fear of corn. This game, which originally popped up on the platform earlier this year, looks set to be the big Roblox horror trend this Halloween, egged on by TikTok and YouTube jumpscare videos that have been doing the rounds. It's a pretty standard run-and-hide game with a truly ludicrous (but somehow still a bit creepy) stalker character pursuing you through a disorienting corn maze.
Here's the link.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mon Amour is the most crazed, loved up take on Flappy Bird you'll ever see]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mon-amour-is-the-most-crazed-loved-up-take-on-flappy-bird-youll-ever-see</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mon-amour-is-the-most-crazed-loved-up-take-on-flappy-bird-youll-ever-see"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:38:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a banner week for Japanese indie game releases. First we had the delightful puzzle platformer ElecHead, now we have the latest from Onion Games, Mon Amour. It's a one-button score attack game in the same vein as Flappy Bird, only instead of piloting a dumpy chicken through a bunch of green pipes, here you're guiding a spinning, mustachioed man toward dozens of smoochable women. But before you arch that eyebrow at its somewhat questionable premise, yes, this is another entry from Onion Games where kissing saves the day, following in the esteemed footsteps of Chulip and Dandy Dungeon - and yes, it is every bit as mad and baffling (and exquisitely designed) as you'd expect.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Karlee build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-karlee</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-karlee"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:09:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Karlee in Back 4 Blood? Karlee isn’t one of the best characters in Back 4 Blood, but she still has some killer abilities that deserve a spot in your team. Most notably, Karlee can sense nearby hazards and Special Ridden, so you won’t be surprised when a Tallboy smashes around the corner. She also gets an extra quick inventory slot (used for defibrillators and stun guns) and increases the team’s use speed by 50%.
This guide will show you how to make the best Karlee build in Back 4 Blood, so you can stop staring at cards and start using them. Of course, you’ll need to unlock all the cleaners in Back 4 Blood before you can play as Karlee.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song Of Farca is great if you don't take it personally]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/song-of-farca-is-great-if-you-dont-take-it-personally</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/song-of-farca-is-great-if-you-dont-take-it-personally"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Often a game can feel frustrating because you can't make decisions that you want to. I had this initially with Song Of Farca. It almost kept me from playing it further, until I came back at it with a different attitude instead, thanks to a few conversations I've had lately about player choice versus narrative.
You play as Izy Song, a hacking-based private investigator in a fictional, dystopian island in the near future. And she's kind of a fool.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 11 za 16,66  € nebo Windows 10 za pouhých 12,52  €]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-11-za-16-66-nebo-windows-10-za-pouhych-12-52</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-11-za-16-66-nebo-windows-10-za-pouhych-12-52"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Získejte doživotní licenci Windows 11 za pouhých 16,66  €, Windows 10 za pouhých 12,52  €. Opět jde o finančně velmi výhodnou nabídku prodejního portálu GoodOffer24.com, kde lze najít kromě nástrojů produktivity také hry, ale i další softwarové produkty.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD konečně zapíná ve výchozím stavu Panel Self Refresh pro nové APU v jádře 5.16]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42912</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-konecne-zapina-ve-vychozim-stavu-panel-self-refresh-pro-nove-apu-v-jadre-5-16/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:29:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Panel Self Refresh (PSR) je vlastnost DisplayPortu, která při statickém obrazu umožňuje snížení spotřeby. AMD konečně zapíná ve výchozím stavu PSR pro nové integrované grafické karty DCN v jádře 5.16.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft vydal Sysmon pro Linux]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42911</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/microsoft-vydal-sysmon-pro-linux/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sysmon (system monitor) je nástroj od Sysinternals pro monitorování systémové aktivity a odhalení škodlivých programů. Včera Mark Russinovich z Microsoftu (je spoluzakladatel Sysinternals, který později Microsoft koupil) oznámil Sysmon pro Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extrémní přetaktování Raspberry Pi CM 4 na 3 GHz]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42910</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/extremni-pretaktovani-raspberry-pi-cm-4-na-3-ghz/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T07:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Claude Schwarz ve středu zveřejnil výsledek extrémního přetaktování Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4 až na 3 GHz.  K dosažení takového výsledku bylo potřeba odstranit víčko SoC a nahradit vodivou pastu lepším tekutým kovem Thermal Grizzly Conductonaut (obsahuje galium, cín a indium).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unsolved Math Problems]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2529/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2529/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KEY Trainings: Je OpenShift tou správnou volbou?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/key-trainings-je-openshift-tou-spravnou-volbou</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/key-trainings-je-openshift-tou-spravnou-volbou"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShift je platforma pro provoz kontejnerů ve firemním prostředí. Usnadňuje standardizaci provozu vašich aplikací a současně zjednodušuje provoz a zvyšuje bezpečnost a spolehlivost provozu. Umožňuje vám přidělit vybraná oprávnění např. dodavatelským firmám a mít tak pod kontrolou větší část nebo celý vývojový cyklus aplikací. Současně vám přináší jednotný způsob monitoringu a sběru logů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 38-40/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-38-40-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-38-40-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Babí léto přineslo aktualizace řady více či méně specializovaných distribucí: přechod na Debian 11 v projektech Emmabuntüs DE4 nejen pro vzdělávání, Q4OS také s desktopovým prostředím Trinity, stabilní obrazy PureOS firmy Purism, dále Redo Rescue pro práci s diskovými oddíly, pokračující experimenty v EasyOS a mezi tím vším občerstvení MidnightBSD, UBports, IPFire, Tails, Feren OS či Debianu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Budování kyberneticky odolné společnosti]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-budovani-kyberneticky-odolne-spolecnosti</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-budovani-kyberneticky-odolne-spolecnosti"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problémy s Wi-Fi mohou ohrozit fungování českých firem. Technologické trendy pro finanční ředitele: hyperautomatizace a inteligentní komponovaný byznys. Od pilotního projektu k produkčnímu nasazení umělé inteligence. S evidencí vandalismu pomůže umělá inteligence, řešení bude hledat Atos Hackathon. Budování kyberneticky odolné společnosti. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (1) Dodávky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 40/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-40-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-40-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Supravodivé hydridy ceru]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-supravodive-hydridy-ceru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-supravodive-hydridy-ceru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Světy s oceány a atmosférou z vodíku. Těžba ve vesmíru s pomocí bakterií. Panspermie v měřítku celé galaxie. Umělá inteligence pro předpověď počasí. Vylepšená uhlíková vlákna.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>