<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-11-02T06:18:11.103Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-11-02T06:18:11.103Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlus Broadcasting Shin Megami Tensei V Live Stream Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123061</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/atlus-broadcasting-shin-megami-tensei-v-live-stream-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T05:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Commentary from the dev team, new merch and more.
One of the major Switch exclusives arriving this month is the Atlus RPG Shin Megami Tensei V. It's looking rather promising and ahead of the game's launch next week, there'll be an official live stream taking place. In fact, it'll be airing the night before the game's release, Japan time.
You'll be able to watch it over on YouTube - keep in mind, the stream is in Japanese. According to Atlus (via Gematsu), the broadcast will introduce 100 demons - with commentary from the development team, and will also share details about new merchandise. There'll be a Shin Megami Tensei series medley performed by a string quartet, too.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Has Now Shut Down Its Dr. Mario World Mobile Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123060</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/nintendo-has-now-shut-down-its-dr-mario-world-mobile-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T04:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Thank you for everything!".

Following on from shock announcement back in July, Nintendo has now officially shut down Dr. Mario World for mobile devices.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel AMX Support Lands For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-Lands-In-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-Lands-In-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After going through a number of rounds of patch revisions over the past year, Intel's kernel-side changes for supporting Advanced Matrix Extensions (AMX) with next-gen Xeon Scalable "Sapphire Rapids" processors has landed for Linux 5.16!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: MVG Takes A Closer Look At Nintendo's N64 Emulation And "What Went Wrong" Over The Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123059</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/video-mvg-takes-a-closer-look-at-nintendos-n64-emulation-and-what-went-wrong-over-the-years"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T03:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From GameCube to Switch.
Last week, Nintendo launched the 'Expansion Pack' tier for its Switch Online service. As you may have noticed, it hasn't gone down well with some players. Apart from the trailer becoming the most disliked Nintendo YouTube video ever, the N64 emulation has been criticised for not even matching the standards set by community efforts.
Game developer and YouTuber, Modern Vintage Gamer, has now taken a look at the history of Nintendo's N64 emulation, which technically dates back to the GameCube era - with the release of the Wind Waker pre-order bonus disc.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenWrt 21.02.1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/openwrt-21.02.1</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/openwrt-21.02.1"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T02:46:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 21.02.1 linuxové distribuce primárně určené pro routery a vestavěné systémy OpenWrt (Wikipedie). Jedná se o první opravné vydání OpenWrt 21.02.0 vydaného v září. Přehled změn v Changelogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Chris Pratt Will Also Be The Voice Of Garfield]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123058</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-chris-pratt-will-also-be-the-voice-of-garfield"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T02:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's-a me...Garfield!".

Nintendo and Illumination recently announced Chris Pratt would be taking over vocal duties for Mario in the upcoming animated movie due out in cinemas next year.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: 15 Exciting New Games Coming To Nintendo Switch In November]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123056</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/video-15-exciting-new-games-coming-to-nintendo-switch-in-november"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T00:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon, GTA, Star Wars and more!
November is looking to be a very exciting month in the world of Nintendo. We've got some neat indies like Demon Turf and Death's Door to look forward to, a number of old classics return including KOTOR, GTA and Diamond & Pearl, and to top it off the Switch exclusive Shin Megami Tensei V. There's even some hardware - Nintendo's Zelda Game & Watch. Here's the lineup:
World War Z - November 2nd

Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Disables 'All Forms Of Wealth Transfers' After Gold Exploit Found]]></title>
        <id>1847978883</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-world-disables-all-forms-of-wealth-transfers-after-1847978883"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T00:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After an exploit was found over the weekend that first let players send images in the chat box,  kick other players unknowingly and  duplicate gold, Amazon has stepped in and taken some drastic action.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam On Linux Marketshare Hits New Multi-Year High, AMD Powering ~40% Of Linux Gaming Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Linux-October-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Linux-October-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-11-02T00:17:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in July Steam on Linux re-crossed the 1.0% marketshare threshold following the announcement of the Steam Deck and continued progress around Steam Play / Proton. The Steam on Linux user-base has continued growing month by month and has hit another high with the numbers published today that cover the month of October...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age Of Empires IV's Fancy Cutscenes Are A Wonder]]></title>
        <id>1847978611</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/age-of-empires-ivs-fancy-cutscenes-are-a-wonder-1847978611"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been playing the new Age of Empires IV this week, and for all the good work that has been done in bringing a classic game into a modern era, the best thing about it are the bits that happen while you’re not even playing.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World turns off all "wealth transfers" to stop gold duplication exploit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-turns-off-all-wealth-transfers-to-stop-gold-duplication-exploit</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-turns-off-all-wealth-transfers-to-stop-gold-duplication-exploit"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:29:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World has temporarily disabled "all forms of wealth transfers" due to an exploit that allows players to duplicate gold. In a post on the game's forum, a community manager warned that punishments would be served to players who used the exploit.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon ROCm 4.5 Released With HIP Runtime Compilation, Unified Memory Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-ROCm-4.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-ROCm-4.5"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:15:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD today released Radeon Open eCosystem 4.5 (ROCm 4.5) as the latest version to their open-source GPU compute stack for Linux systems. ROCm 4.5 brings with it a number of new features and improvements but one area on the consumer Radeon side will leave some potential users frustrated...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Bowser Pleads Guilty To Piracy Charges After Nintendo Pursuit]]></title>
        <id>1847978204</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/gary-bowser-pleads-guilty-to-piracy-charges-after-ninte-1847978204"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Team-Xecuter was a hacking group that sold both software and hardware for stuff like Nintendo consoles. While arguing that they were simply advocating for homebrew programs and a consumer’s right to repair their own property, gaming giants like Nintendo thought otherwise.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knot DNS: zónové transfery aneb přenos zón mezi servery]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15739</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/knot-dns-zonove-transfery-aneb-prenos-zon-mezi-servery/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V úvodním dílu jsme si zprovoznili automatickou synchronizaci zóny na sekundárním serveru. Dnes si ukážeme, jaké jsou další možnosti nastavení zónových transferů a co je jejich obsahem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Daniel Salzman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oslava 55 let od vzniku první implementace programovacího jazyka APL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15741</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/oslava-55-let-od-vzniku-prvni-implementace-programovaciho-jazyka-apl/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před 55 lety, tedy v listopadu 1966, byla vydána první verze programovacího jazyka APL. Jednalo se o přelomový jazyk, který byl založen na (tehdy) nové notaci zápisu matematických operací vymyšlenou Kennethem E. Iversonem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPV 0.34 umožňuje přepínání výstupu za běhu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42966</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mpv-0-34-umoznuje-prepinani-vystupu-za-behu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová verze multimediálního přehrávače MPV, jehož původ sahá až k MPlayeru. Přináší některé nové přepínače pro příkazovou řádku a také vylepšené vlastnosti. Například je přehrávač nyní schopen přepínat za běhu back-end výstupu videa a má vylepšenou podporu Waylandu (dotykové ovládání).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5 and Football Manager 2022 head to Xbox Game Pass in November]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-and-football-manager-2022-head-to-xbox-game-pass-in-november</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-and-football-manager-2022-head-to-xbox-game-pass-in-november"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:56:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost all of the games I'm interested in playing this November will launch on Xbox Game Pass. Microsoft's subscription service on PC will see the arrival of Forza Horizon 5, Football Manager 2022 and Unpacking.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory Folios Merged For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Memory-Folios-Lands-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Memory-Folios-Lands-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:47:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The proposed memory "folios" functionality for Linux 5.16 is happening! This low-level change to the Linux memory management code was merged today for this next kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox's three-day outage prompted by "subtle bug"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/robloxs-three-day-outage-prompted-by-subtle-bug</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/robloxs-three-day-outage-prompted-by-subtle-bug"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox is back online after an extended outage which lasted three days. In a post on the Roblox site, Roblox CEO David Baszucki wrote that the outage was caused by "a combination of several factors."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pomoc eRoušky v boji s epidemií je u konce]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/pomoc-erousky-v-boji-s-epidemii-je-u-konce</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/pomoc-erousky-v-boji-s-epidemii-je-u-konce"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:22:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pomoc eRoušky v boji s epidemií je u konce. Ministerstvo zdravotnictví ČR rozhodlo o pozastavení provozu aplikace od konce října 2021. Zdrojové kódy eRoušky (mobilní i serverová část) zůstávají na GitHubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC & LLVM Patches Pending To Fend Off Trojan Source Attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-LLVM-Trojan-Source</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-LLVM-Trojan-Source"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:11:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making rounds today are the "Trojan Source" attacks by which text displayed to the end-user/developer doesn't match what is actually being executed. The problem stems from Unicode standards and could lead to malicious code being inadvertently introduced into upstream code-bases that could be overlooked during code review processes, etc. GCC and LLVM/Clang are among the early compilers preparing defenses against Trojan Source style attacks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Kart NFT Idea Is The Worst Thing I Have Ever Read]]></title>
        <id>1847977673</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-nft-idea-is-the-worst-thing-i-have-ever-read-1847977673"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bloomberg Wealth has a major feature up today called “Into the Metaverse: Where Crypto, Gaming and Capitalism Collide”. It is as critical and as informative as you’d guess something coming from a finance site would be, but there’s one section in particular that will haunt me, and now you, for the rest of the week.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft want to be "key players" in blockchain gaming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-want-to-be-key-players-in-blockchain-gaming</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-want-to-be-key-players-in-blockchain-gaming"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T21:47:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not content with pivoting to free-to-play games that their audience doesn't want, Ubisoft also want to be one of the "key players" in blockchain gaming according to CEO Yves Guillemot. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World's Most Popular Game Is Getting 'Triple-A,' Open-World Spin-Off]]></title>
        <id>1847977539</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/worlds-most-popular-game-is-getting-triple-a-open-worl-1847977539"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T21:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This weekend, Pokémon Unite and Call of Duty: Mobile developer TiMi Studio announced the development of Honor of Kings: World. It’s to be an “AAA” open-world game based on its smash-hit mobile MOBA, Honor of Kings.  

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Home Paradise Will Be Animal Crossing: New Horizons' One And Only Paid DLC]]></title>
        <id>1847977402</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/happy-home-paradise-will-be-animal-crossing-new-horizo-1847977402"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T21:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo has announced that this week’s Happy Home Paradise expansion will be Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ only paid DLC, and that major updates to the game will be coming to an end following both the DLC and the game’s free version 2.0 update. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: The Sakuna: Of Rice And Ruin Nendoroid Can Now Hold A Cat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123044</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-the-sakuna-of-rice-and-ruin-nendoroid-can-now-hold-a-cat"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And so can you!
Sakuna: Of Rice And Ruin was an unexpected success for developer Edelweiss, selling over a million copies, and getting crossovers with Story of Seasons, Super Smash Bros. Ultimate, and her very own Nendoroid figurine.
That Nendoroid figurine just got better, with the addition of "Long Cat" collectibles. You may already know that Sakuna can pick up cats and dogs — in fact, she can pick up two at a time — and sometimes, they do this:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: The Current World Record Speedrun For Metroid Dread Took Under 1.5 Hours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123038</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-the-current-world-record-speedrun-for-metroid-dread-took-under-1-5-hours"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Speedmus Arun.
Metroid Dread came out less than a month ago, but speedrunners are already hard at work trying to grab the world record for fastest time to completion.
Even just a few days after the release, we were marvelling at how good some players were at the game — and the current world record holder, karterfreak, is an excellent example. With a current time of just 1:22:52 on an Any% run, karterfreak's time is just under a minute ahead of the second place runner-up, Bdog.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy Far Cry 6 Exploit Totally Eliminates Weapon Recoil]]></title>
        <id>1847976598</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/easy-far-cry-6-exploit-totally-eliminates-weapon-recoil-1847976598"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new open-world shooter Far Cry 6 quickly lets you become an unstoppable machine. Here’s a trick that’ll make you even less stoppable: By turning off the game’s camera shake, you’ll completely eliminate recoil for all weapons, including shotguns and extremely high fire-rate machine guns.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many Block Improvements Land In Linux 5.16 - Multi-Actuator Hard Drive Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Block-Changes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Block-Changes"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:40:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The big set of block changes for Linux 5.16 were merged today with the opening of the new kernel cycle. While the massive I/O optimizations tackled recently has been a main focus, there is also much more to the block subsystem coming with Linux 5.16...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From The Makers Of 'Piano', 'Drums', And 'Guitar' Comes... 'Handpan']]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123052</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/from-the-makers-of-piano-drums-and-guitar-comes-handpan"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soon we'll have a full orchestra.
You have to hand it to developer Sabec: their catalogue of games sure does cover all the hits. You'll probably know them best as the people who brought "Calculator" into our lives, but they've got quite the portfolio on Switch, from the newly-announced Popeye game to a game that's literally called "Robox", perhaps in an attempt to cash in on people who are hoping to find Roblox on the eShop.
Sometimes Sabec makes licensed games, like Scalextric, and something called Rainbocorns, but the developer has a side hustle: Switch versions of popular instruments, the latest of which is Handpan.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aplikace eRouška končí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42965</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/aplikace-erouska-konci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:27:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aplikace ministerstva zdravotnictví pro mobilní zařízení s Androidem a iOS eRouška, která rok pomáhala pomocí Exposure Notification API trasovat kontakty s COVID-19 pozitivními lidmi, ode dneška končí. A to i přes to, že v současnosti počet COVID-19 pozitivních případů opět roste.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What a fool! I've only just realised glowing PC parts are secretly meant to be Christmas lights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-a-fool-ive-only-just-realised-glowing-pc-parts-are-secretly-meant-to-be-christmas-lights</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-a-fool-ive-only-just-realised-glowing-pc-parts-are-secretly-meant-to-be-christmas-lights"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:21:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Halloween behind us, it's time to ask: is the 1st of November too early to put up Christmas lights? Is it a grim sign of ravenous consumerism, or a welcome respite from the watching the year die slowly and painfully in its final months? As I untangled my strings of LED lights this morning, I realised that PC gaming is the most Christmassy of gamings. The colourful LEDs people cram into their PC's every orifice and pore aren't just any decoration, they're Christmas lights. That's their purpose. It always has been. Christmas is year-round for PC gamers. So here it is: merry Christmas.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: Are You Preparing Your Island For The Animal Crossing: New Horizons Update?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122835</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-are-you-preparing-your-island-for-the-animal-crossing-new-horizons-update"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time to get back to work?
It's been about a year since I last visited egg, my Animal Crossing: New Horizons island. I played a lot of Animal Crossing: New Leaf, so I knew what to expect when I booted it up again, following the jam-packed Animal Crossing Direct recently: weeds everywhere, cockroaches in my house, and villagers being more disappointed in me than my dad when he found out I wanted to be a games journalist.
"Well, well, well," they would say. "Look who's come CRAWLING back after months. We thought you were dead!" I don't blame them for being annoyed at me, because after all, I'm the only one who can decorate the island and make decisions.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The End Of Dyeus is built on the joy of discovery]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-end-of-dyeus-is-built-on-the-joy-of-discovery</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-end-of-dyeus-is-built-on-the-joy-of-discovery"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I almost don't want to tell you what The End Of Dyeus is. Surprise and discovery are among the things I enjoy most in games, and they're too often undermined in the modern age. Damned kids, with your wikis and your hashed tags. It's a first person fighting and exploration game that drops you in a pastoral fantasy world with no instruction beyond "find Dyeus" and some straightforward control explainers. The only thing I dislike is that I have no idea how to pronounce it, dramatically limiting my pun options.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[True horror is the fridge being left open in Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/true-horror-is-the-fridge-being-left-open-in-marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/true-horror-is-the-fridge-being-left-open-in-marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:49:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spooky season might be behind us now, but man, it’s still pretty scary out there. My inbox sits at 576 unread emails, and in another tab I’m browsing heated clothes airers; things that I now realise are frighteningly expensive. But it’s not just mundane things in real life that give me goosebumps, it now extends to virtual white goods as well.
Right, so, there’s this fridge in Marvel’s Guardians Of The Galaxy and no matter how many times I close it, it won’t stay shut. At first it was funny, but it’s since morphed from a sly chuckle to a howl of agony. My relationship with the game is like that thing Yoda from Star Wars says, “Fear leads to the Dark Side”. Well, I’m almost there, let me tell you.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More People Are Playing Left 4 Dead 2 Than Back 4 Blood]]></title>
        <id>1847975649</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/more-people-are-playing-left-4-dead-2-than-back-4-blood-1847975649"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quick perusal of Steam-tracking sites indicates that players returned to Left 4 Dead 2 in droves following the October 12 launch of spiritual successor Back 4 Blood, so much so that the older game is now more popular than the newer one.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPV 0.34 Released For Popular Linux Media Player]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MPV-0.34-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MPV-0.34-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:33:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPV 0.34 is now available as the newest version of this popular Linux video player that is powered by FFmpeg and forked originally from MPlayer/mplayer2 code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[U.S. Senator Heartbroken Men Watch Porn And Play Video Games]]></title>
        <id>1847975813</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/u-s-senator-heartbroken-men-watch-porn-and-play-video-1847975813"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senator Josh Hawley, Republican of Missouri, took the stage at the National Conservatism Conference yesterday to decry the war on men. In a long and meandering speech, he sounded the alarm about falling marriage rates and college attendance, and argued that more and more men are dropping out of the workforce and…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sega And Microsoft Are Teaming Up To Make "Super Games"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123043</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/sega-and-microsoft-are-teaming-up-to-make-super-games"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic the Cloudhog.
Metaverses are so hot right now, and it looks like Sega is making the moves to create their own. You might know the concept of 'metaverse' from Fortnite, Space Jam, or Ready Player One — it's basically a hub where you can find all of your favourite brands and fictional characters, all in the same place.
Unsurprisingly, with Sega's stable of characters, they're looking to do the same, combining recognisable names like Sonic the Hedgehog, Super Monkey Ball, and Persona into what they're calling a "super game".
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Developers Of Hit Switch Game 'Calculator' Are Making A Popeye Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123048</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/the-developers-of-hit-switch-game-calculator-are-making-a-popeye-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Spinach Oyled.
Don't get us wrong: we love a bit of Popeye the sailor man. What's not to like about a barely-comprehensible spinach-guzzling maniac who spends most of his time upper-cutting his girlfriend's bit on the side? But we have to say — we weren't expecting a Popeye video game any time soon.
The last bit of Popeye news we remember is the announcement of a Genndy Tartakovsky animated movie, which may or may not still be in the works... so perhaps we're due a Popeye revival? And who else to handle it, but the makers of the highly-rated Calculator: the calculator app for Nintendo Switch?
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Loosens The Spectre Defaults Around SSBD / STIBP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Spectre-SECCOMP-To-P</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Spectre-SECCOMP-To-P"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 is adjusting its default Spectre mitigation behavior around Spectre V2 for user-space tasks as well as Speculative Store Bypass Disable (SSBD) for Spectre V4 mitigation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stardew Valley Dev's Next Game Has 'Greater Focus' On Combat]]></title>
        <id>1847975418</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/stardew-valley-devs-next-game-has-greater-focus-on-comb-1847975418"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed just last week, Stardew Valley developer Eric Barone has already provided a nice little update about his next game, Haunted Chocolatier. According to a new blog post, the upcoming action-RPG has a “greater focus on combat” in comparison to his previous hit.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Nintendo Keeps (Jokingly) Tricking Fans Into Watching WarioWare Adverts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123017</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-nintendo-keeps-jokingly-tricking-fans-into-watching-warioware-adverts"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The old bait-and-switch.
WarioWare: Get It Together! has already been out for almost two months now (seriously, where does the time go?) but Nintendo's still busy plugging the game with the occasional social media post. And for good reason – it's excellent and deserves your time.
We can't help but notice that there's a bit of a dastardly theme going on with the title's current marketing, though. You see, fitting in perfectly with Wario's mischievous persona, Nintendo's been using the old bait-and-switch to trick fans into thinking they're watching content based on other Nintendo games. Then BAM, Wario swoops in and it's all been a big lie. Naughty.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Luigi's Afraid Of Mo' Ghosts In New Lego Sets]]></title>
        <id>1847974989</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/luigis-afraid-of-mo-ghosts-in-new-lego-sets-1847974989"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Finally, after first appearing in August, the Lego version of Luigi is getting his own sets. But poor blocky Luigi, it seems Nintendo and Lego want to torture him, because the new sets are all based on Luigi’s Mansion. Don’t they know Luigi (and his Lego variant) is afraid of ghosts! Luckily Professor E. Gadd is here…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Returnal Players Found A Way To Save Scum In Latest Patch]]></title>
        <id>1847974853</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/returnal-players-found-a-way-to-save-scum-in-latest-pat-1847974853"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Housemarque finally took some pity on players of its difficult sci-fi shooter Returnal last week, and added a suspend feature in update 2.0. Now players have found a way to turn it into a full-on save scumming exploit.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Wholesome, Zen Pixel Art Game Is All About Unpacking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123026</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/this-wholesome-zen-pixel-art-game-is-all-about-unpacking"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Little boxes, all the same.
Moving houses sucks. That sounds like the start of a thoughtful haiku that's all about change, but it's not, it's just a fact of life: having to pack up your belongings, your clothes, and your plants, and fit them all into a series of cardboard boxes — which you never seem to have enough of — and then truck everything over to a new place where you can never quite remember where the teaspoons are kept, is a nightmare.

Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Will Now Pay $31,337 To $50,337 For New Linux Kernel Vulnerabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=More-Money-For-Linux-Flaws</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=More-Money-For-Linux-Flaws"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:21:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google announced today that now through at least the end of January they will be providing higher payment amounts for security researchers disclosing new vulnerabilities affecting the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trojan Source Attacks]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/trojan-source-attacks</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/trojan-source-attacks"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byly zveřejněny informace o Trojan Source Attacks (pdf) aneb možných "neviditelných" zranitelnostech ve zdrojových kódech. Pokud vývojové prostředí podporuje Unicode, stačí v názvu funkce použít homoglyf a máme zcela "jinou funkci" (CVE-2021-42694). Pokud vývojové prostředí podporuje řídící znaky Unicode, překládat se může kód s "jinou logikou" (CVE-2021-42574), například z důležité podmínky se udělá poznámka.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact's Cooking Minigame Offers A Cozy Break From Its Roguelike Event]]></title>
        <id>1847974611</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/genshin-impacts-cooking-minigame-offers-a-cozy-break-fr-1847974611"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of Genshin Impact’s ongoing Labyrinth Warriors event, developer miHoYo has launched a limited-time web game called “Yummy! Barbeque Under the Stars.” In this cooking minigame which can be played via your internet browser, players earn in-game items and primogems (premium currency) for their culinary skills.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dialga And Palkia Emojis Hit Twitter Ahead Of This Month's Diamond And Pearl Remakes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123024</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/dialga-and-palkia-emojis-hit-twitter-ahead-of-this-months-diamond-and-pearl-remakes"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only 18 days to go!
Pokémon Brilliant Diamond and Shining Pearl are now right around the corner, with just 18 days to go until the big release. Ahead of that 19th November launch date, it seems The Pokémon Company is celebrating with a series of special hashtags over on Twitter.
As we've seen with other games in the past, the new remakes have been treated to custom emojis on the social media platform. Technically called hashflags (eww), these custom emojis will appear for a limited time when you use select hashtags in your posts.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mandalorian Spin-Off The Book Of Boba Fett Gets First Trailer]]></title>
        <id>1847974639</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/mandalorian-spin-off-the-book-of-boba-fett-gets-first-t-1847974639"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A long time ago (last year) in a galaxy far, far away (Hollywood), Disney execs confirmed a never-ending slew of Star Wars shows, including multiple spin-offs of The Mandalorian (stop reading now if you’re averse to spoilers for season two of that show). Today, Disney released the trailer for the first of those, The…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi a Arduino kontroluje používání blinkrů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42964</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-a-arduino-kontroluje-pouzivani-blinkru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:44:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marc Radinovic vytvořil zařízení, které kontroluje řidiče, jestli při zatáčení používá blinkry. Senzorem jsou dva Arduino Nano 33 BLE moduly. Používá se jejich vestavěný akcelerometr ke zjištění polohy volantu a páčky blinkrů. Senzory pomocí BLE komunikují s Arduino UNO WiFi deskou. Ta je sériově pomocí USB propojena s Raspberry Pi 4.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pocket Camp Reveals The Personalities of Animal Crossing’s Newest Villagers]]></title>
        <id>1847974457</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pocket-camp-reveals-the-personalities-of-animal-crossin-1847974457"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, the personalities of Animal Crossing: New Horizon’s (seemingly) final eight villagers were revealed via Pocket Camp. Their Pocket Camp iterations also include their favorite sayings, catchphrases, and broad descriptions of the characters—which has given me enough information to perform a vibe check.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lots Of Resident Evil And Devil May Cry Games Are Discounted On Switch Right Now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123032</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/lots-of-resident-evil-and-devil-may-cry-games-are-discounted-on-switch-right-now"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deals live for a limited time.
As part of a special Halloween sale (that's still running for a good while yet, don't worry), Capcom has slashed the prices of lots of Resident Evil and Devil May Cry games on Switch.
The full sale, which also includes Onimusha: Warlords as an added bonus, can be seen below. The deals listed will be available on the Switch eShop up until 10th November at 11:59pm PT, and similar offers can also be found on the European store.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Go Adds The Cutest New Monster During Festival Of Lights]]></title>
        <id>1847974384</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-go-adds-the-cutest-new-monster-during-festival-1847974384"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier today, the official Pokémon Go website announced that Dedenne, the adorable electric and fairy-type Pokémon, will be the next monster in the mobile game. Dedenne will be available during the Festival of Lights, the Diwali-inspired event, on November 5 at 10 a.m. through November 14 at 8 p.m. local time.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Blazing Rangers - A New NES Game In 2021? Youbetcha, And It's A Good 'Un]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122520</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nes/blazing-rangers"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Toasty!
Gaming is not short of NES-like experiences these days; titles filled with 8-bit-style blocky pixels, beepy music, and some controllable character for you to take from the left side of the screen to the right. These games tend to chase the past from a comfortable distance, the harsh technical restrictions of almost 40 years ago something to keep in mind for stylistic reasons rather than be tied down to. Blazing Rangers is different.
Blazing Rangers by Karu_gamo, perhaps best known for their work on the Protect Me Knight series, isn’t merely NES-like, it’s a brand new NES game made for use with either original Nintendo hardware or your compatible cartridge-taking equivalent of choice.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 je jádrem s prodlouženou upstream podporou (LTS)]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-5.15-je-jadrem-s-prodlouzenou-upstream-podporou-lts</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-5.15-je-jadrem-s-prodlouzenou-upstream-podporou-lts"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T15:33:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bylo rozhodnuto, že nejnovější Linux 5.15 je jádrem s prodlouženou upstream podporou (LTS). Ta je plánována do října 2023. LTS jader je aktuálně sedm: 4.4, 4.9, 4.14, 4.19, 5.4, 5.10 a 5.15.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Takes Two, The Best Co-Op Game Of The Year, Is Coming To Game Pass]]></title>
        <id>1847973764</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/it-takes-two-the-best-co-op-game-of-the-year-is-comin-1847973764"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xbox Game Pass is starting November off strong. After half a year, It Takes Two, the acclaimed cooperative game from the makers of 2018’s A Way Out, is finally coming to the service, albeit only for those who pay for the premium tier. That’s alongside some other offerings (available to all subscribers). Here’s …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Someone Carved 107 Pokémon Pumpkins To Celebrate The Diamond & Pearl Remakes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123023</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-someone-carved-107-pokemon-pumpkins-to-celebrate-the-diamond-and-pearl-remakes"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gotta carve 'em all.
Carving pumpkins is messy, time-consuming, and leaves you with far more gourdmeat than you're prepared to eat. In fact, if you manage to carve more than one pumpkin in preparation for Halloween, then you're an accomplished and impressive human that's going to have to eat pumpkin-related foods for the next two weeks.
But why stop at one or two? Why not carve yourself ONE HUNDRED AND SEVEN pumpkins? That's what Adrian and friends did, at least — because there are 107 Gen IV Pokémon that were introduced in Diamond and Pearl, and you can't just do some of them.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird West is a smooth, smooth ride through a rough, rough place]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weird-west-is-a-smooth-smooth-ride-through-a-rough-rough-place</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/weird-west-is-a-smooth-smooth-ride-through-a-rough-rough-place"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even though I’ve been dead excited about Weird West since its announcement last summer, when the time finally came for me to play a preview build last week, I found myself unusually hesitant. Primarily, this was because I loved the game’s concept so much (“What if Dishonored and Desperadoes III had a rooting tooting baby, then let it watch way too many horror movies?”), that I didn’t really want to face the possibility that developers WolfEye Studios might have fallen short on it. But more than that, I was worried I’d have to… well, make an effort.


For whatever reason, my enthusiasm to start new games has been taking one of its periodic dips over the last month or so, leaving me in the comforting arms of old favourites I can play on autopilot. Time and time again, I’ll get right to the point of hitting play on something, before convincing myself - completely unreasonably - that it’ll probably be a load of hassle for moderate reward. And however promising a sprawling, top-down immersive sim set in a world of haunted stetsons sounded, I was certain it would involve a lot of fiddling about with inventories, reading long screeds of text, and going on sidequests.


I’m delighted to say, however, that I was completely wrong. Because while Weird West does involve all those things (and features even more emergent complexity than the hefty dose I’d anticipated, to boot) I have not had a smoother time getting into a game in a long while. The build I played only featured one of the game’s five character campaigns, admittedly. But unless the other four are all set in a Tesco car park or something, I can heartily recommend it to you.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nate Crowley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anniversary: Alex Kidd, Mario's First Real Rival, Is 35 Years Old Today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123022</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/anniversary-alex-kidd-marios-first-real-rival-is-35-years-old-today"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He still looks so young!
Before Sonic came along and really gave Super Mario a run for his money, Sega relied on the talents of Alex Kidd, the company mascot during the Master System era.
Alex starred in a series of titles during the late '80s, including Alex Kidd in Miracle World, Alex Kidd: The Lost Stars and Alex Kidd in Shinobi World. While none of these could really hold a candle to the likes of Super Mario Bros. 3 on the NES, Alex nonetheless carved out a receptive fanbase – so much so that he was even afforded a 16-bit outing, Alex Kidd in the Enchanted Castle.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 PC trailer shows off DLSS and ray tracing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-pc-trailer-shows-off-dlss-and-ray-tracing</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-pc-trailer-shows-off-dlss-and-ray-tracing"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T14:24:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 has a new trailer ahead of its November 19th release, and this one is aimed directly at us PC folk. While the action itself is more of the near-future mega-bangs you’ve probably seen in previous teasers (or, indeed, the open beta), it’s all in service of demonstrating the PC-exclusive features: chiefly ray tracing, Nvidia DLSS and Nvidia Reflex support.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Upcoming Nintendo Switch Games And Accessories For November And December 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122704</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/upcoming-nintendo-switch-games-and-accessories-for-november-and-december-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shin Megami Tensei V! Pokémon! Danganronpa!
You hear that? That is the sound of inevitability 2022 racing up on you while you're busy getting over October. Yes, we're into the 11th hour month of the year and we've taken to amusing ourselves with the little-used but thoroughly entertaining strikeout tool in our article intros. It's been a long year, okay!
A long game-filled year, to be precise, and it's not over yet. Nintendo still has a heavy-hitter or two coming in Switch's 2021 line-up that should help make the holidays very happy this year for Switch-owning gamers. Yep, Tiny Tim's getting half a pea and eShop credit under the tree this year, the lucky little fella.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PlatinumGames To Host 'Hideki Kamiya's Very Sorry' Livestream For Sol Cresta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123019</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/platinumgames-to-host-hideki-kamiyas-very-sorry-livestream-for-sol-cresta"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Umm, what?
Nintendo Directs are one thing, but can we tempt you with a Hideki Kamiya's Very Sorry Stream instead?
Yes, PlatinumGames has announced that it'll be hosting a live stream for its upcoming shooter Sol Cresta tomorrow. The stream will be approximately an hour long, although no further details about the show's content have been provided.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FWUPD 1.7.1 Adds Support For Firmware Updates On More Devices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=fwupd-1.7.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=fwupd-1.7.1"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FWUPD 1.7.1 is out today as the newest release of this leading open-source solution for allowing firmware updates from UEFI motherboards to various peripherals under Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dark Pictures Anthology will end first season in a Murder Castle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-will-end-first-season-in-a-murder-castle</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-will-end-first-season-in-a-murder-castle"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:19:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've already finished House Of Ashes, you'll have seen a wee trailer revealing that the next part of The Dark Pictures Anthology will be the "season one finale", named The Devil In Me. Bandai Namco have since publicly announced the next game in Supermassive's interactive horror story series, explaining a bit more of what's going on with the animatronic corpse. Bad news for would-be survivors: it's set in a replica of the infamous 'Murder Castle', a hotel built with traps and torture chambers by American serial killer H. H. Holmes.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Právě vydané jádro 5.15 bude LTS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42963</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/prave-vydane-jadro-5-15-bude-lts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:16:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera vydané jádro 5.15 bude LTS, tedy bude mít dlouhou podporu, jak dnes rozhodl Greg Kroah-Hartman. Podpora je zatím plánována na dva roky, ale podpora může být prodloužena, pokud dostatek uživatelů a společností projeví zájem a budou ochotni testovat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ekstase Is A Techno-Infused Tetris-Like That's Out On Switch Today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123011</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/ekstase-is-a-techno-infused-tetris-like-thats-out-on-switch-today"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who doesn't love a falling block puzzler?
Launching today on Nintendo Switch is Ekstase, a Tetris-like puzzler that'll have you making shapes in more ways than one.
Described as "a love letter to Berlin and its techno scene," Ekstase is a falling block puzzler that features bright, flashy visuals and a soundtrack full of techno beats. While it looks almost identical to Tetris on the surface, the gameplay isn't quite the same; instead of clearing lines, a scan line wipes out a particular colour of block each time it passes. Here's an official description:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Tetris: The Grand Master Home Port Announcement Revealed By Announcement Delay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123013</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/random-tetris-the-grand-master-home-port-announcement-revealed-by-announcement-delay"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, that's one way of doing it.
Tetris: The Grand Master is a series of really hard Tetris games developed for arcades by Japanese company Arika – and it looks like they're finally coming to home consoles.
The news broke following a tweet from Arika vice-president Ichiro Mihara, who stated that the official announcement of the ports was supposed to be today, but it "had to be withheld for reasons beyond our control". So basically, the delay of the announcement is the announcement.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Is This Year's LTS Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-LTS-Kernel</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-LTS-Kernel"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:40:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As we approach the end of the calendar year there was some uncertainty whether Linux 5.15 would be this year's Long-Term Support (LTS) kernel or if it would be Linux 5.16 albeit not likely releasing until the start of 2022.....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valorant's new agent Chamber spawns snazzy guns for himself]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-new-agent-chamber-spawns-snazzy-guns-for-himself</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-new-agent-chamber-spawns-snazzy-guns-for-himself"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:38:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The reason I enjoy Riot's FPS Valorant so much is because it has an excellent mixture of fun abilities and tactical gunplay, which is why I'm not sure what to make of its new character. Chamber is a French weapons designer who's set to arrive in the game's next Act on November 16th, and his abilities mostly involve spawning weapons. Not weapons you can buy normally in-game, but special weapons that he's made himself. Somehow, this feels like cheating.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ace Attorney Fans Voted On Their Favourite Characters And Cases - Do You Agree?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123009</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/ace-attorney-fans-voted-on-their-favourite-characters-and-cases-do-you-agree"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are the final votes.
Just like all the best franchises gaming has to offer, Ace Attorney boasts a memorable cast of characters and plenty of plot points that are sure to tickle that nostalgia bone when looking back. It's fitting, then, that fans of the series have been asked to cast their minds over all of the games released so far to vote for their favourites.
The voting was hosted by Japanese mag, Famitsu, with 1,394 responses being recorded in total. Topics covered favourite characters, lawyers, prosecutors, cases, and even favourite mascots, and Nintendo Everything has shared the full list of votes. Do you agree with these rankings?
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStan 1.0 Released As Leading PHP Static Analyzer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PHPStan-1.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PHPStan-1.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStan 1.0 was released today as the first stable release for this leading open-source PHP static analysis tool...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo's Lawyers Strike Again, This Time Against A Mario NFT Gambling Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123004</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/nintendos-lawyers-strike-again-this-time-against-a-mario-nft-gambling-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project rep fights back against "Nintendo simps".
Here we see a visual representation of Nintendo fighting off copyright infringement cases on a daily basis.
An unofficial game project which used Super Mario assets to promote an NFT-based gambling platform has attracted the attention of Nintendo, so we all know what happens next.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 early access review: a bumpy start]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-early-access-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-early-access-review"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope you like animosity. Darkest Dungeon 2 will eat your eyes and call you selfish for wanting them back. The ferocity with which it treats its players shouldn’t be a surprise to anyone who clawed their way through the crypts of the first Darkest Dungeon, a turn-based homage to Lovecraft and slow-acting poison. It especially won’t surprise anyone who bled their way through the early access version of that game, either. A lot of the difficulty and madness in the sequel comes not from the dangerous creatures along its roguelike turnpike, but from the roughly shorn design of a road trip yet to be completed. This is a faithfully despondent, sometimes frustrating journey of attrition, decay and distrust. A journey you should maybe put off until the wobblesome wagon has all its wheels tightened.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open-World RPG 'Honor Of Kings: World' Looks To Fuse 'Monster Hunter' With 'Zelda: Breath Of The Wild']]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-123005</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/11/open-world-rpg-honor-of-kings-world-looks-to-fuse-monster-hunter-with-zelda-breath-of-the-wild"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announced for 'multiple platforms'.
Tencent Games has announced that TiMi Studio Group is working on an open-world RPG based on the popular Honor of Kings smartphone game (known as Arena of Valor in the west).
Honor of Kings: World is being created in collaboration with acclaimed Chinese science-fiction writer Liu Cixin, who is most famous for penning the 'Remembrance of Earth's Past' trilogy, which is often referred to as The Three-Body Problem. It's one of the most popular Chinese science fiction series of all time, and the opening book was the first Asian novel to win a Hugo Award for Best Novel.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AGDQ 2022 lineup includes blindfolded Sekiro speedrun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/agdq-2022-lineup-includes-blindfolded-sekiro-speedrun</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/agdq-2022-lineup-includes-blindfolded-sekiro-speedrun"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:27:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The clocks have gone back and the cold is creeping in, so now it's time for me to get too excited too early for the winter speedrunning event Awesome Games Done Quick. While it's too early for the full schedule right now, organisers have revealed the current list of accepted games, and there are already some absolute belters. A race to beat every Dark Souls boss and Deathloop's first GDQ outing are amongst the highlights. But the one I'm most looking forward to is a blindfolded Sekiro run. I couldn't finish that game even using my eyes.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStan 1.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/phpstan-1.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/phpstan-1.0"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:05:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PHPStan (PHP Static Analysis Tool), nástroj pro statickou analýzu a hledání chyb v PHP kódu, po šesti letech vývoje dospěl do verze 1.0. Podrobný přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání na GitHubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man Dressed As The Joker From Batman Arrested After Knife Attack]]></title>
        <id>1847972882</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/man-dressed-as-the-joker-from-batman-arrested-after-kni-1847972882"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seventeen people were injured on October 31 in Tokyo during an attack on a subway train. The attack has left one victim, a man in his 70s, in critical condition. A 24-year-old man, dressed as the Joker from Batman, was arrested at the scene for attempted murder.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Nemáte Windows 11? Vezměte si svůj licenční kód za 12 eur]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-nemate-windows-11-vezmete-si-svuj-licencni-kod-za-12-eur</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-nemate-windows-11-vezmete-si-svuj-licencni-kod-za-12-eur"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kupte doživotní licenci Windows 11 nebo Windows 10 a další software na GoodOffer24.com. Můžete si vybrat z nabízených bundlů, nebo projet celý tento prodejní web. Hlavně nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód AX30, na který získáte další slevu 30 %.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncharted director's new studio are making a Marvel game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-directors-new-studio-are-making-a-marvel-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-directors-new-studio-are-making-a-marvel-game"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T10:58:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skydance New Media, the studio led by former Uncharted director Amy Hennig, have announced they're making a game set in the wizarding world of Marvel. They describe the yet-unnamed game as "a narrative-driven, blockbuster action-adventure game, featuring a completely original story and take on the Marvel Universe". Mysteries!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fortnite Is Shutting Down Its Service In China]]></title>
        <id>1847972821</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-is-shutting-down-its-service-in-china-1847972821"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The official site for Fortnite China has announced that on November 15 of this year, the game’s service will end for the country. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FUTEX2's sys_futex_waitv() Sent In For Linux 5.16 To Help Linux Gaming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-sys_futex_waitv</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-sys_futex_waitv"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As expected after first reporting on it a month ago when the FUTEX2 patches were queued up in locking/core, this work with the new sys_futex_waitv() system call for helping the Windows on Linux gaming experience will indeed land for Linux 5.16...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Edge pro Linux v ostré verzi]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42962</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/microsoft-edge-pro-linux-v-ostre-verzi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prohlížeč Microsoft Edge je od minulého čtvrtka pro Linux v ostré verzi označené jako stable microsoft-edge-stable-95.0.1020.38–1 a není tak již označován jako beta. V pátek se objevila verze končící 40–1. Microsoft zatím nic neoznámil, na oficiálních stránkách Edge je stále napsáno „Není podporován pro Linux“. Změny si všimli pracovníci bezpečností firmy Sophos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se Kubernetes na našem dvoudenním školení]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41195</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-kubernetes-na-nasem-dvoudennim-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:41:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kubernetes je dnes nejrozšířenější platformou na hostovaní Docker kontejneru a je podporován velkými hráči na trhu (Google, Amazon, Microsoft) skrz Cloud Native Computing Foundation. Kuberneres pro provoz používají všechny velikosti firem, od startupu po korporace. Pojďme se naučit jej používat na dvoudenním kurzu Úvod do Kubernetes, který proběhne v naší pražské školicí místnosti ve dnech 25. a 26. listopadu. Školení proběhne kombinovaně: tedy prezenčně a zároveň je možné se účastnit online.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux I/O Optimizations, AMD Improvements, NVIDIA GBM Excited Linux Users Last Month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=October-2021-Highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=October-2021-Highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:30:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was an exciting October even amid the ongoing pandemic as at least Linux/open-source enthusiasts were able to enjoy the Ubuntu 21.10 debut, ongoing Linux I/O optimizations many of which are now coming to mainline in 5.16, numerous AMD driver enhancements, NVIDIA's proprietary driver stack finally introducing GBM support, X.Org Server 21.1 released, and much more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft And Sega Are Teaming Up For Next-Gen Cloud Gaming]]></title>
        <id>1847972816</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-and-sega-are-teaming-up-for-next-gen-cloud-ga-1847972816"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With an eye towards the future, Sega is entering into a strategic alliance with Microsoft, in a move that will enable the Tokyo-based game maker to take advantage of the tech giant’s cloud technology.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Linux-libre 5.15 Released - More Deblobbing, Fixing "-Werror" Breakage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Linux-Libre-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Linux-Libre-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T09:06:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right after last night's Linux 5.15 kernel release, the Free Software Foundation folks issued GNU Linux-libre 5.15-gnu as the newest version of their downstream that removes functionality dependent upon binary-only/non-free-software firmware/microcode as well as the ability to load closed kernel modules and other determined non-free-software restrictions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšlo jádro 5.15 s NTFS3 a KSMBD]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42961</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyslo-jadro-5-15-s-ntfs3-a-ksmbd/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T06:48:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds včera vydal jádro 5.15. Mezi novinky patří ovladač NTFS3 od Paragon Software, který má potenciál nahradit FUSE ovladač ntfs-3g. Dále je v jádře implementace Samba serveru KSMBD od Samsungu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtuální Bastlírna a Den Otevřených Spínačů (Dveří)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42960</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/virtualni-bastlirna-a-den-otevrenych-spinacu-dveri/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T06:28:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protože zima se blíží a pravděpodobnost znovuzavedení protiepidemických opatření každý den vzrůstá, rozhodli jsme se příští týden zorganizovat rovnou dvě pravidelné akce z repertoáru projektu MacGyver studentského klubu SiliconHill.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: bkralik)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wirecutter]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2536/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2536/"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trinity Desktop Environment (TDE) R14.0.11]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/trinity-desktop-environment-tde-r14.0.11</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/trinity-desktop-environment-tde-r14.0.11"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T03:35:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze R14.0.11 desktopového prostředí Trinity Desktop Environment (TDE, fork KDE 3.5, Wikipedie). Přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání. Podrobný přehled v Changelogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aspyr 25th Anniversary Bundle]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/aspyr-25th-anniversary-bundle</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/aspyr-25th-anniversary-bundle"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T03:13:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na Humble Bundle běží akce Aspyr 25th Anniversary Bundle. Za 1 € a více lze koupit počítačovou hru Fahrenheit: Indigo Prophecy Remastered. Za přibližně 9 € a více lze koupit navíc hry Layers of Fear: Masterpiece Edition, Morkredd a Lightmatter. Za přibližně 10 € a více ještě navíc BioShock Infinite - Season Pass, BioShock Infinite, Borderlands: The Handsome Collection a Sid Meier’s Civilization: Beyond Earth - The Collection.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T02:43:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds vydal Linux 5.15. Podrobný výčet změn je ke zhlédnutí na stránce Kernel Newbies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relics From A Future Past]]></title>
        <id>1847972315</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/relics-from-a-future-past-1847972315"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T01:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Of the thousands of Fine Art posts we’ve run over the last decade, nearly every single one of them has focused on the digital world, whether they be lavish environmental sketches or 3D models made for a video game. Tonight, I figured we could do with a break, and look at something a little more real.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cosplayer Simply Becomes Angelina Jolie]]></title>
        <id>1847972273</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/cosplayer-simply-becomes-angelina-jolie-1847972273"/>
        <updated>2021-11-01T01:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve featured the work of Alyson Tabbitha a bunch of times here on Kotaku, because she’s just the best. Her make-up work is transformative, and in the past she has shape-shifted into everyone from Wonder Woman to Jack Sparrow to Leeloo Dallas.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Bug Let You Kick Other Players Just By Chatting With Them]]></title>
        <id>1847972062</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-world-bug-let-you-kick-other-players-just-by-chatti-1847972062"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T23:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World’s launch has been plagued by a bunch of weird, sometimes catastrophic bugs, but this latest  is one of the strangest I’ve ever seen: it let you kick other players out of the game just by sending them certain  messages.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: jak si neobjednat drahé předplatné]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15736</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-jak-si-neobjednat-drahe-predplatne/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T23:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes se v týdenním souhrnu bezpečnostních novinek podíváme na podvodnou kampaň UltimateSMS, na platební terminály PAX, na krádež reklamy, na mobilní síť nové generace a na dvě nakažené knihovny na oficiálním úložišti.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CSIRT.CZ)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Začal vývoj Ubuntu 22.04 LTS, Project Trident končí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15737</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/zacal-vyvoj-ubuntu-22-04-lts-project-trident-konci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T23:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Začal vývoj Ubuntu 22.04 s dlouhodobou podporou. Distribuce vycházející z Void Linuxu s grafickým prostředím Lumina ukončuje svůj vývoj. AlmaLinux má nový nástroj pro aktualizaci Enterprise Linux systémů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Week In Games: Dance Like Nobody's Watching]]></title>
        <id>1847971914</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-week-in-games-dance-like-nobodys-watching-1847971914"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T22:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Lady Gaga once said, it’s time to just dance. It’s going to be okay. Da da doo-doo-mmm or something like that. Anyway, Just Dance 2022 is out this week on all major platforms. (Sadly, not the Wii.)

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Released With Initial Intel DG2/Alchemist + Xe HPG Code, New NTFS Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T22:05:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds went ahead and released Linux 5.15 today on Halloween rather than delaying the kernel for another week...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stargate DAW]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/stargate-daw</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/stargate-daw"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T20:34:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stargate DAW je nová multiplatformní digitální pracovní stanice pro práci s audiem (DAW). Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitHubu pod licencí GPLv3. Videoukázky na YouTube.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fantastic Looking Bloodborne PS1 Demake Is Out January 31]]></title>
        <id>1847971763</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/fantastic-looking-bloodborne-ps1-demake-is-out-january-1847971763"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sure, we still don’t have a PC port of Bloodborne, but next year folks will finally be able to play Bloodborne PSX, a fan-made demake of the first section of Bloodborne, complete with boss fights and more. A new trailer released today revealed it’s out for free on January 31, 2022. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 15 Most Interesting Linux 5.15 Kernel Features From NTFS3 To KSMBD & DAMON]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Feature-Look</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Feature-Look"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T17:55:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in September at the end of the Linux 5.15 merge window was our Linux 5.15 feature overview but given the time since then and that the Linux 5.15 stable kernel will likely be released this evening, here is a recap of the most interesting changes in this new kernel version...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94 začne na Linuxu ve výchozím stavu používat EGL místo GLX]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/firefox-94-zacne-na-linuxu-ve-vychozim-stavu-pouzivat-egl-misto-glx</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/firefox-94-zacne-na-linuxu-ve-vychozim-stavu-pouzivat-egl-misto-glx"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T13:43:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94, jenž vyjde v úterý 2. listopadu, začne na Linuxu ve výchozím stavu používat EGL místo GLX. EGL backend přinese vyšší výkon, rychlejší vykreslování WebGL, nižší spotřebu a časem také dekódování videa pomocí VA-API. V případě problémů se bude možné vrátit k GLX změnou gfx.x11-egl.force-disabled v about:config.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trinity Desktop R14.0.11 Released For Continuing To Improve Upon KDE 3.5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Trinity-Desktop-R14.0.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Trinity-Desktop-R14.0.11"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Trinity Desktop Environment as a decade-old project that forked from the KDE 3.5 desktop continues persevering bit-by-bit to improve this once widely enjoyed desktop environment...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory Folios Looks For Inclusion In Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Memory-Folios-Linux-5.16-PR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Memory-Folios-Linux-5.16-PR"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After memory folios failed to make it into Linux 5.15, this low-level change to the kernel memory management code that has possible performance implications is looking to land for Linux 5.16...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-616</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-616"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for changing into your second Halloween costume and returning to that house who gave out KitKat Chunkys. Before you go to hell, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SDL2 Begins Landing More Workable RISC OS Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL2-More-RISC-OS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL2-More-RISC-OS"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T10:20:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in February 2020 SDL2 began seeing early work for RISC OS support. Now being merged this weekend to this key library used by many cross-platform games is now more functioning support for the RISC OS Arm-based operating system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performance Optimizations, Other "Big" Work For Linux 5.16 To The Block Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Block-Improvements</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Block-Improvements"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T09:44:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux block subsystem maintainer and IO_uring lead developer Jens Axboe has prepared his various pull requests ahead of the upcoming Linux 5.16 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GDB Debugger Adds Native Support For OpenRISC On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GDB-Native-OpenRISC-or1k</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GDB-Native-OpenRISC-or1k"/>
        <updated>2021-10-31T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GNU Debugger (GDB) has landed native support for OpenRISC on Linux and GDB server support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix's The Witcher gets a full season two trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-the-witcher-gets-a-full-season-two-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-the-witcher-gets-a-full-season-two-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T22:13:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, Netflix released the trailer for season two of their live action adaptation of The Witcher. And it's fun! You can watch it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté – ceny]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-tiskarny-behem-lockdownu-a-pote-ceny</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-tiskarny-behem-lockdownu-a-pote-ceny"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Polovina ajťáků v Praze vydělá 100 a více tisíc měsíčně. Notebooky a PC v uplynulém období. Dell rozšiřuje IT kapacity směrem na periferii. Servery Lenovo nově v portfoliu Entec Solutions. Hrozby na vzestupu: útoky na dodavatelské řetězce a krádeže výpočetních kapacit. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (3) Ceny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Trident končí, desktopového následovníka PC-BSD nemá kdo vyvíjet]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15738</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/project-trident-konci-desktopoveho-nasledovnika-pc-bsd-nema-kdo-vyvijet/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audacity 3.1 se snadnější editací, X.Org 21.1 s podporou proměnné obnovovací frekvence, Samsung a HDR10+ Gaming, KDE oddělí stavová data aplikací, vlajková loď Nikon Z9, IPTC přidává dva nové prvky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4's next free update will add challenge scenarios]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-next-free-update-will-add-challenge-scenarios</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4s-next-free-update-will-add-challenge-scenarios"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T21:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of people play The Sims 4 by pursuing community-created challenges, whether they're about building particular types of homes, having a particular number of babies, or many more. Next week a free update for The Sims 4 will add these kinds of challenges to the game itself, beginning with two new scenarios.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crusader Kings 3's first DLC delayed as Paradox aren't satisfied with its "stability"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crusader-kings-3s-first-dlc-delayed-as-paradox-arent-satisfied-with-its-stability</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crusader-kings-3s-first-dlc-delayed-as-paradox-arent-satisfied-with-its-stability"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T20:59:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox are going to take longer than first thought to finish Crusader Kings 3's first DLC. Royal Court didn't previously have an announced release date, but it's currently aiming for 2022 as Paradox say they are "not, at the moment, entirely satisfied with Royal Court's progress."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Devil Inside's world map is just as cute as its combat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-devil-insides-world-map-is-just-as-cute-as-its-combat</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-devil-insides-world-map-is-just-as-cute-as-its-combat"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T20:24:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At PlayStation's State Of Play earlier this week, we got another glimpse of Little Devil Inside. The action-adventure game has been rattling around for at least six years, but it's beginning to look more and more like an actual game. Watch the new trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developers write open letter asking Valve to reverse Steam's NFT ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/developers-write-open-letter-asking-valve-to-reverse-steams-nft-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/developers-write-open-letter-asking-valve-to-reverse-steams-nft-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T19:58:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group of developers have written an open letter to Valve asking them to reverse their decision to forbid games containing NFTs and other blockchain technologies on Steam. NFTs are great, they say, arguing that they "make games more decentralized, democratic, interactive, player focused systems." 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 7.3 Alpha 1 Tagged With More Open-Source Office Suite Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LibreOffice-7.3-Alpha-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LibreOffice-7.3-Alpha-1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 7.3 Alpha 1 was tagged on Friday in the first step towards this next open-source office suite update due out early next year...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa's Radeon Vulkan Driver "RADV" Prepares Experimental Mesh Shaders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Mesh-Shaders-PR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Mesh-Shaders-PR"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa's Radeon Vulkan open-source driver "RADV" is preparing to introduce experimental support for mesh shaders...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94 bude používat EGL - lepší výkon a menší spotřeba]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42959</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-94-bude-pouzivat-egl-lepsi-vykon-a-mensi-spotreba/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T13:21:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nadcházející Firefox 94 bude v Linuxu používat EGL backend místo dosavadního GLX. Ve výsledku bude lepší výkon WebGL a menší spotřeba díky podpoře částečného překreslení obrazovky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The weird folk horror of Mundaun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-weird-folk-horror-of-mundaun</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-weird-folk-horror-of-mundaun"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the first things that may strike you about Mundaun, a very unsettling horror game that released earlier this year, is just how comfortable with weirdness it is. There are hay people hunting you in the night, monstrous masks inspired by traditional Swiss carnival costumes, and the decapitated head of the goat Allegria, bleating and chattering from your backpack. 


Many horror games either try to establish a sense of mundane familiarity in a recognisable, contemporary world before shattering that familiarity, or else rely on the dusty, done-to-death setting of haunted manors. In most cases, neither approach does much to surprise. Horror often relies on the grotesque, but Mundaun’s weirdness is different. It is an earthy kind of weirdness, a strangeness with roots so deep that it might be confused with familiarity. It’s a horror that smells not of blood, but of hay and dung, snow and soot. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 94 To Start Using EGL On Linux - Better Performance, Lower Power Use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-94-EGL-Linux-Usage</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-94-EGL-Linux-Usage"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T09:29:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla Firefox 94 will begin using its EGL back-end on the Linux desktop in conjunction with supported graphics drivers in order to provide better performance, lower power usage, and other benefits...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Ends Out October With More Fixes, Continued Polishing To Plasma Wayland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-EO-October-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-EO-October-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T09:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.23 offers much better Plasma Wayland support than prior releases but still the journey of polished Wayland support on-par with X11 is not over. KDE developers ended out October working on more Wayland fixes along with other improvements to this open-source desktop...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenVDB 9.0 Released With NanoVDB GPU Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenVDB-9.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenVDB-9.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T08:50:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenVDB is the software open-sourced by DreamWorks Animations that is now part of the Academy Software Foundation as a sparse volume data structure and associating tooling with a particular focus on visual effects and animations for film production. OpenVDB 9.0 is out today as the latest major update to this library...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When did horror games become team sports?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/when-did-horror-games-become-team-sports</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/when-did-horror-games-become-team-sports"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By the time you read this I'll be playing Back 4 Blood, gunning down hordes of the undead until viscera and gore cake my player’s clothes, and my eyes become infinite pools of horror that have seen more than enough death for one lifetime. Or perhaps I’ll be creeping around a haunted house in Phasmophobia, my smudge stick in-hand and a cavalcade of petrified friends whimpering down their mics. Maybe I’ll be running from Pyramid Head in Dead By Daylight with my pals in tow. A thought has been brewing in the cold recesses of my mind for a while now, and it is simply this: when did horror become a team game?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Heaton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-167</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-167"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Halloween weekend, gang! Oh, hang on, I meant to say: BOO! Alright, there we go. But the greatest horror this weekend isn't any ghost or ghoulie, it's UK clocks switching back to GMT this weekend. Sure, your phone and computer will automatically update, but your heating will be irksome until you again dig out the manual to remember how to change it. And a secondary blast of horror comes from the fact that not every country changes their clocks just yet, so if you deal with business across timezones... good luck, pal. But, what are you playing this weekend?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stargate Is The Newest Open-Source Digital Audio Workstation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Stargate-DAW</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Stargate-DAW"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Ardour is arguably the most well known open-source digital audio workstation (DAW) solution, there are also other offerings like Zrythm and others while now "Stargate" is the newest option available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Void-Linux-Powered Project Trident To Cease Operations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Project-Trident-No-More</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Project-Trident-No-More"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project Trident had been an operating system originally based on TrueOS/FreeBSD before shifting to Void Linux as its base and worked on various innovations like OpenZFS-based root installations but now the developers behind the ambitious advanced desktop OS project have decided to call it quits...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$220 for a 27-in 1440p 144Hz ViewSonic monitor is an absolute steal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/220-for-a-27-in-1440p-144hz-viewsonic-monitor-is-an-absolute-steal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/220-for-a-27-in-1440p-144hz-viewsonic-monitor-is-an-absolute-steal"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T01:14:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's rare to see a legitimately good 1440p 144Hz monitor for less than $250, but right now ViewSonic's VX2758-2KP-MHD is on sale at Newegg for $220 - a stunning $110 (33%) reduction from its original price of $330. 
This 'Shell Shocker' sale ends in just a few hours, so do pick this up if you're in the market for a high-end gaming monitor at bargain basement prices!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD's 2TB SN550 NVMe SSD is well cheap on Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-2tb-sn550-nvme-ssd-is-well-cheap-on-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-2tb-sn550-nvme-ssd-is-well-cheap-on-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-30T00:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of our former best gaming SSD picks, the WD Blue SN550, is down to just £140 on Amazon for a massive 2TB model. That's a historic low price by around £15 and a good £40 what it cost just a few weeks ago, making this a very good time to pick up a high performance NVMe SSD on the cheap. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 43/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-43-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-43-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence a rekurzívní sebezdokonalování]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-rekurzivni-sebezdokonalovani</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-rekurzivni-sebezdokonalovani"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poločas rozpadu neutronu. Máme se bát, pokud umělá inteligence navrhne jinou umělou inteligenci? Superionický led. Počátky počítačů na Slovensku. Na Venuši žádné oceány být nemusely.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mushrooms, mould and killer plants: the best horror isn't animal, it's vegetable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mushrooms-mould-and-killer-plants-the-best-horror-isnt-animal-its-vegetable</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mushrooms-mould-and-killer-plants-the-best-horror-isnt-animal-its-vegetable"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since I witnessed a little red-and-blue plumber-man tumble into the gnashing jaws of a Piranha Plant, I knew vegetables weren’t to be trusted. I see my suspicion of all things green and floral as a natural, even instinctual thing. We ourselves aren’t vegetable, and differences so often motivate our deepest fears. The vegetal realm is entirely inaccessible to us, its behaviour strange and habitats dark. From the carnivorous Venus flytrap to the bleeding tooth fungus, from plants that smell like rotting corpses to one's that trap prey and dissolve them with digestive fluids, it’s an unknown, often dangerous world, and one that overlaps closely with our own. And it makes for a compelling game.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to convince the Worldmind in Guardians Of The Galaxy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-worldmind</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-worldmind"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:59:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to convince the Worldmind in Guardians Of The Galaxy? The adventure to save the galaxy doesn’t just involve shooting Chitauri and cracking jokes. Throughout Guardians Of The Galaxy, you engage in conversations with various characters, in which you can make decisions that will alter the course of the game. Most of these have small, fairly insignificant consequences. However, the conversation with the Worldmind in Chapter 9 could help you get some crucial help in a difficult fight later in the game.
This guide will show you the correct choices to make to convince the Worldmind that Raker can be defeated in Guardians Of The Galaxy.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zink OpenGL On Vulkan Inches Closer To OpenGL 4.6 Conformance, More Games Working]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Zink-Closer-To-4.6-Conformance</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Zink-Closer-To-4.6-Conformance"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:42:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While there has been less major progress to report on Mesa's Zink OpenGL-over-Vulkan code in recent weeks, Mike Blumenkrantz of Valve and others continue optimizing and fixing this increasing useful implementation. Most recently the game Bioshock: Infinite is running on Zink and there are more fixes in aiming toward OpenGL 4.6 conformance...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An ode to Kain from Blood Omen and his Legacy - including Untitled Goose Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-kain-from-blood-omen-and-his-legacy-including-untitled-goose-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-kain-from-blood-omen-and-his-legacy-including-untitled-goose-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:38:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Steam user genre tags can be awful. Cyberpunk 2077 was, for example, tagged ‘masterpiece’ for months before the first gameplay trailer, while the much more reasonable and catchy ‘looks cool sure but too early to say anything definitive if we’re being adults about it’ tag was strangely absent. Happily, they are sometimes wonderful, like the tag alongside ‘comedy’ and ‘indie’ that categorises avian arsehole adventure Untitled Goose Game as having a ‘villain protagonist’. 


I’ve been thinking about villain protagonists a fair amount this week because GOG just graced our collective thinking tellies with 1996 Zelda-like Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain, in all its richly overwrought, gothic, inimitably voice-acted splendour. I would estimate this news finds you, reader, in one of two categories: those who give not a fig, and those who give so many figs they are currently scrabbling the world’s few remaining fig-bearing trees, searching vainly for an adequate quantity of figs.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PUBG company buying Subnautica studio Unknown Worlds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pubg-company-buying-subnautica-studio-unknown-worlds</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pubg-company-buying-subnautica-studio-unknown-worlds"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:10:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Krafton, the South Korean company behind Plunkbat and Tera, today announced that they're buying Unknown Worlds, the studio splendid subaquatic survival sim series Subnautica and the fantastic FPS-RTS hybrid Natural Selection. Huh! The professed plan is for them to keep on as usual, still working on the Subnauticae as well as a mystery game debuting next year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultimate Audio Bang #17: weird and wonderful FPS vocab]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-17-weird-and-wonderful-fps-vocab</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-17-weird-and-wonderful-fps-vocab"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This time, I've returned from a trip to Devon having spent too much time ignoring my friends and playing Hollow Knight instead. But what about FPSes? Well, I didn't play any of those. Thankfully Imogen has all of us covered on this week's episode of the Ultimate Audio Bang, with a news segment rammed with lots of exciting announcements. Namely, Apex Legends gets a new Legend and map, Halo Infinite sees a new trailer, and Call Of Duty's new anti-cheat Ricochet leaks early.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How long is the Guardians Of The Galaxy game?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-length</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-length"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T14:47:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how long it takes to beat Guardians Of The Galaxy? This planet-hopping adventure takes you on the cosmic ride of your life in an original Guardians Of The Galaxy story, involving plenty of punching, shooting, and generally jumping around with jet boots. Throughout the adventure, you'll come across many classic characters, such as Cosmo the spacedog, Adam Warlock, Mantis, Fin Fang Foom, and Lady Hellbender. However, since it isn't based directly on a certain comic storyline or movie, it can be hard to judge how long you'll actually spend playing Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy.
This guide will break down how long it takes to beat Guardians Of The Galaxy, including a list of chapters so that you can figure out how far you are through the adventure.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carve pumpkins for a virtual pumpkin festival in this free indie game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/carve-pumpkins-for-a-virtual-pumpkin-festival-in-this-free-indie-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/carve-pumpkins-for-a-virtual-pumpkin-festival-in-this-free-indie-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T13:41:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last Halloween, Alice Bee visited Ghost Town's 999th Annual Pumpkin Festival, carving a pumpkin of her own to place amongst the spooky virtual showcase. It was a lovely little indie game from Adam "Adamgryu" Robinson-Yu, creator of the much-adored A Short Hike. Well, Halloween is upon us again, and Mayor Bones has returned with another gourd-o-rama, putting servers back online and inviting us to contribute new pumpkins. It's still lovely.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitman 3 and The Riftbreaker are the first games with Intel XeSS support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-3-and-the-riftbreaker-are-the-first-games-with-intel-xess-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-3-and-the-riftbreaker-are-the-first-games-with-intel-xess-support"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T13:32:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amidst all the excitement of Intel’s 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs, let’s not forget that the first Intel dedicated graphics cards are on their way. Codenamed Arc Alchemist, these GPUs will launch alongside XeSS (Xe Super Sampling), an Nvidia DLSS-style upscaling/anti-aliasing piece of tech that promises to boost performance while sharpening up those jagged edges. And we now know the first two games that will support XeSS: Hitman 3 and The Riftbreaker.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where are all the good Stephen King games?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/where-are-all-the-good-stephen-king-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/where-are-all-the-good-stephen-king-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Halloweekend is almost upon us and sitting on my coffee table is my battered old paperback copy of Skeleton Crew, a 1985 collection of short horror stories by Stephen King. Back in my wild teenage years I binged King's entire back-catalogue of published fiction, and now that it's been long enough for me to have forgotten most of the details, I'm treating myself to some selective re-reads. Fair to say some of his stuff hasn't aged brilliantly, but despite many rough edges he undeniably remains one of my all-time favourite authors. I am, after all, a self-confessed horror nerd.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proton nově umí hry chráněné DRM Valve CEG]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42958</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/proton-nove-umi-hry-chranene-drm-valve-ceg/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T12:24:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový Proton Experimental v beta verzi klienta Steam ze včerejška umí spustit windowsové hry chráněné starým ale rozšířeným DRM Valve CEG (custom executable-generation). Jde zatím jen o předběžnou podoru a může se stát, že některá hra s CEG nepojede. Úspěchy i neúspěchy lze hlásit na GitHubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rally Point: The Riftbreaker is light on strategy but carries a lot with it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-the-riftbreaker-is-light-on-strategy-but-carries-a-lot-with-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-the-riftbreaker-is-light-on-strategy-but-carries-a-lot-with-it"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hesitated. Not to play The Riftbreaker, you understand. I'd played its demo last year, which was enough to sell me on playing the full game. But to cover it as a strategy game is another matter.
It does games in particular a disservice to get prescriptive with genre, but there's no question that Riftbreaker falls under 'action strategy', with an even greater emphasis on action than, say, Hostile Waters or Sacrifice. But then, it also has detailed base building, tower defence, and a tonne of resource management. I've given up trying to categorise it, and it will always be distinct from most strategy games, but I think its peers could still learn a few things from it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome i Chromium zranitelné, aktualizujte na 95.0.4638.69]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42957</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chrome-a-chromium-zranitelne-aktualizujte-na-95-0-4638-69/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T11:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera Google vydal mimořádnou bezpečnostní opravu svého prohlížeče Chrome 95.0.4638.69 pro Windows, Linux i macOS, která se týká také Chromium. Opraveno je celkem 8 zranitelností, všechny s vysokou nebezpečností. Obzvlášť nebezpečné jsou chyby CVE-2021–38000 a CVE-2021–38003, protože jsou v současnosti aktivně zneužívány.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook parent company now named Meta, unveiling vision of a metaverse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/facebook-parent-company-now-named-meta-unveiling-vision-of-a-metaverse</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/facebook-parent-company-now-named-meta-unveiling-vision-of-a-metaverse"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T11:01:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The company behind Facebook and Oculus, previously known as Facebook, have unveiled a new name: Meta. Oh christ. Yes, it is named after the metaverse, because tech megacorps can't resist the delusion that their platform to sell adverts is elevating humanity to a new plane of existence. Mark Zuckerberg suggests that in the future they're building, you'll experience everything through virtual and augmented reality, and that definitely won't be a horrible world devoid of intimacy, okay, it'll be great.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se používat Linux správně a bezpečně (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40574</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-pouzivat-linux-spravne-a-bezpecne-online-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T08:40:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxových systémů přibývá, každý den se spouštějí nové servery a někdo se o ně musí starat. To znamená spoustu různých dovedností specifických právě pro linuxové prostředí. Jak to zprovoznit, kudy bezpečně dovnitř, co tam najdeme, jak se o to postaráme a jak to nastavíme nebo rozšíříme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Facebook se přejmenovává na Meta]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42956</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/spolecnost-facebook-se-prejmenovava-na-meta/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T05:47:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera CEO Facebooku Mark Zuckerberg řekl, že se společnost Facebook přejmenovává na Meta. Jména jednotlivých produktů jako Facebook, Whatsapp a Instagram zůstávají stejné. Výjimkou je Oculus s VR brýlemi. Ty budou nově prodávány pod značkou Meta a Oculus už se nebude používat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Cold Viruses]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2535/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2535/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-29T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Black SN750 1TB NVMe SSD is £87 for 1TB: good deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-wd-black-sn750-1tb-nvme-ssd-is-87-for-1tb-good-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-wd-black-sn750-1tb-nvme-ssd-is-87-for-1tb-good-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T22:16:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Black SN750 is a super-fast PCIe 3.0 SSD - and the 1TB model is down to £87 at Amazon UK, a historic low price. That's a fantastic price for what was once among the fastest NVMe SSDs on the planet, with read speeds up to nearly 3500MB/s... before the advent of faster (and more expensive) PCIe 4.0 drives in the last couple of years. 
Still, in terms of value for money, this TLC drive with a DRAM cache is going to be hard to beat - especially as the only real competitors tend to come with QLC NAND or without a DRAM cache, both of which sacrifice performance to hit lower price points!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel bude otevřenější, důkazem je uvedení Alder Lake]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15735</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/intel-bude-otevrenejsi-dukazem-je-uvedeni-alder-lake/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger má za sebou 8 měsíců ve funkci. Intel nyní stojí v bodě zvratu, čerstvě uvedené procesory 12. generace Core zvané Alder Lake mají firmu vrátit na výsluní. Ale to je jen polovina cesty.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer's Viper Ultimate mouse is nearly £100 off at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razers-viper-ultimate-mouse-is-nearly-100-off-at-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razers-viper-ultimate-mouse-is-nearly-100-off-at-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T21:26:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I've mentioned before, the Razer Viper is one of my favourite ultralight gaming mice of all time, and today the Ultimate wireless version is marked it down from £170 all the way to £73 at Amazon UK.
That's an incredibly good price considering this is the model that comes with a handy charging dock to ensure your mouse is always topped up without ever fussing with a cable. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unikly privátní klíče pro tvorbu očkovacích certifikátů, koluje certifikát Adolfa Hitlera]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42955</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/unikly-privatni-klice-pro-tvorbu-ockovacich-certifikatu-koluje-certifikat-adolfa-hitlera/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T20:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Privátní klíč určený k podpisu digitálních očkovacích certifikátů zřejmě unikl a koluje po nejrůznějších platformách včetně sociálních sítí a webových fór. Internetem se také šíří potvrzení o očkování vystavené pro Adolfa Hitlera narozeného 1. ledna 1900. Kromě toho je možné potkat také certifikáty pro jména Mickey Mouse, Sponge Bob a další známá jména. Mobilní aplikace pro kontrolu očkovacích certifikátů je považují za platné.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dění okolo generických typů v Go]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42954</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/deni-okolo-generickych-typu-v-go/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T19:54:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S blížícím se vydáním Go 1.18 dochází k posledním úpravám návrhu generických typů v Go. Tato zatím největší změna od vydání první verze jazyka zahrnuje rozšíření překladače a standardní knihovny. V případě knihovny budou zatím změny provizorní, bez zaručení zpětné kompatibility.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Calculon)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard CEO commits to waiving forced arbitration, and a temporary paycut]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-ceo-commits-to-waiving-forced-arbitration-and-a-temporary-paycut</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-ceo-commits-to-waiving-forced-arbitration-and-a-temporary-paycut"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T18:44:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick has detailed plans for the company to rebuild itself following numerous legal cases and protests over alleged harrassment, discrimination, and retaliation at the company. Key points include a policy of zero-tolerance for harassment and an end to forced abitration in claims of sexual harrassment and discrimination. An employee group call this "a huge win". And Kotick himself has volunteered to take a huge pay cut until they achieve their stated goals.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new hero Ash hunts squads with Titanfall-inspired abilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-hero-ash-hunts-squads-with-titanfall-inspired-abilities</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-hero-ash-hunts-squads-with-titanfall-inspired-abilities"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' next season, Escape, kicks off next week, and it introduces the new playable character Ash. She's a simulacrum (read: human brain in robot body) that you might recognise as the evil pilot from Titanfall 2's Into The Abyss level, or as the overseer of Apex Legends' 3v3 Arenas mode. Now she's descending into the Apex games herself, and having taken her for a spin already, I reckon she has some delightfully aggressive abilities that Wraith players in particular are going to enjoy. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends Ash abilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-ash-abilities-tips-tricks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-ash-abilities-tips-tricks"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know about Ash's abilities in Apex Legends? The upcoming addition to the Apex Legends roster will arrive next week, along with a brand new map, the new CAR SMG, and a host of weapon and Legend balance changes. Ash is turning a lot of heads thanks both to her complex and fascinating backstory and to her powerful and versatile array of abilities.
Below we'll walk you through how each of Ash's abilities work in detail, so you can get off to a great start with her once Season 11 drops. We'll also detail Ash's backstory for those who need to know every last detail about this dangerous new Legend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends CAR SMG stats [Season 11]]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-car-stats</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-car-stats"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for up-to-date and accurate CAR SMG stats for Apex Legends? The CAR is Season 11's addition to the Apex Legends weapons arsenal, and it's got a very impressive array of stats to show off. But what's truly unique about the CAR is its ability to use both Heavy and Light Ammo, and toggle between them at the touch of a button.
Keep reading for an in-depth look at the CAR SMG in Apex Legends, along with detailed stats covering everything from damage profiles and shots to kill to reload times and attachment slots.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new map Stormpoint comes with vicious wildlife and excellent cannons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-map-stormpoint-comes-with-vicious-wildlife-and-excellent-cannons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-map-stormpoint-comes-with-vicious-wildlife-and-excellent-cannons"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beach map! Beach map! Beach map! Apex Legends' next season, Escape, is right around the corner, and it's bringing a tropical island to fight on. It's also bringing a the new Legend Ash, the CAR SMG and more, but most importantly: beach map! I had a chance to play a little of Respawn's battle royale in this new arena, and it is delightful. Named Stormpoint, it's the FPS's fourth map, and not only is it lovely to look at, but it's full of cool locations to explore and dangerous wildlife to dodge. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption is horrifying because it does things games aren't supposed to]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-is-horrifying-because-it-does-things-games-arent-supposed-to</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-is-horrifying-because-it-does-things-games-arent-supposed-to"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Mullins says he's not sure that "horror" is the most accurate way to describe his gruesome new card battler Inscryption. He immediately follows this up by telling me a friend of his had nightmares because of the menacing figure you play cards against, so yeah, maybe it's a bit horror-like. But I kind of understand his point. 


At the start, Inscryption is like a hostage situation, where you're forced to play a card-based roguelike against a sinister games master. Then, just as you start getting the hang of things, the game evolves into something way more complex. If you've played Mullins' other games you'll know his work can go to some weird, meta places. I won't say more above the cut, because I'd hate to spoil it. But for those of you who've already played, read on for more detail on how Mullins created an excellently unsettling world.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix announce Star Ocean The Divine Force]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-announce-star-ocean-the-divine-force</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-announce-star-ocean-the-divine-force"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T13:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tri-Ace's action-RPG series Star Ocean will return with a new game next year, Square Enix have announced. Though the series started 25 years ago on the SNES, you needn't concern yourself with that history because Squeenix say Star Ocean The Divine Force will tell a new story with new characters. Come meet them and see some of the sci-fantasy world in the trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Performance Continues In The Right Direction For AArch64]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30647</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30647"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a good sign ahead of the important Ubuntu 22.04 LTS release in the spring, Ubuntu 21.10 further ups the 64-bit ARM (AArch64) performance. Here is a look at some of the gains in going from Ubuntu 21.04 to the recently released Ubuntu 21.10.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metro má signálem pokrytou celou linku A, v celé síti zbývá už jen pět stanic]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42953</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/metro-ma-signalem-pokrytou-celou-linku-a-v-cele-siti-zbyva-uz-jen-pet-stanic/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T10:48:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pokrývání pražského metra mobilním signálem zdárně pokračuje, o prázdninách byly pokryty čtyři stanice a teď se k nim přidávají další. Od tohoto týdne je vysokorychlostní sítí LTE i 5G pokryt i poslední úsek linky A, tedy stanice Skalka a Depo Hostivař a oba traťové tunely mezi nimi. Cestující na zelené lince tak mohou telefonovat či datovat v celém úseku od Nemocnice Motol po Depo Hostivař. Jedinou výjimku tvoří samotná stanice Jiřího z Poděbrad, do které se LTE síť dostane po dokončení modernizace a vybudování výtahů, píše v oznámení dopravní podnik.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forget Far Cry 6, the bugs in Hollow Knight can send me snarky emails anytime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forget-far-cry-6-the-bugs-in-hollow-knight-can-send-me-snarky-emails-anytime</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forget-far-cry-6-the-bugs-in-hollow-knight-can-send-me-snarky-emails-anytime"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I've heard tales of Far Cry 6 players receiving snarky emails from Ubisoft about how much time they've spent in-game. They're supposed to read as if Anton Castillo, the game's evil dictator, is mocking you for not investing enough of it toppling his regime.
And even if you've spent a lot of time clearing Castillo's map markers, he'll still send you emails anyway. They feature stats like time played, checkpoints cleared, that sort of thing. Many people don't seem to like this, which I totally understand. But a part of me wishes these rude marketing emails were more of a thing. Specifically, I'd like it if the bugs from Hollow Knight spun some my way.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guardians Of The Galaxy tips]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/guardians-of-the-galaxy-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T09:51:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know some tips and tricks for Guardians Of The Galaxy? The adventure will take you across the vast galaxy in search of fortune, fun, and a whole lot of kicking ass, but you won’t make it far without a solid grasp of the mechanics in Guardians Of The Galaxy.
This guide will offer some tips and tricks that you’ll need to get familiar with if you want to turn your rag-tag group of misfits into a heroic team to be feared. We'll cover tips for all of the main aspects of the game, including combat, exploring, and all of the chats that you'll have with your teammates during your adventure.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Zero 2 W: pětkrát vyšší výkon na stejné desce]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42952</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-zero-2-w-petkrat-vyssi-vykon-na-stejne-desce-za-stejnou-cenu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T08:35:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Foundation zveřejnila novou verzi populárního miniaturního jednodeskového počítače Raspberry Pi Zero W ve verzi 2. Hlavní změnou je výměna procesoru – místo obstarožního BCM2835 byl použit BCM2710A1, který je používán i v jednodeskových počítačích Raspberry Pi 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Šrámek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get the brand new SteelSeries Arctis 7P+ gaming headset for 12% off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-brand-new-steelseries-arctis-7p-gaming-headset-for-12-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-brand-new-steelseries-arctis-7p-gaming-headset-for-12-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The SteelSeries Arctis 7P+ is a brand new gaming headset, offering a series of small upgrades over the already-brilliant Arctis 7P. It's rare to see new items discounted right away, but today you can get this new model up for 12% off with code MOUNTAIN12.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PNY's great value DDR4 RAM is going cheap in the US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pnys-great-value-ddr4-ram-is-going-cheap-in-the-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pnys-great-value-ddr4-ram-is-going-cheap-in-the-us"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T00:45:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PNY isn't the first name you might think of when it comes to RAM, but they're sometimes a great value - including today, when a series of RAM kits are on sale in stores across the US. Here are the links - and some words about why you should consider them. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can my Darkest Dungeon 2 party please shut up for five minutes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/can-my-darkest-dungeon-2-party-please-shut-up-for-five-minutes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/can-my-darkest-dungeon-2-party-please-shut-up-for-five-minutes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:13:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In time, you will know the tragic extent of my failings, but in Darkest Dungeon 2 goodness me you'll hear about everyone's failings constantly. The horrific dungeon-crawling sequel entered early access yesterday, and my initial impression is that I'm surrounded by squabbling children. Managing the stress of your heroes is more important than ever, because if anyone is even mildly irked they will interrupt every fight to shout about how their squadmate is a kill-stealing dick. I'm this close to turning the stagecoach back around and embracing the impending apocalypse.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All I want for spook month is more classic survival horror]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-i-want-for-spook-month-is-more-classic-survival-horror</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-i-want-for-spook-month-is-more-classic-survival-horror"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Listen. Outside your window, the chill wind chuckles in raspy glee at autumn’s death rattle. The branches of dying trees rake their gnarled fingers against the glass. You are spooked. You turn to the warm glow of your monitor for comfort. Instead, you find the most terrifying thing imaginable: an unpopular opinion about a videogame. On the internet, no less. You blink and rub your eyes in disbelief. Still, the words remain. Stark. Unforgiving. Undeniably spicy: “Resident Evil Village was disappointing and its success does not bode well for the future of survival horror.” 


You go to type a comment but, uh, your fingers are gone, or something. Just hear me out. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs announced: everything you need to know]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-cpus-specs-price-features</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-cpus-specs-price-features"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a months-long spin around the rumour mill, the first batch of Intel 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs is official. Despite the 11th Gen Rocket Lake chips only launching earlier this year, Alder Lake represents the biggest generational jump for Intel in over half a decade, thanks to its completely redesigned “hybrid” architecture and DDR5 memory support. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Announces 12th Gen Core "Alder Lake" CPUs, Linux Tests Forthcoming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30645</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30645"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel is using their inaugural Intel Innovation virtual event today to formally announce the highly-anticipated 12th Gen Core "Alder Lake" processors. These first desktop processors built on their "Intel 7" process and employ a hybrid architecture will be available in retail channels next week. Today we can talk more about Alder Lake specifications and features while our Linux performance benchmarks and support analysis will come once the Alder Lake review embargo expires next week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Satisfactory adding train signals, train timetables, and train crashes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/satisfactory-adding-train-signals-train-timetables-and-train-crashes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/satisfactory-adding-train-signals-train-timetables-and-train-crashes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T14:24:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As factory-building sim Satisfactory continues to assemble itself through early access, the next major update runs a real risk of becoming a train wreck. Now in public testing, Update 5 introduces new features to manage train timetables and routes, and you'll want to pay attention to those because trains can now crash.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Značka fotoaparátů Olympus se mění na OM SYSTEM]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42951</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/znacka-fotoaparatu-olympus-se-meni-na-om-system/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Více než 80 let byla nedílnou součástí fotografické historie japonská značka Olympus. Mateřská firma téhož jména nakonec před několika měsíci fotografickou divizi prodala do jiných rukou a fotografický svět očekával, jak to „s Olympusem“ dopadne. Dnes přichází v historii této foto značky významná zpráva. Olympus jako foto značka se mění na OM SYSTEM, přičemž v tomto názvu navazujícím na úspěšnou řadu kinofilmových zrcadlovek OM a pozdějších digi bezzrcadlovek OM-D, se nadále ukrývá původní dědictví Olympusu a jeho designéra Yoshihisy Maitaniho.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Platební terminály PAX Technology zneužity ke kybernetickým útokům]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42950</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/platebni-terminaly-pax-technology-zneuzity-ke-kybernetickym-utokum/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T12:16:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server KrebsOnSecurity zveřejnil velmi znepokojivou zprávu o platebních terminálech čínské společnosti PAX Technology, které jsou ve 120 zemích v počtu zhruba 60 milionů. Mají být zodpovědné za kybernetické útoky nejen v USA, ale i v UK a EU.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: jerry_wlk)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core i9 11900K a Windows 11 versus pět linuxových distribucí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42949</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-core-i9-11900k-a-windows-11-versus-pet-linuxovych-distribuci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T11:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server Phoronix otestoval výkon aktuálně nejnovějšího procesoru od Intelu (do příchodu Alder Lake je to model 11900K) na platformě Windows 11 oproti pěti různým linuxovým distribucím. Porovnány byly nejnovější Windows 11 Pro oproti Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS, Ubuntu 21.10, Arch Linuxu, Fedoře Workstation 35 a chybět nemohl ani Intel Clear Linux 35150.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow Warrior 3 delayed into next year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-warrior-3-delayed-into-next-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-warrior-3-delayed-into-next-year"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T10:46:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The fast-paced, fast-talking violence of Shadow Warrior 3 will not arrive this year after all, now pushed back into "early 2022." Devolver Digital and developers Flying Wild Hog explain it's the usual reason: they want more time to make the FPS good, yeah? A good reason. For now, you can watch the new trailer announcing the delay.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NuTyX 21.10.0 s podporou 32bit x86]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42948</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nutyx-21-10-0-s-podporou-32bit-x86/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T08:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Francouzská distribuce NuTyX, stavějící na projektech Linux From Scratch / Beyond Linux From Scratch, přichází po roce v nové verzi, tedy vlastně spíše aktuálním snapshotu označeném jako 21.10.0. Přináší aktualizované verze jádra, desktopových prostředí i dalších aplikací (včetně vlastního správce balíčků cards 2.4.138), přičemž zahrnuje též podporu 32bit procesorů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gitlab CI: automatizujte přímo v Gitlabu (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-38836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gitlab-ci-automatizujte-primo-v-gitlabu-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T08:38:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automatizace pomocí continuous integration přímo v Gitlabu. CI vám pomůže automatizovat rutinní procesy a ušetří vám hromadu času. Pomůže vám od automatického testování, buildy po nasazování. Chcete vědět víc? Přijďte na naše školení GitLab CI, které se uskuteční 18. listopadu a proběhne plně online. Školí Ondřej Sika.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TSMC představil výrobní proces N4P, čipy budou menší, výkonnější, úspornější i levnější]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42947</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/tsmc-predstavil-vyrobni-proces-n4p-cipy-budou-mensi-vykonnejsi-uspornejsi-i-levnejsi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Již třetí velké vylepšení výrobních procesů své 5nm rodiny přináší tchaj-wanská TSMC. N4P stále staví na původní 5nm technologii, ale oproti původní variantě procesu N5 přináší o 11% vyšší výkon čipů, oproti dosud nejnovější inkarnaci N4 pak o 6% vyšší. Současně zvyšuje energetickou efektivitu o 22 % a hustotu tranzistorů v čipech o 6 %. Výrobní proces také pracuje s menším počtem masek, klesá tak komplexita výroby waferů a za stejný čas bude možné jich továrnou prohnat víc.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yubico nabízí Security Key C NFC s USB-C za 29 eur]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42946</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/yubico-nabizi-security-key-c-nfc-s-usb-c-za-29-eur/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T06:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po zbrusu novém YubiKey Bio se čtečkou otisků prstů přichází společnost Yubico s novinkou v modré řade Security Key. Konkrétně jde o model Security Key C NFC, který nenabízí všechny možnosti autentizace jako velký YubiKey, ale zaměřuje se na standard FIDO. S ním se přihlásíte k mnoha webovým službám, k novějším verzím OpenSSH nebo ke službám státní správy pomocí mojeID.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CETIN začne v některých lokalitách nabízet optiku místo DSL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42945</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/cetin-zacne-v-nekterych-lokalitach-nabizet-optiku-misto-dsl/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CETIN přestává v některých pražských lokalitách poskytovat své služby pomocí DSL a místo toho nabídne připojení pomocí optiky. CETIN tímto oznamuje záměr ukončit nabídku a poskytování služby zpřístupnění prostřednictvím účastnického metalického vedení z důvodu přechodu na přístupy realizované prostřednictvím účastnického optického vedení, píše se v oznámení společnosti [PDF].]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retractable Rocket]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2534/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2534/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rychlá oprava dotazů ve vyhledávači pomocí neuronových sítí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15721</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/rychla-oprava-dotazu-ve-vyhledavaci-pomoci-neuronovych-siti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dotazy zadané do vyhledání obsahují řadu chyb. Vyhledávače umí tyto chyby odstranit a díky tomu nalézt lepší výsledky. V Seznamu jsme nedávno zrychlili a zlepšili opravu dotazů pomocí neuronových sítí.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ondřej Filip)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (27. 10. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15728</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-27-10-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si představíme nástroj pro automatické klikání, vyzkoušíme sofistikovanou kalkulačku, podíváme se na otevřeného klienta pro OneNote a řekneme si o nástroji pro auditování a obnovu hesel ve Windows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD's insanely big 14TB HDD is down to £222, almost £90 off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-insanely-big-14tb-hdd-is-down-to-222-almost-90-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-insanely-big-14tb-hdd-is-down-to-222-almost-90-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T20:37:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Western Digital's 14TB Elements external hard drive is one of the largest you can buy, making it ideal for backing up entire computers, storing massive media libraries and generally being a massive data hoarder. It normally retails for around £300, but today it's dropped down to £222, an £89 discount below RRP. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best PCIe 4.0 SSD we've tested is going cheap at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-pcie-40-ssd-weve-tested-is-going-cheap-at-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-pcie-40-ssd-weve-tested-is-going-cheap-at-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T20:18:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WD's SN850 SSD is the fastest SSD we've ever tested, beating out rivals like the Samsung 980 Pro and Crucial P5 Plus in most workloads. If you've got a PCIe 4.0 compatible PC - or a PS5 - then this is the NVMe SSD you want! Today, both the 1TB and 2TB sizes are discounted at Amazon UK, making it a great time to upgrade to the latest and greatest NVMe SSD. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can visit New Vegas again in a Fallout 4 mod]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-visit-new-vegas-again-in-a-fallout-4-mod</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-visit-new-vegas-again-in-a-fallout-4-mod"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T18:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What happens in New Vegas stays in New Vegas, they say, though New Vegas itself will not stay in Fallout: New Vegas. A new mod named Project Mojave is attempting to recreate a lot of the post-apocalyptic Sin City and surrounding areas as a Fallout 4 mod, and you can play the first slice now. But to manage your expectations: it is not an attempt to recreate Obsidian Entertainment's game Fallout: New Vegas inside Fallout 4.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turbo Overkill is the most fun you'll have with a chainsaw leg]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turbo-overkill-is-the-most-fun-youll-have-with-a-chainsaw-leg-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turbo-overkill-is-the-most-fun-youll-have-with-a-chainsaw-leg-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T17:46:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually, I'd assume that if a chainsaw was near someone's leg, that'd be a problem. But, when the chainsaw is embedded into your own leg and you can flick it out every time you do a butt slide, well then, it's much more of a problem for your enemies' ankles. This is exactly what you're in for with Turbo Overkill, an upcoming shooter which took Apex Legends' excellent sliding mechanics and asked, "What if we added deadly spinning blades?" I've had a chat with game director Sam Prebble and even played a little bit myself, and I think you'll like the answer. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 is out now in early access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-is-out-now-in-early-access</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-is-out-now-in-early-access"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T16:16:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 has launched in early access, inviting us all on a delightfully stressful wagon ride. The sequel to Red Hook Studios' dark roguelike moves away from expeditions in the gloomy Hamlet, and instead sends you on a journey through horrific lands to stop an apocalypse. The devs recently told me about why they're taking their gothic tale on the road, and it has something to do with wanting to emulate a rather uncomfortable road trip.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 41-42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-41-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-41-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V říjnu bylo dosud vydáno Ubuntu 21.10, OpenBSD 7.0 nebo ruská, na Mandrivě založená ROSA Fresh Desktop R12. Na Debian „Bullseye“ přešly jeho deriváty bez systemd Devuan a MX Linux. Také byly aktualizovány distribuce KaOS, GhostBSD, Porteus Kiosk, Redcore Linux či NuTyX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to enable Auto HDR in Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-enable-auto-hdr-in-windows-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-enable-auto-hdr-in-windows-11"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T15:32:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11 may not be an essential upgrade yet, but its Auto HDR feature is mightily impressive: in games that don’t support HDR (high dynamic range) natively, it can apply similar brightness-boosting, colour-emboldening effects. There’s no performance loss, so if you’ve going to upgrade to Windows 11 on your gaming rig, it’s worth giving Auto HDR a try – and this guide will show you how to enable it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can batter people with fish in Chivalry 2's new tavern brawl mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-batter-people-with-fish-in-chivalry-2s-new-tavern-brawl-mode</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-batter-people-with-fish-in-chivalry-2s-new-tavern-brawl-mode"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T15:04:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Swords are cool and all but the medieval fight I find a delight is a tavern brawl, so I'm chuffed to heck to see Chivalry 2 focus on them in a new mode. 'Brawl' mode has players rumble through feasts and halls, fighting with found weapons including chairs, steins, and giant fish. Oh yes, thank you. Also in the field of delightful foolishness is a new headbutt move for armless players to launch one desperate last attack.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Step back from the brink in Precipice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/step-back-from-the-brink-in-precipice</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/step-back-from-the-brink-in-precipice"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brinkmanship doesn't get explored all that much in games. Precipice is almost certainly derived from Balance of Power, a political strategy simulation from 1985 about the Cold War powers and their winner-armageddons-all staring contest. It was impressively original, complex, and completely unplayable. Happily, Precipice has kept most of what made that game interesting to begin with, and dumped the baggage.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rad roguelike Caves Of Qud has added friendlier modes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rad-roguelike-caves-of-qud-has-added-friendlier-modes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rad-roguelike-caves-of-qud-has-added-friendlier-modes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T13:52:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've heard a lot about sci-fantasy roguelike Caves Of Qud, split between "This game is amazing" and "This game sounds amazing but what am I doing and why do I keep dying?" Good news for both types: the latest early access update has added new areas, factions, and items for experienced players to enjoy, while also adding two new friendlier modes. Character creation is overhauled too, complete with some helpful presets.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lo-fi horror and the allure of an uncanny Bitsy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-horror-and-the-allure-of-an-uncanny-bitsy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-horror-and-the-allure-of-an-uncanny-bitsy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A glitched out corner, textures too-smooth in some places and too-rough in others. Play some distorted audio, and add some film grain. That’s lo-fi horror, baby, and the lo-fi games that fit this brief can prey on the valley between the uncanny and the unknown. It’s no secret that the unknown is the scariest part of any horror media. Well, aside from that clown with extremely sharp and pointy teeth - but that’s a kind of unknown. Like... Who’s their dentist? Where’d they get that axe? You know what... I take it back. I don’t want to know that one. Let’s get back to those lo-fi videogames.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kat Brewster</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phasmophobia has added a haunted campsite map and new ghosts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/phasmophobia-has-added-a-haunted-campsite-and-new-ghosts</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/phasmophobia-has-added-a-haunted-campsite-and-new-ghosts"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T10:14:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If Halloween is best spent doing scary things with pals, Phasmophobia is one of the best games to play this Halloween. The cooperative game sends us to investigate haunted places, trying to capture evidence of ghosts without getting murdered by them. And now it's even more Halloween-y (well, technically Friday The 13th-y) thanks to a big new early access update, which has added a new map set in a haunted campground, new types of ghost, and new spooky weather. Great, just what I wanted in a game I'm already too scared to play.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve confirm Steam autumn, winter, and Halloween sale dates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-confirm-steam-autumn-winter-and-halloween-sale-dates</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-confirm-steam-autumn-winter-and-halloween-sale-dates"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T09:07:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve can't keep sales secret. Every year, the big dates leak well in advance, whether whispered by devs or blasted by PayPal newsletters. This year, Valve are apparently content to say them in public where anyone might here. Hey, it's just a sale, why the secrecy? So yup, we now definitely know dates for the Steam Halloween Sale, the Steam Autumn Sale, and the Steam Winter Sale.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best LAPA loadout in Warzone Season 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-lapa-loadout-warzone</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-lapa-loadout-warzone"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T08:36:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best LAPA loadout in Warzone Season 6? Treyarch and Raven Software are sending Cold War out with a bang, adding a series of unusual, interesting weapons in the final seasons. The LAPA SMG is the latest, and one of the most intriguing yet. Several of its barrel attachments alter the LAPA’s damage and fire rate. That variety makes the LAPA a very fun gun to customize and play around with. Of course, there is always a best configuration. Once you’ve had your fun and are ready to sweat, we’re here to help.

The LAPA’s range isn’t great, but up close it has monstrous potential. Its high neck and head multipliers make for a skill-dependant weapon, but in the right hands, with the right build, the LAPA fries. Here’s our build of choice:

As usual, we’re starting off with an Agency Suppressor. Added range and bullet velocity on a suppressor remain nigh-impossible to pass up. As long as you’re using a Cold War weapon, you’ll want this attachment. Things get interesting with the barrel. We’ve gone with the Rifled Barrel, which provides the most consistent damage profile. The LAPA very much relies on chest, neck, and headshots, but the Rifled Barrel helps even out the damage to the stomach and limbs. All of the barrels are frankly pretty close in power though, so try a few and see what feels right.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knot DNS: správa zóny a zónové soubory]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15730</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/knot-dns-sprava-zony-a-zonove-soubory/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V předchozím díle jsme si vytvořili jednoduchou zónu ve formě zónového souboru a dnes si povíme, jak s takovým souborem pracovat. Jedná se o nejčastější uživatelskou operaci a je užitečné jí porozumět.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Daniel Salzman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operace s daty uloženými v binárních souborech v knihovnách NumPy a Pandas]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15731</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/operace-s-daty-ulozenymi-v-binarnich-souborech-v-knihovnach-numpy-a-pandas/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poměrně často se můžeme setkat s požadavkem analýzy dat uložených v binárních souborech. S těmito soubory dokáže do určité míry pracovat jak knihovna NumPy, tak i knihovna Pandas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moonglow Bay review: a relaxing fishing RPG that's all about keeping it reel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonglow-bay-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonglow-bay-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything in the seaside town of Moonglow Bay has seen better days. That includes you, a middle-aged accountant who’s moved out of the big city for a fresh start. But things never go quite to plan, do they? The moment-to-moment of Moonglow Bay is a chilled-out experience of getting out onto the waves, exploring various biomes, catching fish, and cooking them up to sell or gift to the townspeople. But within that is an exploration of things going awry, and letting go of old dreams in order to build new ones.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Please, stop with all the godawful emails about NFT gaming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-stop-with-all-the-godawful-emails-about-nft-gaming</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-stop-with-all-the-godawful-emails-about-nft-gaming"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T16:21:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It started a few months ago: we got an email about shoes designed using 'blockchain technology', and had a good laugh about it as a concept. But in retrospect, this email was merely the ripple on a glass of water that go ahead of a T-Rex's mighty tread. Except in this analogy the T-Rex is one of 10,001 unique dinosaurs programatically generated from different traits. And it's wearing wacky sunglasses and smoking a pipe.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No More Heroes developers Grasshopper bought by NetEase]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-more-heroes-developers-grasshopper-bought-by-netease</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-more-heroes-developers-grasshopper-bought-by-netease"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T14:36:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese publishers NetEase have bought Grasshopper Manufacture, the Japanese studio behind stylish, swaggering games including No More Heroes, The Silver Case, and Killer7. While NetEase have roots in mobile games, they have been investing in fancier things. Grasshopper say that with NetEase's cash, they plan to release "three even higher-quality 'Grasshopper Manufacture Games'" over the next decade.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite campaign trailer shows big levels with bases to capture]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-campaign-trailer-shows-big-levels-with-bases-to-capture</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-campaign-trailer-shows-big-levels-with-bases-to-capture"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T13:51:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After focusing a lot of attention on Halo Infinite's multiplayer, Microsoft have turned back to showing off the story campaign. Today's new campaign trailer, sadly, did not give us another hot WWE promo from a space-ape but it did kinda have Far Cry-ish vibes. Watch on for Master Chef zooming around big levels in vehicles, causing big explosions, upgrading his abilities, and bantering with his new Tamagotchi girlfriend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy review: a blast from the past]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a video game landscape that's pocked with millions of map markers and vast open worlds, Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy is a linear action adventure game with a clear beginning, middle and an end. It's an approach that feels refreshingly old-school, in the way it guides you smoothly from one story bit to another. But this doesn't mean it's one big flatline without any peaks, troughs, or surprises.
If anything, the game as a whole is a wonderful surprise. Planet-hopping as Star Lord is great fun, made even better by his colourful compatriots and the genuinely funny craic they share. Marvel fan or clueless layman? Doesn't matter, you're in for a good time no matter where you sit on the MCU scale.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Halloween on RPS! Have a load of horror-themed writing to celebrate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/happy-halloween-on-rps-have-a-load-of-horror-themed-writing-to-celebrate</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/happy-halloween-on-rps-have-a-load-of-horror-themed-writing-to-celebrate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:39:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Halloween comes but once per year, and it's nearly over already! But here on RPS we celebrated the reason for the season (i.e. horror things; scary stuff; being scared, you know) in style. We had a whole host of spooky themed articles this year, and what a troupe of little devils they are to behold!
Whether you're staying in for a quiet one, pelting fun-size chocolate bars from your upstairs window at the neighbour children with vicious force, or you're having a heavy weekend and will need to recover come Sunday morning, have a look at the Halloween 2021 for some dark delights. Or read on in this article!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch's McCree will be renamed Cole Cassidy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatchs-mccree-will-be-renamed-cole-cassidy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatchs-mccree-will-be-renamed-cole-cassidy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:10:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard have announced that Overwatch's McCree will be known as Cole Cassidy going forward. They're renaming the cowboy to distance him from his real-life namesake, former Blizzard employee Jesse McCree. He left the developer due to unknown reasons in August, but his departure came after the State of California filed a lawsuit against Activision Blizzard, alleging the company fostered a "frat boy" culture of sexual harassment and discrimination. The name change will take effect in-game tomorrow.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Beatrix Potter and a fear of open water inspired the surreal, Limbo-like horror puzzler Silt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-beatrix-potter-and-a-fear-of-open-water-inspired-the-surreal-limbo-like-horror-puzzler-silt</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-beatrix-potter-and-a-fear-of-open-water-inspired-the-surreal-limbo-like-horror-puzzler-silt"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["I have a phobia of animal suits, and I have done my entire life," says surreal artist and Spiral Circus' co-founder Tom Mead. I'm listening to him talk about the making of his latest game, Silt, at EGX 2021. First announced at the PC Gaming Show earlier in the year, Silt is a surreal 2D puzzle game in which you play a mysterious diver who can project their soul through the window of their diving helmet to possess nearby fish. Piranhas can chomp through chains and ropes, for example, while hammerhead sharks can help bash crumbling walls to create new pathways. Hand drawn by Mead using a simplified version of his signature cross hatching and fineliner penmanship, Silt instantly calls to mind the likes of Limbo and Inside. And yet the origins of this strange, watery tale stem from a far more innocuous source of inspiration. 
"The main influence to any of my work is good old Beatrix Potter, believe it or not," Mead continues. "I blame my mum entirely because she made me and my sister watch this horrible ballet when I was a kid, and I still haven't watched it since then. Over the years, though, I realised that this was one of my main things that fuelled my characters, and the fox man character, I started drawing him and he became my main character for years."
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age Of Empires 4 review: a confident and moreish strategy epic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/age-of-empires-4-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/age-of-empires-4-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T07:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's tempting to bang on about the history of Age Of Empires, but let's be real here, you already know it well enough. Even if you haven't played them, the Age Of Empires games were a pillar of RTS design, and probably the most popular candidate for a comeback since publishers largely abandoned the genre in the 2000s.
Let's not argue about which of its elements is the defining one. They're base building, four-resource-gathering contests between factions based on historical world powers, and progress throughout a match happens in explicitly tiered eras that loosely represent historical ages. Age Of Empires 4 has all of that, across four 9-mission single player campaigns, 17 skirmish maps (which can be slightly modified with seed numbers, and we're told more map options are coming), and 8 playable, well-differentiated and slightly unequal civilisations. And I kinda like it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slope Hypothesis Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2533/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2533/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Organizace letos vynaloží na technologie podporující budoucnost práce 656 miliard dolarů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-organizace-letos-vynalozi-na-technologie-podporujici-budoucnost-prace-656-miliard-dolaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-organizace-letos-vynalozi-na-technologie-podporujici-budoucnost-prace-656-miliard-dolaru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat novými aktualizacemi podporuje edge computing. Organizace letos vynaloží na technologie podporující budoucnost práce 656 miliard dolarů. HPE GreenLake přináší inovativní architekturu správy dat. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (2) Nedostatek dílů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-615</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-615"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for nearly having a heart attack when the toaster pops. Before you jolt awake, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-166</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-166"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I ate my first mince pie this week, which feels like a betrayal of my belief that Christmastime should not start before Halloween is over. That said, it wasn't a mince puff, so does it really count? Please, tell me about your festive eating. And may as well mention what you're playing this weekend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CD Projekt have bought the studio behind The Flame In The Flood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-have-bought-the-studio-behind-the-flame-in-the-flood</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-have-bought-the-studio-behind-the-flame-in-the-flood"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T16:35:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk and Witcher crew CD Projekt have acquired The Molasses Flood, the American studio behind post-apocalyptic raft ride The Flame In The Flood and base-building game Drake Hollow. Huh! The studio will be making a game set in one of CD Projekt's worlds, which warrants a second: huh! It's all secret for now.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My hunger for games like Warcraft 2 is slowly being sated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-hunger-for-games-like-warcraft-2-is-slowly-being-sated</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-hunger-for-games-like-warcraft-2-is-slowly-being-sated"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:38:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I think back to the games of my childhood, nothing puts a warm, fuzzy smile on my face like Warcraft 2. As one of the few PC games I had growing up, I ended up playing the campaign over and over again - or at least starting it over and over again - for what felt like actual years. I loved building up my fort and endlessly poking the peasants and peons until they shouted back at me in annoyance, and man alive, there is nothing sweeter than ordering a tooled-up army across the map and absolutely wrecking the enemy in one fell swoop of doom and destruction. 
It is something I wish I could play again now with all my heart. I know there's version of it on GOG, but I'd also just quite like, you know, a newer, shinier version with a more up to date UI and all that jazz, and one whose map didn't whizz over to the other side of the screen with a single tap of the arrow key. I'd also like a version that isn't, somehow, made by Activision Blizzard because... *gestures to all their ongoing harassment lawsuits*. Fortunately, I've happened upon a couple of games in recent weeks that have really scratched that old Warcraft 2 itch of mine. I've already written about one of them - Diplomacy Is Not An Option - and the other is Age Of Darkness: Final Stand, a game with the most boring name imaginable, but is secretly very good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to uninstall Windows 11 and go back to Windows 10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-uninstall-windows-11-and-go-back-to-windows-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-uninstall-windows-11-and-go-back-to-windows-10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:33:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Change isn’t for everyone: just ask the 5% of Steam Hardware Survey respondents still using Windows 7. Sadly, even the most eager of early adopters might be looking to find out how to uninstall Windows 11, the very latest of Microsoft’s operating systems. It could be the newly centralised Start menu; it could be the lack of DirectStorage support among games making the best SSDs perform below their full capability; it could just be a single unsquished bug, which remains a risk with the infant OS. Fortunately, if you decide to want to switch back to Windows 10 within 10 days of installing its successor, it’s possible to roll back in just a few, mildly regretful clicks.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to upgrade to Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-11"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:32:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, fine, here’s how to upgrade to Windows 11 from Windows 10. The current stance of this hardware ed is that Windows 11 has some cool features but is yet to fulfil its potential, largely owing to the missing DirectStorage capability – which, to be fair, could be a very big deal when games start supporting it. For now, then, it’s a free but absolutely not an essential upgrade, and you can think of this post as the RPS equivalent of that video where Valve tore down a Steam Deck: we’re not saying you should do this, just that you can do this. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Truck Simulator now supports mods in multiplayer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/truck-simulator-now-supports-mods-in-multiplayer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/truck-simulator-now-supports-mods-in-multiplayer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T14:06:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After adding official multiplayer modes to American Truck Simulator and Euro Truck Simulator 2, developers SCS Software have now made both support mods in multiplayer too. They're games many truckers mod with the trucks and decor of their dreams, so it'll be nice to show everyone your true truck self. I'd call this your drivatar but Forza has already claimed that.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto remastered trilogy's first trailer looks shiny yet cartoony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-remastered-trilogys-first-trailer-looks-shiny-yet-cartoony</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-remastered-trilogys-first-trailer-looks-shiny-yet-cartoony"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:32:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a stretch of teasing and leaking, Rockstar today revealed how they've renovated the GTA 3 trilogy for the upcoming horribly named collection, Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition. A new trailer and screenshots reveal that GTA 3, Vice City, and San Andreas still have distinctly cartoon vibes, now paired with fancy reflections and effects. Rockstar also announced a release date of November 11th and a price of... £55? Gosh. See the new look for yourself in the trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doom Eternal's Horde mode arrives next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-eternals-horde-mode-arrives-next-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-eternals-horde-mode-arrives-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday the 26th of October, Doom Eternal players will be able to rip and tear through the hellish shooter's new horde mode. If you're not quite satisfied with murdering demons in a linear fashion, you'll be able to jump into a match to fight off waves of the beasties instead. It's arriving in the game's 6.66 update, along with two new master levels and Battlemode 2.0.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite will let you host a cross-platform LAN party on a PC dedicated server]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-let-you-host-a-cross-platform-lan-party-on-a-pc-dedicated-server</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-let-you-host-a-cross-platform-lan-party-on-a-pc-dedicated-server"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:25:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After decades of Halo being primarily an Xbox series [settle down, disgruntled elderly Mac fanatics -ed.], Halo Infinite will buck that with a simultaneous launch on PC too. With that December launch drawing near, a new trailer focuses on the PC edition, detailing various graphics settings and multiplayer options and noting the interesting detail that you'll be able to use a PC to host a dedicated server for a cross-platform LAN party. Watch on for lots of shots of scrolling through options menus.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World character transfers paused due to gold duping glitch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-character-transfers-paused-due-to-gold-duping-glitch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-character-transfers-paused-due-to-gold-duping-glitch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World's long-awaited character transfers have been taken away almost as soon as they arrived, because they've caused a glitch that allows players to duplicate gold. The bug came about after the MMORPG's 1.0.3 update this week. It makes it so characters don't save properly after transferring, letting them trade gold and items to others while magically keeping it in their own pockets. Amazon have paused server transfers for the time being to work on a fix, and have warned players that those caught exploiting the glitch will be banned.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Psychonauts 2 turns the mind inside out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-psychonauts-2-turns-the-mind-inside-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-psychonauts-2-turns-the-mind-inside-out"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“It’s all in your head.” It’s a response that encapsulates all the condescension and ignorance surrounding mental health issues. And yet, in a way, it’s true. Subjective experience is an objective reality – that just so happens to be located and locked away in your head. 
These individual realities can only be conveyed through language and other subjective means of communication, and more and more games are grasping this fact, turning inward to explore and map the inland empires of the mind. They have all the tools of the medium at their disposal to turn the invisible workings of the mind into landscapes of audio-visual and mechanical metaphors that can be explored and interacted with. At their best, they convey the dynamic and complex mechanisms of the psyche in a way that only this medium can.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022's early access beta is available now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022s-early-access-beta-is-available-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022s-early-access-beta-is-available-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T23:22:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022 pre-launch beta is live now. If you buy the kicking sim on Steam or Epic, you can immediately start playing a nearly-finished version of the game. If you're really committed you can probably be sacked at least once before the sun comes up.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Man's Sky's new update lets you ride on flying worms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-new-update-lets-you-ride-on-flying-worms</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-new-update-lets-you-ride-on-flying-worms"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:07:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At this point, it has become a cliché to say that space sim No Man's Sky has come a long way since its initial release. And yet, is there any better example of its long development journey than the sandworms? Initially shown in pre-release trailers only to be cut from the release version, they were finally added in some recent updates. Now the most recent update and seasonal event adds new sandworm varieties, including rideable sandworms. The worm has indeed turned.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence a signály odměn]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problém zpětnovazebného učení u skutečné umělé inteligence. Primordiální černé díry. Záhadné rádiové vlny. Nejchytřejší psi. Drony jako hasiči.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's flagship Virtuoso RGB Wireless XT headset is 26% off in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-flagship-virtuoso-rgb-wireless-xt-headset-is-26-off-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-flagship-virtuoso-rgb-wireless-xt-headset-is-26-off-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's Virtuoso RGB Wireless XT is just as fancy as its long-ass name implies, and today it's £65 off as part of Corsair's autumn sale. That drops the price from £250 to £185, considerably less than even the going price on Amazon of £230. I think this is a great deal if you've got a hefty budget for an all-in-one wireless headset, so let me share a little on why I'm so convinced!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haunted Chocolatier is the Stardew Valley developer's next RPG]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:38:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The developer of Stardew Valley has revealed their next game: Haunted Chocolatier. It's again a game about moving to a new town to "try your hand at a new way of living", but instead of a farm, you're opening a chocolate shop staffed by ghosts. There's an adorable trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a high-spec 1TB NVMe SSD for £139 after a 21% off voucher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-high-spec-1tb-nvme-ssd-for-139-after-a-21-off-voucher</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-high-spec-1tb-nvme-ssd-for-139-after-a-21-off-voucher"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:34:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The XPG S70 Blade is one of the few 'second-gen' PCIe 4.0 SSDs on the market, offering incredible speeds on PC and even full compatibility with PS5. Today the 1TB model is heavily discounted at Amazon UK, with the NVMe drive dropping from £176 all the way to £139. To get the reduced price, tick the box where it says 'Apply 21% voucher'; the reduced price will be visible at the checkout. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 will tweak maps, UI and more in response to beta feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-will-tweak-maps-ui-and-more-in-response-to-beta-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-will-tweak-maps-ui-and-more-in-response-to-beta-feedback"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:11:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 has been and gone, and now its developers have written about what they learned based on player feedback. There are some straight fixes, some explanations, and lot more in a post on the Battlefield blog. 

Also: a look at the five previously unrevealed specialists you'll be able to play as when the game launches.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Uncharted movie finally has a trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-uncharted-movie-finally-has-a-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-uncharted-movie-finally-has-a-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T20:52:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Uncharted series will arrive on PC early next year with Uncharted 4: A Thief's End. That game features a retired Nathan Drake being coaxed into another adventure, but you therefore might want to experience some of the Indylike's earlier treasure hunts first. There is literally only one way I can think of to do that: watching the Uncharted movie, which is also due to release in cinemas early next year.

The first trailer just released, starring Tom Holland and Mark Wahlberg.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer cap RazerCon announcements with first PSU and liquid cooler components]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-cap-razercon-announcements-with-first-psu-and-liquid-cooler-components</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-cap-razercon-announcements-with-first-psu-and-liquid-cooler-components"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T18:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Razer, purveyors of green and black gaming peripherals, have announced they’re having a proper go at PC components as well. The Razer Hanbo AIO liquid CPU cooler series, Razer Katana PSUs, Razer Kunai case fans and Razer Pulse Width Modulator (PWM) Fan Controller all debuted during this year's RazerCon showcase.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dwarf Fortress Steam edition video demonstrates convenience of seeing what's happening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-edition-video-demonstrates-convenience-of-seeing-whats-happening</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-edition-video-demonstrates-convenience-of-seeing-whats-happening"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T16:45:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["You will not believe what the hell just happened in Dwarf Fortress!" my pal will tell me, proceeding to share a screenshot which, to me, is indistinguishable from e.g.:

██,.,,;lz,zl;L:@gjse,.gm.,,.m.zm,.m,x.zm.amL:m3jp5jkmToiHy*
████()ht23htuhqIJg.......UG.uos\kjk:███/,,p,c.xz/,c./z,c;\/.
██'z,c./xz,c./zx,cpaswf/w.qfw.,/f,aa███,g.ew/t,3wq./t,,2..@|
█3/.6t,.esg,f.e/sg,./ewt,./w4t4..,1t6,m42ijpnz\kuiys8fun/.|█
█|?|..../\/\..|@@@%%$|"(((|..FHzFhLlk@A}||||....*|JGH,.3████
zZ./@Z@@'Z'@@LSXCl;a,sl;FLZL;@'A:@,;'F":%T@:H^OQHOh8^£$.\/.█

"That's wild!" I will reply, not wanting to hurt their feelings. But how delightful, then, to watch the latest video from the upcoming premium edition, where co-creator Zach Adams demonstrates defending against a goblin attack and you can actually see it's a goblin attack.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amanita's unhappy Happy Game is coming in time for Halloween]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amanitas-unhappy-happy-game-is-coming-in-time-for-halloween</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amanitas-unhappy-happy-game-is-coming-in-time-for-halloween"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T16:12:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amanita Design are known for their cheery and charming adventure games, wonders like Samorost, Machinarium, Botanicula, and Chuchel. Their next game sounds like it should be their cheeriest yet, given that it's named Happy Game. Reader dear, this is a trick. Happy Game is blood and death and horror. You will see this soon, as Amanita today announced plans to release Happy Game on the 28th of October. Or you can try a demo now!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim will add aquariums in its Anniversary Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrim-will-add-aquariums-in-its-anniversary-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrim-will-add-aquariums-in-its-anniversary-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T15:56:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim: Anniversary Edition comes out next month, and it's quickly becoming the fishiest version of the RPG yet. Bethesda have announced it will let you add aquariums to your Skyrim homes. We already know this edition will let us go fishing too, so I'm hoping we'll be able to yank those suckers straight out of the sea to put on display in our homes. Can't believe I'm going to buy yet another version of Skyrim just to have pet fish.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 161: the best songs special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-161-the-best-songs-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-161-the-best-songs-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It occurs to me now that "best songs" is probably not a great topic for the podcast, given that we do not perform any of the songs, or put them in the show. But on this week's episode of The Electronic Wireless show, we talk about them songs real good. Plus, we are joined by Randy Newman, who sounds a surprising amount like Matthew Castle.
Matthew himself has a new awkward food related story to share, Nate has been watching Squid Game, and a listener has sent in a very special musical theme for Sweeten The Deal!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podzimní smršť novinek od Aceru. SentinelOne v ČR nabere 300 lidí a investuje miliardu. Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci. Dodávky a ceny osobních počítačů z pohledu výrobce. VMworld: Zabezpečení na principu nulové důvěry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence v kooperativních hrách]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový typ magnetismu nezpůsobují spiny. Beethovenovu slavnou 10. symfonii dokončila umělá inteligence  Studium neuronových sítí může pomoci při zkoumání toho, jak se do mozku ukládají konspirační teorie. Minirobot se pohybuje díky gradientům teploty. Splynutí obřích černých děr provázejí nejen gravitační vlny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 41/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>