<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-10-19T12:23:58.665Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-19T12:23:58.665Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck Verified: hodnocení bezproblémovosti chodu her]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42921</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/steam-deck-verified-hodnoceni-bezproblemovosti-chodu-her/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T11:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve v rámci zkonzolovatění Linuxu na Decku spustilo hodnocení her, jak zákazníkům na Decku poběží. Hodnocení zahrnuje následující varianty:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Smrž)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new character is a familiar face from Titanfall 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-character-is-a-familiar-face-from-titanfall-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-character-is-a-familiar-face-from-titanfall-2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T11:17:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends is adding a second spooky murderbot to its roster, one that both Apex and Titanfall 2 fans might recognise. Ash is a simulacrum (human consciousness in a freaky robot) who was previously a baddie in Titanfall 2. Since May this year, she's been overseeing Apex's new 3v3 Arenas mode - you know, that ominous voice that tells you to crush your enemies. But in the battle royale's next season, Escape, she'll be joining the fight herself.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nascar Heat Ultimate Edition+ Speeds Onto Switch Next Month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122480</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/nascar-heat-ultimate-editionplus-speeds-onto-switch-next-month"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With 39 tracks and online play supported.
Motorsports Games has announced that Nascar Heat Ultimate Edition+ will be speeding onto a Switch near you next month, bringing the series to Nintendo's hybrid platform for the first time.
This is the official video game of the 2020 season, with all the 2020 official teams, drivers, cars and schedule from the three Nascar National Series present and correct. It also features the Xtreme Dirt Tour, with 39 tracks being included in the game in total.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple představil nové MacBooky Pro s novými vlastními čipy M1 Pro a M1 Max]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/apple-predstavil-nove-macbooky-pro-s-novymi-vlastnimi-cipy-m1-pro-a-m1-max</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/apple-predstavil-nove-macbooky-pro-s-novymi-vlastnimi-cipy-m1-pro-a-m1-max"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:52:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple představil nové MacBooky Pro s  novými vlastními čipy M1 Pro a M1 Max. Nejvýkonnější M1 Max má na sobě 10 CPU jader a 32 GPU jader. Vývojáři Asahi Linuxu si díky podpoře na Patreonu nové MacBooky Pro již objednali.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact's Latest Update Shows MiHoYo's Deep Respect For Japanese Culture]]></title>
        <id>1847890519</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/genshin-impacts-latest-update-shows-mihoyos-respect-for-1847890519"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact’s Inazuma region is based on Japan. The country’s culture can be incredibly complex, and whether that’s sakura or swords, it’s easy to not get things quite right. MiHoYo’s decision to push through a subtle fix underscoring those nuances is impressing Japanese players. 
Before the update, the NPC…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sakurai Celebrates Super Smash Bros. Ultimate's Complete Roster With DLC Screenshots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122474</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/sakurai-celebrates-super-smash-bros-ultimates-complete-roster-with-dlc-screenshots"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone is here.
Well, that's it. Super Smash Bros. UItimate's enormous roster is finally complete with Kingdom Hearts' Sora officially joining the ranks.
It's been one heck of a ride with regular character additions, Direct appearances, and wild speculation fueling hype for the game ever since its launch in 2018. All good things must come to an end, though, and Ultimate is now all done and dusted.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm sorry to say it New World, but you need mounts, mate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-to-say-it-new-world-but-you-need-mounts-mate</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-to-say-it-new-world-but-you-need-mounts-mate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My heart sinks every time I accept a quest in MMORPG New World, which isn't ideal. These are tickets to adventure, to discovery, to that sweet, sweet EXP. But the more time I spend with the game, the more I'm beginning to loathe them. It's got nothing to do with what you actually do in them, it's the getting there that's the problem. I have to run my little legs ragged and I'm tired. I'm so very tired of it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ActRaiser Renaissance review: raise one for a great remake of a 16-bit classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actraiser-renaissance-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actraiser-renaissance-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[1990's ActRaiser is special. Most video games released in the late '80s tasked you with saving a princess from a dragon. ActRaiser says, “Hey, would you mind playing God with the people living on the demon-scarred land you just liberated? They're really squishy and helpless. Thanks, you’re a peach."
The game's developer, Quintet, was pretty special, too. Once a branch of Enix before the latter joined with Squaresoft in 2003, Quintet was behind a lot of SNES-era RPGs that are still fondly remembered today, such Illusion of Gaia and Terranigma. They’re all solid adventures that share a canon, albeit vaguely, and tackle some pretty heavy subject matter, including colonialism, poverty, and the slave trade. Alas, Quintet disbanded when Square Enix was born, and most of its team scattered to the winds. There’s been a Q-shaped hole in my heart ever since, so I hope I can be excused for yelling like a madwoman when ActRaiser Renaissance made a surprise debut at the September 2021 Nintendo Direct presentation.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Oxford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Developing "SiliFuzz" For Fuzzing CPUs To Uncover Electrical Defects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-SiliFuzz-CPU-Defects</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-SiliFuzz-CPU-Defects"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:50:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With OSS-Fuzz for continuous fuzzing of open-source projects and along with working on the various sanitizers for compilers, Google has been doing a lot for proactively uncovering software defects in key open-source projects. Now though a group of their engineers have been working on SiliFuzz for software aiming to discover new CPU defects...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Build HAT]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-build-hat</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-build-hat"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:44:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rodina produktů Raspberry Pi se rozrostla o rozšiřující desku Raspberry Pi Build HAT umožňující propojit Raspberry Pi s motory a senzory LEGO Technic z portfolia LEGO Education SPIKE. Současně byl představen 48W napájecí zdroj pro Raspberry Pi Build HAT a knihovna pro Python Build HAT.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RPS Asks: you to please take our 2021 readership survey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-you-to-please-take-our-2021-readership-survey</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-you-to-please-take-our-2021-readership-survey"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:40:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's that time of year again where we come to you with a single question: would you fill out our RPS Readership Survey, please? It should only take around 5-10 minutes of your time to complete, and it will be a big help to us going forward - particularly when it comes to shaping the future of the RPS supporter program.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Unite Producer Discusses The Game's Unexpected Character Roster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122470</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/pokemon-unite-producer-discusses-the-games-unexpected-character-roster"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who's your favourite?
While its initial reception was rather lukewarm (and that's putting it nicely), Pokémon Unite has been winning over fans ever since its launch back in July. For hardcore fans of the series, one of its plus points is the character roster, which includes some unusual, and therefore welcome, selections.
While some fan-favourites like Pikachu and Charizard are in there, the roster includes a nice mix of characters you wouldn't necessarily expect like Cramorant, Crustle, Eldegoss, and Absol – all fine Pokémon, but ones that wouldn't usually get a spot in the limelight.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Childe build (Tartaglia)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-childe-build-tartaglia</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-childe-build-tartaglia"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:06:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Childe build in Genshin Impact? Thanks to his unique ability set that enables both close-range and long-range combat, Hydro Bow user Childe (also known as Tartaglia) is especially powerful in almost any situation and is great as a main or sub DPS. As the 11th Harbinger of the Fatui, he’s an incredibly fierce warrior who also cares deeply for those he loves.
This guide will show you how to create the best Childe build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Childe, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Enables NGG Shader Culling For Navi 1x Consumer GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-NGG-Culling-Navi-1x</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-NGG-Culling-Navi-1x"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As another possible performance win for RadeonSI Gallium3D as AMD's open-source Radeon OpenGL driver on Linux systems is enabling of NGG culling for Navi 1x consumer graphics processors rather than limiting it only to newer Navi 2x (RDNA2) GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early Progress Made On Porting Radeon Vulkan Driver To BeOS-Inspired Haiku OS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Port-WIP-For-Haiku</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Port-WIP-For-Haiku"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After successfully getting Mesa's software-based Lavapipe Vulkan implementation building on Haiku last month along with related Mesa code for headless support, a developer independent of AMD has started work on porting the Mesa Radeon Vulkan driver "RADV" to Haiku...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Forget Dread, It's All About Metroid: Other M On Twitter Right Now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122466</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/random-forget-dread-its-all-about-metroid-other-m-on-twitter-right-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fans are "defending" the Wii entry for all sorts of reasons.
Metroid Dread might have just been released for the Nintendo Switch (and it's outstanding by the way), but over on social media, the conversation is all about Team Ninja's 2010 Wii title, Metroid: Other M. While it was mostly well-received back then, as time went on it's fallen out of favour.
So, what's all the fuss about now? While many have been talking about MercurySteam's latest release, it seems an offshoot of this is about whether or not 'Other M' was a blight on the Metroid series' history. A lot of Metroid fans are apparently "defending" the title, while others still don't really like it. Here's a round-up of just some of the many responses to this topic, which has now generated more than 80k Tweets.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smash Bros. Ultimate's Final DLC Fighter Has Arrived - Sora From Kingdom Hearts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122465</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/smash-bros-ultimates-final-dlc-fighter-has-arrived-sora-from-kingdom-hearts"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone is here, at last!

Well, the day has finally arrived - the fighter roster for Super Smash Bros. Ultimate is officially complete. Today's update (Version 13.0.0) sees the arrival of the last DLC fighter - the Kingdom Hearts' representative, Sora.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Smash Bros. Ultimate Version 13.0.0 Is Now Live, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122464</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/super-smash-bros-ultimate-version-13-0-0-is-now-live-here-are-the-full-patch-notes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T01:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sora joins the battle as the final DLC fighter.
Nintendo has released Version 13.0.0 of Super Smash Bros. Ultimate. This update adds in Sora from Kingdom Hearts as paid DLC. Sora comes with his very own stage - Hollow's Bastion - and there are a total of nine Kingdom Hearts songs included.
There are also new spirits and new Mii Outfits which can be purchased from the eShop. Last but not least are some game balance adjustments, fighter adjustments and fixes to improve the overall gameplay experience. Below are the full patch notes, courtesy of Nintendo's official support page:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh No Oh No]]></title>
        <id>1847889302</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/oh-no-oh-no-1847889302"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vii Wong is an artist based in China.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analogue Pocket Is Getting Its Own OS - Allowing Users To Explore, Discover And Preserve Video Game History]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122463</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/analogue-pocket-is-getting-its-own-os-allowing-users-to-explore-discover-and-preserve-video-game-history"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's all for the love of video games".

The creators of the Analogue Pocket - a portable FPGA-based device compatible with the entire Game library and other systems via adapters - have announced Analogue OS.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$440 Super Mario Bros. x One Piece Crossover Has Wonderful Hair]]></title>
        <id>1847888860</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/440-super-mario-bros-x-one-piece-crossover-has-wonder-1847888860"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T00:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Custom toy company Fat Lane Toys have made this new statue that takes Mario and wonders, like maybe six other people on Earth have maybe ever wondered, what he’d look like if he was also Gold Roger from One Piece.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arcade Archives Publisher Hamster Has Filed A Trademark For 'Console Archives']]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122462</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/arcade-archives-publisher-hamster-has-filed-a-trademark-for-console-archives"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T23:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is even more retro goodness on the way?
Hamster Corporation has been pumping out enhanced arcade releases since the Nintendo Switch arrived on the scene in 2017, but it might finally be time for it to take the next big step in retro preservation.
According to a story over on Gematsu, the Japanese company filed a trademark for "Console Archives" in English and Japanese earlier this month on October 6th. While it's probably best not to get too excited, it seems like there's a real possibility it could be planning to re-release older console titles.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead By Daylight Is Selling Some Bullshit Hellraiser NFTs]]></title>
        <id>1847888652</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/dead-by-daylight-is-selling-some-stupid-hellraiser-nfts-1847888652"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T23:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s the spooky season! And nothing says true horror like a popular video game deciding that now, despite everything we  know and has come to pass, is the time to sell some NFTs.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing Fans Are Playing Again After Months Of Hopelessness]]></title>
        <id>1847888537</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-fans-are-playing-again-after-months-of-1847888537"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a hot minute since Animal Crossing: New Horizons received an update, with the last one, the Super Mario 35th Anniversary Event, launching way back in March 2021. But that’s about to change now that Nintendo’s announced the Happy Home Paradise DLC dropping on November 5. This paid DLC is so big, in fact, that…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's New Rating System Shows Which Games Play Best On Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>1847888425</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/valves-new-rating-system-shows-which-games-play-best-on-1847888425"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gaming on-the-go has gotten a lot of much-needed attention lately with not only the Nintendo Switch and the shiny new Nintendo Switch - OLED Model, but with the highly anticipated Steam Deck as well. The upcoming portable gaming PC enables players to take at least a decent chunk of their Steam libraries on the move,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CZ.NIC zkušebně vypne tunelovací technologie Teredo a 6to4 pro IPv6]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15717</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/cz-nic-zkusebne-vypne-tunelovaci-technologie-teredo-a-6to4-pro-ipv6/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CZ.NIC se rozhodl, že obě IPv6 tunelovací technologie na zkoušku vypne 25. října 2021 na dobu 24 hodin. Pokud se nestane nic neočekávaného, budou servery definitivně vypnuty už 1. listopadu 2021. Proč k tomu dojde?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Václav Steiner)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic-256: další moderní reinkarnace BASICu určená pro výuku programování]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15718</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/basic-256-dalsi-moderni-reinkarnace-basicu-urcena-pro-vyuku-programovani/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prozatím poslední moderní reinkarnací programovacího jazyka BASIC, s níž se seznámíme, je Basic-256. Opět se jedná o jazyk (a vývojové prostředí) určené primárně pro výuku programování, které navíc podporuje i práci s grafikou.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple představil až 10jádrová SoC M1 Pro a M1 Max]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42920</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/apple-predstavil-az-10jadrova-soc-m1-pro-a-m1-max/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dva nové čipy pro své počítače představil Apple v souvislosti s novými Macbooky Pro. Firma navyšuje počet CPU i GPU jader a hovoří až o 70 % vyšším CPU výkonu oproti M1 a o 2× rychlejším GPU v M1 Pro, resp. 4× rychlejším v M1 Max. Jinými slovy: už tak rychlé a úsporné řešení jménem Apple M1 v nových Macboocích Pro bude značně rychlejší a nikdo nemůže ani vzdáleně hovořit o tom, že by bylo (z hlediska výkonu) lepší, kdyby s Apple vrátil k Intelu (což je mimochodem plán Pata Gelsingera).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dune Is The Latest Beloved Property To Be Swallowed By The Fortnite Worm]]></title>
        <id>1847887636</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/dune-is-the-latest-beloved-property-to-be-swallowed-by-1847887636"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T21:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the latest movie adaptation’s release this weekend, Dune content has been discovered in Fortnite. How wonderful it is to see one of my favorite books and least favorite game come together for an awkward bit of brand synergy.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Things I Wish I Knew Before Starting Back 4 Blood]]></title>
        <id>1847887557</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/13-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-starting-back-4-blood-1847887557"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T20:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At first glance, Back 4 Blood might seem like a paint-by-numbers co-op shooter whose lineage traces back to Left 4 Dead. You might think you know the drill: point, shoot, pick up weapon, point, shoot again. Make it to the end of the level. Try not to die. But there’s a deceptive layer of complexity in this zombie…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[11 Things You Might Have Missed From The Animal Crossing: New Horizons Nintendo Direct]]></title>
        <id>1847886735</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/11-things-you-might-have-missed-from-the-animal-crossin-1847886735"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week’s Animal Crossing: New Horizons’ Nintendo Direct was an avalanche of info about new items, gameplay, and characters coming to the game in both its free update and paid Happy Home Paradise DLC on November 5. Read on for some neat little details about everything that’s coming that you might not have noticed…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 LTS "Jammy Jellyfish" Begins Development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.04-LTS-Development</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.04-LTS-Development"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T20:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical today formally opened the "Jammy" archive for development for what will be the next version of Ubuntu, 22.04 LTS "Jammy Jellyfish"...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell's 1440p 240Hz Alienware monitor is back to £550]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dells-1440p-240hz-alienware-monitor-is-back-to-550</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dells-1440p-240hz-alienware-monitor-is-back-to-550"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T19:58:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Dell Alienware AW2721D is one of our top recommended monitors, sitting right in the emerging 1440p 240Hz sweet spot preferred by players of fast-paced shooters and racing titles. Right now, the monitor has returned to the lowest price we've ever seen for it, £550, down from a nominal RRP of over £800. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal Crossing Fans Are Deeply In Love With Wardell The Manatee]]></title>
        <id>1847886641</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/animal-crossing-fans-are-deeply-in-love-with-wardell-th-1847886641"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T19:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between the upcoming massive free update and the paid Happy Home Paradise downloadable content, Nintendo announced a whole lot of stuff for Animal Crossing: New Horizons last Friday. But none of those announcements, even the return of the fabled froggy chair, are as important as our new friend Wardell the Manatee.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looks Like Dune's Coming To Fortnite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122459</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/looks-like-dunes-coming-to-fortnite"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh, worm?
Fortnite has never shied away from representing big brands in its games, so it comes as no surprise that the latest addition to the metaverse is Dune. The upcoming movie, starring Timothée Chalamet as Paul Atreides and Zendaya as Chani, has now been Fortnite-ified, according to a leak on Twitter from HYPEX:
The Zendaya model looks pretty faithful to her real-life counterpart in these higher definition screenshots:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Announces The M1 Pro / M1 Max, Asahi Linux Starts Eyeing Their Bring-Up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-Pro-M1-Max</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-Pro-M1-Max"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple today announced the M1 Pro and M1 Max as their most powerful SoCs ever built by the company. The new chips feature up to a 10-core processor, 32-core GPU, and up to 64GB of unified memory...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve Launches "Steam Deck Verified" Program For Games That Run Well On The Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Deck-Verified</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Deck-Verified"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:15:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve is introducing a Steam Deck Verified system for helping gamers find out what games have been verified to work well on their forthcoming AMD+Linux-powered handheld game console...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Here's how you'll know which games will run on Valve's Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve have always maintained that the Steam Deck is closer to a conventional PC than a handheld console, and as such should be able to run your existing library of games on Steam. But while the official Steam Deck Twitter is full of videos showing games performing well on dev kits, the compatibility status of many more games remains up in the air. That could just be through a lack of confirmation, or it could be deep-lying technical issues relating to hardware requirements or anti-cheat services that needed tweaks to work on the Deck’s Proton-based OS. Ahead of the planned December launch, Valve have unveiled their plan to bring clarity on whether specific games will be able to run (and run effectively) on the Steam Deck.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blue Box Studios Asks Gamers To Stop Sending Death Threats, Please]]></title>
        <id>1847885646</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/blue-box-studios-asks-gamers-to-stop-sending-death-thre-1847885646"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last few months, gamers have theorized that Blue Box Game Studios and its upcoming horror game Abandoned are somehow connected to or directly affiliated with Metal Gear creator Hideo Kojima and or Konami, the publisher behind Silent Hill and MGS. And even though the studio has directly addressed these claims…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a WD Blue 4TB SSD for just $339 at Newegg - $50 off its normal price]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wd-blue-4tb-ssd-for-just-339-at-newegg-50-off-its-normal-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wd-blue-4tb-ssd-for-just-339-at-newegg-50-off-its-normal-price"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T17:20:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Blue SATA SSD is a great choice if you want a lot of fast storage at a cheap price, and today Newegg are offering $50 off the giant 4TB size when you use the code EMC2AAZA827. This knocks the price to $339, the cheapest we've seen a 4TB drive in some time and $40 below the current Amazon price. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Ends Switch's Three-Year Run As Best-Selling Console]]></title>
        <id>1847885112</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-5-ends-switchs-three-year-run-as-best-selli-1847885112"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After almost three years as the top-selling console in the U.S., the Nintendo Switch has been ousted by Sony’s PlayStation 5. According to Mat Piscatella, an NPD analyst, the PS5 was the best-selling gaming hardware platform in both units sold and overall dollars earned in September 2021. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poll: As Sora Joins Smash Bros. Ultimate, How Much Of The DLC Roster Do You Own?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122437</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/poll-as-sora-joins-smash-bros-ultimate-how-much-of-the-dlc-roster-do-you-own"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA['None' is an ok answer, no judgement here...
After the frenzy around the final character reveal for Super Smash Bros. Ultimate, we're now in the home stretch before Sora drops and concludes the DLC and updates for the iconic platform fighter. It's a big deal for those that have devoted a lot of time and, indeed, money to the game, while for the rest it's a bit of a toss up as to whether or not to drop money on the Kingdom Hearts hero.
As one perspective, this scribe played the game a lot in the first 3-4 months after release, but fell away as online play could sometimes be rather laggy and, probably the bigger reason, most players were too good. Practice makes perfect, yes — git gud and all that — but after a few dozen hours and a lot of fun it was time to play other games. It was a great purchase and is a nice part of the collection, but there's been no personal motivation to go back even as the multiple fighter passes and additions have rolled in.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton 2.5]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/vkd3d-proton-2.5</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/vkd3d-proton-2.5"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:33:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton byl vydán ve verzi 2.5. Jedná se fork knihovny vkd3d z projektu Wine pro Proton. Knihovna slouží pro překlad volání Direct3D 12 na Vulkan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rampaging Link Fights A Lynel, Guardian, And Hynox At Once In BotW]]></title>
        <id>1847884826</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/botws-favorite-twink-fights-lynel-guardian-hynox-at-o-1847884826"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wanted to see a young, blonde twink have a no-good, very bad day? Then boy do I have the game and video for you, as someone has managed to get Link to fight a Hynox, Lynel, and multiple Guardians, at the same time in Breath of the Wild. This, to me, sounds like a terribly stressful day given the fact…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot Wheels Unleashed Goes Big On Batman And DC DLC This Winter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122447</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/hot-wheels-unleashed-goes-big-on-batman-and-dc-dlc-this-winter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Joker-themed environment ain't no joke.
Hot Wheels Unleashed earned itself a bit of buzz online when it launched at the end of September, and even with a nod to its heavy paid-DLC focus post-launch we rather liked it in our review. As previously outlined in its roadmap there's a lot of DLC planned, and now the next couple of months have been outlined in detail.
Following all of the hype around the DC FanDome event over the past weekend, more details have been shared on the DC and Batman DLC that are around the corner.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton 2.5 Released With Experimental DXR 1.1, More Games Working]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VKD3D-Proton-2.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VKD3D-Proton-2.5"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:04:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton as Valve's Direct3D 12 over Vulkan implementation for Steam Play's Proton is out with a big feature update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Returns To This Year's Macy's Day Parade With A Special Pikachu And Eevee Balloon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122433</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/pokemon-returns-to-this-years-macys-day-parade-with-a-special-pikachu-and-eevee-balloon"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Make it double.
There's just over a month to go until this year's Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade gets underway, and The Pokémon Company has confirmed that it'll be in attendance with its very own balloon.
This year's event, which will once again take place in New York City, will be the 95th edition of the annual parade. While Pikachu has appeared as a balloon on several occasions, even making it as one of the lead stars on 2014's event poster, this year's Pokémon balloon will feature two fan-favourite characters.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit review: a gorgeous roguelike shooter that sadly descends into comfortable familiarity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know how some games, like, throb? I mean your Thumpers, your Devil Daggers, your Dooms. Games you disappear into, but not in that namby pamby, prancing around fulfilling all your desires sense. I mean games that will eat you alive unless you stop them. Games set in pulsating, hostile dimensions in which you don’t belong; games that fling their menageries at the battered windows of your soul, where survival teeters on a combo of hair-trigger reflexes and total concentration.


Into The Pit is one of those, until it isn’t. You know you’re in trouble when the demonic eldritch hell portal starts feeling too comfortable. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise PC vs Switch: how the demo compares]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-pc-vs-switch-how-the-demo-compares</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-pc-vs-switch-how-the-demo-compares"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:45:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The recent launch of the Monster Hunter Rise demo on PC has given us a free look at how this soon-to-be-former Nintendo Switch exclusive will run and play when it releases in full in January 2022. This calls, naturally, for some screenshot comparisons.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Žaloba na Canon: není možné skenovat bez inkoustu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42919</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/zaloba-na-canon-protoze-nejde-skenovat-bez-inkoustu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:40:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canon USA je žalován kvůli multifunkčním all-in-one tiskárnám PIXMA MG6320, MG5420 a MX860, které s prázdnými zásobníky inkoustu odmítají skenovat i když k tomu žádný inkoust potřeba není. Na problém si stěžovalo přes dva tisíce uživatelů, ale Canon jim odpověděl, že je potřeba vyměnit zásobník s inkoustem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[With mage hunts and talking trees, Salt And Sacrifice is looking like a worthy successor to Salt And Sanctuary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/salt-and-sacrifice-preview-a-worthy-successor-to-salt-and-sanctuary</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/salt-and-sacrifice-preview-a-worthy-successor-to-salt-and-sanctuary"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:35:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you liked Dark Soulsy side-scroller Salt And Sanctuary, I have some great news. I got hands-on with an early portion of its sequel Salt And Sacrifice, and it seems set to deliver all the things that made its predecessor tick. The punishing enemies, the smooth combat, the vast skill trees, and the interconnected world are all still doing good things, but this time around they've just been joined by a few new additions, or seen some tweaks to keep things fresher, but no less difficult.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Yes, Twitch Once Had A ‘Do Not Ban’ List]]></title>
        <id>1847884492</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/report-yes-twitch-once-had-a-do-not-ban-list-1847884492"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch’s big leak this month included more than just source code and payday info. Details emerged about a “do not ban” list, which sure sounds like the sort of nefarious document that allows certain people to play the same game by different rules. But a new Washington Post report indicates that the list is not quite…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Sword And Shield Shiny Zacian/Zamazenta Distribution Confirmed For US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122442</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/pokemon-sword-and-shield-shiny-zacianzamazenta-distribution-confirmed-for-us"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how to get them.
After initially being revealed for South Korea, and then eventually Japan, the distribution of Shiny Zacian and Shiny Zamazenta for Pokémon Sword and Shield has now been confirmed for fans living in the US.
The distribution will be taking place in partnership with GameStop; players can head in-store to grab a free code while supplies last. Here's all the info you need:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machinarium is selling the best merch: a bronze statuette of its adorable star]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/machinarium-is-selling-the-best-merch-a-bronze-statuette-of-its-adorable-star</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/machinarium-is-selling-the-best-merch-a-bronze-statuette-of-its-adorable-star"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:29:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don't buy video game merch, and if I did buy video game merch I wouldn't buy statues, and yet... my heart melts looking at Machinarium's hot new merch drop. Amanita are selling a limited run of bronze statuettes of the adventure game's adorable scrap robot star, Josef, and I love him. 405 grams of bronze might sound cold to hold but I know he'd warm my heart.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Cards Of Katy Perry, Post Malone, And J Balvin Are Too Good To Be Real]]></title>
        <id>1847884344</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-cards-of-katy-perry-post-malone-and-j-balvin-1847884344"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating last week’s launch of Pokémon 25: The Album, The Pokémon Company has mocked up a trio of trading cards featuring anime versions of artists Katy Perry, J Balvin, and Post Malone with various pocket monster partners. None of them are real, physical cards, but dammit, they should be.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dash to Dock 70]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/dash-to-dock-70</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/dash-to-dock-70"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:11:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření GNOME Shellu Dash to Dock bylo po roce vydáno v nové verzi 70. Přidána byla podpora GNOME Shellu 40.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: Super Smash Bros. Collection Tour - A Game for Every Fighter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122429</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/video-super-smash-bros-collection-tour-a-game-for-every-fighter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They're all here!
It's almost time, with Sora and version 13.00 of Super Smash Bros. Ultimate imminent, bringing an end to an era for one of the system's most popular titles. Masahiro Sakurai and his team have put together an enormous roster and feature set, ensuring that the 'Ultimate' in the name is no hyperbole.
With the big moment so close, over the weekend the marvellous Jon Cartwright shared a video on our YouTube channel that showcases his extensive collection with the fun spin of showing games for each member of the roster. That's a lot of games.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption review: a sinister and excellently crafted card game with a darkly comic underbelly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/inscryption-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Be afraid. Inscryption is both a love letter to card games and a twisted, jocular caricature of their numerical excess. It had me grinning ear to ear, sometimes nervously, sometimes with the joy of someone who simply loves thumbing through new cards, even when a rustic antagonist with big hands is reaching for my throat. This is not your average deckbuilder. It's a card game with an escape room built on top, and other sinister secrets buried beneath. The depth of its rabbit hole isn't apparent at first. It starts off as a familiar card battler, if a little darkly themed. You are in a cabin, playing cards against a face shrouded in darkness. It seems like Slay The Spire or Hand Of Fate. 
Then the cards start talking.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elden Ring delayed to February 25th, 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-delayed-to-february-25th-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-delayed-to-february-25th-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:51:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In game development, the flow of time itself is convoluted, with projects centuries old phasing in and out, so we shouldn't be surprised that Bandai Namco have delayed the launch of Elden Ring. The long-awaited new game from the makers of Dark Souls was expected to launch on January 21st, but now it's due on February 25th. Sounds like the usual reason: they want more time to make it good, yeah? Oh, and supposed leaked gameplay footage is doing the rounds, though I warn you that it's a bad and disappointing clip.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Unite's Halloween Event Is Its Biggest And Most Exciting Patch Yet]]></title>
        <id>1847884271</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-unites-halloween-event-is-its-biggest-and-most-1847884271"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just in time for the spooky season, TiMi Studio Group will kick off a Pokémon Unite Halloween event on October 20 that’s dedicated to all things frightening. It’s a pretty massive patch, too, packing in a brand-new playable monster, extra gear, and more.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elden Ring Delayed, But It Also Keeps Leaking]]></title>
        <id>1847884071</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-delayed-but-it-also-keeps-leaking-1847884071"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[February 2022 was already packed full of big game releases. Now FromSoftware has added another to the list, delaying Elden Ring a month from its original January 21, 2022 release date. In the meantime, the game will get a player demo next month as grainy in-development footage continues to leak online.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Animal Crossing Player Perfectly Recreates Link’s Awakening's Mabe Village]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122423</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/random-animal-crossing-player-perfectly-recreates-linkrs-awakenings-mabe-village"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's the little details...
With Animal Crossing: New Horizons' mega Version 2 update just around the corner as well as the delightful looking Happy Home Paradise DLC, we're once again feeling that specific brand of deserted island hype right now.
While we've been busy gushing over all the new content headed our way in November, however, other players have been cracking on with some fantastic creations on their islands. The latest to catch our eye is this wonderful effort from Twitter user @ACNH_Barkenos, who has recreated Zelda: Link's Awakening's Mabe Village with incredible attention to detail.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Succubus has censorship on by default, and it's unintentionally the most hilarious thing I've ever seen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/succubus-censorship-on-by-default</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/succubus-censorship-on-by-default"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes a game is so clearly desperate for attention that you are loathe to give it any. Like that one guy whose entire brand is getting in loud quote-tweet arguments on Twitter every eight to ten weeks, you know both exactly what it wants, and that you shouldn't go there. For months now I have been getting regular emails from the Succubus devs, all of which contain 112% of my daily recommended nipple allowance, and I know - I know - I shouldn't be writing about it. It is an action-adventure-hell-titty game that is, on every level, very bad. But I am breaking my silence now because the censored version of it is, quite possibly, the funniest thing I have encountered in my recent memory, and accidentally better than anything the devs could have made on purpose. You win, Madmind Studio. You win.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say hello to RPS' new guides writers, Rebecca Jones and Hayden Hefford]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/say-hello-to-rps-new-guides-writers-rebecca-jones-and-hayden-hefford</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/say-hello-to-rps-new-guides-writers-rebecca-jones-and-hayden-hefford"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:08:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After months of searching, I'm pleased to announce that the RPS guides team has finally added two fresh faces to its ranks. Please say hello to Rebecca Jones and Hayden Hefford.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reminder: Sora And Version 13.0.0 Arrive In Super Smash Bros. Ultimate Today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122408</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/reminder-sora-and-version-13-0-0-arrive-in-super-smash-bros-ultimate-today"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's when Sora goes live in Smash Ultimate.
Super Smash Bros. Ultimate's monstrous roster is just hours away from being complete, with the release of final fighter Sora and the game's Version 13.0.0. update both imminent.
Revealed during the special Smash Bros. Direct earlier this month, Sora arrives in-game on Monday 18th October in the US, and on Tuesday 19th October in Europe. While an exact time hasn't been given, the timezone differences suggest that the new content will arrive somewhere between 4pm and midnight PT today (which equates to 12am - 8am CEST on Tuesday morning).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay aktualizoval spoustu klasických her, aby fungovaly v Linuxu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42918</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/interplay-aktualizoval-spoustu-klasickych-her-aby-fungovaly-v-linuxu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T13:43:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve čtvrtek Interplay Entertainment oznámil, že aktualizoval spoustu klasických her na Steamu, aby fungovaly v Linuxu a macOS. Většinou půjde o přidání DOSBoxu. V seznamu her od Inteplay uvidíte nově velké množství her spustitelných v Linuxu (logo Steam). Jde třeba o Battle Chess, Battle Chess II: Chinese Chess, Battle Chess 4000, Descent a Descent 2.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[For The First Time In 33 Months, Switch Wasn't The US' Best-Selling Console In September]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122428</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/for-the-first-time-in-33-months-switch-wasnt-the-us-best-selling-console-in-september"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Still, 33 months ain't bad...
New US games sales data has revealed that the Switch's incredible streak as the country's best-selling console month after month has now come to an end.
For the first time in 33 months, a console other than Nintendo Switch topped the US charts in September. As reported by The NPD Group's Mat Piscatella, Sony's PlayStation 5 was September's best-selling hardware platform in both units and dollar sales.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Metroid Dread: Samus Doesn’t Need To Be An Emotionless Robot To Be Badass]]></title>
        <id>1847875658</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/dear-metroid-dread-samus-doesn-t-need-to-be-an-emotion-1847875658"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samus Aran.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Aeon Must Die! - An Aggressively Repetitive Beat 'Em Up That Tries Way Too Hard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122013</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/aeon-must-die"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As long as it DOES die.
Do you have that friend who'll compromise the enjoyment of the group in order to indulge their own ego? You know, the 'wacky' friend who not only has to do everything just a little differently, they need you to know that they're special and unique and out there and WILL YOU JUST ORDER A NORMAL COFFEE, CLIVE?
Ahem, sorry. Anyway, the point is, Aeon Must Die! is avowedly, aggressively different, but in a way that unfortunately highlights its shortcomings rather than elevating proceedings into something fresh. It's trying super-duper hard to impress, but it comes off a little — as the kids say — cringe.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feature: We Take A Peek At Danganronpa S: Ultimate Summer Camp's Hype Cards And Story]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122359</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/we-take-a-peek-at-danganronpa-s-ultimate-summer-camps-hype-cards-and-story"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plus details on the Danganronpa 10th Anniversary: Ultimate Class Reunion.
Danganronpa Decadence is coming to Switch on 3rd December and will pack a whopping four games in one bundle, all available separately on the Switch eShop, if you prefer. It will include the three main games in the visual novel adventure series (Danganronpa: Trigger Happy Havoc Anniversary Edition, Danganronpa 2: Goodbye Despair Anniversary Edition, and Danganronpa V3: Killing Harmony Anniversary Edition), plus a brand new game: Danganronpa S: Ultimate Summer Camp.
The latter is a boardgame-style affair featuring characters from the series interacting at — you guessed it — a summer camp. Having got a little heads-up from developer Spike Chunsoft via some press materials, in this feature we'll be taking a look at the prologue and the Hype Card mechanic of this new game.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Legendary Namco Graphic Designer Hiroshi Ono Dies At 64]]></title>
        <id>1847883296</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/legendary-namco-graphic-designer-hiroshi-ono-dies-at-64-1847883296"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiroshi Ono, better known as “Mr. Dotman,” passed away on October 16. The news was announced by his official Twitter account. According to Automaton, Ono had been hospitalized for autoimmune hepatitis. He was 64 years old. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Month After An Iconic Tokyo SEGA Arcade Closed, Another Will Open Across The Street]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122421</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/a-month-after-an-iconic-tokyo-sega-arcade-closed-another-will-open-across-the-street"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, that's nice.
The unique challenges and economic downturn of 2020 proved to be an extremely difficult period for arcades and 'in person' businesses. In Tokyo, a city beloved for its iconic gaming sites, SEGA closed down its Akihabara 2nd arcade in 2020, before confirming that Sega Ikebukuro Gigo was to close in September due to the end of a building lease. It was given an emotional farewell by its supporters.
In a rather positive shift after that disappointing news, SEGA has confirmed that a new arcade centre will be opened on 22nd October just across the street (hat-tip to @ausretrogamer).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game & Watch: The Legend of Zelda Gets A Snazzy New Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122422</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/game-and-watch-the-legend-of-zelda-gets-a-snazzy-new-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hoping for one in your stocking?
After its Super Mario Bros. Game & Watch proved to be a bit of a must-have festive gift, Nintendo is hoping to hit the mark again when it releases Game & Watch: The Legend of Zelda to celebrate the IP's anniversary. Now Nintendo has released a snazzy new trailer to showcase its charms ahead of the 12th November release.
Announced during E3 in the Summer, the Zelda Game & Watch features The Legend of Zelda, Zelda II: The Adventure of Link, The Legend of Zelda: Link's Awakening and a special version of the Game & Watch title Vermin, which features Link as the playable character. There's also a special clock mode, and as you can see in the trailer it's playable.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Radeon Gaming With KDE Plasma vs. GNOME Shell + Wayland vs. X.Org]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30617</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30617"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:14:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With last week's release of Ubuntu 21.10, here are some fresh benchmarks looking at the Linux gaming performance on this new release while testing both the GNOME Shell 40 default desktop to that of its KDE Plasma 5.22 based option. Both the X.Org and Wayland sessions for KDE and GNOME were benchmarked for seeing how the Linux gaming performance compares with the Radeon open-source GPU driver stack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action-RPG Crystar, Once A PS4 Console-Exclusive, Is Coming To ﻿Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122417</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/action-rpg-crystar-once-a-ps4-console-exclusive-is-coming-to-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Western launch confirmed!
Update: And just like that, a western release for Crystar has now been confirmed.
NIS America has confirmed that the game will be launching in Europe in spring 2022, complete with all previously released DLC content. A Limited Edition physical release is now available to pre-order on the NIS America Europe Online store (yes, that really is the store's name), as well as a standard version.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh, nope, Microsoft's big hint at Fable news today was nothing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-nope-microsofts-big-hint-at-fable-news-today-was-nothing</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-nope-microsofts-big-hint-at-fable-news-today-was-nothing"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T11:46:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, Microsoft's Xbox Game Studios Publishing Twitter account offered what sure sounded like tantalising hints that Monday would bring big news on the mysterious upcoming new Fable game. Like, really sounded like. Like, totally sounded like the sort of obvious hint marketing campaigns drop when they're pretending it's a surprise but want you to know full well what's up. Nope. They've now deleted those tweets and apologised, saying no, no Fable news today. Oh.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telegram dosáhl miliardy stažení v Google Play]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42917</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/telegram-dosahl-miliardy-stazeni-v-google-play/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T11:31:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obchod Google Play hlásí, že si oficiálního klienta Telegram stáhla více než miliarda uživatelů. Pavel Durov, zakladatel tohoto komunikačního nástroje, přitom na začátku letošního roku tvrdil, že jej měsíčně použije asi půl miliardy uživatelů. Překročení miliardového milníku bylo urychleno také nedávnými velkými výpadky Facebooku, které postihly také WhatsApp a Messenger a přivedly Telegramu desítky milionů nových uživatelů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Kids We Were Will Offer A Charming Exploration Of 1980s Japan On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122414</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/the-kids-we-were-will-offer-a-charming-exploration-of-1980s-japan-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Switch edition will add a new story chapter.
The routes that Indie games take to the Switch vary a great deal, and one of them is to make a start on mobile before arriving on Nintendo's system in a 'premium' iteration down the road. The Kids We Were is following that approach having earned awards and plenty of praise on Android and iOS, with a release date of 26th January now confirmed for Switch and Steam.
Developed by GAGEX, The Kids We Were is a narrative adventure game that adopts blocky voxel-style visuals - think The Touryst but with a calmer colour palette. On mobile it boasts of high user review averages full of comments praising the story, and it does sound like the concept and setting could make for an intriguing experience. It involves a bit of time travel, a 'Back to the Future'-esque quest and a setting of 1980s Tokyo suburbs.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back 4 Blood jukebox music list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-jukebox</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-jukebox"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want a list of songs that play on the Back 4 Blood jukebox? A few missions into Act 1, you’ll come across the Bar Room Blitz mission. Sure, there are some story points about distracting zombies and saving people, but this mission is a smash-hit for one reason. There’s a jukebox that plays some very cool tunes in the background whilst you shoot, slash, and slaughter zombies from every angle. If you really like that one scene in Shaun Of The Dead, then this will be your fever dream.
This guide will show you all of the songs that you can hear on the Back 4 Blood jukebox, so that you can repeatedly replay Bar Room Blitz whilst waiting for someone to inevitably get Simon Pegg and Nick Frost to play the mission on Youtube.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kódové jméno Ubuntu 22.04 LTS odhaleno, vyšlo OpenBSD 7.0]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15714</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/kodove-jmeno-ubuntu-22-04-lts-odhaleno-vyslo-openbsd-7-0/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:44:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kódové jméno Ubuntu 22.04 LTS odhaleno. Vyšlo OpenBSD 7.0. Vznikl alternativní klient pro Snap, který umí pracovat i s repozitáři mimo Canonical. Společnost Pine64 zahájila předobjednávky pro svůj telefon PinePhone Pro.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Habana Labs For Linux 5.16 To Bring Peer-To-Peer Support With DMA-BUF]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Habana-Labs-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Habana-Labs-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:38:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The drama around DMA-BUF code for the Habana Labs AI driver appears to be wrapping up with the Linux 5.16 cycle that is coming up...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After Iconic Sega Arcade Closes, A New One Will Open Soon Nearby]]></title>
        <id>1847882984</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/after-iconic-sega-arcade-closes-a-new-one-will-open-so-1847882984"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month, hundreds of fans gathered in Tokyo’s Ikebukuro to say goodbye to an iconic arcade. After 28 years, Sega Ikekuburo Gigo called it a day. But this month, a new Sega arcade will open right across the way. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metroid Dread Studio Hit With Allegations Of Poor Organisation And Management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122413</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/metroid-dread-studio-hit-with-allegations-of-poor-organisation-and-management"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["The bad atmosphere is constant and it is very tense".
Following on from disputes over Metroid Dread developer MercurySteam's policy regarding the in-game crediting of staff, further allegations have surfaced in the last few days which suggest questionable management practices and handling of employees at the Spanish studio, makers of the Castlevania: Lords of Shadow games, Metroid: Samus Returns, and — of course — the latest entry in the Metroid series.
Spanish website Anait Games has published further information after speaking to multiple former staff members regarding their time at the studio working on Dread. Programmers and artists who worked on the game talk about management and organisation issues, and a negative, stressful culture at MercurySteam.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Bloody Rally Show' Skids To Switch In November, Mashes Top-Down Racing With Reality TV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122298</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/bloody-rally-show-skids-to-switch-in-november-mashes-top-down-racing-with-reality-tv"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skid game.
Indie studio Kodo Linija's Bloody Rally Show is a top-down arcade-style racer which released on PC in 2020 and it's making its way to Switch on 4th November.
We say 'studio', but Kodo Linija is comprised of solo dev Tomas Varaneckas, so this hyperviolent reality TV racer is in fact a one-man-show. The reveal trailer above give a good idea of the bloody carnage involved as you blast and boost your way about the place, jostling for position and generally tearing up the competition. The game's set in a dystopian future (is there any other kind) where drivers compete in a Mad Max-style (death) race for glory for the pleasure of viewers everywhere.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gotham Knights trailer introduces its baddies, the Court of Owls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gotham-knights-trailer-introduces-its-baddies-the-court-of-owls</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gotham-knights-trailer-introduces-its-baddies-the-court-of-owls"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T09:46:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your reaction to hearing that the villains of Batman 'em up Gotham Knights are the Court of Owls is "Hoo?", 1) wow, good grief 2) you might want to watch these new trailers. Released over the weekend during the DC FanDome pow-o-rama, they introduce the secret society who pull Gotham's strings, as well as giving us a peek at the game's version of Penguin.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Japan, The Xbox Series X/S Is Doing Better Than The Xbox One]]></title>
        <id>1847882953</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/in-japan-the-xbox-series-x-s-is-doing-better-than-the-1847882953"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of struggling in Japan, the Xbox Series X/S is showing more than signs of life in Japan. In comparison to previous efforts, it’s actually doing well. 
Famitsu reports that as of October 10, Microsoft has sold 64,284 Xbox Series X consoles and another 38,307 Xbox Series S consoles. That’s a total of 102,591…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 22.0 Lands Some Patches Toward OpenCL Image Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-22.0-OpenCL-Image-Prep</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-22.0-OpenCL-Image-Prep"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T09:29:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 22.0-devel is one step closer to having OpenCL image support that is sought after by many individuals for allowing more OpenCL-enabled desktop software to work nicely with this open-source OpenCL component in Mesa...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proxmox: moderní virtualizační platforma schopná nahradit VMware (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40445</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/proxmox-moderni-virtualizacni-platforma-schopna-nahradit-vmware-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T09:13:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proxmox je moderní virtualizační platforma, která v mnoha případech může nahradit VMware. Je open-source, zdarma a je postaven na otevřených technologiích jako KVM, LXC, CEPH a dalších. Pokud potřebujete provozovat virtualizaci, Proxmox je pro vás ideální stack a na našem workshopu se dozvíte, jak na něj.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc6 Ticks Up In Size, Stops Using AMD SME By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc6-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T08:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds is out with Linux 5.15-rc6 and its increase in size has him slightly worried...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WhatsApp přestane od 1. listopadu fungovat na Androidu 4.0.4 a starším]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42916</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/whatsapp-prestane-od-1-listopadu-fungovat-na-androidu-4-04-a-starsim/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T08:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WhatsApp přestane od 1. listopadu fungovat na Androidu 4.0.4 a starším. Ke svému běhu bude potřebovat alespoň Android 4.1.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Měsíc bude mít svůj internet LunaNet]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42915</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mesic-bude-mit-svuj-internet-lunanet/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T06:11:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V rámci programu Artemis plánuje NASA návrat astronautů na Měsíc v roce 2024. Předtím bude na Měsíci vybudována síť LunaNet, která bude podobná jako WiFi s velkým počtem vysílačů. To umožní využívat také přesnou polohu a čas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical Trials]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2530/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2530/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[L0phtCrack je nově open source]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/l0phtcrack-je-nove-open-source</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/l0phtcrack-je-nove-open-source"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T03:23:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[L0phtCrack (Wikipedie), nástroj pro auditování a obnovu hesel v Microsoft Windows, je nově open source. Zdrojové kódy nejnovější verze 7.2.0 byly zveřejněny na GitLabu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Player 67]]></title>
        <id>1847836581</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/player-67-1847836581"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T00:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vimal Kerketta is an artist at DNEG, a visual effects studio that has recently worked on stuff like No Time To Die and Star Trek: Discovery.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PS5 Console Plate Makers Provoke Sony, Then Hit Legal Trouble]]></title>
        <id>1847881873</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sony-threatens-dbrand-with-legal-action-over-ps5-plates-1847881873"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T23:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might not remember since February 2021 was actually 19 years ago, but earlier this year phone and console skin makers Dbrand released a set of black PS5 faceplates. Not content with merely releasing them, though, the company also bizarrely baited Sony to sue them, and Sony is now obliging.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Week In Games: Time To Buy Resident Evil 4 (Again)]]></title>
        <id>1847881693</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-week-in-games-time-to-buy-resident-evil-4-again-1847881693"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One day, I’ll no longer walk this planet. I’ll be dust in history. But until then, I’ll be buying Resident Evil 4 over and over and over... Well, you get the idea. And now with a VR version of the classic game hitting Oculus Quest later this week, I’ll be buying it again.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podzimní smršť novinek od Aceru. SentinelOne v ČR nabere 300 lidí a investuje miliardu. Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci. Dodávky a ceny osobních počítačů z pohledu výrobce. VMworld: Zabezpečení na principu nulové důvěry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: co odhalil phishing na CoinBase]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15715</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-co-odhalil-phishing-na-coinbase/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes se podíváme na jemnou hodinářskou práci útočníků při získávání OTP hesel, koukneme se na nové povinnost provozovatelů informačních systémů a také na to, co můžeme čekat v oblasti kybernetické bezpečnosti od nové vlády.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CSIRT.CZ)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seven Weeks After Launch, Fewer Than 800 People Are Playing Aliens: Fireteam Elite]]></title>
        <id>1847881309</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/seven-weeks-after-launch-less-than-800-people-are-play-1847881309"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T19:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aliens: Fireteam Elite was released on August 23 to mixed reviews, but on Steam it averaged around or above 10k players for the first few weeks after release. But a lack of content, small updates, and possibly the release of the popular Back 4 Blood recently have killed the player base on PC, with only 792 players…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux To No Longer Enable AMD SME Usage By Default Due To Problems With Some Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-SME-No-Default-Use</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-SME-No-Default-Use"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being sent in as a fix for the Linux 5.15 kernel this morning and to be back-ported to existing stable series is a behavior change that the Linux kernel will no longer use AMD Secure Memory Encryption (SME) by default on supported hardware but rather making it now opt-in due to shortcomings of some platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex86 Processors Finally Seeing Work In 2021 For Proper Handling Under Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Linux-Detection</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Linux-Detection"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T10:13:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Vortex86 32-bit SoCs have worked under Linux for those distributions still maintaining 32-bit x86 support and where not hitting corner-cases of some i686 level features not being supported by some Vortex86 cores, but there is finally a pending kernel patch to provide proper CPU detection for Vortex86 hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-614</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-614"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for inhaling the smell of a new book. Before you lean in, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Axboe Achieves 8M IOPS Per-Core With Newest Linux Optimization Patches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=8M-IOPS-Per-Core-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=8M-IOPS-Per-Core-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just last week that Linux optimizations were leading to possible 6M IOPS per core and then at the start of this week new patches pushed Linux past 7M IOPS per-core with an ideal hardware configuration as well. In ending out the week, 8M IOPS has been reached!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GTA: The Trilogy system requirements and details allegedly leak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-the-trilogy-system-requirements-and-details-allegedly-leak</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-the-trilogy-system-requirements-and-details-allegedly-leak"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T23:26:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rockstar finally announced their long-rumoured Grand Theft Auto remasters a little over a week ago. Official confirmation that they were on the way hasn't stopped the leaks, however. A user of GTAForums has seemingly leaked a more detailed description of the games and their system requirements.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dota 2's next hero is Marci from the Dota: Dragon's Blood anime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dota-2s-next-hero-is-marci-from-the-dota-dragons-blood-anime</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dota-2s-next-hero-is-marci-from-the-dota-dragons-blood-anime"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:42:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dota 2 is getting a new hero this autumn. It's Marci, the mute bodyguard from Netflix's Dota anime, Dota: Dragon's Blood. She'll join the game in an update "coming soon."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tweet2Doom lets you play Doom via Twitter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tweet2doom-lets-you-play-doom-via-twitter</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tweet2doom-lets-you-play-doom-via-twitter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:06:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doom is now playable on Twitter - sort of. Thanks to Tweet2Doom bot, you can send replies to the account with a list of actions - move, turn, shoot, etc. - and get a video clip of Doom showing the results sent back to you. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence v kooperativních hrách]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový typ magnetismu nezpůsobují spiny. Beethovenovu slavnou 10. symfonii dokončila umělá inteligence  Studium neuronových sítí může pomoci při zkoumání toho, jak se do mozku ukládají konspirační teorie. Minirobot se pohybuje díky gradientům teploty. Splynutí obřích černých děr provázejí nejen gravitační vlny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[První Xbox měl mít CPU od AMD, Apple je sponzorem Blenderu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15716</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/prvni-xbox-mel-mit-cpu-od-amd-apple-je-sponzorem-blenderu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10, nový referenční AV1 kodér, 25 let KDE a Plasma 5.23, nový linuxový smartphone PinePhone Pro, změny v systému aktualizací openSUSE Leap, Strawberry 1.0, fork Clementine běžící na Qt6.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rocksteady's Suicide Squad gets a new story trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rocksteadys-suicide-squad-gets-a-new-story-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rocksteadys-suicide-squad-gets-a-new-story-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T21:27:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's DC FanDome event brought another trailer for Rocksteady's Suicide Squad: Kill The Justice League. There's still no gameplay, but the story trailer filled out the world, its cast, and heck, it's good fun. Watch it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games Store will "welcome games that make use of blockchain tech"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-store-will-welcome-games-that-make-use-of-blockchain-tech</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-store-will-welcome-games-that-make-use-of-blockchain-tech"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T20:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday Valve told developers that they wouldn't allow games featuring NFTs or cryptocurrency on their digital storefront, Steam. Since then, Epic have followed up by telling The Verge that the Epic Games Store would be "open to games that support cryptocurrency or blockchain-based assets."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft Dungeons adds roguelikelike singleplayer mode this December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-dungeons-adds-roguelikelike-singleplayer-mode-this-december</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-dungeons-adds-roguelikelike-singleplayer-mode-this-december"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft Dungeons has finished telling its story through a number of DLCs that have released over the last year, but Mojang isn't done with the blocky Diablo-like just yet. They're introducing seasonal updates that they're calling Seasonal Adventures, adding progression systems, challenges and more - similar to the new Sea Of Thieves' Seasons. Season 1 will be called The Cloudy Climb, and it's coming this December. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft's The Wild Update will add excellent frogs after Caves & Cliffs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecrafts-the-wild-update-will-add-excellent-frogs-after-caves-cliffs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecrafts-the-wild-update-will-add-excellent-frogs-after-caves-cliffs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Minecraft's Caves & Cliffs part 2 nearly upon us, Mojang have revealed the next big update that will follow it. Named The Wild Update, it'll focus on enhancing some of the existing areas we can explore and, importantly, adding colourful frogs! They'll arrive with the new Mangrove Swamp biome, along with tadpoles, fireflies and more. The Wild Update will also introduce the Deep Dark biome, which was supposed to arrive with Caves & Cliffs, but needed a little more time in the oven. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft will soon bundle Java and Bedrock editions together]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-will-soon-bundle-java-and-bedrock-editions-together</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-will-soon-bundle-java-and-bedrock-editions-together"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years and years, Minecraft's Java and Bedrock editions have lived apart, but Mojang finally have plans to unite them. They plan to package the two together next year as the Minecraft PC Bundle, so if you own one you'll get the other too. Ahead of this, both Java and Bedrock are coming to Xbox Game Pass for PC on November 2nd, which is lovely news. I've only ever owned Java, so it'll be nice to have the option to jump into Bedrock too.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust-Based Cloud-Hypervisor 19.0 Released With Improved Live Migration, Faster Boot Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cloud-Hypervisor-19.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cloud-Hypervisor-19.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T17:33:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud-Hypervisor 19.0 debuted this week as the Intel-led open-source VMM focused on supporting modern cloud workloads and written in the Rust programming language while leveraging the Linux's KVM virtualization code or the Microsoft MSHV hypervisor on Windows...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxový telefon PinePhone Pro]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42914</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linuxovy-telefon-pinephone-pro/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T11:25:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost PINE64 včera představila linuxový telefon PinePhone Pro, který je vylepšením původního PinePhone. Obsahuje SoC Rockchip RK3399S (2× A72 + 4× A53 na 1,5 GHz) a 4 GB RAM. Interní úložiště má 128 GB eMMC a je možné připojit SDCX kartu až do velikosti 2 TB.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 LTS bude Jammy Jellyfish]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42913</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-22-04-lts-bude-jammy-jellyfish/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T10:57:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Následující vydání oblíbené distribuce Ubuntu 22.04 LTS bude mít označení Jammy Jellyfish. Tedy šťastná medúza nebo také medúza marmeládové konzistence.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realtek 802.11ax WiFi Driver "rtw89" Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Realtek-802.11ax-rtw89</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Realtek-802.11ax-rtw89"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T09:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arriving in the wireless-drivers-next branch this week is the "rtw89" driver as a Realtek-contributed open-source 802.11ax WiFi driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's Plasma Wayland Session Continues Seeing More Crash Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-More-Crash-Fixes-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-More-Crash-Fixes-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T09:27:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week marked the release of Plasma 5.23 in celebrating 25 years of the KDE desktop project while celebrations didn't last long with developers already hard at work on the Plasma 5.23.1 point release, feature work for Plasma 5.24, and also improvements to the KDE Applications and KDE Frameworks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bareflank Hypervisor 3.0 Pre-Release Debuts With Many Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0-Pre-Release</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0-Pre-Release"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T08:46:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Bareflank Hypervisor project designed to prototype new hypervisors across Intel, AMD, and AArch64 platforms issued their long-awaited 3.0 pre-release on Friday...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-165</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-165"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A week of goodbyes. Vid bud Colm waved goodbye on Monday, and Friday was the final shift at the news face for longtime evening freelancer Lauren Morton. She leaves us to join cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer and they'll be lucky to have her, as we were. Say goodbye, gang.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genode-Based Sculpt OS 21.10 Adds Intel GPU Acceleration, USB Web Camera Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Sculpt-OS-21.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Sculpt-OS-21.10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Thursday in addition to the releases of Ubuntu 21.10 (plus its derivatives) and OpenBSD 7.0, the Genode OS Framework based Sculpt OS saw its 21.10 release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCL 3.0.9 Specification Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenCL-3.0.9</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenCL-3.0.9"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T23:32:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Khronos Group's OpenCL working group did a quiet Friday evening tagging of OpenCL 3.0.9...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portal speedrunner explains their wild tricks to Valve developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/portal-speedrunner-explains-their-wild-tricks-to-valve-developers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/portal-speedrunner-explains-their-wild-tricks-to-valve-developers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:48:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm constantly in awe of the wild tricks that speedrunners discover in just about any game they set their collective minds to. It's always a treat to hear developers being equally astounded though, and Valve's developers are no exception. Three of them recently got to have a chat with Portal speedrunner "CantEven" to ask about extremely calculated trick shots, weird save glitches, and all the other things that game developers don't always know about their own games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch are "confident" no passwords or credit cards were exposed in leak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-confident-no-passwords-or-credit-cards-were-exposed-in-leak</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-confident-no-passwords-or-credit-cards-were-exposed-in-leak"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:07:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch were hit by a rather big source code and data breach earlier this month, which they say they've since been investigating. They've updated users again today, reiterating that the breach was made possible by a server configuration change and that they're confident no passwords, login credentials, or credit card numbers were exposed.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 41/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retro sci-fi thriller The Invincible now has a proper trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/retro-sci-fi-thriller-the-invincible-now-has-a-proper-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/retro-sci-fi-thriller-the-invincible-now-has-a-proper-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T21:05:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Retro-future sci-fi romp The Invincible is the upcoming thriller from some folks formerly of The Witcher, Cyberpunk, Dying Light, and others. It's based on the sci-fi novel of the same title from the 60s by Polish author Stanisław Lem. The first we saw of The Invincible last year was mostly a teaser set to some nice tunes, but now there's a full cutscene-style trailer to check out and it sure does look like some classic space stuff.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam is banning games with NFTs and cryptocurrency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-is-banning-games-with-nfts-and-cryptocurrency</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-is-banning-games-with-nfts-and-cryptocurrency"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T20:14:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve appear to be laying down some new rules for games on Steam, specifically games that involve trading or receiving cryptocurrancy and NFTs. The change has been shared by SpacePirate Games, developers of Age Of Rust, who say they were notified this week about the new prohibition. Over in the Steamworks portal, a new type of content that cannot be published on Steam has been added. "Applications built on blockchain technology that issue or allow exchange of cryptocurrencies or NFTs."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hodnota Bitcoinu opět překonala 60 000 dolarů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/hodnota-bitcoinu-opet-prekonala-60-000-dolaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/hodnota-bitcoinu-opet-prekonala-60-000-dolaru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T19:50:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V dubnu letošního roku byla hodnota Bitcoinu, decentralizované kryptoměny téměř 65 000 dolarů. V červnu hodnota klesla pod 30 000 dolarů. Aktuálně opět překonala 60 000 dolarů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lo-fi adventure Chasing Static is now out with some classic horror puzzling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-adventure-chasing-static-is-now-out-with-some-classic-horror-puzzling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-adventure-chasing-static-is-now-out-with-some-classic-horror-puzzling"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:56:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chasing Static is both the name of this lo-fi Welsh horror story and also an accurate description of me attempting to track down a post about it on RPS. Someone's written about it. I just know it. Oh no, we've just mentioned it several times in a roundabout way. Well, I've finally pinned it down—chased the clues and cornered it now that it's launched and I can tell you a thing or two about it. Chasing Static is a swell and spooky story so far with a good chunk of classic horror game puzzling and just a bit of sudden scares. Come on and have a quick look.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultimate Audio Bang #16: all things FPS merch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-16-all-things-fps-merch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-16-all-things-fps-merch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T16:24:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've returned from my trip to the Lake District, with aching calves and a desire to talk about online shooters with Imogen. On this week's episode of the Ultimate Audio Bang, we don't chat sore muscles, instead, we focus on various Halloween events in games like Apex Legends and Rainbow Six: Siege, our thoughts on the Battlefield 2042 beta, Destiny 2 vaulting yet more stuff, and Call Of Duty: Vanguard finally introducing anti-cheat.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TFI Friday: three indie puzzle games with slightly melancholy vibe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-three-indie-puzzle-games-with-slightly-melancholy-vibe</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-three-indie-puzzle-games-with-slightly-melancholy-vibe"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year has finally turned, reader. I am having discussions at home about putting the heating on. When I leave the office it isn't dark, but it's fuzzy around the edges. My knuckles are cold. It's the time of year, before the Skeleton War memes begin in earnest, to luxuriate in feeling a bit melancholy. It's healthy to feel sad sometimes, you know. Didn't you watch Inside Out? I did, and in my screening at the cinema a child called out "Where's Bing Bong?" when the heroic Bing Bong disappeared...
This week, I have collected three different puzzle games with very different vibes. I know I'm biased in favour of puzzle games more than the usual reader, but these ones are very good and worth a punt, and at least one should pique the old interest. And they all gave me that happy-sad feeling. Like, I want to wrap up in a blanket and play these games and maybe think about my granny a bit. That sort of feeling.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Roblox horror games: great scary games in Roblox]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roblox-horror-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roblox-horror-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:42:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are the best horror games in Roblox? It's October once again, so naturally our minds are turning to Halloween. There are so, so many horror games in the world to choose from, especially since it's a genre that lends itself so well to short indie offerings. What I'm getting at here is that there are tons of scary games on Roblox, and if you fancy giving some a go this spooky season, we've put together a list of all-time favourites and current big trends.
You might have seen "scary corn game" trending in Roblox circles recently, and if you're wondering why that is, it's because no-one can spell or pronounce Kalampokiphobia — the technical name for fear of corn. This game, which originally popped up on the platform earlier this year, looks set to be the big Roblox horror trend this Halloween, egged on by TikTok and YouTube jumpscare videos that have been doing the rounds. It's a pretty standard run-and-hide game with a truly ludicrous (but somehow still a bit creepy) stalker character pursuing you through a disorienting corn maze.
Here's the link.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mon Amour is the most crazed, loved up take on Flappy Bird you'll ever see]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mon-amour-is-the-most-crazed-loved-up-take-on-flappy-bird-youll-ever-see</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mon-amour-is-the-most-crazed-loved-up-take-on-flappy-bird-youll-ever-see"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T15:38:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a banner week for Japanese indie game releases. First we had the delightful puzzle platformer ElecHead, now we have the latest from Onion Games, Mon Amour. It's a one-button score attack game in the same vein as Flappy Bird, only instead of piloting a dumpy chicken through a bunch of green pipes, here you're guiding a spinning, mustachioed man toward dozens of smoochable women. But before you arch that eyebrow at its somewhat questionable premise, yes, this is another entry from Onion Games where kissing saves the day, following in the esteemed footsteps of Chulip and Dandy Dungeon - and yes, it is every bit as mad and baffling (and exquisitely designed) as you'd expect.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Karlee build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-karlee</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-karlee"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:09:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Karlee in Back 4 Blood? Karlee isn’t one of the best characters in Back 4 Blood, but she still has some killer abilities that deserve a spot in your team. Most notably, Karlee can sense nearby hazards and Special Ridden, so you won’t be surprised when a Tallboy smashes around the corner. She also gets an extra quick inventory slot (used for defibrillators and stun guns) and increases the team’s use speed by 50%.
This guide will show you how to make the best Karlee build in Back 4 Blood, so you can stop staring at cards and start using them. Of course, you’ll need to unlock all the cleaners in Back 4 Blood before you can play as Karlee.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novinky od PINE64 - 10/2021 - PinePhone Pro]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/novinky-od-pine64-10-2021-pinephone-pro</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/novinky-od-pine64-10-2021-pinephone-pro"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost PINE64 stojící za telefonem PinePhone, notebooky Pinebook a Pinebook Pro, IP kamerou PineCube, hodinkami PineTime, páječkou (pájecím perem) Pinecil, zdroji PinePower nebo RISC-V vývojovou deskou PineCone publikovala na svém blogu říjnový souhrn novinek (YouTube) a představila nový vylepšený PinePhone Pro.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song Of Farca is great if you don't take it personally]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/song-of-farca-is-great-if-you-dont-take-it-personally</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/song-of-farca-is-great-if-you-dont-take-it-personally"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Often a game can feel frustrating because you can't make decisions that you want to. I had this initially with Song Of Farca. It almost kept me from playing it further, until I came back at it with a different attitude instead, thanks to a few conversations I've had lately about player choice versus narrative.
You play as Izy Song, a hacking-based private investigator in a fictional, dystopian island in the near future. And she's kind of a fool.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 11 za 16,66  € nebo Windows 10 za pouhých 12,52  €]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-11-za-16-66-nebo-windows-10-za-pouhych-12-52</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-11-za-16-66-nebo-windows-10-za-pouhych-12-52"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Získejte doživotní licenci Windows 11 za pouhých 16,66  €, Windows 10 za pouhých 12,52  €. Opět jde o finančně velmi výhodnou nabídku prodejního portálu GoodOffer24.com, kde lze najít kromě nástrojů produktivity také hry, ale i další softwarové produkty.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PinePhone Pro Announced As New Linux Smartphone]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PinePhone-Pro</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PinePhone-Pro"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PinePhone Pro is being announced this morning as the organization's new smartphone building upon the successes and experience of the original PinePhone Linux smartphone...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to play Far Cry 6 in co-op multiplayer mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-co-op-multiplayer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-co-op-multiplayer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:57:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to play Far Cry 6 in co-op multiplayer? Ubisoft's bombastic open-world FPS franchise is always best played with company. Double the players, double the devastation, after all. And Far Cry 6 has taken after its predecessors in offering players a couple of different ways to play the game in co-op. Whether you're looking for self-contained co-op missions or you want to play through the entire story with a friend, read on to find out how to set up Far Cry 6 for multiplayer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 bude Jammy Jellyfish]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-22.04-bude-jammy-jellyfish</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-22.04-bude-jammy-jellyfish"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:46:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 bude Jammy Jellyfish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crysis 2 & 3 Remastered are out now, making the trilogy maximum shiny]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-2-3-remastered-are-out-now-making-the-trilogy-maximum-shiny</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-2-3-remastered-are-out-now-making-the-trilogy-maximum-shiny"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:33:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All three games of the Crytek's super-powered shooter trilogy are now available fancied up with modern graphical bells and whistles, with Crysis 2 Remastered and Crysis 3 Remastered today following the first game's 2020 revamp. Given that developers Crytek were always years ahead of most shooters in shininess, the originals hardly look hideous but hey, you can pay for extra fancieness. The first game was always the best though.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Compute-Runtime 21.41.21220 Ships Updated DG1 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Compute-21.41.21220</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Compute-21.41.21220"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source engineers have shipped Compute-Runtime 21.41.21220 as the newest version of this Linux compute stack enabling OpenCL and Level Zero support with their graphics processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sysinternals Sysmon pro Linux]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/sysinternals-sysmon-pro-linux</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/sysinternals-sysmon-pro-linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:06:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt Sysinternals, tj. technické informace, nástroje pro diagnostiku, monitorování a hledání chyb v Microsoft Windows, včera slavil 25 let. Při této příležitosti byl představen Sysinternals Sysmon pro Linux. Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitHubu. Další informace v příspěvku na blogu Microsoft Tech Community.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AV1 Codec Library libaom v3.2 Brings More Performance Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AV1-libaom-3.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AV1-libaom-3.2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:31:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Libaom 3.2 is now available as the latest version of the official AOMedia/Google-developed AV1 Codec Library. With libaom 3.2 comes compression efficiency improvements, perceptual quality improvements, and a variety of speed-ups and memory optimizations...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD konečně zapíná ve výchozím stavu Panel Self Refresh pro nové APU v jádře 5.16]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42912</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-konecne-zapina-ve-vychozim-stavu-panel-self-refresh-pro-nove-apu-v-jadre-5-16/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:29:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Panel Self Refresh (PSR) je vlastnost DisplayPortu, která při statickém obrazu umožňuje snížení spotřeby. AMD konečně zapíná ve výchozím stavu PSR pro nové integrované grafické karty DCN v jádře 5.16.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft vydal Sysmon pro Linux]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42911</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/microsoft-vydal-sysmon-pro-linux/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sysmon (system monitor) je nástroj od Sysinternals pro monitorování systémové aktivity a odhalení škodlivých programů. Včera Mark Russinovich z Microsoftu (je spoluzakladatel Sysinternals, který později Microsoft koupil) oznámil Sysmon pro Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rally Point: how to pay the deposit and enjoy playing strategy games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rally-point-how-to-pay-the-deposit-and-enjoy-playing-strategy-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rally-point-how-to-pay-the-deposit-and-enjoy-playing-strategy-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Strategy games are, as everyone knows, much like moving house. Whether it's your first, daunting one and you don't yet know that the whole "most stressful thing in life" line is a total lie, or you stopped counting house moves after your 15th, there's one obstacle that never stops getting in the way: the deposit.

You know you can pay it, theoretically. You could gather together the energy and focus it takes. It is not beyond you to learn how a new game works and take the time to situate yourself within its world. But doing it all at once? Right now? Ach. Now you're asking.
That's the deposit. And it prevents you from playing games you'd love.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Warzone's shiny new anti-cheat might have leaked already]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-warzones-shiny-new-anti-cheat-might-have-leaked-already</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-warzones-shiny-new-anti-cheat-might-have-leaked-already"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T11:48:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week, Activision revealed Ricochet, their new kernel-level anti-cheat that will be used for Call Of Duty: Vanguard and Warzone. They've been in a constant battle with cheaters for ages now, so it's nice to see them stepping up their anti-cheat game. Unfortunately, Ricochet might have already leaked, and it's claimed cheat-makers are currently working on reverse-engineering it. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gitlab CI: automatizujte přímo v Gitlabu (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-38836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gitlab-ci-automatizujte-primo-v-gitlabu-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T11:32:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automatizace pomocí continuous integration přímo v Gitlabu. CI vám pomůže automatizovat rutinní procesy a ušetří vám hromadu času. Pomůže vám od automatického testování, buildy po nasazování. Chcete vědět víc? Přijďte na naše školení GitLab CI, které se uskuteční 18. listopadu a proběhne plně online. Školí Ondřej Sika.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Jim build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-jim</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-jim"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T10:59:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Jim in Back 4 Blood? Jim is quick to take aim and fire thanks to his increased ADS speed, but damage is his real strength. With each precision kill, Jim gains 2.5% stacking damage, which stays until you are hit. This means you could increase Jim’s damage to ridiculous levels if you avoid damage. Oh, and he also gets a 10% boost to team weakspot damage, so it shouldn’t come as a surprise that Jim deserves a spot on your team in Back 4 Blood.
This guide will show you everything that you need to know to make the best Jim build in Back 4 Blood.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cluster Scheduler Support Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Cluster-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Cluster-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T10:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cluster scheduler support has been queued up for landing in the Linux 5.16 kernel for AArch64 and x86_64 systems for improving the CPU scheduler behavior for systems that have clusters of CPU cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gears Tactics and Dirty Bomb devs working on a new sci-fi game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gears-tactics-and-dirty-bomb-devs-working-on-a-new-sci-fi-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gears-tactics-and-dirty-bomb-devs-working-on-a-new-sci-fi-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T10:22:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Splash Damage, the folks who made Gears Tactics and Brink, have announced they're working on a new sci-fi game. They've worked on a number of series created by other developers over the years, including Wolfenstein and Gears, but haven't made their own PC game since Dirty Bomb in 2014. It'll be interesting to see what they have in store - perhaps a first-person shooter like Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory? Or maybe something more strategic, given Gears Tactics' success.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SALSA Back In Development As A Small ALSA Library For Linux Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SALSA-Linux-Audio-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SALSA-Linux-Audio-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T10:03:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux sound subsystem maintainer Takashi Iwai of SUSE is back to hacking on SALSA, the "small ALSA" library that he started a decade ago but hadn't seen a new release in six years or any code activity for the past four years... until this week...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Hoffman build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-hoffman</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-hoffman"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T09:59:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Hoffman in Back 4 Blood? Hoffman is one of the best characters in Back 4 Blood, as he has a chance to find ammo when he kills Ridden, whilst also increasing the team’s max ammo capacity by 10%. As a bonus, he also carries an extra grenade so that you can make more zombies go boom.
This guide will show you everything you need to know to make the best Hoffman build in Back 4 Blood. However, don't expect to play as Hoffman straight away. You'll need to actually unlock all of the cleaners in Back 4 Blood first.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop's first "major" update fixes stuttering, adds DLSS support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloops-first-major-update-fixes-stuttering-adds-dlss-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloops-first-major-update-fixes-stuttering-adds-dlss-support"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T09:52:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exactly one month after launch, Deathloop received its "first major game update" last night. Along with (hopefully?) fixing lingering issues with stuttering framerates, it has added DLSS support to give Nvidia folks a big FPS boost, fixed some crashes and other bugs, including a nasty one where a bad menu option would reset Colt's progress, and generally improved things. And this is the point where I think I'll finally play the game.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Finally Enabling PSR By Default For Newer Hardware With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Linux-5.16-PSR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Linux-5.16-PSR"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T09:33:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With it getting late into the Linux 5.15 kernel cycle, the focus is shifting by the Direct Rendering Driver maintainers from new feature work targeting the next cycle (5.16) to instead on bug fixes. AMD sent out a pull request of new AMDGPU Linux 5.16 material this week that is primarily delivering bug fixes but one notable addition is finally enabling PSR by default for newer GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strawberry 1.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/strawberry-1.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/strawberry-1.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T08:42:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Správce sbírky a přehrávač hudby Strawberry, fork Clementine, duchovního nástupce původního Amaroku z KDE 3.x, dospěl k vydání 1.0.0. Používá Qt 6, doplňuje několik funkcí včetně podpory ALSA PCM zařízení a unikátní identifikace souborů ve sbírce.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extrémní přetaktování Raspberry Pi CM 4 na 3 GHz]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42910</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/extremni-pretaktovani-raspberry-pi-cm-4-na-3-ghz/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T07:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Claude Schwarz ve středu zveřejnil výsledek extrémního přetaktování Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4 až na 3 GHz.  K dosažení takového výsledku bylo potřeba odstranit víčko SoC a nahradit vodivou pastu lepším tekutým kovem Thermal Grizzly Conductonaut (obsahuje galium, cín a indium).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The "What If" Performance Cost To Kernel Page Table Isolation On AMD CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30613</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30613"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Made public this week by CPU security researchers at Graz University of Technology and CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security was the research paper published "AMD Prefetch Attacks through Power and Time". The paper points to AMD CPUs suffering from a side-channel leakage vulnerability through timing and power variations of the PREFETCH instruction. The paper argues that AMD CPUs should activate stronger page table isolation by default. AMD has now published their security response where they are not recommending any mitigation changes at this time. But what if Kernel Page Table Isolation (KPTI/PTI) proves necessary for AMD CPUs? Here are some initial benchmarks showing what that performance impact could look like.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unsolved Math Problems]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2529/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2529/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2 Resurrected's servers falling over due to "modern player behaviour"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrecteds-servers-falling-over-due-to-modern-player-behaviour</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrecteds-servers-falling-over-due-to-modern-player-behaviour"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T23:21:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo II: Resurrected launched to widespread and ongoing server issues. Today, a Blizzard community manager offered some insight into the nature of the problem - and it's partly some 20-year-old code, and partly some modern player behaviour.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FIFA reportedly wants double the old licence fee from EA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fifa-reportedly-wants-double-the-old-licence-fee-from-ea</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fifa-reportedly-wants-double-the-old-licence-fee-from-ea"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T22:09:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, EA said they were considering renaming FIFA, their long-running football series. The issue is that their licensing deal with football's world governing body is up for renewal. Now a report by the New York Times says that the issue is that FIFA want double what they were getting before for EA to continue using the name.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adobe Flash ještě není mrtvý: firma dál tvrdě potírá související projekty]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15713</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/adobe-flash-jeste-neni-mrtvy-firma-dal-tvrde-potira-souvisejici-projekty/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adobe už léta hlásá konec Flashe. Dokonce i oficiálně začátkem roku 2021 skončil. Přesto právníci Adobe využívají DMCA, aby vynutili konec alternativního projektu instalátoru Flashe v čínské variantě.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dungeon Encounters is out now, offering encounters in dungeons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dungeon-encounters-is-out-now-offering-encounters-in-dungeons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dungeon-encounters-is-out-now-offering-encounters-in-dungeons"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:28:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes a functional game strikes me as bland or forgettable. Dungeon Encounters appeals to me, oddly. I look at this game about exploring 99 levels of a dungeon, fighting enemies using an iteration of Final Fantasy's Active Time Battle System, designed by the man who created it, and I think: yes, you should be called Dungeon Encounters.

It's out now, and there's a new launch trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard's Zombie mode shows new supernatural powers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-zombie-mode-shows-new-supernatural-powers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-zombie-mode-shows-new-supernatural-powers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T21:08:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard has finally revealed its zombie mode. It continues the zombies storyline from the Black Ops series, returning to WW2, where you'll be fighting Nazi zombies with the aid of new 'Dark Aether' powers. The reveal trailer is below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is this the cheapest 4TB SSD ever? $312 for a Samsung 870 Qvo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/is-this-the-cheapest-4tb-ssd-ever-312-for-a-samsung-870-qvo</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/is-this-the-cheapest-4tb-ssd-ever-312-for-a-samsung-870-qvo"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T20:20:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The massive 4TB Samsung 870 Qvo has hit a historic low price at Newegg, where you can use code EMCXHEHU2 to knock this drive from $390 to just $312. That's an incredible price for a high-speed SATA SSD, just 8¢ per gigabyte (!!). 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Impish Indri přináší Wayland na kartách Nvidia]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42909</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-21-10-impish-indri-prinasi-wayland-na-kartach-nvidia/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T20:15:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podle plánu vyšla nová verze Ubuntu 21.10 s kódovým jménem Impish Indri. Toto vydání bude podporováno devět měsíců, tedy do července 2022. Kromě hlavní verze Ubuntu jsou k dispozici také všechny oficiální odnože: Kubuntu, Lubuntu, Ubuntu Budgie, Ubuntu Kylin, Ubuntu MATE, Ubuntu Studio a Xubuntu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devuan 4.0 Chimaera je Debian 11 Bullseye bez systemd]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42908</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/devuan-4-0-chimaera-je-debian-11-bullseye-bez-systemd/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T20:01:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rok a čtvrt po předchozím vydání je k dispozici nová verze distribuce Devuan s označením 4.0 a kódovým jménem Chimaera. Ten je postaven na čerstvém Debianu 11 Bullseye a vynechává z instalace závislost na systemd. Místo něj je možné si vybrat mezi SysVInit, Runit nebo OpenRC.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo's Legion 5 Pro RTX 3070 laptop is back in stock and 10% off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lenovos-legion-5-pro-rtx-3070-laptop-is-back-in-stock-and-10-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lenovos-legion-5-pro-rtx-3070-laptop-is-back-in-stock-and-10-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T19:44:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo's Legion 5 Pro 16 hits the current sweet spot for a high-end gaming laptop: an RTX 3070 graphics card, an AMD Ryzen 7 5800H processor and a 2560x1600 165Hz screen. These screens are a new addition for 2021, and make a massive difference when it comes to the amount of visible detail for playing games or just browsing the web.
This particular laptop has been out of stock for some time, but it's finally returned to Lenovo's online store - and you can get it for 10% off when you sign up to Lenovo's email newsletter. That knocks £150 off the price, bringing this high-spec laptop to £1350.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 RC2 Brings Fix For Mixed VRR/Non-VRR Multi-Monitor Setups]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-RC2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-RC2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T19:36:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 continues running slightly behind schedule but out today is a second release candidate of that upcoming xorg-server version -- the first in more than three years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox considered cancelling Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-considered-cancelling-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-considered-cancelling-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T19:22:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Paradox Interactive made the remarkable decision to take Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 away from its original developers, Hardsuit Labs, the company considered outright cancelling the game. That's according to returning CEO Fredrik Wester in a recent interview. Paradox still aren't saying who's making the World Of Darkness RPG now nor when it will be done, but apparently it's still happening?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devuan 4.0 Released As Debian 11 Without Systemd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Devuan-4.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Devuan-4.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:46:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Devuan 4.0 "Chimaera" is officially out today as the latest stable release of this Linux distribution known for being a close rebuild of Debian but without a dependence on systemd...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 has added a Sorcerer class and new region in latest patch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-has-added-a-sorcerer-class-and-new-region-in-latest-patch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-has-added-a-sorcerer-class-and-new-region-in-latest-patch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:37:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Baldur's Gate 3 continues its adventure through early access, the fantasy RPG from the makers of Divinity: Original Sin has whacked in a load of newness. Patch 6 hit today to continue the story, add a Sorcerer class, open the new region called Grymforge, and spruce up the graphics. Some might focus on those big features, me I'm all about a little one: a Sorcerer spell which lets you turn characters tiny or giant. We'll see who's a tadpole now!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweat, Shar and sorcerers make for a killer new update for Baldur’s Gate 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sweat-shar-and-sorcerers-make-for-a-killer-new-update-for-baldurs-gate-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sweat-shar-and-sorcerers-make-for-a-killer-new-update-for-baldurs-gate-3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Larian put blood, sweat and tears into Baldur’s Gate 3’s latest patch. I mean, they’ve literally put them in: venture into the scorching heat of a subterranean forge and you’ll see a greasy sheen on your hero’s face during conversational close-ups. Get blood spattered on you in battle and it’ll remain until you take a long rest to wash it away. Same goes for dirt, and bruises that bloom at low health. “We want you to feel you’ve been adventuring a bit,” says lead systems designer Nick Pechenin, “rather than just stepping out of a modelling agency.”


If he’d seen the potato-faced oddballs I’ve repeatedly made in character creation (saves are not compatible between big patches) Pechenin would not be so generous. Even so, I like seeing heroes wearing evidence of their travels. An earlier patch already made the camping system feel more demanding - a small price in food means you can’t just spam it after every fight - and now those longer treks between naps can visually sell you on the difficult journey heroes are undertaking, too. A journey that, with patch six, has gotten a little longer.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ElecHead review: a clever puzzle platformer with real spark]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elechead-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elechead-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T16:35:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ElecHead is one of those devilishly clever puzzle platformers that delights at every turn. Developed by solo dev NamaTakahashi, you play as the titular Elec, a tiny robot whose body can electrify whatever surface he touches, causing it to light up a dazzling shade of yellow in the dark halls of a strange, underground facility. 
Technically, it's his head where his electrical currents stem from, which you quickly learn how to throw in order to flip switches from afar, create new platforms and dodge deadly obstacles in order to get from one side of the room to the other. The catch? Elec's body only has ten seconds of power left when he's without his head, causing him to explode if he doesn't reach it in time. The result is a stunningly good puzzle game whose bank of brilliantly conceived ideas is executed to perfection, and it left me with a big fat grin on my face for the whole of its three hour run-time.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 secret ending]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-secret-ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-secret-ending"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:46:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to get the secret ending in Far Cry 6? If you've played previous entries in Ubisoft's long-running open-world FPS series, you'll likely have come to expect a secret ending somewhere early on. But fittingly for a game of this scale, in Far Cry 6 the secret ending comes not right at the very beginning, but a few hours into the game once everything starts to open up. Keep reading to learn exactly what to do to unlock Far Cry 6's secret ending.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Windows 11 update made AMD performance even worse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-windows-11-update-made-amd-performance-even-worse</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-windows-11-update-made-amd-performance-even-worse"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:45:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The problems keep coming for Windows 11. Besides missing gaming features and a vote of no confidence by cloud PC providers, perhaps the worst of it has been a bug that drastically increases L3 cache latency on most AMD chips. That includes some of the best CPUs for gaming, like the Ryzen 5 5600X, and while both AMD and Microsoft have promised fixes, an unrelated Windows 11 update appears to have made the problem even worse.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 160: the best cities special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-episode-160-the-best-cities-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-episode-160-the-best-cities-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:25:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week the Electronic Wireless Show podcast is going the place you can always go when you're alone and life is making you lonely. That's right: down town! We're talking about our favourite cities in games, although we spend a lot of time talking about city builders even though we decide they probably don't meet the brief.
Surprisingly, though, we talk about games so much this week that we run out of time to do a Cavern Of Lies! Even though I had actually prepared one! Unprecedented scenes. Don't worry, though, because there are plenty of diversions this week too, including Nate's unwise excursion into green milk, and Matthew eating something he shouldn't ought to have ate.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Doc build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-doc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-doc"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Doc in Back 4 Blood? Doc is the resident healer in Back 4 Blood, so she takes on a supportive role like Mom. Doc’s passive bonuses allow her to heal each teammate for 25 health once per level, whilst also increasing her healing efficiency and the team’s trauma resistance. However, you'll need to know how to unlock all cleaners in Back 4 Blood before you can select Doc in your campaign.
This guide will show you everything that you need to know to create the best Doc build in Back 4 Blood, so that you can keep your teammates at the top of their game.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042's Hazard Zone mode strikes me as a bit Hunt: Showdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042s-hazard-zone-mode-strikes-me-as-a-bit-hunt-showdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042s-hazard-zone-mode-strikes-me-as-a-bit-hunt-showdown"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:01:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiplayer FPS Battlefield 2042's Conquest and Breakthrough modes are largely about shooting bullets across vast distances on a vast map while trying to capture a vast number of objectives. They are vast, mate. But the newly revealed Hazard Zone mode? Nope, this is smaller, more survival-oriented, with a hint of Hunt: Showdown.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Good Life review: tonally stupid, structurally broken, surprisingly deep and occasionally self-aware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-good-life-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-good-life-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Good Life – which has nothing to do with the 1970s British television show about a couple of doom-prepping swingers who owned an allotment in Surbiton – is a colourful open world adventure in which you play an investigative photographer charged with uncovering the secrets of an idyllic English town.


Like so many of Swery’s previous games, most notably Deadly Premonition, The Good Life is characteristically goofy and haphazard. It can be broadly categorised as a daily life simulator — in the vein of Stardew Valley and Animal Crossing, but not like either of those — with a Pokémon Snap style camera mechanic in which you take photographs of interesting things and people about town for kudos and cash rewards. You can also turn into a dog or a cat whenever you like.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Hogarty</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liquid cooling vs air cooling: which is better?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/liquid-cooling-vs-air-cooling-which-is-better</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/liquid-cooling-vs-air-cooling-which-is-better"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:55:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like just about everything else in your PC, the CPU can get very hot, very quickly. That’s why not even the best CPUs are complete without a dedicated cooler, but which of the two main types are better: liquid coolers or air coolers?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Released With GNOME 40 Desktop, Many Underlying Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:53:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 "Impish Indri" is now officially available as the latest six-month update to Ubuntu Linux and also serving as the last release prior to the next long-term support cycle, Ubuntu 22.04 LTS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenBSD 7.0 přináší podporu pro 64bitové procesory RISC-V]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42902</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/openbsd-7-0-prinasi-podporu-pro-64bitove-procesory-risc-v/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:53:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili novou verzi operačního systému OpenBSD s číselným označením 7.0. Zatímco budete stahovat čerstvé obrazy, můžete si přečíst o hlavních změnách, které nová verze přináší. Především je to nová platforma risc64 pro 64bitové procesory RISC-V. Plně podporována je zatím jen jediná deska HiFive Unmatched, ale na dalších se pracuje.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 Rides: all four Ride locations and how to unlock them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-rides</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-rides"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for more Far Cry 6 Rides to unlock? There is a huge variety of cars and other vehicles to hijack and take back to Vehicle Dropoff Points in Far Cry 6, but none of them compare to the four Rides that you can unlock. These heavily modified cars are the pride of your collection, and can be customised and fitted with all sorts of powerful guns and other armaments.
Below you'll find out how to unlock all four Rides in Far Cry 6. Once you know the locations, you can easily go round and unlock them all in 20 minutes or so. So let's get driving!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 495 Linux Beta Driver Released With GBM Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-495.29.05-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-495.29.05-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T13:36:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 495.29.05 is out today as the first public Linux driver in the 495 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenBSD 7.0 Released With RISC-V 64-bit Port, Better Apple Silicon Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenBSD-7.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenBSD-7.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T13:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not only is Ubuntu 21.10 releasing today but over on the BSD side of the table is the debut this morning of OpenBSD 7.0...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This new battle royale is an FMV game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-new-battle-royale-is-an-fmv-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-new-battle-royale-is-an-fmv-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:38:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just when you thought we'd seen every possible permutation of battle royale, here comes the strangest form yet: a movie. An interactive movie, specifically. Bloodshore will drop our laaad onto an island to fight for big money in murderous reality show Kill/Stream, with our decisions pushing the story down different paths and affecting relationships with other contestants. What's next, a battle royale novel?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mega65: moderní verze nikdy nevydaného Commodore 65]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42907</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mega65-moderni-verze-nikdy-nevydaneho-commodore-65/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:15:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Počítač Commodore 65 byl nikdy nevydaným nástupcem legendárního Commodore 64. Byl vyvinut mezi lety 1990 a 1991 a mělo jít o nejvýkonnější 8bitový počítač na trhu – měl 128K RAM, grafiku s rozlišením až 1280×400, stereo zvuk a 3,5" disketovou mechaniku.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo 2 and Halo 3 have official modding tools now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-2-and-halo-3-have-official-moding-tools-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-2-and-halo-3-have-official-moding-tools-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T11:38:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fancy tweaking some Halo games to make some cool or cursed content? Then good news! Yesterday, developers 343 industries released modding tools for Halo 2 and Halo 3 alongside the Master Chief Collection's season 8 update. Halo: Combat Evolved got its own official modding tools back in June, and the new tools for 2 and 3 offer similar programs for modders to mess with. I look forward to seeing what good stuff they make.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Mom build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-mom</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-mom"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T11:19:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Mom in Back 4 Blood? Mom is one of the best characters in Back 4 Blood, with the ability to instantly revive a teammate once per level. She also grants the team an extra life and has an increased support inventory, which you can use for bandages, painkillers, or other medicinal goodies that you find on your zombie-stomping adventures.
With our Mom build, we push these supportive capabilities to the limit. Mom won't be able to match more combat-focused characters like Walker when fighting the undead, but she'll definitely pull you back from the brink of death and defeat. This guide will show you how to make the best Mom build in Back 4 Blood.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Live-action System Shock show planned for a new streaming site]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/live-action-system-shock-show-planned-for-a-new-streaming-site</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/live-action-system-shock-show-planned-for-a-new-streaming-site"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T10:33:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As if they weren't busy enough remaking System Shock, Nightdive Studio have announced plans for a live-action web TV series based on Looking Glass's sci-fi FPS. It'd be headed to Binge, an upcoming gaming-focused streaming platform which also has plans for a Driver series. Yeah yeah, but who's gonna play Shodan?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox Squid Game: the best Squid Game experiences in Roblox]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-squid-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-squid-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T10:16:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are the best Squid Game experiences on Roblox? Odds are you're at least somewhat aware of Squid Game, the Netflix original thriller that came out of nowhere and has been taking the world by storm since its first season released on September 17th. If you've somehow missed it, suffice to say that it's a fictional TV show about a group of desperate people participating in a series of six deadly children's games — so, naturally, the video game imitations have already started to roll in, largely courtesy of Roblox.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAlt zveřejnil program letošní online konference, proběhne 6. a 7. listopadu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42906</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/openalt-zverejnil-program-letosni-online-konference-probehne-6-a-7-listopadu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T09:19:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Konference OpenAlt zveřejnila svůj rozsáhlý program rozdělený do čtyř samostatných paralelních skupin (tracků). Letošní ročník proběhne opět online a ve znamení otevřených a alternativních řešení a nových možností pro každý den, které řeší nebo otevírají moderní technologie dnešního světa.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NÚKIB: české vzdělávací instituce hlásí více útoků, ransomware je zpět]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42905</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nukib-ceske-vzdelavaci-instituce-hlasi-vice-utoku-ransomware-je-zpet/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T09:02:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Národní úřad pro kybernetickou a informační bezpečnost (NÚKIB) vydal zprávu o kybernetických incidentech [PDF] pokrývající září letošního roku. Z hlediska počtu incidentů jde o nejklidnější měsíc letošního roku, přesto si zpráva všímá zajímavých trendů. Jednak jsou zpět útoky pomocí ransomware a jednoznačně také přibývá incidentů na české vzdělávací instituce.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Silverlight je mrtev, ať žije OpenSilver]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42904</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/silverlight-je-mrtev-at-zije-opensilver/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T08:04:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft oficiálně ukončil podporu platformy Silverlight, která byla určena pro běh komplexních webových aplikací. Mělo jít o přímou konkurenci k Adobe Flash, který ale ve své době jednoznačně v prohlížečích kraloval. Přesto zřejmě existuje řada aplikací, které Silverlight využívají a ty již není možné v současných prohlížečích používat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riders Republic is most fun when it turns into a platformer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-is-most-fun-when-it-turns-into-a-platformer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-is-most-fun-when-it-turns-into-a-platformer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having given Riders Republic a go over its free-to-play day, I can confirm that it really leans into Ubisoft's current obsession. Splashes of yellow and pink with the word "Blamo!" graffitied over the top, that whole thing. This is a Forza Horizon-esque trip, only you're not going to a pleasant festival in a car, you're going to an extreme sports resort with a roving band of TikTokers.
Swerve through the cringe on your bike, though, and there's some decent fun to be had. And for me, this wasn't so much in the game's fast and furious moments, but when it slowed the pace right down and transformed into a platformer of sorts.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Desktopové prostředí KDE slaví 25. narozeniny]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42903</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/desktopove-prostredi-kde-slavi-25-narozeniny/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T07:48:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Přesně před čtvrt stoletím, tedy 14. října 1996, odeslal Matthias Ettrich do linuxové diskusní skupiny dlouhou zprávu, ve které oznámil vznik nového projektu Kool Desktop Environment (KDE). V ní napsal, že popularita unixových operačních systémů roste, ale chybí pořádné desktopové prostředí. Uvědomoval si, že existuje řada správců oken a různých grafických knihoven, ale žádné ucelené prostředí pro práci.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former State Of Decay founder launches new studio Possibility Space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-state-of-decay-founder-launches-new-studio-possibility-space</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/former-state-of-decay-founder-launches-new-studio-possibility-space"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T23:14:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jeff Strain—co-founder of Guild Wars studio ArenaNet and founder of State Of Decay studio Undead Labs—is now founding a new game studio once again. Strain's studio Possibility Space has already drawn in a group of leadership talent worth paying attention to with history at the likes of Valve, Electronic Arts, Ubisoft, BioWare, Double Fine, and more. Possibility Space doesn't have a game to announce just yet, but is hiring up for their first "joyful game" that Strain describes as his "dream for many years."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's fast Ryzen 9 5900X CPU has hit new lows at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amds-superbly-fast-ryzen-9-5900x-is-467-at-amazon</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amds-superbly-fast-ryzen-9-5900x-is-467-at-amazon"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:48:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: The price has dropped further on the 5900X, with the chip now costing £453 at Amazon. Original article continues below... 
The AMD Ryzen 9 5900X is the company's latest high-end consumer processor, offering 12 cores and 24 threads using the incredibly fast Zen 3 design. AMD's latest generation CPUs have made incredible strides against Intel*, and are now often the best choice for both gaming and content creation - an unthinkable situation just five years ago when Ryzen first launched. 
The 5900X has been the hardest Ryzen 5000 model to find at a good price, thanks to low supply and incredible demand, but today you can pick one up for a significant discount - £43 below RRP, or £466.92. That's a great price for a CPU of this quality, especially in the middle of a silicon shortage.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our 'best premium gaming headset' pick, Logitech's G Pro X, is £63 today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-logitech-g-pro-x-is-our-best-premium-gaming-headset-and-its-just-63-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-logitech-g-pro-x-is-our-best-premium-gaming-headset-and-its-just-63-today"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:24:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Logitech G Pro X is a fantastic headset - a comfy and well-built premium option that sounds fantastic. Today, it's not so premium any more, as Currys has discounted the headset from its original RRP of £110 to just £62.99 - a massive bargain. To get that price, you'll need to use code FNDDGAMING at the checkout. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision introduce Call Of Duty's upcoming Ricochet Anti-Cheat system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-introduce-call-of-dutys-upcoming-ricochet-anti-cheat-system</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-introduce-call-of-dutys-upcoming-ricochet-anti-cheat-system"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:04:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As it goes in online competitive games, Activision are in a constant battle against cheaters in Call Of Duty games. They've banned more than half a million cheaters in Call Of Duty: Warzone and yet there are always more. They've announced a new tool to help crack down: their Ricochet Anti-Cheat system. When it launches in Warzone and Call Of Duty: Vanguard it will include server-side tools along with a kernel-level driver to monitor applications interacting with the game.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KEY Trainings: Je OpenShift tou správnou volbou?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/key-trainings-je-openshift-tou-spravnou-volbou</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/key-trainings-je-openshift-tou-spravnou-volbou"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShift je platforma pro provoz kontejnerů ve firemním prostředí. Usnadňuje standardizaci provozu vašich aplikací a současně zjednodušuje provoz a zvyšuje bezpečnost a spolehlivost provozu. Umožňuje vám přidělit vybraná oprávnění např. dodavatelským firmám a mít tak pod kontrolou větší část nebo celý vývojový cyklus aplikací. Současně vám přináší jednotný způsob monitoringu a sběru logů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nasazujeme Knot DNS na vlastní doméně: praktický návod]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15712</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/nasazujeme-knot-dns-na-vlastni-domene-prakticky-navod/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Uživatelé se často ptají, jak zprovoznit vlastní DNS server. Na praktických příkladech si tedy přiblížíme základy i pokročilejší možnosti Knot DNS, autoritativního serveru z dílen českého sdružení CZ.NIC.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Daniel Salzman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vestavěné objekty Small Basicu: práce s grafikou, časovačem, reakce na události]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15711</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/vestavene-objekty-small-basicu-prace-s-grafikou-casovacem-reakce-na-udalosti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve druhém a současně i závěrečném článku o Small Basicu si ukážeme práci s vestavěnými objekty, zejména s grafickým oknem. Taktéž si popíšeme želví grafiku a systém událostí (a reakcí na ně). Zmíníme se i o alternativně ke Small Basicu, jímž je Basic-256.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact version 2.2 is here with a new island and your free 5-star Aloy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-version-22-is-here-with-a-new-island-and-your-free-5-star-aloy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-version-22-is-here-with-a-new-island-and-your-free-5-star-aloy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T20:11:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As it does, action and explore 'em up Genshin Impact has rolled out another game update adding more characters, weapons, a domain, and a new island too. Genshin Impact version 2.2 has launched today, opening up more of that new Inazuma area and bringing its first crossover character Aloy of Horizon Zero Dawn fame to the game. You can hop into the new update titled "Into the Perilous Labyrinth of Fog" as of today to get started on all the new activities.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyper Light Drifter developer's next game Solar Ash delayed to December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hyper-light-drifter-developers-next-game-solar-ash-delayed-to-december</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hyper-light-drifter-developers-next-game-solar-ash-delayed-to-december"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T18:37:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Solar Ash is the next action-y adventure from the folks behind Hyper Light Drifter, which they've described as "Super Mario Galaxy meets Shadow Of The Colossus, and sprinkle in a bit of Jet Set Radio." It was coming up quite soon, and ranked on RPS's list of best games in October to look forward to thanks to that colourful world and skater-like movement. The monthly list has taken a hit again, as there's a bit longer to wait for it now. Heart Machine have just announced a delay, though fortunately a short one.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battle royale Naraka: Bladepoint is adding a 1v1 mode tomorrow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battle-royale-naraka-bladepoint-is-adding-a-1v1-mode-tomorrow</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battle-royale-naraka-bladepoint-is-adding-a-1v1-mode-tomorrow"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T16:33:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After launching in August, mostly-melee battle royale 'em up Naraka: Bladepoint rated on RPS's list of best battle royale games for its parkour and grabble hook fights. If you're all about the battle and less about the royale, Naraka is queueing up a new game mode for you. The new 1v1 mode is inspired by and named after the movie Bloodsport, pitting sixteen players against one another in an elimination tourney until just one emerges as the winner. Naraka's new Bloodsport mode is kicking off tomorrow for you to go face to face and sword to sword with solo challengers.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim's Anniversary Edition might break many mods badly, modder warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrims-anniversary-edition-might-break-many-mods-badly-modder-warns</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrims-anniversary-edition-might-break-many-mods-badly-modder-warns"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T16:28:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[November may bring an unpleasant surprise for Skyrim Special Edition players, as one prolific modder has warned that changes in an update will mean a large part of Skyrim modding "is going to be broken for an unknown length of time". While it's common for updates to break mods, supposedly this will require a whole lot more work than usual to get back on track. And there's a risk some will never be fixed.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demon Slayer: The Hinokami Chronicles review: simple, unfiltered fun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/demon-slayer-kimetsu-no-yaiba-the-hinokami-chronicles-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love a bit of anime fighting. The darting back and forth over a battlefield the size of a small town, the gravity-defying jumps through the air, the razing of entire cities with the flick of a thumb, the volume of someone’s yell equating to their increase in power - it’s all equal parts enrapturing melodrama and total lunacy. 


Demon Slayer -Kimetsu no Yaiba- The Hinokami Chronicles gets this. It gets that, when I am playing a 3D fighting game adapting a popular manga, I really want to inhabit the part of an incredibly wholesome anime boy, journeying across feudal Japan to cure my younger sister of her demonic sickness and smack around some otherworldly folk on the way there. Tanjiro Kamado is about as pure as anime protagonists come, and if there’s one lovable anime lad whose shoes I had to step into, it’d probably be his.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hirun Cryer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s the AMD Radeon RX 6600, and where to buy it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-rx-6600-announced</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-rx-6600-announced"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T15:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD have finally launched the Radeon RX 6600, the new entry-level model (which is still kind of a mid-ranger) in the RX 6000 graphics cards series. As expected, it’s a tuned-down relative of the Radeon RX 6600 XT, with fewer cores and lower clock speeds – but the same 8GB of GDDR6 VRAM. As far as I can see, it’s also sold out immediately, despite just releasing with models from Asus, MSI, Gigabyte, XFX, PowerColor and more. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding zen in rally sim WRC 10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/finding-zen-in-rally-sim-wrc-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/finding-zen-in-rally-sim-wrc-10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T15:09:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it called rally driving or rally racing? Oh, it's neither of these options: it's called rallying. As you can see, I'm no expert on the act of flinging cars around dirt tracks. The only experience I've got is watching other people do so rather beautifully. In fact, that's what inspired me to give rally simulator WRC 10 a whirl and finally learn how to drive, drive.
But what I've really learned is terrible, actually. I've learned to totally ignore the bloke who sits next to you and dictates corners. I've learned not to pay attention at all. I'm in my own head, thinking back to that Greek yoghurt I just had. And I'm driving superbly. If I concentrate for even just a second my drive goes to shambles. So long as I find zen, I'm in control.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Holly build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-holly</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-holly"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T14:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best build for Holly in Back 4 Blood? Holly is our own Alice Bee’s favourite character, and with very good reason. Holly recovers 10 stamina each time she kills a Ridden, gets +10% damage resistance, and even gives the whole team an extra 25 stamina. However, with the right cards, you can push Holly even further, making her an absolute powerhouse and solidifying her position as one of the best characters in Back 4 Blood.
This guide will show you how to create the best build for Holly in Back 4 Blood, so you can dive into a session and start punching, stabbing, and smacking Ridden with your choice of melee weapon.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now a union has objected to Activision Blizzard's settlement too]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/now-a-union-has-objected-to-activision-blizzards-settlement-too</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/now-a-union-has-objected-to-activision-blizzards-settlement-too"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T14:29:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Communications Workers Of America union (CWA) have filed an objection to the proposed settlement between Activision Blizzard and the USA's Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC). As part of the settlement to this, one of several current legal battles, ActiBliz have agreed to create an $18 million fund for those who experienced harm from "sexual harassment, pregnancy discrimination and/or related retaliation". But the CWA says there are "a number of serious deficiencies" with the agreement, and are requesting a fairness hearing to address them. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh my god, Fallout 3 has removed Games For Windows Live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-my-god-fallout-3-has-removed-games-for-windows-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oh-my-god-fallout-3-has-removed-games-for-windows-live"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:17:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 13 years, Fallout 3 has finally removed Microsoft's reviled (and broken) Games For Windows Live service from the Steam release. Hooray! FO3 is still busted because Bethesda haven't updated the game to run happily on modern Windows, but I'll take any opportunity to dance on GFWL's grave. However, avoid the update if you play FO3 with lots of mods.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Arataki Itto: everything we know so far]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-arataki-itto-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-arataki-itto-build"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:17:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When will Arataki Itto be coming to Genshin Impact? Arataki Itto is an upcoming playable character in Genshin Impact whose imminent arrival as a potential party member is causing a great deal of excitement, and let's not pretend we can't work out why.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XIV: Endwalker has re-motivated me to reach the finish line]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-xiv-endwalker-preview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-xiv-endwalker-preview"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow Hulk and I, we've been through a lot in MMORPG Final Fantasy XIV. I've learned to love his run, and together we've been largely been taken aback at just how nice everyone in the game is. Right now, though, we've hit a bit of a wall. We're deep in what I've dubbed the 'Filler City' quest line, as we attempt to reach the game's first expansion, Heavensward. Motivation has dipped considerably as of late.
But you should have seen me at the Endwalker hands-on preview, Final Fantasy XIV's upcoming fourth expansion. I played as a tall bunny boy, not Shadow Hulk. I was suddenly at the highest level cap, not the foothills of the early-mid game. I soared over new zones and wrestled through a new dungeon in a state of delirium. And now, writing this in the present, I desperately want to go back. Motivation? Renewed.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pořadatelé konference Internet a Technologie představili program a spustili registraci]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42901</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/poradatele-konference-internet-a-technologie-predstavili-program-a-spustili-registraci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sdružení CZ.NIC, pořadatel konference Internet a Technologie (21.2), zveřejnilo webové stránky akce a otevřelo registraci. Tato tradiční konference správce české národní domény se uskuteční 10. listopadu v konferenčních prostorech hotelu Grandior (Na Poříčí 1052/42, Praha 1). Program, registrační formulář a další informace včetně archivu minulých ročníků jsou k dispozici na webu akce.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Vilém Sládek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nasaďte moderní web server s Nginx (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-38548</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nasadte-moderni-web-server-s-nginx-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:22:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nginx je dnes přibližně na třetině web serverů na internetu a toto číslo stále roste. Je výkonný, spolehlivý, má spoustu funkcí a dobře se spravuje. Pokud potřebujete dobrý web server pro svůj projekt, bude Nginx správnou volbou.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can you play Split Screen in Back 4 Blood?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-split-screen</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-split-screen"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T11:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can you play Split Screen co-op in Back 4 Blood? Back 4 Blood harkens back to some classic co-op games like Left 4 Dead, so many of you are probably wondering whether you can hunker down on the sofa and play split screen like you did before.
This guide will let you know whether you can play split screen in Back 4 Blood, so that you can jump into a match, pick up a gun, and start slaying all kinds of zombies and Special Ridden with your friends.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riot are removing cross-team text chat in League Of Legends]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riot-are-removing-cross-team-text-chat-in-league-of-legends</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riot-are-removing-cross-team-text-chat-in-league-of-legends"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T10:51:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Riot Games have announced they're disabling /all chat in matchmade queues in League Of Legends to cut back on verbal abuse. Players in the same team will still be able to type to each other, and post-match chat will remain cross-team too, so you'll still be able to throw out your "ggs". But, as of League's next patch, you'll no longer be able to see messages from enemies mid-game. Good riddance, I say.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to enable Crossplay in Back 4 Blood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-crossplay</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-crossplay"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T10:16:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to enable crossplay in Back 4 Blood? Nightmare mode can be pretty tough, so you’ll want to assemble the best team possible to survive the zombie onslaught in Back 4 Blood. Although you won't be able to play wit friends using split screen on the same device, you can stretch beyond your platform to find only the best zombie slayers by enabling crossplay.
This guide will explain how to enable and disable crossplay, so that you can pick and choose exactly who you play with in Back 4 Blood. Before hopping online, you should probably finish up the tutorial and figure out how to unlock all cleaners so that you can fit into any team.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World endgame content: things to do when you hit Level 60]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-endgame</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-endgame"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T09:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is there to do once you reach the endgame in New World? Currently at least, New World has a level cap of 60. There's a debate among MMO fans as to whether reaching the endgame should be the whole point of playing, or if it's really just a nice bonus after you've finished the satisfying business of levelling your character up from nothing. Whichever opinion you hold, most can agree that it's nice to have something to keep you coming back to the game that you've spent all those hours mastering.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Back 4 Blood Walker build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-walker</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/back-4-blood-walker"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T09:09:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know the best Walker build in Back 4 Blood? Walker is a sharpshooter who gains increased accuracy with precision kills. He also deals 10% more damage and increases everyone’s health by 10, making him an invaluable member of any team. However, to really unlock his full potential, you need to create the best build using all of the cards at your disposal. There are over 100 cards in Back 4 Blood, so check out our Supply Lines guide to see how you can start unlocking them all.
If you want to stop looking at stat numbers and start looking at mushy piles of zombies, then you’re in the right place. This guide will cover everything that you need to know to make the best Walker build in Back 4 Blood.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Eula build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-eula-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-eula-build"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T09:05:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Eula build in Genshin Impact? While Cryo Claymore user Eula isn’t the most loved by her fellow Mondstadt citizens thanks to her family’s tyrannical history, you’re sure to love her if you have her on your team. Eula has an all-around solid moveset, making her a stellar main DPS.
This guide will show you how to create the best Eula build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Eula, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat najímá dalšího vývojáře pro GPU]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42900</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/red-hat-najima-dalsiho-vyvojare-pro-gpu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T07:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tým v Red Hatu věnující se GPU subsystému a věcem souvisejícím už obsahuje velká jména jako David Airlie (správce DRM) či dalších vývojářů pracujících v rámci projektu MESA. Nyní Red Hat hledá dalšího experta přes GPU, který se bude věnovat oblasti GPU hardware enablement.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flag Map Sabotage]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2528/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2528/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard's writers want to make two sequels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-writers-want-to-make-two-sequels</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-writers-want-to-make-two-sequels"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T22:50:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard has started to dribble out a few more details about its story in new trailers, with a particular focus on its five new protagonists. If those characters are appealing, then good news: Vanguard's developers say that they hope to make a Vanguard 2 and 3 with the same cast.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Team Fortress 2 Halloween cosmetic gets restricted, prices skyrocket]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/team-fortress-2-halloween-cosmetic-gets-restricted-prices-skyrocket</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/team-fortress-2-halloween-cosmetic-gets-restricted-prices-skyrocket"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T22:13:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Team Fortress 2 launched its Halloween update last week. Scream Fortress XIII adds new maps, cosmetics, taunts and contracts, amongst a lot else. One of the additions has caused a stir, however.

The "Corpse Carrier" is a cosmetic item wearable by Scouts that makes the speedster look as if he's carrying his own severed torso. It's a nightmare for snipers for obvious reasons, but it was initially easy to obtain and wearable all year round. Valve have since changed both of those things - and in turn, created a new, highly valuable item within TF2's trading marketplace.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logování v PHP: možnosti výstupů logování zajišťovaných handlery]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15673</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/logovani-v-php-moznosti-vystupu-logovani-zajistovanych-handlery/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ve druhém článku si ukážeme poměrně podrobně možnosti výstupů logování zajišťovaných handlery. Tyto možnosti jsou vcelku rozsáhlé a evidentně reagují na reálnou poptávku takřka „ze života“.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Herout)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (13. 10. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15705</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-13-10-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si přidáme anotace k obrázkům, zvýšíme si výdrž baterie u notebooku, proměníme skripty z Pythonu ve webové aplikace a stáhneme si informace z chytrých hodinek.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-standing Spelunky speedrun record revealed as fraudulent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/long-standing-spelunky-speedrun-record-revealed-as-fraudulent</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/long-standing-spelunky-speedrun-record-revealed-as-fraudulent"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T21:03:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2012, a player named BarryMode completed Spelunky Classic in two minutes and 30 seconds. Since then, this time has stood as the world record, and no other speedrunner has come close. Now, BarryMode's speedrun has been revealed as fraudulent. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Ironhide loadout in Warzone Season 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-ironhide-loadout-warzone</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-ironhide-loadout-warzone"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T20:21:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best Ironhide loadout in Warzone? The new lever-action Shotgun probably won’t crack the meta, but it’s aesthetically killer. If you’re looking for something different now that the Gallo has been nerfed, the Ironhide is an excellent choice. With two-shot kill potential, it’s a menace up close. To maximize its strengths though, you’re going to need the best build.

To make Shotguns work in Warzone, you need as much range and hipfire accuracy as you can get. Target those stats with this build:

This may be a shotgun, but we’re still starting off with an Agency Choke and Task Force Barrel. Both attachments grant a big boost to damage range, though the Task Force comes with a hipfire penalty. That's why the SOF Target Designator is also a must on Cold War shotguns, as it provides even more of the two stats we need; hipfire accuracy and damage range. You have some options in the stock slot, but we’ve gone with No Stock here. This is the biggest mobility boost you can get on your Ironhide, which is a big help when dueling SMG users. Unfortunately, it also comes with a hipfire penatly. These unfortunate tradeoffs have really held Cold War shotguns back in the meta. If you find the hipfire spread on this build isn't tight enough, a Wire Stock boosts sprint-to-fire speed without a penalty. Finally, we’ve gone with the 7 Round Tube magazine to help take on groups of foes without a reload.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Grav loadout in Warzone Season 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-grav-loadout-warzone</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-grav-loadout-warzone"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T20:19:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best Grav loadout in Warzone Season 6? Warzone’s newest rifle packs a potent combination of damage and fire rate that makes for excellent time-to-kill numbers. The Grav also boasts one of the highest bullet velocities in the Assault Rifle category and is one of the only Cold War weapons with a caliber-conversion magazine. Get a handle on its beastly recoil, and the Grav has the potential to be a top-tier rifle. Here are the best ways to build it out.

The Grav’s excellent damage and bullet velocity make it highly effective at long-range if you can control the recoil. That’s no easy task, but this build will help:

As usual, you’ll want to start with an Agency Suppressor and Task Force Barrel. I’m as tired of writing that sentence as you are of reading it, but until Vanguard drops this is the long-range combo for every Cold War weapon. The pile of damage range and recoil control stats these two attachments provide are too good to pass up. You’ll want a Field Agent Grip as well for maximum recoil control. The Grav has a lot of vertical climb, so even skilled players should welcome the help. You’ll want some zoom for range as well, and the Axial Arms 3x remains the go-to. If you prefer a Royal and Kross 4x or other optic though, you’ll have no issues making a substitution. 
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox staff allege "culture of silence" in new reports of toxic workplace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-staff-allege-culture-of-silence-in-new-reports-of-toxic-workplace</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-staff-allege-culture-of-silence-in-new-reports-of-toxic-workplace"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T20:09:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New reports have been published containing further allegations of abuse at Swedish publisher Paradox Interactive. The reports, published initially by Swedish newspaper Svenska Dagbladet (paywalled), are based primarily on interviews with Paradox staff who wished to remain anonymous.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 38-40/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-38-40-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-38-40-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Babí léto přineslo aktualizace řady více či méně specializovaných distribucí: přechod na Debian 11 v projektech Emmabuntüs DE4 nejen pro vzdělávání, Q4OS také s desktopovým prostředím Trinity, stabilní obrazy PureOS firmy Purism, dále Redo Rescue pro práci s diskovými oddíly, pokračující experimenty v EasyOS a mezi tím vším občerstvení MidnightBSD, UBports, IPFire, Tails, Feren OS či Debianu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Nobel Prizes]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2527/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2527/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Budování kyberneticky odolné společnosti]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-budovani-kyberneticky-odolne-spolecnosti</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-budovani-kyberneticky-odolne-spolecnosti"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problémy s Wi-Fi mohou ohrozit fungování českých firem. Technologické trendy pro finanční ředitele: hyperautomatizace a inteligentní komponovaný byznys. Od pilotního projektu k produkčnímu nasazení umělé inteligence. S evidencí vandalismu pomůže umělá inteligence, řešení bude hledat Atos Hackathon. Budování kyberneticky odolné společnosti. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (1) Dodávky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 40/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-40-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-40-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Supravodivé hydridy ceru]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-supravodive-hydridy-ceru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-supravodive-hydridy-ceru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Světy s oceány a atmosférou z vodíku. Těžba ve vesmíru s pomocí bakterií. Panspermie v měřítku celé galaxie. Umělá inteligence pro předpověď počasí. Vylepšená uhlíková vlákna.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jaderné noviny – přehled za září 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-zari-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-zari-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Přehled zářijových vydání Jaderných novin: stav vydání jádra, citáty týdne a seznam článků týkajících se jádra.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Vztah mezi bezpečností, IT a vývojem se musí zlepšit]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-vztah-mezi-bezpecnosti-it-a-vyvojem-se-musi-zlepsit</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-vztah-mezi-bezpecnosti-it-a-vyvojem-se-musi-zlepsit"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM Cloud a jeho umělá inteligence i ve vlastním datacentru. HPE představilo nové cloudové služby pro platformu HPE GreenLake. Pure nabízí Database-as-a-Service pro Kubernetes. Internet věcí nás obklopuje na každém kroku, účastníci Atos Hackathonu se naučí s ním zacházet. Vztah mezi bezpečností, IT a vývojem se musí zlepšit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>