<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-10-28T08:17:52.246Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-28T08:17:52.246Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Zero 2 W Launches As Newer, Faster $10 Single Board Computer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-Zero-2-W</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-Zero-2-W"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Raspberry Pi Foundation today is launching the Raspberry Pi Zero 2 W as their newest single board computer succeeding the $10 Raspberry Pi Zero W...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: Atlus Releases New Shin Megami Tensei V 'World In Ruins' Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122867</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/video-atlus-releases-new-shin-megami-tensei-v-world-in-ruins-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T03:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["The ambitions of God and human clash".
Ahead of the launch of the upcoming Switch exclusive Shin Megami Tensei V next month, Atlus has released a new trailer.
Unfortunately, we can't show the English version here on Nintendo Life due to the age restrictions in place, so head on over to YouTube to check it out with subtitles. Of course, you'll need to be signed into YouTube to view it.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim IRL TikTok Star Arrested, Charged With Murdering His Wife & Her Friend]]></title>
        <id>1847952568</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/skyrim-irl-tiktok-star-arrested-charged-with-murdering-1847952568"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T02:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ali Nassar Abulaban, aka JinnKid, is the actor behind Skyrim In Real Life, a series of incredibly popular TikTok videos. He was arrested last week and charged with murdering two people, including his wife.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Releases Surprise Metroid Dread Demo]]></title>
        <id>1847952398</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-releases-surprise-metroid-dread-demo-1847952398"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most people who have played Metroid Dread say the game is very good, but what if you are not one of those people, and for whatever reason do not trust those people? Well, now you can simply download part of the game for free and try it for yourself.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Halloween! Nintendo Has Released A Free Metroid Dread Demo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122862</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/happy-halloween-nintendo-has-released-a-free-metroid-dread-demo"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["All treat, no trick".
Well, this is a nice surprise! If you haven't already picked up Metroid Dread on the Switch, Nintendo has now released a free demo on the Switch eShop - allowing you to try before you buy.

This Halloween, suit up as Samus Aran and see what goes bump in the night on planet ZDR with a fun-sized bite of the Metroid™ Dread game. Download the free demo now from Nintendo.com or Nintendo eShop on your device!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On The Mic]]></title>
        <id>1847952027</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/on-the-mic-1847952027"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liu Xiao is an artist based in Beijing, China.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise Version 3.5.0 Is Now Live, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122861</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/monster-hunter-rise-version-3-5-0-is-now-live-here-are-the-full-patch-notes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost 'n Goblins, new haircuts and more!
Capcom might not be able to add cross-play and cross-save progression to Monster Hunter Rise, but on the plus side, it's added more haircut styles in the latest update.
To access it, you'll need to head on over to the eShop and download it. You can then access it via the mail in-game. Apart from this, Version 3.5.0 adds new events and fixes a whole lot of bugs. A Ghosts 'n Goblins collab event will also unlock on 29th October and new voice DLC has been added, too.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get the brand new SteelSeries Arctis 7P+ gaming headset for 1%2 off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-brand-new-steelseries-arctis-7p-gaming-headset-for-12-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-brand-new-steelseries-arctis-7p-gaming-headset-for-12-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T01:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The SteelSeries Arctis 7P+ is a brand new gaming headset, offering a series of small upgrades over the already-brilliant Arctis 7P. It's rare to see new items discounted right away, but today you can get this new model up for 12% off with code MOUNTAIN12.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PNY's great value DDR4 RAM is going cheap in the US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pnys-great-value-ddr4-ram-is-going-cheap-in-the-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pnys-great-value-ddr4-ram-is-going-cheap-in-the-us"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T00:45:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PNY isn't the first name you might think of when it comes to RAM, but they're sometimes a great value - including today, when a series of RAM kits are on sale in stores across the US. Here are the links - and some words about why you should consider them. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anniversary: Can You Believe It? Super Mario Odyssey Is Now Four Years Old]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122860</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/anniversary-can-you-believe-it-super-mario-odyssey-is-now-four-years-old"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T00:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mario is now an adventurous globe-trotter.
It might seem like yesterday or a lifetime ago, depending on who you talk to, but this week marks the fourth year since Super Mario Odyssey made its debut on the Nintendo Switch.
The title is currently the sixth best-selling Switch game of all time - having now shifted over 21 million copies around the world. Alongside Mario Kart 8 Deluxe, that makes it one of the highest-selling Mario games on the platform.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lost Judgment: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847889597</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/lost-judgment-the-kotaku-review-1847889597"/>
        <updated>2021-10-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I loved Judgment, Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio’s 2018 spinoff from the Yakuza series. Arriving just as the main games were getting ready to go through the biggest changes in their long-running history, along came a lawyer and his himbo best friend to keep some beloved old Yakuza fundamentals alive.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devolver Digital Is Bringing The Indie Gem Death's Door To Switch Next Month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122859</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/devolver-digital-is-bringing-the-indie-gem-deaths-door-to-switch-next-month"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T23:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the creator of Titan Souls.

At Sony's State of Play livestream today, the focus was on third-party and indie offerings. While it was a PlayStation event, some of the announcements were for other platforms, too.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warzone 2100 4.2.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/warzone-2100-4.2.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/warzone-2100-4.2.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T23:17:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Realtimová strategie Warzone 2100 (Wikipedie) byla vydána ve verzi 4.2.0. Podrobný přehled novinek, změn a oprav v ChangeLogu na GitHubu. Nejnovější verzi Warzone 2100 lze instalovat také ze Snapcraftu. Brzy i z Flathubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rumour: "Warner Bros Multiversus" Is A Smash Bros. Imitator With Batman, Gandalf And, Er, Shaggy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122708</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/rumour-warner-bros-multiversus-is-a-smash-bros-imitator-with-batman-gandalf-and-er-shaggy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T23:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Roster supposedly leaks online.

The rumour of a Warner Bros. Smash Bros. is gathering more steam, as YouTuber and pro Super Smash Bros. Melee player hungrybox shared an alleged leaked image of the roster, as well as a title, "Warner Bros Multiversus":
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Vicarious Visions Changing Its Name After Blizzard Merger]]></title>
        <id>1847951518</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/report-vicarious-visions-changing-its-name-after-blizz-1847951518"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January it was announced that Vicarious Visions, the studio famous for its work on the Tony Hawk remakes and a whole library of excellent licensed games, was going to be merging with Blizzard. Now it’s emerged that this corporate move means the developer will be changing its name as well.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3-rc3 Released With Many Zink OpenGL-On-Vulkan Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T22:41:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest weekly test release of Mesa 21.3 is now available ahead of the anticipated stable debut in November...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Fatal Frame: Maiden Of Black Water - A Ghostly Wii U Treat Resurfaces On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122455</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/fatal-frame-maiden-of-black-water"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maiden voyeurage.
Were you to see a ghost cutting about, what would be your first instinct? Forgive us for this assumption, but we imagine it's probably not "take a polaroid of it", right? Tell that to the various heroes of Fatal Frame: Maiden of Black Water — Project Zero in Europe — who seem to fancy themselves budding Sir Donald McCullins and get snap-happy each and every time they see a geist, malevolent or otherwise. Us, though, we'd leg it. Full Shaggy-from-Scooby-Doo leg it.
Still, it's worth noting that we're not talking about an ordinary camera here. The device wielded by the Fatal Framers (they're not actually called that) is the Camera Obscura, which captures more than just treasured memories. Indeed, utilising it carefully can allow its wielder to capture spooks, which in practice is effectively the same as killing them. Again. Look, the point is that you're essentially photographing ghosts to death. We're just getting ahead of ourselves.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything Shown Today At Sony's October State of Play For PS4, PS5]]></title>
        <id>1847950943</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/everything-shown-today-at-sonys-october-state-of-play-1847950943"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T21:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s relatively short—even by livestreamed press conference standards—State of Play event was not the most eventful update we’ve ever seen, but here’s a roundup of everything showed up.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Ocean Is Back And It Looks Kinda Like Monster Hunter]]></title>
        <id>1847950820</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/star-ocean-is-back-and-it-looks-kinda-like-monster-hunt-1847950820"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T21:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At long last, Square Enix’s interstellar JRPG series Star Ocean is back. Star Ocean The Divine Force is set to launch on PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Series X/S, and PC in 2022, the company revealed during today’s PlayStation State of Play livestream.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GOTY Contender Death's Door Heads To PlayStation And Switch Next Month]]></title>
        <id>1847950730</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/deaths-door-opens-on-playstation-and-switch-next-month-1847950730"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T21:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announced today via Sony’s State of Play event and on Twitter via Devolver Digital, Acid Nerve’s acclaimed dungeon crawler Death’s Door makes the jump from PC and Xbox to PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and Nintendo Switch on November 23. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathverse Is A Surprise Follow-Up To Suda's Let It Die]]></title>
        <id>1847950566</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/deathverse-is-a-surprise-follow-up-to-sudas-let-it-die-1847950566"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T21:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2016, Goichi Suda’s Grasshopper Manufacture and Supertrick Games released Let It Die, a roguelike that had players climbing up a tower killing everything in their paths. Today, Sony announced a surprise successor to the game, only this time it’s a multiplayer “survival action game,” instead.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Among Us Teases Next Update With New Role: The Shapeshifter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122847</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/among-us-teases-next-update-with-new-role-the-shapeshifter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Also, new loading bar?!
The next Among Us update is around the corner, and Innersloth Community Director Victoria Tran has just posted a little peek at what to expect.
We knew that new roles were coming, and we've got a look at the first one: The Shapeshifter, a role for Impostors only, which — as the title may imply — can change their appearance. For example, you can change into another player to frame them, but the disguise will eventually wear off, and you'll leave evidence behind.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/x.org-server-21.1.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/x.org-server-21.1.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T20:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X Server (xorg-server) 21.1.0 byl oficiálně vydán. Mezi stěžejními novinkami je jmenována podpora např. proměnlivé obnovovací frekvence v modesetting, 2D akcelerace GLAMOR v Xvfb, gest touchpadu v XInput 2.4 nebo dokončení přechodu z Autotools na Meson. XWayland byl již dříve vydán samostatně.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch: Modern Vintage Gamer Shares An In-Depth Look At The Pros And Cons Of Nintendo's N64 Emulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122846</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/watch-modern-vintage-gamer-shares-an-in-depth-look-at-the-pros-and-cons-of-nintendos-n64-emulation"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["For the majority... this will be good enough".
By now, you've probably seen the tweets and posts about the Nintendo Switch Online Expansion Pack's N64 emulation not quite being what people hoped it was. In fact, if you haven't already seen some version of these screenshots, you're most likely not on the internet as much as we are (which, trust us, is a good thing):
But perhaps you're wondering just what everyone's so fussed about, and just how bad could it be that a bunch of 25-year-old games don't have fog? Well, Modern Vintage Gamer, who's quite knowledgeable about emulation, has put together a bit of an explainer on the subject.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty’s Ridiculous Donnie Darko Crossover Is Kinda Funny, Kinda Sad]]></title>
        <id>1847949055</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-s-ridiculous-donnie-darko-crossover-is-kin-1847949055"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T19:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Suffice to say, video game crossovers can be pretty bogus outside of the Super Smash Bros. series. But putting Donnie Darko stuff in Call of Duty: Warzone and Black Ops Cold War takes the cake. This might be the single most ridiculous mash-up I’ve ever seen. The whole thing is so stupid that I’m ironically coming…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon II Tries Something New, And It Mostly Works]]></title>
        <id>1847948896</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/darkest-dungeon-ii-tries-something-new-and-it-mostly-w-1847948896"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T19:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon II is nothing if not evocative—a positive quirk it shares with the first game. When my party reaches the Mountain at its heart, they are brought low. This place has haunted their dreams for weeks—a different configuration for each of them.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leak: Batman, Steven Universe Come Together In Smash Bros.-Style Fighting Game]]></title>
        <id>1847948812</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/leak-batman-steven-universe-come-together-in-smash-br-1847948812"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T19:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following recent reports that Warner Bros. was working on a platform fighting game similar to Super Smash Bros. called Multiversus, a possible roster for the project featuring characters from Batman, Steven Universe, Adventure Time, and more appears to have leaked online.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: The Nintendo 64 Controller Works With Any Switch Game (Kinda)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122843</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/video-the-nintendo-64-controller-works-with-any-switch-game-kinda"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well... define "works".
There's been a lot of rage and indignation going around about all this Nintendo 64 stuff, including the fact that the games aren't playing well, the N64 controllers don't work with accessories, or connect to the PC. Safe to say it's probably not a great time to be dropping a ton of money on the Nintendo Switch Online Subscription Expansion Pack!
However, our lovely Jon Cartwright has put together a video about the N64 controller, or, as he calls it, "The Big Boy". There are a few new things, and a few different things, like the fact that the Rumble Pak is now included within the housing itself, and not as a separate, chunky attachment. RIP, Rumble Pak :(
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact’s New Event Is A Surprisingly Great Roguelike]]></title>
        <id>1847948578</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/genshin-impact-s-new-event-is-a-surprisingly-great-rogu-1847948578"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T18:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Genshin Impact was definitely not a game in which I expected to find great roguelike gameplay. Its open world design (which was frequently compared to Breath of the Wild at launch) seemed antithetical to the restrictive conditions of an interesting roguelike. I’m glad to find that I was very, very wrong. The new…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KungFu Kickball Bounces Onto Nintendo Switch This Holiday Season]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122842</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/kungfu-kickball-bounces-onto-nintendo-switch-this-holiday-season"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon(foot)ball Z.
Right, what do you think of when someone says "kickball"? Is it "children yelling and kicking each other in the face", or perhaps "what on earth is kickball"? Well, pals, if football is The Beautiful Game, then kickball (AKA soccer baseball, or football rounders) is its slightly-more-homely, but still-kinda-cute cousin. Combine kickball with kung-fu and you get...
KungFu Kickball! Fusing the best parts of martial arts (kicking) and the best part of kickball (kicking), it's a match made in heaven. Or nirvana, more likely.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tier List: The Best Goths In Video Games]]></title>
        <id>1847947474</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/tier-list-the-best-goths-in-video-games-1847947474"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Halloween right around the corner, it’s the perfect time for us to immerse ourselves in the signature styles of video gaming’s greatest and most fashionable goths, as well as those whose fashion sense makes them goth-adjacent.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sky Kid Is The Next HAMSTER Arcade Archives Release, Out This Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122840</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/sky-kid-is-the-next-hamster-arcade-archives-release-out-this-week"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looping round for another shot.
The HAMSTER Arcade Archives series keeps on rolling, delivering a broad range of classics with impressive emulation (and extra goodies) of iconic cabinets. This week's arrival, on 28th October, will be Sky Kid; as usual for this series it'll cost $7.99USD with regional equivalents.
The name may be familiar to eager retro fans that used to raid the 3DS and Wii U eShop, with the NES port having previously been released on those platform's Virtual Consoles. This is the debut of the arcade version, though, along with the usual HAMSTER bonuses of various settings and online leaderboards.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Wakefield Is OpenJDK's Effort To Improve Java On Wayland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wakefield-OpenJDK-Java-Wayland</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wakefield-OpenJDK-Java-Wayland"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project Wakefield is the recently established OpenJDK initiative to implement native Wayland support within Java...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buzz Lightyear Trailer Makes No Sense, Breaks Internet's Brain]]></title>
        <id>1847947531</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/buzz-lightyear-trailer-makes-no-sense-breaks-internets-1847947531"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I woke up today, I expected my kitchen to be a mess because I binged The Morning Show instead of cleaning it last night. Despite it already being Wednesday, I was also prepared to be overwhelmed by the truckload of tasks I have yet to cross off my to-do list this week. What I was not ready for was Pixar releasing …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 Released With Variable Rate Refresh In Modesetting Driver, Other Work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:33:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 is now officially available as this first xorg-server update in three years and what began development as X.Org Server 1.21 prior to the versioning change...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soapbox: Nintendo's N64 Emulation Is Serviceable, But Treasured Memories Deserve Better]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122817</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/soapbox-nintendos-n64-emulation-is-serviceable-but-treasured-memories-deserve-better"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hazy memories.
Anyone who's ever spent a decent amount of time with video games probably has a small handful of momentous memories etched on their brains. Not just that time you beat a gruelling boss or played Mario Kart with your pals at Paul's birthday party — more pretentious than that. We mean a time when your perception of what was possible in the medium itself was expanded in some way; an instant when you thought Wow... I didn't realise games could do that.
Thinking back, I remember watershed moments playing online with friends in Call of Duty: Modern Warfare (the first one) and Left 4 Dead which felt as potent as any team-based activity in the real world, perhaps more so thanks to the bonds formed through digital hardship involving zombies and gunships. Though not the first open-world video game ever, Breath of the Wild will have expanded the horizons of many players poking at its possibility space and discovering its joys for the first time. Everyone will have their own games and experiences that stuck with them for one reason or another, and for me one particularly potent moment from the 64-bit era sticks in my mind — and it was nothing more than a calm vista following a hard night in Hyrule Field.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[That Dark Souls III Twitch Streamer's Bananas Single-Button Run, Explained]]></title>
        <id>1847947150</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/that-dark-souls-iii-twitch-streamers-bananas-single-but-1847947150"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week, Twitch streamer Dylan “Rudeism” Beck blew our minds by beating Dark Souls III using a single-button setup to hammer out Morse code. It’s an impressive feat to be sure and one that also touches on something Rudeism is quite passionate about: accessibility in games.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can my Darkest Dungeon 2 party please shut up for five minutes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/can-my-darkest-dungeon-2-party-please-shut-up-for-five-minutes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/can-my-darkest-dungeon-2-party-please-shut-up-for-five-minutes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:13:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In time, you will know the tragic extent of my failings, but in Darkest Dungeon 2 goodness me you'll hear about everyone's failings constantly. The horrific dungeon-crawling sequel entered early access yesterday, and my initial impression is that I'm surrounded by squabbling children. Managing the stress of your heroes is more important than ever, because if anyone is even mildly irked they will interrupt every fight to shout about how their squadmate is a kill-stealing dick. I'm this close to turning the stagecoach back around and embracing the impending apocalypse.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Brain Academy: Brain vs. Brain Pre-Orders From My Nintendo Store UK Come With A Free Gift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122838</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/big-brain-academy-brain-vs-brain-pre-orders-from-my-nintendo-store-uk-come-with-a-free-gift"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cerebral celebrations.
Big Brain Academy: Brain vs. Brain is the latest in the brain-testing series of brain-related games, which pits you against other members of your family/friend group/loveably dorky pub quiz team to determine once and for all who has The Most Brain. It's due out in early December, just in time for fun, festive multiplayer times with whoever you're spending Christmas with.
And, as a bonus, all pre-orders from My Nintendo Store UK — including ones already made — will receive a free gift with purchase. That free gift is these cute sticky notes, for writing down all your best brain thoughts:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot Wheels Unleashed Devs On Making 2021's Most Surprising Racing Game]]></title>
        <id>1847946535</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/hot-wheels-unleashed-devs-on-making-2021s-most-surprisi-1847946535"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Italian studio Milestone is known for racing sims. MotoGP, MXGP, Ride, the World Rally Championship series—that’s all Milestone. Hot Wheels Unleashed, the surprise hit arcade racer featuring Mattel’s iconic toy cars racing through physics-defying loops and making heart-stopping jumps, is about as far from a hardcore…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pokémon Company Is Getting Into Sumo Wrestling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122828</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/the-pokemon-company-is-getting-into-sumo-wrestling"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Su and Pokémon Mo.
We've been saying for years that sumo wrestling is basically the same as Pokémon, except with more consent and less catching-your-defeated-foe-in-a-ball. Now, finally, the two are becoming one, as The Pokémon Company is becoming an official sponsor of sumo wrestling, in partnership with the Nihon Sumo Kyokai (H/T Kotaku for the translation).
As part of the collaboration, The Pokémon Company is sponsoring several kensho banners, which are paraded around the sumo wrestling ring before a match. The banners will feature well-known Pokémon, from Pikachu to Makuhita, whose design is based on sumo wrestlers. There will be 200 different banners in total.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All I want for spook month is more classic survival horror]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-i-want-for-spook-month-is-more-classic-survival-horror</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-i-want-for-spook-month-is-more-classic-survival-horror"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Listen. Outside your window, the chill wind chuckles in raspy glee at autumn’s death rattle. The branches of dying trees rake their gnarled fingers against the glass. You are spooked. You turn to the warm glow of your monitor for comfort. Instead, you find the most terrifying thing imaginable: an unpopular opinion about a videogame. On the internet, no less. You blink and rub your eyes in disbelief. Still, the words remain. Stark. Unforgiving. Undeniably spicy: “Resident Evil Village was disappointing and its success does not bode well for the future of survival horror.” 


You go to type a comment but, uh, your fingers are gone, or something. Just hear me out. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dune’s Timothée Chalamet Was Once An Xbox YouTuber]]></title>
        <id>1847946368</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/dune-s-timothee-chalamet-was-once-an-xbox-youtuber-1847946368"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Timothée Chalamet: Hollywood superstar, GQ cover model, and...former gaming YouTuber? Yes, more than a decade ago, the Dune actor used to operate a YouTube channel under the handle ModdedController360, where he showed off custom paint jobs of Xbox 360 controllers.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs announced: everything you need to know]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-cpus-specs-price-features</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/intel-12th-gen-alder-lake-cpus-specs-price-features"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a months-long spin around the rumour mill, the first batch of Intel 12th Gen Alder Lake CPUs is official. Despite the 11th Gen Rocket Lake chips only launching earlier this year, Alder Lake represents the biggest generational jump for Intel in over half a decade, thanks to its completely redesigned “hybrid” architecture and DDR5 memory support. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Announces 12th Gen Core "Alder Lake" CPUs, Linux Tests Forthcoming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30645</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30645"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel is using their inaugural Intel Innovation virtual event today to formally announce the highly-anticipated 12th Gen Core "Alder Lake" processors. These first desktop processors built on their "Intel 7" process and employ a hybrid architecture will be available in retail channels next week. Today we can talk more about Alder Lake specifications and features while our Linux performance benchmarks and support analysis will come once the Alder Lake review embargo expires next week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Mobile Smash Hit 'Retro Bowl' Will Bring American Football To Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122829</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/exclusive-mobile-smash-hit-retro-bowl-will-bring-american-football-to-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inspired by Tecmo Bowl.
The Switch eShop has a decent range of sports games, including varied options for NFL / American Football enthusiasts. Another that is targeting a release in Q1 2022 is Retro Bowl from New Star Games, which will be looking to continue the outstanding momentum it's achieved on mobile for both iOS and Android platforms.
At the time of writing it's the number one free-to-play game on iOS in the US, for example, achieving viral success with young players and on TikTok in particular. It takes inspiration from Tecmo Bowl and mixes in a surprising amount of management depth alongside matches; you both try to build up your franchise as a GM / coach and play the games.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Announces New Developer Zone To Showcase Their Wide Array Of Software]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-New-Dev-Zone</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-New-Dev-Zone"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with announcing Alder Lake and other hardware advancements, Intel is using their new Innovation event kicking off today to also talk more about their vast collection of software... This follows Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger's comments from earlier in the week around a bias towards open-source and a pledge to openness. As part of this, Intel is today announcing a new and unified Developer Zone...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 Has A Cool Far Cry Primal Shout-Out]]></title>
        <id>1847945226</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/far-cry-6-has-a-cool-far-cry-primal-shout-out-1847945226"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone knows that Ubisoft games are full of things to do. In Far Cry 6, there’s a lot to see, too. To wit: Last night, while exploring the open-world shooter’s El Este region, I stumbled upon what I’m pretty sure—like, 99 percent sure—is a reference to 2016’s Far Cry Primal, the series spinoff set in the Stone Age.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former World of Warcraft Devs Start Studio Where Only Female Staffer Is A Dog]]></title>
        <id>1847945629</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/former-world-of-warcraft-devs-start-studio-where-only-f-1847945629"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Blizzard developers who started Notorious Studios seem to have exactly zero women on their development team. The staff page shows nine developers and two advisors, all of which are men, and one canine “Chief Morale Officer” named Ellie. Which means that the studio has more dogs than women. Yikes. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[M2 Is Bringing Yet Another Classic Shmup To Switch Next Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122831</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/m2-is-bringing-yet-another-classic-shmup-to-switch-next-year"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hishou Same! Same! Same! arrives in 2022.
Like shmups? Then listen up – port specialist M2 has just announced Hishou Same! Same! Same! for Switch and PS4 as part of its ongoing M2 ShotTriggers / Toaplan Arcade Garage series.
Like the just-released Toaplan Arcade Garage: Kyukyoku Tiger-Heli, Hishou Same! Same! Same! will include ports of the 1987 arcade title Hishou Zame! (Sky Shark in North America and Flying Shark in Europe). It will also include the 1989 sequel Same! Same! Same! (Fire Shark), which was famously ported to the Sega Mega Drive / Genesis.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Nintendo Physical Rewards Have Disappeared In North America]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122827</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/my-nintendo-physical-rewards-have-disappeared-in-north-america"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sad times.

This week brought a big update to Nintendo Switch Online with the Expansion Pack, but we've also seen a disappointing change on My Nintendo in North America. Earlier this week the physical rewards disappeared entirely, leaving just virtual rewards on the service.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Datamine Hints At Smash Bros. And Other N64 Games Coming]]></title>
        <id>1847944937</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-datamine-hints-at-smash-bros-and-other-1847944937"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Switch Online Expansion Pack arrived earlier this week, bringing nine N64 games to Nintendo’s portable console. That’s...not a lot, and people have been eager to know what other classics will be headed to the subscription-based library. Recently datamined files offer a few hints.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Satisfactory adding train signals, train timetables, and train crashes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/satisfactory-adding-train-signals-train-timetables-and-train-crashes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/satisfactory-adding-train-signals-train-timetables-and-train-crashes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T14:24:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As factory-building sim Satisfactory continues to assemble itself through early access, the next major update runs a real risk of becoming a train wreck. Now in public testing, Update 5 introduces new features to manage train timetables and routes, and you'll want to pay attention to those because trains can now crash.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surviving The Aftermath Will Bring Post-Apocalyptic Strategy To Switch Soon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122824</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/surviving-the-aftermath-will-bring-post-apocalyptic-strategy-to-switch-soon"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Useful practice.
It was around a year ago that Paradox Interactive and developer Iceflake Studios featured in a Mini Nintendo Direct with Surviving the Aftermath, a rather intriguing strategy title. Now, after an extended time in early access on PC - that contributed to 20 major updates based on community feedback - it's ready to go to version 1.0 and join the Switch eShop. It arrives on 16th November priced at $29.99 USD / £26.99 GBP / €29.99 EUR.
Its most recent reviews on Steam point to the game having progressed and improved a good deal, so it'll be interesting to see how it stacks up on Nintendo's system. As you'd expect it'll be pretty challenging as you attempt to survive and thrive after a 'world-ending event'; check out some of the official description below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Going To Holland Soon? Then Make Sure You Play This 'Lost' Super Mario World Sequel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122819</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/random-going-to-holland-soon-then-make-sure-you-play-this-lost-super-mario-world-sequel"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's a Wacky World, alright.
Mario has starred in a fair few million-selling games, but he's also contributed to some titles which are less well-known – including Super Mario's Wacky Worlds, a canned platformer for the Philips CD-i multimedia system from the early '90s.
Developed in the US by Malibu-based NovaLogic – famous for the Comanche and Delta Force series – Wacky Worlds was pitched as a sequel to the legendary Super Mario World. Because of its deal with Nintendo relating to the Super NES CD-ROM add-on (inked when Nintendo left Sony at the altar), Philips had the right to use Nintendo characters in CD-i games (we have this deal to thank for the three Zelda titles on that platform).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poll: Pikmin Is Now 20 Years Old - Which Is Your Favourite Game In The Series?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122812</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/poll-pikmin-is-now-20-years-old-which-is-your-favourite-game-in-the-series"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whistle-blower.
With all the talk around the launch (and state) of Nintendo 64 games with the Nintendo Switch Online Expansion Pack, it may well have slipped your notice that Pikmin — the Nintendo RTS series that grew from an idea Shigeru Miyamoto had while chilling in his garden — is now two decades old.
Yes, time marches on and we retro gaming fans feel more decrepit by the day. It was 20 years ago yesterday (26th October) that Pikmin launched in Japan and Nintendo fans got their first look at an IP both disarmingly cute and alarmingly cruel in equal measure. We often think back on the legions of little Pikmin we unwittingly marched to their doom with a tinge of sadness and not a small amount of full-on guilt.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Značka fotoaparátů Olympus se mění na OM SYSTEM]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42951</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/znacka-fotoaparatu-olympus-se-meni-na-om-system/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Více než 80 let byla nedílnou součástí fotografické historie japonská značka Olympus. Mateřská firma téhož jména nakonec před několika měsíci fotografickou divizi prodala do jiných rukou a fotografický svět očekával, jak to „s Olympusem“ dopadne. Dnes přichází v historii této foto značky významná zpráva. Olympus jako foto značka se mění na OM SYSTEM, přičemž v tomto názvu navazujícím na úspěšnou řadu kinofilmových zrcadlovek OM a pozdějších digi bezzrcadlovek OM-D, se nadále ukrývá původní dědictví Olympusu a jeho designéra Yoshihisy Maitaniho.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Platební terminály PAX Technology zneužity ke kybernetickým útokům]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42950</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/platebni-terminaly-pax-technology-zneuzity-ke-kybernetickym-utokum/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T12:16:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server KrebsOnSecurity zveřejnil velmi znepokojivou zprávu o platebních terminálech čínské společnosti PAX Technology, které jsou ve 120 zemích v počtu zhruba 60 milionů. Mají být zodpovědné za kybernetické útoky nejen v USA, ale i v UK a EU.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: jerry_wlk)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thunderful Acquires Robot Teddy To Expand Into Game Investment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122813</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/thunderful-acquires-robot-teddy-to-expand-into-game-investment"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T11:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digging for exciting game projects.
It's not particularly long ago that Image & Form was a talented but little-known developer that caught the eye - and major success - with SteamWorld Dig. The SteamWorld series has continued to grow in the years since, of course, but through investment and hard-earned success Image & Form has evolved and transformed almost beyond recognition.
Now, of course, it's Thunderful, a publisher and developer that is undoubtedly among the larger companies in the 'Indie' space. Its publishing library continues to grow with the likes of Lonely Mountains: Downhill and the upcoming Cursed to Golf, among many others, while its next major internal release will be Xbox / PC exclusive The Gunk.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core i9 11900K a Windows 11 versus pět linuxových distribucí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42949</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-core-i9-11900k-a-windows-11-versus-pet-linuxovych-distribuci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T11:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server Phoronix otestoval výkon aktuálně nejnovějšího procesoru od Intelu (do příchodu Alder Lake je to model 11900K) na platformě Windows 11 oproti pěti různým linuxovým distribucím. Porovnány byly nejnovější Windows 11 Pro oproti Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS, Ubuntu 21.10, Arch Linuxu, Fedoře Workstation 35 a chybět nemohl ani Intel Clear Linux 35150.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guilty Verdict For Death Threats Against Japanese Game Developer Arika]]></title>
        <id>1847943796</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/guilty-verdict-for-death-threats-against-japanese-game-1847943796"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in September 2019, threats insinuating murder were sent to Tokyo-based game developer Arika. The threats were made against the company as well as a corporate execute and sent through the Arika website’s contact form. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow Warrior 3 delayed into next year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-warrior-3-delayed-into-next-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/shadow-warrior-3-delayed-into-next-year"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T10:46:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The fast-paced, fast-talking violence of Shadow Warrior 3 will not arrive this year after all, now pushed back into "early 2022." Devolver Digital and developers Flying Wild Hog explain it's the usual reason: they want more time to make the FPS good, yeah? A good reason. For now, you can watch the new trailer announcing the delay.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Longtime Persona Composer Shoji Meguro Is Leaving Atlus]]></title>
        <id>1847943643</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/longtime-persona-composer-shoji-meguro-is-leaving-atlus-1847943643"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Japanese composer Shoji Meguro announced that he has left Atlus, resigning from the Tokyo-based game company this past September. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Switch N64 Controller Doesn't Play Nice With Everything, For Now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122808</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/the-switch-n64-controller-doesnt-play-nice-with-everything-for-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mac, PC and Pi inputs appear hit-and-miss at the moment.
There was a lot of chatter around the Nintendo Switch Online Expansion Pack yesterday, plenty of it quite heated on social media. Well, it's social media, so that's no surprise. Another topic that had less air but is potentially quite interesting is related to the NSO Nintendo 64 controller, which started to drop through lucky gamers' mailboxes; this scribe's didn't, resulting in long despairing stares out of the window.
Of course, enthusiasts that are knee-deep in emulation technology were immediately trying to use the controller on everything but a Switch, and have discovered it's trickier than with Nintendo's past controllers. While the Switch Pro Controller and indeed the previous wireless NES and SNES pads are pretty easy to connect to other devices, the N64 controller is putting up a bit of a fight.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt 6.2.1 Released With 200+ Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-6.2.1-LTS-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-6.2.1-LTS-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T09:38:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been just shy of one month since Qt 6.2 debuted as the first Qt6 Long-Term Support (LTS) release and ported many of the remaining modules over from Qt5. Shipping today is now Qt 6.2.1 as the first point release with more than two-hundred fixes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ashwalkers Is A Bleak Survival Sim That's Heading To Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122807</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/ashwalkers-is-a-bleak-survival-sim-thats-heading-to-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T09:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No-one said the apocalypse would be fun.
The Switch continues to attract some intriguing PC titles, and another that'll join the ranks in Q1 next year will be Ashwalkers, which is published by Dear Villagers and developed by Nameless XIII.
As you can see in the trailer it has an eye-catching colour-palette for its particular brand of grim post-apocalyptic survival, while offering up an interesting mix of exploration and narrative storytelling.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Controller Driver Finally Set For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Nintendo-HID-For-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Nintendo-HID-For-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T09:06:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After stalling last year when it was queued up in HID's "for-5.10/nintendo" branch only to not make it into HID-next at the time, that threshold has now been crossed with the latest Nintendo Switch controller driver now ready for introduction in Linux 5.16. This open-source driver enables the Nintendo Switch Joy-Con and Pro controllers to work under Linux with a mainline kernel driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pokémon x Sumo Collab We've Been Waiting For]]></title>
        <id>1847943551</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-pokemon-x-sumo-collab-weve-been-waiting-for-1847943551"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the years, Pokémon has done an array of collabs, including New Era, Oreo, Levi’s, and Casio. Some have been more interesting than others. But finally, Pocket Monsters is teaming up with sumo wrestling. It’s about time!
Think about it. This makes perfect sense. In sumo, you have two wrestlers facing off to see…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NuTyX 21.10.0 s podporou 32bit x86]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42948</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nutyx-21-10-0-s-podporou-32bit-x86/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T08:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Francouzská distribuce NuTyX, stavějící na projektech Linux From Scratch / Beyond Linux From Scratch, přichází po roce v nové verzi, tedy vlastně spíše aktuálním snapshotu označeném jako 21.10.0. Přináší aktualizované verze jádra, desktopových prostředí i dalších aplikací (včetně vlastního správce balíčků cards 2.4.138), přičemž zahrnuje též podporu 32bit procesorů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gitlab CI: automatizujte přímo v Gitlabu (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-38836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gitlab-ci-automatizujte-primo-v-gitlabu-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T08:38:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automatizace pomocí continuous integration přímo v Gitlabu. CI vám pomůže automatizovat rutinní procesy a ušetří vám hromadu času. Pomůže vám od automatického testování, buildy po nasazování. Chcete vědět víc? Přijďte na naše školení GitLab CI, které se uskuteční 18. listopadu a proběhne plně online. Školí Ondřej Sika.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Silicon GPIO Driver Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-Silicon-GPIO-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-Silicon-GPIO-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T08:34:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with the Apple Silicon PCIe driver, another new driver for supporting Apple Silicon (primarily with a focus on the Apple M1 for now) with the upcoming Linux 5.16 cycle is a new pinctrl/GPIO driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TSMC představil výrobní proces N4P, čipy budou menší, výkonnější, úspornější i levnější]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42947</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/tsmc-predstavil-vyrobni-proces-n4p-cipy-budou-mensi-vykonnejsi-uspornejsi-i-levnejsi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Již třetí velké vylepšení výrobních procesů své 5nm rodiny přináší tchaj-wanská TSMC. N4P stále staví na původní 5nm technologii, ale oproti původní variantě procesu N5 přináší o 11% vyšší výkon čipů, oproti dosud nejnovější inkarnaci N4 pak o 6% vyšší. Současně zvyšuje energetickou efektivitu o 22 % a hustotu tranzistorů v čipech o 6 %. Výrobní proces také pracuje s menším počtem masek, klesá tak komplexita výroby waferů a za stejný čas bude možné jich továrnou prohnat víc.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yubico nabízí Security Key C NFC s USB-C za 29 eur]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42946</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/yubico-nabizi-security-key-c-nfc-s-usb-c-za-29-eur/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T06:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po zbrusu novém YubiKey Bio se čtečkou otisků prstů přichází společnost Yubico s novinkou v modré řade Security Key. Konkrétně jde o model Security Key C NFC, který nenabízí všechny možnosti autentizace jako velký YubiKey, ale zaměřuje se na standard FIDO. S ním se přihlásíte k mnoha webovým službám, k novějším verzím OpenSSH nebo ke službám státní správy pomocí mojeID.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CETIN začne v některých lokalitách nabízet optiku místo DSL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42945</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/cetin-zacne-v-nekterych-lokalitach-nabizet-optiku-misto-dsl/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CETIN přestává v některých pražských lokalitách poskytovat své služby pomocí DSL a místo toho nabídne připojení pomocí optiky. CETIN tímto oznamuje záměr ukončit nabídku a poskytování služby zpřístupnění prostřednictvím účastnického metalického vedení z důvodu přechodu na přístupy realizované prostřednictvím účastnického optického vedení, píše se v oznámení společnosti [PDF].]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qualcomm MSM DRM Driver Improvements Submitted Ahead Of Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MSM-Changes-For-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MSM-Changes-For-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MSM DRM driver for supporting the open-source display/graphics support with Qualcomm Snapdragon SoCs has submitted their main feature pull request to DRM-Next ahead of the upcoming Linux 5.16 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon Quest X Offline "Data Transfer" Will Connect With The Online Version]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-122805</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/dragon-quest-x-offline-data-transfer-will-connect-with-the-online-version"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T05:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clear the offline game and get a head start online.

The upcoming Square Enix release, Dragon Quest X Offline, is set to arrive on the Switch on 26th February 2022.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retractable Rocket]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2534/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2534/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Go Creators' New Mobile Game Is Pikmin Bloom]]></title>
        <id>1847942115</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-go-creators-new-mobile-game-is-pikmin-bloom-1847942115"/>
        <updated>2021-10-27T00:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Briefly and vaguely announced back in March, Nintendo and Niantic just took the wraps off Pikmin Bloom, the latest game to come from the partnership between the two companies.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alternative Python Implementation "Pyston" Plans For Greater Performance, 64-bit ARM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Pyston-Roadmap-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Pyston-Roadmap-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T22:56:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pyston as the alternative Python implementation open-sourced originally by Dropbox is forming ambitious plans for a bright future...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rychlá oprava dotazů ve vyhledávači pomocí neuronových sítí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15721</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/rychla-oprava-dotazu-ve-vyhledavaci-pomoci-neuronovych-siti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dotazy zadané do vyhledání obsahují řadu chyb. Vyhledávače umí tyto chyby odstranit a díky tomu nalézt lepší výsledky. V Seznamu jsme nedávno zrychlili a zlepšili opravu dotazů pomocí neuronových sítí.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ondřej Filip)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (27. 10. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15728</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-27-10-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si představíme nástroj pro automatické klikání, vyzkoušíme sofistikovanou kalkulačku, podíváme se na otevřeného klienta pro OneNote a řekneme si o nástroj pro auditování a obnovu hesel ve Windows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Element One propojí Matrix, WhatsApp, Signal a Telegram]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/element-one-propoji-matrix-whatsapp-signal-a-telegram</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/element-one-propoji-matrix-whatsapp-signal-a-telegram"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T21:37:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři komunikátoru Element, dříve Riot, představili Element One. Za 5 dolarů měsíčně propojí Matrix, WhatsApp, Signal a Telegram.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD's insanely big 14TB HDD is down to £222, almost £90 off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-insanely-big-14tb-hdd-is-down-to-222-almost-90-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-insanely-big-14tb-hdd-is-down-to-222-almost-90-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T20:37:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Western Digital's 14TB Elements external hard drive is one of the largest you can buy, making it ideal for backing up entire computers, storing massive media libraries and generally being a massive data hoarder. It normally retails for around £300, but today it's dropped down to £222, an £89 discount below RRP. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js 12]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/next.js-12</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/next.js-12"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T20:28:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na konferenci Next.js Conf bylo oznámeno vydání nové verze 12 open source frameworku Next.js (Wikipedie) pro psaní webových aplikací v Reactu. Přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best PCIe 4.0 SSD we've tested is going cheap at Amazon UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-pcie-40-ssd-weve-tested-is-going-cheap-at-amazon-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-pcie-40-ssd-weve-tested-is-going-cheap-at-amazon-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T20:18:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WD's SN850 SSD is the fastest SSD we've ever tested, beating out rivals like the Samsung 980 Pro and Crucial P5 Plus in most workloads. If you've got a PCIe 4.0 compatible PC - or a PS5 - then this is the NVMe SSD you want! Today, both the 1TB and 2TB sizes are discounted at Amazon UK, making it a great time to upgrade to the latest and greatest NVMe SSD. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can visit New Vegas again in a Fallout 4 mod]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-visit-new-vegas-again-in-a-fallout-4-mod</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-visit-new-vegas-again-in-a-fallout-4-mod"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T18:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What happens in New Vegas stays in New Vegas, they say, though New Vegas itself will not stay in Fallout: New Vegas. A new mod named Project Mojave is attempting to recreate a lot of the post-apocalyptic Sin City and surrounding areas as a Fallout 4 mod, and you can play the first slice now. But to manage your expectations: it is not an attempt to recreate Obsidian Entertainment's game Fallout: New Vegas inside Fallout 4.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel AMX Support Appears Ready For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-For-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-For-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T18:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been over one year since Intel disclosed Advanced Matrix Extensions and began posting patches for bringing up AMX support under Linux in anticipation of Xeon Scalable "Sapphire Rapids" processors. While the compiler-side work to GCC and LLVM/Clang has been landing, finally with the forthcoming Linux 5.16 cycle that AMX support appears ready for landing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turbo Overkill is the most fun you'll have with a chainsaw leg]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turbo-overkill-is-the-most-fun-youll-have-with-a-chainsaw-leg-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/turbo-overkill-is-the-most-fun-youll-have-with-a-chainsaw-leg-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T17:46:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually, I'd assume that if a chainsaw was near someone's leg, that'd be a problem. But, when the chainsaw is embedded into your own leg and you can flick it out every time you do a butt slide, well then, it's much more of a problem for your enemies' ankles. This is exactly what you're in for with Turbo Overkill, an upcoming shooter which took Apex Legends' excellent sliding mechanics and asked, "What if we added deadly spinning blades?" I've had a chat with game director Sam Prebble and even played a little bit myself, and I think you'll like the answer. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 is out now in early access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-is-out-now-in-early-access</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-is-out-now-in-early-access"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T16:16:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 has launched in early access, inviting us all on a delightfully stressful wagon ride. The sequel to Red Hook Studios' dark roguelike moves away from expeditions in the gloomy Hamlet, and instead sends you on a journey through horrific lands to stop an apocalypse. The devs recently told me about why they're taking their gothic tale on the road, and it has something to do with wanting to emulate a rather uncomfortable road trip.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 41-42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-41-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-41-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V říjnu bylo dosud vydáno Ubuntu 21.10, OpenBSD 7.0 nebo ruská, na Mandrivě založená ROSA Fresh Desktop R12. Na Debian „Bullseye“ přešly jeho deriváty bez systemd Devuan a MX Linux. Také byly aktualizovány distribuce KaOS, GhostBSD, Porteus Kiosk, Redcore Linux či NuTyX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to enable Auto HDR in Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-enable-auto-hdr-in-windows-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-enable-auto-hdr-in-windows-11"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T15:32:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11 may not be an essential upgrade yet, but its Auto HDR feature is mightily impressive: in games that don’t support HDR (high dynamic range) natively, it can apply similar brightness-boosting, colour-emboldening effects. There’s no performance loss, so if you’ve going to upgrade to Windows 11 on your gaming rig, it’s worth giving Auto HDR a try – and this guide will show you how to enable it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 495.44 Linux Driver Released With GBM Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-495.44-Linux-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-495.44-Linux-Driver"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T15:07:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the NVIDIA 495 beta Linux driver from earlier this month, NVIDIA 495.44 is out today for Linux users as the stable release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can batter people with fish in Chivalry 2's new tavern brawl mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-batter-people-with-fish-in-chivalry-2s-new-tavern-brawl-mode</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-batter-people-with-fish-in-chivalry-2s-new-tavern-brawl-mode"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T15:04:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Swords are cool and all but the medieval fight I find a delight is a tavern brawl, so I'm chuffed to heck to see Chivalry 2 focus on them in a new mode. 'Brawl' mode has players rumble through feasts and halls, fighting with found weapons including chairs, steins, and giant fish. Oh yes, thank you. Also in the field of delightful foolishness is a new headbutt move for armless players to launch one desperate last attack.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Step back from the brink in Precipice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/step-back-from-the-brink-in-precipice</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/step-back-from-the-brink-in-precipice"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brinkmanship doesn't get explored all that much in games. Precipice is almost certainly derived from Balance of Power, a political strategy simulation from 1985 about the Cold War powers and their winner-armageddons-all staring contest. It was impressively original, complex, and completely unplayable. Happily, Precipice has kept most of what made that game interesting to begin with, and dumped the baggage.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rad roguelike Caves Of Qud has added friendlier modes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rad-roguelike-caves-of-qud-has-added-friendlier-modes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rad-roguelike-caves-of-qud-has-added-friendlier-modes"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T13:52:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've heard a lot about sci-fantasy roguelike Caves Of Qud, split between "This game is amazing" and "This game sounds amazing but what am I doing and why do I keep dying?" Good news for both types: the latest early access update has added new areas, factions, and items for experienced players to enjoy, while also adding two new friendlier modes. Character creation is overhauled too, complete with some helpful presets.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core i9 11900K: Five Linux Distros Show Sizable Lead Over Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30640</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30640"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T13:09:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that Windows 11 has been out as stable and the initial round of updates coming out, I've been running fresh Windows 11 vs. Linux benchmarks for seeing how Microsoft's latest operating system release compares to the fresh batch of Linux distributions. First up is the fresh look at the Windows 11 vs. Linux performance on an Intel Core i9 11900K Rocket Lake system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Looking For Community Feedback As Ubuntu 22.04 LTS Development Begins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Feedback-For-Ubuntu-22.04-LTS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Feedback-For-Ubuntu-22.04-LTS"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T12:25:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Ubuntu 22.04 LTS "Jammy Jellyfish" beginning development, Canonical is soliciting community feedback as they plot out more of the planned changes for this next major release and areas to focus on enhancing over the next six months...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yuzu umí hry pro Nintendo Switch v rozlišení 2K/4K/8K]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/yuzu-umi-hry-pro-nintendo-switch-v-rozliseni-2k-4k-8k</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/yuzu-umi-hry-pro-nintendo-switch-v-rozliseni-2k-4k-8k"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T12:22:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři open source emulátoru přenosné herní konzole Nintendo Switch Yuzu (Wikipedie) na svém blogu informují, že v nejnovějších sestaveních Yuzu je již k dispozici nejžádanější funkce Resolution Scaler aneb hry navržené pro rozlišení 720p/900p/1080p lze hrát v rozlišení 2K/4K/8K.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony Xperia Pro-I, smartphone s 1palcovým snímačem a 4k/120p 12bit videem]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42944</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/sony-xperia-pro-i-smartphone-s-1palcovym-snimacem-a-4k-120p-12bit-videem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T12:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sony inzeruje nový telefon Xperia Pro-I jako filmařský. Do vínku mu dala špičkovou výbavu a hlavně 1" stacked CMOS snímač, což je její aktuální špička v této třídě (a tedy i světová špička). Počin sám o sobě je to zajímavý právě tím, že se podařilo vměstnat fotoaparát s 1palcovým snímačem do těla smartphonu. V minulosti už to takové produkty byly. Panasonic před lety nabízel rozměrově velký model CM1, později Sharp přinesl smartphone Aquos R6 s ekv. 19mm f/1.9 objektivem nad 1" snímačem, v obou případech na objektivu čněl nápis LEICA.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lo-fi horror and the allure of an uncanny Bitsy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-horror-and-the-allure-of-an-uncanny-bitsy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lo-fi-horror-and-the-allure-of-an-uncanny-bitsy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A glitched out corner, textures too-smooth in some places and too-rough in others. Play some distorted audio, and add some film grain. That’s lo-fi horror, baby, and the lo-fi games that fit this brief can prey on the valley between the uncanny and the unknown. It’s no secret that the unknown is the scariest part of any horror media. Well, aside from that clown with extremely sharp and pointy teeth - but that’s a kind of unknown. Like... Who’s their dentist? Where’d they get that axe? You know what... I take it back. I don’t want to know that one. Let’s get back to those lo-fi videogames.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kat Brewster</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ovladač V3DV pro Raspberry Pi 4 úspěšně prošel testy kompatibility s Vulkan 1.1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ovladac-v3dv-pro-raspberry-pi-4-uspesne-prosel-testy-kompatibility-s-vulkan-1.1</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ovladac-v3dv-pro-raspberry-pi-4-uspesne-prosel-testy-kompatibility-s-vulkan-1.1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T11:33:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nadace Raspberry Pi informuje, že ovladač V3DV pro Raspberry Pi 4 úspěšně prošel testy kompatibility s Vulkan 1.1 u Khronosu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do ovladače AMDGPU míří podpora DisplayPort 2.0 Multi-Stream Transport]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42943</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/do-ovladace-amdgpu-miri-podpora-displayport-2-0-multi-stream-transport/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T11:08:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jednou ze změn, které zamířily v těchto dnech do větve DRM-Next, je podpora rozhraní DisplayPort ve verzi 2.0 v rámci otevřeného ovladače AMDGPU pro Radeony. Jde o počáteční várku kódu, samostatný pull request řeší podporu DisplayPort 2.0 Multi-Stream Transport (MST). Jde zhruba o 400 řádků zdrojového kódu, vše v rámci příprav na příští generaci GPU AMD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phasmophobia has added a haunted campsite map and new ghosts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/phasmophobia-has-added-a-haunted-campsite-and-new-ghosts</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/phasmophobia-has-added-a-haunted-campsite-and-new-ghosts"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T10:14:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If Halloween is best spent doing scary things with pals, Phasmophobia is one of the best games to play this Halloween. The cooperative game sends us to investigate haunted places, trying to capture evidence of ghosts without getting murdered by them. And now it's even more Halloween-y (well, technically Friday The 13th-y) thanks to a big new early access update, which has added a new map set in a haunted campground, new types of ghost, and new spooky weather. Great, just what I wanted in a game I'm already too scared to play.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 4 Granted Official Vulkan 1.1 Conformance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-4-Official-VLK-1.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-4-Official-VLK-1.1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T10:05:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week I mentioned how Mesa landed Vulkan 1.1 support for the V3DV driver most notably used by the Raspberry Pi 4 and newer. With those changes in Mesa Git, The Khronos Group has now officially granted this driver Vulkan 1.1 conformance for the Raspberry Pi 4...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDGPU DP 2.0 MST Support Sent In For DRM-Next]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-DP-2.0-MST-PR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-DP-2.0-MST-PR"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T09:58:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMDGPU changes already queued up in DRM-Next for Linux 5.16 brought initial code for DisplayPort 2.0 ahead of next-gen GPUs with this connectivity support. Sent out today as a separate pull request is wiring up the DisplayPort 2.0 Multi-Stream Transport (MST) capability for the AMDGPU kernel driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BLK-MQ Support For OpenZFS Pending As Latest Performance Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-Zvol-BLK-MQ-PR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-Zvol-BLK-MQ-PR"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T09:34:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new pull request is pending for implementing multi-queue block (blk-mq) support within OpenZFS' Zvol code, which can lead to sizable performance benefits...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve confirm Steam autumn, winter, and Halloween sale dates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-confirm-steam-autumn-winter-and-halloween-sale-dates</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-confirm-steam-autumn-winter-and-halloween-sale-dates"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T09:07:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve can't keep sales secret. Every year, the big dates leak well in advance, whether whispered by devs or blasted by PayPal newsletters. This year, Valve are apparently content to say them in public where anyone might here. Hey, it's just a sale, why the secrecy? So yup, we now definitely know dates for the Steam Halloween Sale, the Steam Autumn Sale, and the Steam Winter Sale.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best LAPA loadout in Warzone Season 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-lapa-loadout-warzone</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-lapa-loadout-warzone"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T08:36:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best LAPA loadout in Warzone Season 6? Treyarch and Raven Software are sending Cold War out with a bang, adding a series of unusual, interesting weapons in the final seasons. The LAPA SMG is the latest, and one of the most intriguing yet. Several of its barrel attachments alter the LAPA’s damage and fire rate. That variety makes the LAPA a very fun gun to customize and play around with. Of course, there is always a best configuration. Once you’ve had your fun and are ready to sweat, we’re here to help.

The LAPA’s range isn’t great, but up close it has monstrous potential. Its high neck and head multipliers make for a skill-dependant weapon, but in the right hands, with the right build, the LAPA fries. Here’s our build of choice:

As usual, we’re starting off with an Agency Suppressor. Added range and bullet velocity on a suppressor remain nigh-impossible to pass up. As long as you’re using a Cold War weapon, you’ll want this attachment. Things get interesting with the barrel. We’ve gone with the Rifled Barrel, which provides the most consistent damage profile. The LAPA very much relies on chest, neck, and headshots, but the Rifled Barrel helps even out the damage to the stomach and limbs. All of the barrels are frankly pretty close in power though, so try a few and see what feels right.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[25. stretnutie komunity Cloud Native – Kubernetes (online)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42940</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/25-stretnutie-komunity-cloud-native-kubernetes-online/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T07:44:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[10.11.2021 od 18:00 do 20:00, nosná téma meetupu: Day-2 operations (wins/fails)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc7 o 1 den později, finální verze na spadnutí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42942</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-5-15-rc7-o-1-den-pozdeji-finalni-verze-na-spadnuti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obvykle vydává Linus Torvalds nové verze jádra v neděli, novou vývojovou verzi Linuxu 5.15 však nechal na pondělí, neb je na cestách. Každopádně Linux 5.15 RC7 je na světě a jsme zase o kousek blíže k finálnímu vydání a přechod na vývoj v rámci větve budoucího Linuxu 5.16.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux prolomil hranici 10 miliónů IOPS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42941</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-prolomil-hranici-10-milionu-iops/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T07:09:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Několikrát jsme zpravodajství Jense Axboeho o pokračujících optimalizacích linuxového IO subsystému vynechali. Včera Jens informoval o dosažení nové mety, která překonává kulatou hranici 10 miliónů IOPS na jedno CPU jádro. Testovací stroj je přitom stále stejný, tedy AMD Ryzen 9 5950X v kombinaci s dvojicí úložišť Intel Optane 5800X.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Continues To Improve Power Management For Older NVIDIA Tegra SoCs To Avoid Overheating]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.17-Tegra-PM-Hot</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.17-Tegra-PM-Hot"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Tegra 2 and Tegra 3 SoCs are a decade old, the mainline Linux kernel continues working to improve the power management / thermal behavior for them in order to deal with heating issues for devices relying on these SoCs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PiBox, NAS postavený na Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/pibox-nas-postaveny-na-raspberry-pi-compute-module-4</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/pibox-nas-postaveny-na-raspberry-pi-compute-module-4"/>
        <updated>2021-10-26T02:29:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PiBox je NAS postavený na Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4. Na Kickstarteru byla spuštěna kampaň na jeho podporu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knot DNS: správa zóny a zónové soubory]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15730</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/knot-dns-sprava-zony-a-zonove-soubory/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V předchozím díle jsme si vytvořili jednoduchou zónu ve formě zónového souboru a dnes si povíme, jak s takovým souborem pracovat. Jedná se o nejčastější uživatelskou operaci a je užitečné jí porozumět.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Daniel Salzman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operace s daty uloženými v binárních souborech v knihovnách NumPy a Pandas]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15731</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/operace-s-daty-ulozenymi-v-binarnich-souborech-v-knihovnach-numpy-a-pandas/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poměrně často se můžeme setkat s požadavkem analýzy dat uložených v binárních souborech. S těmito soubory dokáže do určité míry pracovat jak knihovna NumPy, tak i knihovna Pandas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc7 Released A Day Late Due To Travels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc7"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds normally releases new kernel versions on Sundays like clockwork, but yesterday was one of the rare occasions where that trend was interrupted...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger's Open-Source Bias, Intel's Pledge To Openness]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Pledge-To-Open</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Pledge-To-Open"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T18:38:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of Intel's inaugural Intel Innovation event taking place virtually later this week, Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger published an open letter to an open ecosystem...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newest Linux Optimizations Can Achieve 10M IOPS Per-Core With IO_uring]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-IO_uring-10M-IOPS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-IO_uring-10M-IOPS"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T18:27:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just one week ago Linux block subsystem maintainer Jens Axboe was optimizing the kernel to get 8 million IOPS on a single CPU core. He progressed the week hitting around ~8.9M IOPS per-core and began to think he was hitting the hardware limits and running out of possible optimizations. However, this week he is kicking things off by managing to hit 10 million IOPS!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moonglow Bay review: a relaxing fishing RPG that's all about keeping it reel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonglow-bay-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/moonglow-bay-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything in the seaside town of Moonglow Bay has seen better days. That includes you, a middle-aged accountant who’s moved out of the big city for a fresh start. But things never go quite to plan, do they? The moment-to-moment of Moonglow Bay is a chilled-out experience of getting out onto the waves, exploring various biomes, catching fish, and cooking them up to sell or gift to the townspeople. But within that is an exploration of things going awry, and letting go of old dreams in order to build new ones.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Castello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Please, stop with all the godawful emails about NFT gaming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-stop-with-all-the-godawful-emails-about-nft-gaming</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-stop-with-all-the-godawful-emails-about-nft-gaming"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T16:21:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It started a few months ago: we got an email about shoes designed using 'blockchain technology', and had a good laugh about it as a concept. But in retrospect, this email was merely the ripple on a glass of water that go ahead of a T-Rex's mighty tread. Except in this analogy the T-Rex is one of 10,001 unique dinosaurs programatically generated from different traits. And it's wearing wacky sunglasses and smoking a pipe.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No More Heroes developers Grasshopper bought by NetEase]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-more-heroes-developers-grasshopper-bought-by-netease</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-more-heroes-developers-grasshopper-bought-by-netease"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T14:36:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese publishers NetEase have bought Grasshopper Manufacture, the Japanese studio behind stylish, swaggering games including No More Heroes, The Silver Case, and Killer7. While NetEase have roots in mobile games, they have been investing in fancier things. Grasshopper say that with NetEase's cash, they plan to release "three even higher-quality 'Grasshopper Manufacture Games'" over the next decade.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ODROID Smart Power3]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42939</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/odroid-smart-power3/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T14:33:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hardkernel, výrobce jednodeskových počítačů ODROID, uvedl dvoukanálový měřič proudu a spotřeby ODROID Smart Power3. Ten má pomoci vývojářům malých zařízení například redukovat jejich spotřebu. Zařízení používá ESP32 a výstup je možné přenášet po sériové lince přes USB do počítače.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite campaign trailer shows big levels with bases to capture]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-campaign-trailer-shows-big-levels-with-bases-to-capture</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-campaign-trailer-shows-big-levels-with-bases-to-capture"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T13:51:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After focusing a lot of attention on Halo Infinite's multiplayer, Microsoft have turned back to showing off the story campaign. Today's new campaign trailer, sadly, did not give us another hot WWE promo from a space-ape but it did kinda have Far Cry-ish vibes. Watch on for Master Chef zooming around big levels in vehicles, causing big explosions, upgrading his abilities, and bantering with his new Tamagotchi girlfriend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy review: a blast from the past]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxy-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a video game landscape that's pocked with millions of map markers and vast open worlds, Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy is a linear action adventure game with a clear beginning, middle and an end. It's an approach that feels refreshingly old-school, in the way it guides you smoothly from one story bit to another. But this doesn't mean it's one big flatline without any peaks, troughs, or surprises.
If anything, the game as a whole is a wonderful surprise. Planet-hopping as Star Lord is great fun, made even better by his colourful compatriots and the genuinely funny craic they share. Marvel fan or clueless layman? Doesn't matter, you're in for a good time no matter where you sit on the MCU scale.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Will Be A Great Christmas Gift For Open-Source Fans With Many New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Early-Feature-Look</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Early-Feature-Look"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:42:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Linux 5.15 isn't even making its debut for another week or two, there is already a lot to look forward to when it comes to Linux 5.16. Here is a look at some of the new features expected for the 5.16 cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Halloween Week on RPS, and we've got a load of horror-themed writing to celebrate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/happy-halloween-on-rps-have-a-load-of-horror-themed-writing-to-celebrate</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/happy-halloween-on-rps-have-a-load-of-horror-themed-writing-to-celebrate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:39:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Halloween you horrible little monsters! To celebrate the spookiest of all seasons - with the big day itself coming up at the weekend - we've got a whole host of horror-themed articles that you'll see spread out over the week. Like ectoplasm. Or toxic waste. Something thematically oozey. 
These will get you in the mood for dressing as a character from a Resident Evil game, or a scary cat of some description. Keep checking the Halloween 2021 tag to see more appearing, out of thin air - like a g-g-g-ghost.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel vydal jako open source ControlFlag pro automatickou kontrolu kódu v C/C++]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42938</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-vydal-jako-oepn-source-controlflag-pro-automatickou-kontrolu-kodu-v-c-c/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:25:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minulý týden Intel uvolnil svůj nástroj ControlFlag jako open source pod licencí MIT. ControlFlag automaticky kontroluje kód v C/C++ a využívá speciální samoučící detekci vzorů. Naučen byl na asi miliardě řádek zdrojových kódů open source software na GitHubu. Dokáže detekovat anomálie v kódu, které by mohly být potenciálně zdroji chyb.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch's McCree will be renamed Cole Cassidy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatchs-mccree-will-be-renamed-cole-cassidy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatchs-mccree-will-be-renamed-cole-cassidy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:10:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard have announced that Overwatch's McCree will be known as Cole Cassidy going forward. They're renaming the cowboy to distance him from his real-life namesake, former Blizzard employee Jesse McCree. He left the developer due to unknown reasons in August, but his departure came after the State of California filed a lawsuit against Activision Blizzard, alleging the company fostered a "frat boy" culture of sexual harassment and discrimination. The name change will take effect in-game tomorrow.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Beatrix Potter and a fear of open water inspired the surreal, Limbo-like horror puzzler Silt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-beatrix-potter-and-a-fear-of-open-water-inspired-the-surreal-limbo-like-horror-puzzler-silt</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-beatrix-potter-and-a-fear-of-open-water-inspired-the-surreal-limbo-like-horror-puzzler-silt"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["I have a phobia of animal suits, and I have done my entire life," says surreal artist and Spiral Circus' co-founder Tom Mead. I'm listening to him talk about the making of his latest game, Silt, at EGX 2021. First announced at the PC Gaming Show earlier in the year, Silt is a surreal 2D puzzle game in which you play a mysterious diver who can project their soul through the window of their diving helmet to possess nearby fish. Piranhas can chomp through chains and ropes, for example, while hammerhead sharks can help bash crumbling walls to create new pathways. Hand drawn by Mead using a simplified version of his signature cross hatching and fineliner penmanship, Silt instantly calls to mind the likes of Limbo and Inside. And yet the origins of this strange, watery tale stem from a far more innocuous source of inspiration. 
"The main influence to any of my work is good old Beatrix Potter, believe it or not," Mead continues. "I blame my mum entirely because she made me and my sister watch this horrible ballet when I was a kid, and I still haven't watched it since then. Over the years, though, I realised that this was one of my main things that fuelled my characters, and the fox man character, I started drawing him and he became my main character for years."
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kodi "Matrix" 19.3]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/kodi-matrix-19.3</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/kodi-matrix-19.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T10:44:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána třetí opravná verze 19.3 v únoru vydané verze 19.0 multimediálního centra Kodi (dříve XBMC, Wikipedie) s kódovým označením Matrix.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynatron A39 - A Good Heatsink For Threadripper/EPYC 4U Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30639</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30639"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T10:11:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quietly released earlier this year was the Dynatron A39 heatsink that is capable of up to 280 Watts heat dissipation for satisfying even the very latest, high-end AMD EPYC 7003 "Milan" processors. This Dynatron A39 TR4/sTRX4/SP3 heatsink has been working out very well for those needing to cool a Threadripper/EPYC system in a 3U or larger enclosure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12 Merges Initial Support For RISC-V's Bitmanip Extensions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-Bitmanip-Extension</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-Bitmanip-Extension"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T09:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the recent RISC-V Bitmanip work in Binutils, the GCC 12 compiler has now landed preliminary support for the RISC-V ISA's bit manipulation extension...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age Of Empires 4 review: a confident and moreish strategy epic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/age-of-empires-4-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/age-of-empires-4-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T07:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's tempting to bang on about the history of Age Of Empires, but let's be real here, you already know it well enough. Even if you haven't played them, the Age Of Empires games were a pillar of RTS design, and probably the most popular candidate for a comeback since publishers largely abandoned the genre in the 2000s.
Let's not argue about which of its elements is the defining one. They're base building, four-resource-gathering contests between factions based on historical world powers, and progress throughout a match happens in explicitly tiered eras that loosely represent historical ages. Age Of Empires 4 has all of that, across four 9-mission single player campaigns, 17 skirmish maps (which can be slightly modified with seed numbers, and we're told more map options are coming), and 8 playable, well-differentiated and slightly unequal civilisations. And I kinda like it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevConf.cz 2022 - deadline na přihlášení přednášek prodloužen do 31. října]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42936</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/devconf-cz-2022-deadline-na-prihlaseni-prednasek-prodlouzen-do-31-rijna/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T06:35:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Čtrnáctý ročník konference DevConf.cz proběhne 28–29. ledna v hybridním formátu: fyzicky na FIT VUT a zároveň v online prostředí. Pokud chcete přispět do programu svou vlastní přednáškou nebo workshopem, čas na přihlášení máte do 31. října, tedy do konce tohoto týdne, prostřednictvím online formuláře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nejlepší open source software pode InfoWorld 2021 Bossie Awards]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42937</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nejlepsi-open-source-software-pode-infoworld-2021-bossie-awards/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T06:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Známý americký server o informačních technologiích InfoWorld ocenil nejlepší open source software za rok 2021 cenou Bossie (Best of Open Source Software) pro development, analýzu dat a strojové učení. Oceněno bylo 28 projektů, mezi nimi například Windows Terminal, který používá akceleraci GPU a je až o řád rychlejší než tradiční Windows konzole.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slope Hypothesis Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2533/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2533/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-25T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: Intel SGX prolomen, enklávy nejsou v bezpečí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15724</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-intel-sgx-prolomen-enklavy-nejsou-v-bezpeci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V dnešním díle postřehů se podíváme na útoky v jižní Asii, na e-mailovou kampaň trojanu FlawedGrace, na varování před chybami, na zatýkání kyberzločinců a na ostatní zajímavosti ze světa výpočetní techniky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CESNET CERTS)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu zrychluje Snap, GNOME 41 v repozitářích openSUSE]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15726</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/ubuntu-zrychluje-snap-gnome-41-v-repozitarich-opensuse/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři Ubuntu se snaží zrychlit Snap. Desktopové prostředí GNOME 41 je dostupné v repozitářích openSUSE. Vývojáři operačního systému Haiku začali práci na portování ovladačů Mesa Radeon Vulkan. Otevřený operační systém Sculpt OS založený na frameworku Genode vydal svou novou verzi.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meson v0.60 Build System Brings Numerous Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Meson-0.60-Build-System</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Meson-0.60-Build-System"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T17:54:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meson 0.60 was released on Sunday as the newest version of this increasingly popular and widely-used cross-platform build system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Continues Work On USB4 Support In Their Linux Graphics Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-More-USB4-DC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-More-USB4-DC"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T15:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month AMD's open-source driver engineers began posting patches for the AMDGPU kernel driver to handle USB4 DP tunneling. That tunneling for DisplayPort with USB4 is for upcoming Yellow Carp / Rembrandt APUs. The USB4 driver bring-up  within AMDGPU continues...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Toolchain Begins Landing LoongArch Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Binutils-LoongArch</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Binutils-LoongArch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T14:53:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to Loongson working on Linux kernel support for their MIPS-derived LoongArch CPU architecture, the first bits of the GNU toolchain support for this Chinese CPU architecture have been merged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Organizace letos vynaloží na technologie podporující budoucnost práce 656 miliard dolarů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-organizace-letos-vynalozi-na-technologie-podporujici-budoucnost-prace-656-miliard-dolaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-organizace-letos-vynalozi-na-technologie-podporujici-budoucnost-prace-656-miliard-dolaru"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat novými aktualizacemi podporuje edge computing. Organizace letos vynaloží na technologie podporující budoucnost práce 656 miliard dolarů. HPE GreenLake přináší inovativní architekturu správy dat. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (2) Nedostatek dílů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Continues Work On User-Managed Concurrency Groups For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-UMCG-Linux-v0.7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-UMCG-Linux-v0.7"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T10:21:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year was news that Google is finally working to open-source their Fibers user-space scheduling framework. For the better part of the past decade they have been developing this user-space scheduling framework and finally now are working on offering public, open-source code intended for upstream around their work...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-615</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-615"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for nearly having a heart attack when the toaster pops. Before you jolt awake, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bareflank 3.0 Hypervisor Released With Microkernel Design, AMD Virtualization Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T09:37:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bareflank, as what started a few years ago as a Linux hypervisor written in modern C++ and focused on security and other new features as a "hypervisor SDK" of sorts, is now up to version 3.0...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sociální síť Truth Social porušuje licenci AGPLv3]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/socialni-sit-truth-social-porusuje-licenci-agplv3</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/socialni-sit-truth-social-porusuje-licenci-agplv3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T23:33:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Trump Media & Technology Group (TMTG) založena bývalým prezidentem USA Donaldem Trumpem spouští sociální síť Truth Social. Ta je založena na open source sociální síti Mastodon, jejíž zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici pod licencí AGPLv3 (GNU Affero General Public License). Zdrojové kódy Truth Social ale k dispozici nejsou a tím pádem je licence AGPLv3 porušována. Dle organizace Software Freedom Conservancy má TMTG 30 dnů na nápravu, tj. zveřejnění zdrojových kódů Truth Social. Pokud se tak nestane, přijde o práva ke zdrojovým kódům sítě Mastodon.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Distributions Timeline 21.10]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-distributions-timeline-21.10</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/linux-distributions-timeline-21.10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T22:14:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fabio Loli vydal verzi 21.10 časové osy linuxových distribucí Linux Distributions Timeline. Ke stažení je png i svg. Jedná se o fork již neaktualizovaného GLDT (GNU/Linux Distribution Timeline).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Panasonic končí s výrobou TV v ČR, SiFive má o polovinu rychlejší jádro RISC-V]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15729</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/panasonic-konci-s-vyrobou-tv-v-cr-sifive-ma-o-polovinu-rychlejsi-jadro-risc-v/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšel MX Linux 21 „Wildflower“ přechází na Debian 11, GIMP 2.99.8, XWayland 21.1.3 přidá podporu ovladače Nvidia 495.xx, Wine 6.20 opravuje 29 chyb, PipeWire 0.3.39 vylepšuje Libcamera i podporu JACK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mediatek Posts 8k Lines Of New Linux Kernel Driver Code For AI Processing Unit Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mediatek-MT8192-APU-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mediatek-MT8192-APU-Driver"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T21:24:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a number of months Mediatek engineers have been posting some Linux kernel driver code for bringing up the AI Processing Unit (APU) within the MT8192 SoC while out this weekend is the complete patch series at more than eight thousand lines of code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex86 Processor Detection Landing For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Detection-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Detection-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T16:47:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I wrote about Vortex86 processors seeing detection work under Linux for improving the state of these aging x86 32-bit SoCs. That work is now slated to be introduced in the upcoming Linux 5.16 cycle for those running these aging SoCs/processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-166</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-166"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I ate my first mince pie this week, which feels like a betrayal of my belief that Christmastime should not start before Halloween is over. That said, it wasn't a mince puff, so does it really count? Please, tell me about your festive eating. And may as well mention what you're playing this weekend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 42/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-42-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CD Projekt have bought the studio behind The Flame In The Flood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-have-bought-the-studio-behind-the-flame-in-the-flood</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-have-bought-the-studio-behind-the-flame-in-the-flood"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T16:35:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk and Witcher crew CD Projekt have acquired The Molasses Flood, the American studio behind post-apocalyptic raft ride The Flame In The Flood and base-building game Drake Hollow. Huh! The studio will be making a game set in one of CD Projekt's worlds, which warrants a second: huh! It's all secret for now.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My hunger for games like Warcraft 2 is slowly being sated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-hunger-for-games-like-warcraft-2-is-slowly-being-sated</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/my-hunger-for-games-like-warcraft-2-is-slowly-being-sated"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:38:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I think back to the games of my childhood, nothing puts a warm, fuzzy smile on my face like Warcraft 2. As one of the few PC games I had growing up, I ended up playing the campaign over and over again - or at least starting it over and over again - for what felt like actual years. I loved building up my fort and endlessly poking the peasants and peons until they shouted back at me in annoyance, and man alive, there is nothing sweeter than ordering a tooled-up army across the map and absolutely wrecking the enemy in one fell swoop of doom and destruction. 
It is something I wish I could play again now with all my heart. I know there's version of it on GOG, but I'd also just quite like, you know, a newer, shinier version with a more up to date UI and all that jazz, and one whose map didn't whizz over to the other side of the screen with a single tap of the arrow key. I'd also like a version that isn't, somehow, made by Activision Blizzard because... *gestures to all their ongoing harassment lawsuits*. Fortunately, I've happened upon a couple of games in recent weeks that have really scratched that old Warcraft 2 itch of mine. I've already written about one of them - Diplomacy Is Not An Option - and the other is Age Of Darkness: Final Stand, a game with the most boring name imaginable, but is secretly very good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to uninstall Windows 11 and go back to Windows 10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-uninstall-windows-11-and-go-back-to-windows-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-uninstall-windows-11-and-go-back-to-windows-10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:33:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Change isn’t for everyone: just ask the 5% of Steam Hardware Survey respondents still using Windows 7. Sadly, even the most eager of early adopters might be looking to find out how to uninstall Windows 11, the very latest of Microsoft’s operating systems. It could be the newly centralised Start menu; it could be the lack of DirectStorage support among games making the best SSDs perform below their full capability; it could just be a single unsquished bug, which remains a risk with the infant OS. Fortunately, if you decide to want to switch back to Windows 10 within 10 days of installing its successor, it’s possible to roll back in just a few, mildly regretful clicks.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to upgrade to Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-upgrade-to-windows-11"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:32:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, fine, here’s how to upgrade to Windows 11 from Windows 10. The current stance of this hardware ed is that Windows 11 has some cool features but is yet to fulfil its potential, largely owing to the missing DirectStorage capability – which, to be fair, could be a very big deal when games start supporting it. For now, then, it’s a free but absolutely not an essential upgrade, and you can think of this post as the RPS equivalent of that video where Valve tore down a Steam Deck: we’re not saying you should do this, just that you can do this. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby bude mít just-in-time compiler YJIT]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42935</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ruby-bude-mit-just-in-time-compiler-yjit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T15:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maxime Chevalier-Boisvertová představila v úterý just-in-time compiler pro Ruby s názvem YJIT, který používá Lazy Basic Block Versioning (LBBV). YJIT je průměrně o 23 % rychlejší než CRuby. Podle plánu by YJIT měl být v Ruby 3.1, jen nebude ve výchozím stavu zapnut.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Truck Simulator now supports mods in multiplayer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/truck-simulator-now-supports-mods-in-multiplayer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/truck-simulator-now-supports-mods-in-multiplayer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T14:06:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After adding official multiplayer modes to American Truck Simulator and Euro Truck Simulator 2, developers SCS Software have now made both support mods in multiplayer too. They're games many truckers mod with the trucks and decor of their dreams, so it'll be nice to show everyone your true truck self. I'd call this your drivatar but Forza has already claimed that.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto remastered trilogy's first trailer looks shiny yet cartoony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-remastered-trilogys-first-trailer-looks-shiny-yet-cartoony</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grand-theft-auto-remastered-trilogys-first-trailer-looks-shiny-yet-cartoony"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:32:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a stretch of teasing and leaking, Rockstar today revealed how they've renovated the GTA 3 trilogy for the upcoming horribly named collection, Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - The Definitive Edition. A new trailer and screenshots reveal that GTA 3, Vice City, and San Andreas still have distinctly cartoon vibes, now paired with fancy reflections and effects. Rockstar also announced a release date of November 11th and a price of... £55? Gosh. See the new look for yourself in the trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doom Eternal's Horde mode arrives next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-eternals-horde-mode-arrives-next-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-eternals-horde-mode-arrives-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday the 26th of October, Doom Eternal players will be able to rip and tear through the hellish shooter's new horde mode. If you're not quite satisfied with murdering demons in a linear fashion, you'll be able to jump into a match to fight off waves of the beasties instead. It's arriving in the game's 6.66 update, along with two new master levels and Battlemode 2.0.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite will let you host a cross-platform LAN party on a PC dedicated server]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-let-you-host-a-cross-platform-lan-party-on-a-pc-dedicated-server</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-let-you-host-a-cross-platform-lan-party-on-a-pc-dedicated-server"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:25:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After decades of Halo being primarily an Xbox series [settle down, disgruntled elderly Mac fanatics -ed.], Halo Infinite will buck that with a simultaneous launch on PC too. With that December launch drawing near, a new trailer focuses on the PC edition, detailing various graphics settings and multiplayer options and noting the interesting detail that you'll be able to use a PC to host a dedicated server for a cross-platform LAN party. Watch on for lots of shots of scrolling through options menus.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nová sociální síť TRUTH Social bývalého prezidenta Donalda Trumpa porušuje AGPL]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42934</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nova-socialni-sit-truth-social-byvaleho-prezidenta-donalda-trumpa-porusuje-agpl/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T11:16:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bývalému prezidentovi USA Donaldu Trumpovi byl na konci volebního období zablokován účet na Twitteru i Facebooku kvůli útoku jeho příznivců na Kapitol. Donald si však vytvořil vlastní sociální síť TRUTH Social, která je v současné době pouze na pozvání a měla by být volně dostupná od příštího roku.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World character transfers paused due to gold duping glitch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-character-transfers-paused-due-to-gold-duping-glitch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-character-transfers-paused-due-to-gold-duping-glitch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World's long-awaited character transfers have been taken away almost as soon as they arrived, because they've caused a glitch that allows players to duplicate gold. The bug came about after the MMORPG's 1.0.3 update this week. It makes it so characters don't save properly after transferring, letting them trade gold and items to others while magically keeping it in their own pockets. Amazon have paused server transfers for the time being to work on a fix, and have warned players that those caught exploiting the glitch will be banned.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Psychonauts 2 turns the mind inside out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-psychonauts-2-turns-the-mind-inside-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-psychonauts-2-turns-the-mind-inside-out"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“It’s all in your head.” It’s a response that encapsulates all the condescension and ignorance surrounding mental health issues. And yet, in a way, it’s true. Subjective experience is an objective reality – that just so happens to be located and locked away in your head. 
These individual realities can only be conveyed through language and other subjective means of communication, and more and more games are grasping this fact, turning inward to explore and map the inland empires of the mind. They have all the tools of the medium at their disposal to turn the invisible workings of the mind into landscapes of audio-visual and mechanical metaphors that can be explored and interacted with. At their best, they convey the dynamic and complex mechanisms of the psyche in a way that only this medium can.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proxmox: moderní virtualizační platforma schopná nahradit VMware (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40445</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/proxmox-moderni-virtualizacni-platforma-schopna-nahradit-vmware-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:13:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proxmox je moderní virtualizační platforma, která v mnoha případech může nahradit VMware. Je open-source, zdarma a je postaven na otevřených technologiích jako KVM, LXC, CEPH a dalších. Pokud potřebujete provozovat virtualizaci, Proxmox je pro vás ideální stack a na našem workshopu se dozvíte, jak na něj.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oprava pomalejších procesorů Ryzen ve Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42933</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/oprava-pomalejsich-procesoru-ryzen-ve-windows-11/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T08:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před dvěma týdny jsme psali, že Windows 11 je až o 15 % pomalejší na procesorech AMD Ryzen. Včera Microsoft vydal opravu problému s časováním vyrovnávací paměti L3 u procesorů AMD Ryzen, která je součástí kumulativní preview opravy KB5006746.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chyba v GPSD vás může o víkendu přenést do března 2002]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42932</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chyba-v-gpsd-vas-muze-o-vikendu-prenest-do-brezna-2002/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T05:40:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Program GPSD se používá k obsluze GPS přijímačů v Linuxu a to nejen ke zjištění polohy, ale také k velmi přesné synchronizaci času. GPS formát data však má jen 10 bitů pro kódování týdne. To stačí jen na zhruba 20 let.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Censored Vaccine Card]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2532/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2532/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022's early access beta is available now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022s-early-access-beta-is-available-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022s-early-access-beta-is-available-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T23:22:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022 pre-launch beta is live now. If you buy the kicking sim on Steam or Epic, you can immediately start playing a nearly-finished version of the game. If you're really committed you can probably be sacked at least once before the sun comes up.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Man's Sky's new update lets you ride on flying worms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-new-update-lets-you-ride-on-flying-worms</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-mans-skys-new-update-lets-you-ride-on-flying-worms"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:07:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At this point, it has become a cliché to say that space sim No Man's Sky has come a long way since its initial release. And yet, is there any better example of its long development journey than the sandworms? Initially shown in pre-release trailers only to be cut from the release version, they were finally added in some recent updates. Now the most recent update and seasonal event adds new sandworm varieties, including rideable sandworms. The worm has indeed turned.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence a signály odměn]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-a-signaly-odmen"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problém zpětnovazebného učení u skutečné umělé inteligence. Primordiální černé díry. Záhadné rádiové vlny. Nejchytřejší psi. Drony jako hasiči.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 „Impish Indri“: poslední verze před velkým dubnovým LTS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15725</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/ubuntu-21-10-impish-indri-posledni-verze-pred-velkym-dubnovym-lts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nové Ubuntu přináší jednu významnou evoluční změnu, GNOME 40. Jinak jde z velké části o poklidné vody připravující půdu pro příští vydání s dlouhou podporou. Současné novinky napovídají, kam se vývoj ubírá.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's flagship Virtuoso RGB Wireless XT headset is 26% off in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-flagship-virtuoso-rgb-wireless-xt-headset-is-26-off-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/corsairs-flagship-virtuoso-rgb-wireless-xt-headset-is-26-off-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Corsair's Virtuoso RGB Wireless XT is just as fancy as its long-ass name implies, and today it's £65 off as part of Corsair's autumn sale. That drops the price from £250 to £185, considerably less than even the going price on Amazon of £230. I think this is a great deal if you've got a hefty budget for an all-in-one wireless headset, so let me share a little on why I'm so convinced!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haunted Chocolatier is the Stardew Valley developer's next RPG]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-chocolatier-is-the-stardew-valleys-developers-next-rpg"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:38:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The developer of Stardew Valley has revealed their next game: Haunted Chocolatier. It's again a game about moving to a new town to "try your hand at a new way of living", but instead of a farm, you're opening a chocolate shop staffed by ghosts. There's an adorable trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a high-spec 1TB NVMe SSD for £139 after a 21% off voucher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-high-spec-1tb-nvme-ssd-for-139-after-a-21-off-voucher</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-high-spec-1tb-nvme-ssd-for-139-after-a-21-off-voucher"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:34:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The XPG S70 Blade is one of the few 'second-gen' PCIe 4.0 SSDs on the market, offering incredible speeds on PC and even full compatibility with PS5. Today the 1TB model is heavily discounted at Amazon UK, with the NVMe drive dropping from £176 all the way to £139. To get the reduced price, tick the box where it says 'Apply 21% voucher'; the reduced price will be visible at the checkout. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 will tweak maps, UI and more in response to beta feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-will-tweak-maps-ui-and-more-in-response-to-beta-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-will-tweak-maps-ui-and-more-in-response-to-beta-feedback"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T21:11:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 has been and gone, and now its developers have written about what they learned based on player feedback. There are some straight fixes, some explanations, and lot more in a post on the Battlefield blog. 

Also: a look at the five previously unrevealed specialists you'll be able to play as when the game launches.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Uncharted movie finally has a trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-uncharted-movie-finally-has-a-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-uncharted-movie-finally-has-a-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T20:52:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Uncharted series will arrive on PC early next year with Uncharted 4: A Thief's End. That game features a retired Nathan Drake being coaxed into another adventure, but you therefore might want to experience some of the Indylike's earlier treasure hunts first. There is literally only one way I can think of to do that: watching the Uncharted movie, which is also due to release in cinemas early next year.

The first trailer just released, starring Tom Holland and Mark Wahlberg.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer cap RazerCon announcements with first PSU and liquid cooler components]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-cap-razercon-announcements-with-first-psu-and-liquid-cooler-components</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-cap-razercon-announcements-with-first-psu-and-liquid-cooler-components"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T18:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Razer, purveyors of green and black gaming peripherals, have announced they’re having a proper go at PC components as well. The Razer Hanbo AIO liquid CPU cooler series, Razer Katana PSUs, Razer Kunai case fans and Razer Pulse Width Modulator (PWM) Fan Controller all debuted during this year's RazerCon showcase.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dwarf Fortress Steam edition video demonstrates convenience of seeing what's happening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-edition-video-demonstrates-convenience-of-seeing-whats-happening</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-edition-video-demonstrates-convenience-of-seeing-whats-happening"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T16:45:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["You will not believe what the hell just happened in Dwarf Fortress!" my pal will tell me, proceeding to share a screenshot which, to me, is indistinguishable from e.g.:

██,.,,;lz,zl;L:@gjse,.gm.,,.m.zm,.m,x.zm.amL:m3jp5jkmToiHy*
████()ht23htuhqIJg.......UG.uos\kjk:███/,,p,c.xz/,c./z,c;\/.
██'z,c./xz,c./zx,cpaswf/w.qfw.,/f,aa███,g.ew/t,3wq./t,,2..@|
█3/.6t,.esg,f.e/sg,./ewt,./w4t4..,1t6,m42ijpnz\kuiys8fun/.|█
█|?|..../\/\..|@@@%%$|"(((|..FHzFhLlk@A}||||....*|JGH,.3████
zZ./@Z@@'Z'@@LSXCl;a,sl;FLZL;@'A:@,;'F":%T@:H^OQHOh8^£$.\/.█

"That's wild!" I will reply, not wanting to hurt their feelings. But how delightful, then, to watch the latest video from the upcoming premium edition, where co-creator Zach Adams demonstrates defending against a goblin attack and you can actually see it's a goblin attack.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amanita's unhappy Happy Game is coming in time for Halloween]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amanitas-unhappy-happy-game-is-coming-in-time-for-halloween</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amanitas-unhappy-happy-game-is-coming-in-time-for-halloween"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T16:12:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amanita Design are known for their cheery and charming adventure games, wonders like Samorost, Machinarium, Botanicula, and Chuchel. Their next game sounds like it should be their cheeriest yet, given that it's named Happy Game. Reader dear, this is a trick. Happy Game is blood and death and horror. You will see this soon, as Amanita today announced plans to release Happy Game on the 28th of October. Or you can try a demo now!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim will add aquariums in its Anniversary Edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrim-will-add-aquariums-in-its-anniversary-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/skyrim-will-add-aquariums-in-its-anniversary-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T15:56:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrim: Anniversary Edition comes out next month, and it's quickly becoming the fishiest version of the RPG yet. Bethesda have announced it will let you add aquariums to your Skyrim homes. We already know this edition will let us go fishing too, so I'm hoping we'll be able to yank those suckers straight out of the sea to put on display in our homes. Can't believe I'm going to buy yet another version of Skyrim just to have pet fish.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 161: the best songs special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-161-the-best-songs-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-161-the-best-songs-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It occurs to me now that "best songs" is probably not a great topic for the podcast, given that we do not perform any of the songs, or put them in the show. But on this week's episode of The Electronic Wireless show, we talk about them songs real good. Plus, we are joined by Randy Newman, who sounds a surprising amount like Matthew Castle.
Matthew himself has a new awkward food related story to share, Nate has been watching Squid Game, and a listener has sent in a very special musical theme for Sweeten The Deal!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can’t buy an RTX 3080? GeForce Now will let you play with one in the cloud]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cant-buy-an-rtx-3080-geforce-now-will-let-you-play-with-one-in-the-cloud</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cant-buy-an-rtx-3080-geforce-now-will-let-you-play-with-one-in-the-cloud"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:24:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nvidia’s GeForce Now cloud gaming service is getting a new, ultra-premium subscription tier powered by its GeForce RTX 3080 GPU. While one of the best graphics cards around, especially for higher resolutions, the RTX 3080 has remained frustratingly hard to find in stock since it launched last year – for many, this GeForce Now tier could be the best chance of seeing what it’s like to play with one, even if is simply streaming from a server rather than a dedicated gaming PC.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter From The Editor #03: EGX Rezzed is dead, long live EGX Rezzed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/letter-from-the-editor-03</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/letter-from-the-editor-03"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:12:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello folks. Sorry to be writing this letter so late into October. This time two weeks ago I was walking the halls of London's ExCel on my way to host the first RPS Presents panel at EGX 2021, and all the planning and organising I had to do for it rather cut back on my available writing time. I then took some time off to recuperate a bit, and here we are, three weeks into October and I'm only just getting round to doing my monthly editor's letter. I do apologise. But! We are here now and there's plenty to talk about. A lot of it is EGX-related, but you'll hopefully have noticed some new site features being introduced these last few weeks as well, which I'll explain below. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charming tower defence Toy Soldiers has an HD remaster now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/charming-tower-defence-toy-soldiers-has-an-hd-remaster-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/charming-tower-defence-toy-soldiers-has-an-hd-remaster-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:07:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2010 tower defence game Toy Soldiers has two big neat ideas: it looks like a toybox upended onto battlefield dioramas built on bedroom tables; and you can take to the battlefield yourself to control units and vehicles. It's a good'un, and today it relaunched with an 'HD' version. I liked the original enough to buy it on both Xbox 360 and PC, but wasn't interested in getting it again until I heard Toy Soldiers: HD offers more than the usual high-res texture overhaul.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dark Pictures Anthology: House Of Ashes review: very nearly a fun horror romp]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-house-of-ashes-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-dark-pictures-anthology-house-of-ashes-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a real soft spot for Supermassive Games. Until Dawn was a knowingly schlocky teen slasher horror film made into an interactive adventure game, and it was great for at least two thirds of its runtime. I've also felt the same about their more recent project, The Dark Pictures Anthology, which began with Man Of Medan in 2019. Every time a new instalment comes out I believe it's in with a shot of being well good - although each one has since made me doubt the "knowing" part of my interpretation of Until Dawn. The latest entry, House Of Ashes, comes the closest yet to recapturing the daft thrills of Until Dawn, with a classic survival-horror setup that's half The Descent and half Aliens.
The five playable protagonists you flit between are trapped in an ancient Sumerian temple that leads into an even deeper cavern, and then an even deeperer, ancienter ruin. The turducken of potholing. But instead of delicious stuffing, the surprise in these layers is a race of vampiric monsters whose vision is based on sound, and whose spit is LSD. Your job is to get your goons out alive, and the main problem is that the goons in question are - instead of a busload of teens on a field trip gone wrong - a small team of US marines searching for WMDs in 2003 Iraq. Wakka wakka.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Austin Powers spliced into Mass Effect makes a disturbingly good Shepard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/austin-powers-spliced-into-mass-effect-makes-a-disturbingly-good-shepard</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/austin-powers-spliced-into-mass-effect-makes-a-disturbingly-good-shepard"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T13:04:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The geth have begun launching seemingly random attacks on human colonies. Rumours are circling that ancient machines will soon emerge from darkspace. There is only one man equipped to deal with these threats: Intergalactic Man Of Mystery, Austin Powers. Someone has made a video editing Mike Myers' 60s spy into Mass Effect and I'm astounded at how well it works. I don't know what else to say. This is Mass Effect in its ultimate form. Please watch it, it's the best minute I've spent all week.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit was inspired by Devil Daggers and a Nicolas Cage film]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-was-inspired-by-devil-daggers-and-a-nicolas-cage-film</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-was-inspired-by-devil-daggers-and-a-nicolas-cage-film"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit is a fast-paced roguelike shooter with hints of Doom, and excellent hands that shoot magical bullets. It's not the first occult-themed game to turn hands into guns (and I sure hope it won't be the last), but is inspired by one. I spoke to Into The Pit's creator, Tom Betts, who told me about the game's Devil Daggers influences, from weaponry to aesthetics, and why the occult setting works so well for the roguelike genre. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 4 s 2 GB paměti dočasně zvyšuje cenu z 35 na 45 dolarů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42931</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/raspberry-pi-4-s-2-gb-pameti-docasne-zvysuje-cenu-z-35-na-45-dolaru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T10:45:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dodavatelské řetězce jsou nestabilní a projevuje se to dlouhými lhůtami na dodávku součástek a narůstajícími cenami. Zasáhlo to také výrobce jednodeskových počítačů Raspberry Pi, který musel poprvé v historii zvýšit cenu modelu RPi 4 zpět z 35 na 45 dolarů. Eben Upton zdůrazňuje, že jde o dočasné zdražení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bethesda's new Starfield trailer introduces mercenary and pirate factions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesdas-new-starfield-trailer-introduces-mercenary-and-pirate-factions</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesdas-new-starfield-trailer-introduces-mercenary-and-pirate-factions"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T10:08:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm fighting off a real Bethesda itch right now. I know I'll hate myself if I start yet another Skyrim playthrough, and I'm too fussy to decide on a Fallout to sink another fifty hours into. But now there's a new Starfield trailer, and it's making me pine for those damned RPGs all the more. The developers have dived into Starfield's history, and revealed a handful of factions we'll come across on our space travels. It's mostly concept art, but hey, it's very nice concept art.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World now lets you transfer your character to another server]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-now-lets-you-transfer-your-character-to-another-server</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-now-lets-you-transfer-your-character-to-another-server"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T09:46:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server transfers opened up in New World overnight, letting players shunt their explorers from one world to another. This is a desirable feature in many MMOs, and particularly in this one because servers were so overloaded at launch that Amazon recommended players join any old server then transfer to their desired home later once things settled. All players get one transfer for free, but only one, with Amazon planning to start selling that service later.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evertried review: a rough-hewn roguelike that fails to stand out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/evertried-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/evertried-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is no mouse cursor in Evertried. You control everything with the keyboard, from the hops and scythe attacks of your cute otherworldly hero, to the settings in the pause menu. It's a strange omission but one that is representative of the feeling this roguelike evokes throughout your time climbing its purgatorial tower of baddies. That is to say, a feeling that there's something important missing. In fact, there seems to be a lot missing from this tile-based timewaster, small touches that could have given its solid foundation the polish it needed to excel. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Základy práce s grafickou plochou v jazyku Basic-256]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15722</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/zaklady-prace-s-grafickou-plochou-v-jazyku-basic-256/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T22:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pro výuku programování se velmi často používají jazyky s grafickým výstupem. Výjimkou není ani Basic-256, který obsahuje grafickou plochu s podporou vykreslení běžných 2D entit, jednotlivých pixelů, ale i zobrazení pohyblivých spritů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matematické měření rozlišení softwarově korigovaného dalekohledu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15553</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/matematicke-mereni-rozliseni-softwarove-korigovaneho-dalekohledu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarově změříme ostrost obrazu, abychom zjistili skutečné zvýšení rozlišení díky jeho použití. Matematiky možná potěší vlastní funkce Fourierovy transformace a centrální limitní věta.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Karel Kulhavý)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get the outstanding Razer Viper ultralight mouse for 50% off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-outstanding-razer-viper-ultralight-mouse-for-50-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-the-outstanding-razer-viper-ultralight-mouse-for-50-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T20:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Razer Viper is one of my favourite mice of all time, whether we're talking about the wireless Ultimate version, the compact Mini model or the vanilla Viper. It's this OG model that is on sale today at Amazon, who have marked it down from £80 to just £40 - an incredible bargain for an ultralight mouse with a high-end optical sensor, optical mouse buttons, flexible cable and low weight of just 69 grams. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get an RTX 3070 gaming laptop for £1250 after a £150 discount]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3070-gaming-laptop-for-1250-after-a-150-discount</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3070-gaming-laptop-for-1250-after-a-150-discount"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T20:05:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Asus Tuf Gaming A15 is a great value gaming laptop that attracted warm reviews for its design and performance, and today it's also the cheapest RTX 3070 gaming laptop we can find*. The A15 FA506QR-HN006T specification, which includes a Ryzen 7 5800H processor, 16GB of RAM and 512GB SSD, is down to just £1250 at Overclockers after a £150 reduction. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CD Projekt Red delay The Witcher 3's next-gen update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-red-delay-the-witcher-3s-next-gen-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cd-projekt-red-delay-the-witcher-3s-next-gen-update"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T19:17:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The update adding raytracing and other mod cons to The Witcher 3 will not launch this year, developers CD Projekt Red announced today. They've been fancying up their fantasy RPG for the latest console generation, and those 'next-gen' additions are headed to PC in a patch too. But not this year. Instead, look to be blinded by the light in spring 2022. They've also delayed the next-gen version of Cyberpunk 2077 for consoles.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[God Of War is coming to PC in January 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/god-of-war-is-coming-to-pc-in-january-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/god-of-war-is-coming-to-pc-in-january-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T16:32:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As was rumoured, the dadtastic godstabber God Of War is indeed coming to PC. Sony today announced that the PlayStation-exclusive action-adventure game will launch for PC on the 14th of January, 2022. Good game, that. It'll have support for assorted PC technical fanciness too.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Subnautica mods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-subnautica-mods</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-subnautica-mods"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:36:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subnautica was a game I spent a lot of time just living in. It was a rare combination of survival and relaxation. I loved the base building, crafting what amounted to a reverse aquarium clinging to an underwater sea cliff. It grew from a small bulb of oxygen into a proper little sanctuary. When I picked it up, it was fairly late into its life, and a number of mods were already waiting to be installed. I quickly dialed down the game’s frustrations and made my time under the sea all the more enjoyable, so here are our picks for the best Subnautica mods available today.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Craig Pearson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave 1.31 s Brave Search jako výchozím vyhledávačem]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42930</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/brave-1-31-s-brave-search-jako-vychozim-vyhledavacem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:33:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová verze webového prohlížeče Brave 1.31 je spojena s přechodem na vlastní vyhledávač jako výchozí – v USA, Kanadě a UK nahrazuje Google, ve Francii střídá Qwant, v Německu zase v Brave přecházejí z DuckDuckGo. Další země se budou přidávat postupně. Uživatelé samozřejmě mohou změnit na jakýkoli jiný a stávajícím uživatelům samozřejmě zůstává jejich nastavení. Brave Search má vlastní nezávislý index i engine, nesleduje uživatele ani jejich vyhledávání a kliknutí. V tuto chvíli nezobrazuje reklamy, ale v budoucnu bude reklamami podporován (plus bude možné používat Premium službu bez reklam).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 20 people reported for behaviour now gone from Activision Blizzard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-20-people-reported-for-behaviour-now-gone-from-activision-blizzard</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-20-people-reported-for-behaviour-now-gone-from-activision-blizzard"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard's initial response to allegations of workplace harrassment and discrimination was disappointing enough that thousands of current and former employees signed an open letter condemning it then hundreds staged a walkout in July. With several legal cases against the Warcraft and Call Of Duty owners underway, they've now admitted they haven't done enough. Yesterday, Along with laying out their next steps, they confirmed that over 20 people have "exited" Activision Blizzard in connection with reports against them.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD Blue SN570 review: The best cheap SSD grows up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wd-blue-sn570-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wd-blue-sn570-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T15:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a time, not so long ago, when the WD Blue line exemplified that “good but boring” quality that sees many a budget SSD damned by faint praise. Fast enough yet rarely eye-catchingly rapid, even when the WD Blue SN500 ditched SATA for the much quicker NVMe interface, they’ve always been sensible purchases that nonetheless lived in the shadow of the WD Black lineup. That all changes with the latest WD Blue SN570: it’s not just an excellent M.2 drive for the money, but quite possibly the single most compelling SSD for anyone sticking with PCIe 3.0.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The zombies in Back 4 Blood are more fashionable than me]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-zombies-in-back-4-blood-are-more-fashionable-than-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-zombies-in-back-4-blood-are-more-fashionable-than-me"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T14:41:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don't know what I was expecting to take away from co-op FPS Back 4 Blood. A greater sense of comradery between myself and my friends? An appreciation of the weighty guns and how magazines snap into place with each reload? The sheer amount of blood that splashes on your person with each wave of zombies you cut down? Yes, all of these things.
But none more so than what the zombies wear. They favour comfortable clothing, but mainly the gilet. They love gilets. And they now have me questioning my fashion choices. Should I also join them as a wearer of gilets?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that we know about Fireflies in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-fireflies</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-fireflies"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T14:40:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about Fireflies in Minecraft? Whether you call them Fireflies, glowbugs, or lightning bugs, they’ll all occupy the same two pixels when they come to Minecraft and it’s time to get fired up for their arrival. Fireflies were announced at Minecraft Live 2021, which also shared more details on the upcoming Caves and Cliffs part 2 update.
This guide will explain everything that you need to know about Fireflies in Minecraft, including when you can expect Fireflies to come to Minecraft, where Fireflies will appear, and what they do.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about mangrove swamps in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-mangrove-swamp</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-mangrove-swamp"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T11:42:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about mangrove swamps in Minecraft? At Minecraft Live 2021, Mojang revealed that mangrove swamps - one of the options in the biome vote way back in 2019 - are finally coming to Minecraft. Many of the ideas mentioned back then, including mangrove trees and frogs, will be key features of the mangrove swamp biome.
This guide will explain everything that you need to know about mangrove swamps in Minecraft, including when mangrove swamps will be released, what you will find in the new biome, and how to grow your own mangrove trees with propagules.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard want harassment lawsuit paused over conflict of interest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-want-harassment-lawsuit-paused-over-conflict-of-interest</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-want-harassment-lawsuit-paused-over-conflict-of-interest"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T10:58:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard have filed an application to halt the harassment and discrimination lawsuit from the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing (DFEH). This follows an update on the suit last week, which revealed that two DFEH lawyers previously worked for the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), who're also going through legal proceedings with Actiblizzard, creating a conflict of interest. Now the Call Of Duty and World Of Warcraft publishers want the DFEH's case to be paused so they can investigate, and decide whether they want to try and get the case disqualified, or find "other appropriate remedies". 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomhaven review: a loving adaptation that nails the ambition and detail of the tabletop original]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gloomhaven-pc-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gloomhaven-pc-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gloomhaven’s scoundrel has a custom animation for her flintlock pistol, and I am still jazzed about it. Releasing today in full after lurking in early access for the last two years, there are 17 classes in this digital adaptation of Cephalofair’s tabletop legacy dungeon crawler, hereafter referred to as ‘Tablehaven’. Each class, from psychic rodent Mindthief to basalt shithouse Cragheart, has around 30 ability cards each. And Flaming Fowl, alongside offering Tablehaven’s entire branching campaign, map editors, and a digi-only ‘Guildmaster’ campaign, have animated this single flintlock shot. It’s almost opulent. 
All right, so I probably won’t use it much. Five damage at range four is a belter, but that burn hurts for a single target ability. I’ll be smiling when I do, though. Grinning as the scoundrel whips the silver pistol from her hip and deletes a cultist just before he summons a skeleton. Just as I’ve been grinning at these detailed, cel-shaded dungeons and grimy sewers, or the spoken narration before each quest. All Gloomhaven needed to do was not get in Tablehaven’s way too much. Accuracy and usability would have been just fine. But there’s enough passion and pizzaz in this wonderful package that a part of me wishes I was new here, just so I could be surprised all over again.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything we know about Frogs in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-frogs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-frogs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about Frogs in Minecraft? If you’ve always looked at lakes and rivers in Minecraft and thought ‘those need some slimy little amphibians that leap on lily pads and whip fireflies out of the sky with their tongues’, then you’re in luck! At Minecraft Live 2021, the team shared that we are getting Frogs in Minecraft, and they’ll actually have a lot more depth than you might expect.
This guide will explain everything that we currently know about Frogs in Minecraft, including how to get the different Frog variants and how they act.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Genshin Impact Hu Tao build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-hu-tao-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-hu-tao-build"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:53:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Hu Tao build in Genshin Impact? As the 77th Director of the Wangsheng Funeral Parlor, Hu Tao has the help of ghosts in battle, where she’ll stir up a fright as she absolutely demolishes enemies. Despite being a bit of a prankster, the Pyro Polearm wielder will make a great DPS addition to your team.
This guide will show you how to create the best Hu Tao build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Hu Tao, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google představil telefony Pixel 6 a Pixel 6 Pro s vlastním 5nm čipem Tensor]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42929</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/google-predstavil-telefony-pixel-6-a-pixel-6-pro-s-vlastnim-5nm-cipem-tensor/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T09:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový 5nm procesor Google Tensor, displej s 90Hz a HDR10+, sklo Gorilla Glass Victus, nová baterie foťáků s podporou 4k/60p videa či 30W nabíjení s USB PD a samozřejmě Android 12, to jsou v základu nové Pixely od Googlu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that we know about the Allay in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-allay</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-allay"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T08:52:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about the Allay in Minecraft? For the past few years, Minecraft Live has included lots of announcements about new updates, as well as a fan vote for a new Minecraft mob. For Minecraft Live 2021, the options were the Glare, the Copper Golem, and the Allay. Ultimately, the Allay came out on top, and will be added to Minecraft in 2022.
Here’s everything that you need to know about the adorable Allay, including when it will arrive in Minecraft and what the Allay will do.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Arts]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2531/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2531/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riders Republic will offer a free trial week before launch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-will-offer-a-free-trial-week-before-launch</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/riders-republic-will-offer-a-free-trial-week-before-launch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T23:11:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm exhausted at the mere thought of most Ubisoft games now, but I do want to fall down mountains in Riders Republic. To make that easier for me, Ubisoft are offering a trial week for their bigly multiplayer extreme sports 'em up. From October 21st until the 27th, you'll be able to play four hours of Riders Republic for free, with progress carrying over to the full game should you buy it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator is getting more free updates with GOTY edition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-is-getting-more-free-updates-with-goty-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-is-getting-more-free-updates-with-goty-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T22:18:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator is getting a 'Game Of The Year' edition. The skybound sim has received regular free updates since launch, each adding new cities and points of interest. The GOTY edition will bring even more, including new potogrammetry cities, 8 new airpirts, and 5 new aircraft. It'll launch on November 18th and be free to all existing players.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo and Disintegration's Marcus Lehto founding new studio with EA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-and-disintegrations-marcus-lehto-founding-new-studio-with-ea</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-and-disintegrations-marcus-lehto-founding-new-studio-with-ea"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T21:55:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marcus Lehto, former creative director at Bungie and the artist responsible for Master Chief, has joined EA to found a new studio that will make first-person games. Lehto's last company was V1 Interactive, who released the short-lived Disintegration last year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead By Daylight's Hellraiser models are now an NFT]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-models-are-now-an-nft</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-models-are-now-an-nft"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T21:33:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you enjoy the feeling of having pins hammered into your head? Then allow me to introduce you to: our modern reality. 

Today's pin to the brow is that you can now buy NFTs based on Dead By Daylight's in-game models of Hellraiser's Pinhead. I can tell the difference between pleasure and pain, and this is pain.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked 'do not ban' list reveals how Twitch dealt with rule breakers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leaked-do-not-ban-list-reveals-how-twitch-dealt-with-rule-breakers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/leaked-do-not-ban-list-reveals-how-twitch-dealt-with-rule-breakers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T20:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among the many discoveries of this month's Twitch source code and data leak was a file called "do_not_ban_list." While not as black and white as the name suggest, the file sheds light on the otherwise opaque way Twitch has enforced its rules when streamers break them.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get an RTX 3060 gaming laptop for $850 in an early Black Friday deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3060-gaming-laptop-for-850-in-an-early-black-friday-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-an-rtx-3060-gaming-laptop-for-850-in-an-early-black-friday-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T19:16:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MSI GF65 Thin is the first Black Friday gaming laptop deal we've spotted, around a month before the shopping holiday traditionally begins. At Best Buy, you can pick up this RTX 3060 equipped machine for $850, a cool $250 below its usual price of $1100. That's a fantastic value for a laptop that's seen strong reviews since its release earlier this year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade your PC with two sticks of 8GB 3200MHz RAM for £55]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/upgrade-your-pc-with-two-sticks-of-8gb-3200mhz-ram-for-55</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/upgrade-your-pc-with-two-sticks-of-8gb-3200mhz-ram-for-55"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T18:01:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adata is one of the best brands for budget RAM, and their long-standing Gammix D10 series offers a good balance of low price and high performance. Right now you can pick up two 8GB sticks of DDR4-3200 CL16 memory from Ebuyer for £56, around £10 cheaper than you'd pay for RAM with the same specs on Amazon. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grotto review: a grim, mystical tale about the limitations of language]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grotto-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/grotto-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's a hard life, being a soothsayer in Grotto. You live in a dingy little cave, the locals look at you with varying levels of distrust and suspicion, and occasionally your campfire will perk up and talk to you when no one's looking, its yellow flames turning an ominous shade of blue as it whispers dread-filled words about failure and the beating heart of the mountain into your ear. It's unclear how you ended up like this, but day after day you're tasked with consulting the handful of stars visible through a crack in the cave's ceiling to dole out advice to the local tribespeople, a group of anthropomorphic animals known only as The Brutes. 
Said advice comes in the form of 24 constellations you can discover by looking up and drawing shapes in the sky with your mouse. You'll need to give one of them to each Brute that asks you a question, but when every constellation has its own fortune-cookie-like meaning attached to it, finding the right one to answer their question successfully can be a challenge. As the toad man Ouuch tells you at the start, if you ask three separate people what the word 'blue' means to them, you'll get three separate answers. Sometimes, your intentions will be misinterpreted, while others will willfully ignore you. But one thing Grotto always manages to do is to keep you coming back for more. Once you've set this car crash of consequences in motion, it's very hard to tear your eyes away.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crysis Remastered Trilogy: new and old versions compared]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-remastered-trilogy-new-and-old-versions-compared</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crysis-remastered-trilogy-new-and-old-versions-compared"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T16:11:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Crysis Remastered Trilogy is out, complete with all the angry nanosuit men, angry alien squids, and solitary angry Cockney bloke of the originals – now with 8K support. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minecraft 1.19 release date: The Wild Update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-1-19-the-wild-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-1-19-the-wild-update"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T15:17:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about the Minecraft 1.19 update? The Wild Update was revealed at Minecraft Live 2021, where we got details about all of the new additions, including frogs, fireflies, and mangrove swamps. This will be the first Minecraft update in 2022, and will be the next major update after Caves and Cliffs part 2.
This guide will explain everything that you can expect with Minecraft 1.19, so that you don’t go wild looking for details all over.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 trailer shows Grand Cathay and Tzeentch rumbling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-trailer-shows-grand-cathay-and-tzeentch-rumbling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-trailer-shows-grand-cathay-and-tzeentch-rumbling"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T14:04:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a lot of explaining how the factions of Grand Cathay and Tzeentch will work in Total War: Warhammer 3, Creative Assembly today demonstrated with a nine-minute video dramatically recapping a battle between the two. The third game in their fantasy real-time strategy series has needed to invent and fill out a lot of armies not present in the tabletop game, so it's interesting to see them in action. Got some nice colours and weird warmen, at the very least.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Games investigating New World invulnerability exploit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazon-games-investigating-new-world-invulnerability-exploit</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amazon-games-investigating-new-world-invulnerability-exploit"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T12:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World players have found an exploit that lets you turn invincible, which is certainly not the sort of exploit you want in your PvP-focused MMORPG. According to players who've encountered the bug, it's pretty easy to replicate, and folks are calling for wars to be disabled until there's a fix. Amazon Games say they're aware of the problem and are investigating, so hopefully they'll patch the game soon to make sure everyone's staying vincible.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Valhalla's educational Discovery Tour is out today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-valhallas-educational-discovery-tour-is-out-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-valhallas-educational-discovery-tour-is-out-today"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T12:31:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best part of primary school in the UK is learning about Vikings: getting to make and decorate cardboard swords and jewellery, write stories about legends, and maybe even escape school with a visit to a historical site. Well, Assassin's Creed Valhalla might not offer the same crafting opportunities, but you can learn a lot about the game's history with the new Discovery Tour mode. It hits Valhalla today in a free update, and will also be sold separately for folks who don't want Valhalla.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends' new character is a familiar face from Titanfall 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-character-is-a-familiar-face-from-titanfall-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-new-character-is-a-familiar-face-from-titanfall-2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T11:17:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends is adding a second spooky murderbot to its roster, one that both Apex and Titanfall 2 fans might recognise. Ash is a simulacrum (human consciousness in a freaky robot) who was previously a baddie in Titanfall 2. Since May this year, she's been overseeing Apex's new 3v3 Arenas mode - you know, that ominous voice that tells you to crush your enemies. But in the battle royale's next season, Escape, she'll be joining the fight herself.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm sorry to say it New World, but you need mounts, mate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-to-say-it-new-world-but-you-need-mounts-mate</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-sorry-to-say-it-new-world-but-you-need-mounts-mate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My heart sinks every time I accept a quest in MMORPG New World, which isn't ideal. These are tickets to adventure, to discovery, to that sweet, sweet EXP. But the more time I spend with the game, the more I'm beginning to loathe them. It's got nothing to do with what you actually do in them, it's the getting there that's the problem. I have to run my little legs ragged and I'm tired. I'm so very tired of it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ActRaiser Renaissance review: raise one for a great remake of a 16-bit classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actraiser-renaissance-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actraiser-renaissance-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[1990's ActRaiser is special. Most video games released in the late '80s tasked you with saving a princess from a dragon. ActRaiser says, “Hey, would you mind playing God with the people living on the demon-scarred land you just liberated? They're really squishy and helpless. Thanks, you’re a peach."
The game's developer, Quintet, was pretty special, too. Once a branch of Enix before the latter joined with Squaresoft in 2003, Quintet was behind a lot of SNES-era RPGs that are still fondly remembered today, such Illusion of Gaia and Terranigma. They’re all solid adventures that share a canon, albeit vaguely, and tackle some pretty heavy subject matter, including colonialism, poverty, and the slave trade. Alas, Quintet disbanded when Square Enix was born, and most of its team scattered to the winds. There’s been a Q-shaped hole in my heart ever since, so I hope I can be excused for yelling like a madwoman when ActRaiser Renaissance made a surprise debut at the September 2021 Nintendo Direct presentation.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Oxford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RPS Asks: you to please take our 2021 readership survey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-you-to-please-take-our-2021-readership-survey</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-asks-you-to-please-take-our-2021-readership-survey"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:40:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's that time of year again where we come to you with a single question: would you fill out our RPS Readership Survey, please? It should only take around 5-10 minutes of your time to complete, and it will be a big help to us going forward - particularly when it comes to shaping the future of the RPS supporter program.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Childe build (Tartaglia)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-childe-build-tartaglia</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-childe-build-tartaglia"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T09:06:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Childe build in Genshin Impact? Thanks to his unique ability set that enables both close-range and long-range combat, Hydro Bow user Childe (also known as Tartaglia) is especially powerful in almost any situation and is great as a main or sub DPS. As the 11th Harbinger of the Fatui, he’s an incredibly fierce warrior who also cares deeply for those he loves.
This guide will show you how to create the best Childe build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Childe, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell's 1440p 240Hz Alienware monitor is back to £550]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dells-1440p-240hz-alienware-monitor-is-back-to-550</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dells-1440p-240hz-alienware-monitor-is-back-to-550"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T19:58:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Dell Alienware AW2721D is one of our top recommended monitors, sitting right in the emerging 1440p 240Hz sweet spot preferred by players of fast-paced shooters and racing titles. Right now, the monitor has returned to the lowest price we've ever seen for it, £550, down from a nominal RRP of over £800. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Here's how you'll know which games will run on Valve's Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve have always maintained that the Steam Deck is closer to a conventional PC than a handheld console, and as such should be able to run your existing library of games on Steam. But while the official Steam Deck Twitter is full of videos showing games performing well on dev kits, the compatibility status of many more games remains up in the air. That could just be through a lack of confirmation, or it could be deep-lying technical issues relating to hardware requirements or anti-cheat services that needed tweaks to work on the Deck’s Proton-based OS. Ahead of the planned December launch, Valve have unveiled their plan to bring clarity on whether specific games will be able to run (and run effectively) on the Steam Deck.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a WD Blue 4TB SSD for just $339 at Newegg - $50 off its normal price]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wd-blue-4tb-ssd-for-just-339-at-newegg-50-off-its-normal-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wd-blue-4tb-ssd-for-just-339-at-newegg-50-off-its-normal-price"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T17:20:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Blue SATA SSD is a great choice if you want a lot of fast storage at a cheap price, and today Newegg are offering $50 off the giant 4TB size when you use the code EMC2AAZA827. This knocks the price to $339, the cheapest we've seen a 4TB drive in some time and $40 below the current Amazon price. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Into The Pit review: a gorgeous roguelike shooter that sadly descends into comfortable familiarity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/into-the-pit-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You know how some games, like, throb? I mean your Thumpers, your Devil Daggers, your Dooms. Games you disappear into, but not in that namby pamby, prancing around fulfilling all your desires sense. I mean games that will eat you alive unless you stop them. Games set in pulsating, hostile dimensions in which you don’t belong; games that fling their menageries at the battered windows of your soul, where survival teeters on a combo of hair-trigger reflexes and total concentration.


Into The Pit is one of those, until it isn’t. You know you’re in trouble when the demonic eldritch hell portal starts feeling too comfortable. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise PC vs Switch: how the demo compares]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-pc-vs-switch-how-the-demo-compares</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-pc-vs-switch-how-the-demo-compares"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T15:45:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The recent launch of the Monster Hunter Rise demo on PC has given us a free look at how this soon-to-be-former Nintendo Switch exclusive will run and play when it releases in full in January 2022. This calls, naturally, for some screenshot comparisons.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-roste-podil-softwaru-ktery-vyuziva-umelou-inteligenci"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podzimní smršť novinek od Aceru. SentinelOne v ČR nabere 300 lidí a investuje miliardu. Roste podíl softwaru, který využívá umělou inteligenci. Dodávky a ceny osobních počítačů z pohledu výrobce. VMworld: Zabezpečení na principu nulové důvěry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Umělá inteligence v kooperativních hrách]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-umela-inteligence-v-kooperativnich-hrach"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový typ magnetismu nezpůsobují spiny. Beethovenovu slavnou 10. symfonii dokončila umělá inteligence  Studium neuronových sítí může pomoci při zkoumání toho, jak se do mozku ukládají konspirační teorie. Minirobot se pohybuje díky gradientům teploty. Splynutí obřích černých děr provázejí nejen gravitační vlny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 41/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-41-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 11 za 16,66  € nebo Windows 10 za pouhých 12,52  €]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-11-za-16-66-nebo-windows-10-za-pouhych-12-52</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-11-za-16-66-nebo-windows-10-za-pouhych-12-52"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Získejte doživotní licenci Windows 11 za pouhých 16,66  €, Windows 10 za pouhých 12,52  €. Opět jde o finančně velmi výhodnou nabídku prodejního portálu GoodOffer24.com, kde lze najít kromě nástrojů produktivity také hry, ale i další softwarové produkty.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KEY Trainings: Je OpenShift tou správnou volbou?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/key-trainings-je-openshift-tou-spravnou-volbou</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/key-trainings-je-openshift-tou-spravnou-volbou"/>
        <updated>2021-10-13T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShift je platforma pro provoz kontejnerů ve firemním prostředí. Usnadňuje standardizaci provozu vašich aplikací a současně zjednodušuje provoz a zvyšuje bezpečnost a spolehlivost provozu. Umožňuje vám přidělit vybraná oprávnění např. dodavatelským firmám a mít tak pod kontrolou větší část nebo celý vývojový cyklus aplikací. Současně vám přináší jednotný způsob monitoringu a sběru logů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 38-40/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-38-40-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-38-40-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Babí léto přineslo aktualizace řady více či méně specializovaných distribucí: přechod na Debian 11 v projektech Emmabuntüs DE4 nejen pro vzdělávání, Q4OS také s desktopovým prostředím Trinity, stabilní obrazy PureOS firmy Purism, dále Redo Rescue pro práci s diskovými oddíly, pokračující experimenty v EasyOS a mezi tím vším občerstvení MidnightBSD, UBports, Lakka, IPFire, Tails, Feren OS či Debianu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Budování kyberneticky odolné společnosti]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-budovani-kyberneticky-odolne-spolecnosti</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-budovani-kyberneticky-odolne-spolecnosti"/>
        <updated>2021-10-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problémy s Wi-Fi mohou ohrozit fungování českých firem. Technologické trendy pro finanční ředitele: hyperautomatizace a inteligentní komponovaný byznys. Od pilotního projektu k produkčnímu nasazení umělé inteligence. S evidencí vandalismu pomůže umělá inteligence, řešení bude hledat Atos Hackathon. Budování kyberneticky odolné společnosti. Tiskárny během lockdownů a poté (1) Dodávky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>