<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-10-07T00:52:42.998Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-07T00:52:42.998Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Stories 2: Wings Of Ruin - Title Update #4 Adds Dreadking Rathalos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121943</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/monster-hunter-stories-2-wings-of-ruin-title-update-4-adds-dreadking-rathalos"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T00:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another Monstie has arrived!
Capcom's been working non-stop this year on patches for both of its Monster Hunter games this year, and now the latest update for Monster Hunter Stories 2: Wings of Ruin has arrived.
This is the second part of Title Update #4 - adding in the Dreadking Rathalos Monstie and seven new quests (four of them being co-op).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 470.62.05 Beta Brings Vulkan Video Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-470.62.05-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-470.62.05-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA today published their newest Vulkan beta driver update for Windows and Linux with some new extension support plus Vulkan Video enhancements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Konami's New Soccer Game Is A Complete Disaster]]></title>
        <id>1847798848</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/konamis-new-soccer-game-is-a-complete-disaster-1847798848"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have heard that Konami’s new football games, eFootball 2022, is bad. I am here today to tell you exactly why it is bad, and just how bad it is.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6: should you pick male or female Dani?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-male-female-dani</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-male-female-dani"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering whether to choose male or female Dani in Far Cry 6? Ubisoft's latest title in the massive open-world FPS series departs from the formulae of the previous games in more than a few ways - one of which is the addition of two fully voiced versions of the main character, Dani Rojas: one male, and one female. But which should you choose, and is there any difference between them? Find out below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get Gunpowder in Far Cry 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-gunpowder</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-gunpowder"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Confused about how to get Gunpowder in Far Cry 6? Gunpowder is a fairly sparse but very important resource in Ubisoft's colossal open-world FPS title, as it is a required component for upgrading your weapons arsenal throughout the game. There are only a few ways you can get your hands on Gunpowder in Far Cry 6, so follow the tips below to learn how to amass a healthy stockpile of Gunpowder while you play.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get Depleted Uranium in Far Cry 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-depleted-uranium</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-depleted-uranium"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know where to find Depleted Uranium in Far Cry 6? Depleted Uranium is a very important resource in Far Cry 6, the latest title in Ubisoft's massive open-world FPS series. Although in this case, it's actually less of a resource and more of a currency which you can use to purchase powerful and unique gear from your comrade, Juan.
Learn how to get Depleted Uranium in Far Cry 6 below, along with how to use it up purchasing awesome new equipment once you have it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 ammo types and damage types explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-ammo-types</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-ammo-types"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know about the different ammo types in Far Cry 6? Each type of ammo in Ubisoft's behemoth of a FPS deals a different type of damage to enemies, and each of them is particularly effective against certain foes in Anton Castillo's army.
Learn about the different damage and ammo types in Far Cry 6 below, and how you can learn which enemies are susceptible to certain types of damage.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to fish in Far Cry 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-fishing-rod-how-to-fish</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-fishing-rod-how-to-fish"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to fish in Far Cry 6? First you'll need a Fishing Rod. Sounds obvious, doesn't it? Sadly, you can't just walk up to those fishing points dotted about the coasts of Yara in Far Cry 6 and start catching fish, though.
Below we'll teach you how to get the Fishing Rod, how the actual fishing minigame works in Far Cry 6, and how to use the fish you've caught to cook delicious meals and trade for crafting materials.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to destroy Anti-Aircraft Cannons in Far Cry 6]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-anti-aircraft-cannons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-anti-aircraft-cannons"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Confused about how to destroy Anti-Aircraft Cannons in Far Cry 6? There's a very respectable number of in-game tutorials in Ubisoft's latest open-world FPS, but they really could have done with a tutorial about what it takes to destroy those giant, seemingly invulnerable skyward-pointing turrets. Without the right weapons, these things are pretty much impossible to take down - so read on to find out exactly how to destroy Anti-Aircraft Cannons in Far Cry 6.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can you save your progress in Far Cry 6?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-save-autosave</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-save-autosave"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it possible to save your progress in Far Cry 6? Like many Ubisoft games, Far Cry 6 uses an autosave feature to save your progress rather letting you save manually, but how does the game decide when to autosave? In such a colossal open-world FPS game, where you're often spending time crossing large distances and getting lots of different things done in a short space of time, it's important that Far Cry 6 features a robust save system. But what can you do to ensure that your progress is saved when you need it to be? Learn the answers to these questions below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 Amigos list: how to unlock all seven Far Cry 6 pets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-amigos</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-amigos"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know about the different Amigos in Far Cry 6 and how to get them? Guns For Hire are a thing of the past in this latest installment of Ubisoft's open-world FPS franchise, and replacing them are Amigos - animal allies you can give orders to in combat and stealth situations.
Some of these Amigos are very easy to unlock, while others require far more work to obtain. Learn how to unlock all seven Amigos in Far Cry 6 below, and the strengths and abilities of each one.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 map: which territory should you go to first?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-map-territories</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-map-territories"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know which territory you should go to first in Far Cry 6? In true Ubisoft fashion, Far Cry 6 drops players into an incredibly large and open-ended map, where shortly after the first starting missions you'll have the freedom to pick where in the enormous island of Yara you want to visit. Each of the three major territories is packed with content, characters, and pets - so have a read about each one below and find out which territory you should start with in the Far Cry 6 map.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 tips and tricks: a beginner's guide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-tips-and-tricks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-tips-and-tricks"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for tips and tricks on how to begin your Far Cry 6 journey with a bang? Ubisoft's latest installment in their flagship open-world FPS series is the biggest we've seen so far. Far Cry 6 unleashes players on the colossal, fictional Caribbean country of Yara, and it is jam-packed with things to do. It can be a daunting prospect when you're first starting out, particularly if you've never played a Far Cry game before.
In this beginner's guide to Far Cry 6, we'll walk you through our top tips and tricks that will help you get prepared and equipped for any situation early on. From crafting weapons and piloting choppers to getting unique weapons and animal companions, we'll show you the things worth knowing on day one.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Of Warcraft Update Removes Suggestive Flirts & Jokes]]></title>
        <id>1847813633</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/world-of-warcraft-update-removes-suggestive-flirts-jo-1847813633"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blizzard’s work on cleaning up World of Warcraft in the wake of historical allegations of harassment at the company continue, with the latest round targeting a series of suggestive jokes and flirts that are being removed as part of update 9.1.5.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mon Amour, A ' Flappy Kissing Game' From Onion Games, Swoops Onto Switch Soon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121927</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/mon-amour-a-flappy-kissing-game-from-onion-games-swoops-onto-switch-soon"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["The more you kiss, the better you get".
Onion Games is a studio with some much admired developers in the team, and has won a number of fans on platforms like Switch with recent releases like Moon and Dandy Dungeon - Legend of Brave Yamada. Well known for its eccentric style, the developer is sticking to its approach with the bizarre but intriguing Mon Amour. 

You can see some of its weirdness in the trailer above - described as a 'flappy kissing game', you need just one button to try and navigate increasingly tricky stages, seemingly with those you have kissed following behind.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 Beta Feels Wild, Yet Somehow Plays It Safe]]></title>
        <id>1847813625</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-2042-beta-feels-wild-yet-somehow-plays-it-1847813625"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One minute into my first match of Battlefield 2042, I accidentally fell out of a helicopter. I somehow survived, then blew up a wall with my rocket launcher and took out the enemy hiding behind it. I died seconds later...not totally sure how, but it must’ve been badass. My lively outing ended as I called out for a…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exhausted Man, A Game For All Of Us Right Now]]></title>
        <id>1847813659</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/exhausted-man-a-game-for-all-of-us-right-now-1847813659"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T22:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m tired. You, reading this right now, are probably tired. Tired is a constant state of being for most of us these days thanks to, you know, everything. Now, you can play a game that’s all about being tired.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Game That Gets Easier The More Tired You Are]]></title>
        <id>1847812268</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-game-that-gets-easier-the-more-tired-you-are-1847812268"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T22:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week’s Steam Next Fest, during which hundreds of in-development PC games released demos, features a game that really seems to care about how you’re doing just now. Please, Touch the Artwork is a puzzle adventure in which you’re allowed to prod at the paintings in an exhibition, and it picks the difficulty based…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fotografování dalekohledem: masky korekce vinětace]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15552</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/fotografovani-dalekohledem-masky-korekce-vinetace/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V minulém díle byly ukázky fotografií, mobilní aplikace Neoshot, adaptér na dalekohled a optické vady. Dnes přesuneme snímky po Wi-Fi, nafotíme masky korekce vinětace a konvertujeme obrázky do PNG.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Karel Kulhavý)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manipulace s vektory a maticemi v projektu SciLua]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15696</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/manipulace-s-vektory-a-maticemi-v-projektu-scilua/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes budou popsány základní operace s vektory i s maticemi, tedy se základními datovými strukturami, s nimiž tento projekt nějakým způsobem manipuluje. Prozatím bude nejvíce prostoru věnováno spojování vektorů a matic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Old School RuneScape has added a new Group Ironman challenge mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/old-school-runescape-has-added-a-new-group-ironman-challenge-mode</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/old-school-runescape-has-added-a-new-group-ironman-challenge-mode"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T21:57:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Old School RuneScape's Ironman Mode is all about going it alone. The special account type requires you to tackle the game without trading, PvP, and other group activities. As of today, Ironman Mode is getting a big new change. Now you'll be able to play alone together. Jagex have now added the ability to form a group of up to five players who will all head out into the world as an Ironman team to tackle all of OSRS's big baddies as a crew.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ploopy Thumb Trackball]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ploopy-thumb-trackball</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ploopy-thumb-trackball"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T21:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DIY palcový trackball Ploopy (Thumb Trackball) byl prohlášen za hotový. Schémata jsou k dispozici na GitHubu, jakožto i návod k sestavení sady. Předobjednávky jsou otevřeny za ceny 130-220 CAD. Zatím jde pouze o variantu do pravé ruky. Tvar připomíná klasický Microsoft Trackball Optical, podobně jako první model Ploopy připomínal MS Trackball Explorer. Používá 38mm kouli, 6 tlačítek, kolečko, snímač PMW-3360, volitelný podstavec pro navýšení úhlu ruku, firmware QMK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only Three Percent Of Twitch’s Top-Earning Streamers Are Women, Apparently]]></title>
        <id>1847812847</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/only-three-percent-of-twitch-s-top-earning-streamers-ar-1847812847"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Twitch leak from 4chan confirmed what a lot of people already know: The majority of the platform’s most successful content creators are men. But what’s shocking is the disparity. Out of the top 100 creators, only three of them are women. Only one of them is a woman of color.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Patch 6 will add another class and weaponized salami]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-6-will-add-another-class-and-weaponized-salami</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-6-will-add-another-class-and-weaponized-salami"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T20:42:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 is venturing forth into anther early access milestone. Larian say that BG3's next major update, Patch 6, is nearly here. It is, once again, their biggest patch so far, they say. Another new class is getting added, as is an equippable meat easter egg from their LARPing livestream earlier this year. Here are the few details they've shared so far before giving a proper introduction to Patch 6 soon.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tales Of Arise Reminds Me Why I Fell In Love With JRPGs]]></title>
        <id>1847812742</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/tales-of-arise-reminds-me-why-i-fell-in-love-with-jrpgs-1847812742"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T20:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man wearing an iron mask who doesn’t remember his past. A woman who electrocutes people and has a magic rock hidden in her chest. A rag-tag band of rebels trying to overthrow an empire. The start of Tales of Arise is ridiculous, and also the most fun I’ve had with a JRPG in years.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's Steam Deck Teardown Video Warns Against Tearing Down Your Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>1847812597</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/valves-steam-deck-teardown-video-warns-against-tearing-1847812597"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T20:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new teardown video demonstrating how (or rather, how not) to replace Steam Deck parts, Valve said that tampering with the handheld PC’s chassis to get a look inside “might mess things up, like, profoundly.” How profoundly you ask? The gaming giant said the batteries could explode, which might kill you.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: Digital Foundry Gives Its Assessment Of The Switch OLED Model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121916</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/video-digital-foundry-gives-its-assessment-of-the-switch-oled-model"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's the best display on any handheld games machine we've used".
It's a rather exciting week in the world of Nintendo, with Metroid Dread arriving alongside the Nintendo Switch OLED Model this week. That's a bumper line-up at any time, and you can see our reviews of both below.

Nintendo Switch OLED - The Screen's The Star
Metroid Dread Review (Switch)

At the top of this page, though, you can check out Digital Foundry's technical review of the system, which looks at multiple iterations of hardware and even takes a look at the original PS Vita's OLED as a comparison. If you prefer reading to video you can check out the write-up on Eurogamer.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve say don't crack open your Steam Deck but also show you how to do it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-say-dont-crack-open-your-steam-deck-but-also-show-you-how-to-do-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-say-dont-crack-open-your-steam-deck-but-also-show-you-how-to-do-it"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T19:26:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're getting closer to the first ship dates for Valve's handheld gaming PC Steam Deck. As PC hardware folks do, everyone apparently wants to see exactly what's inside. Naturally, Valve say they think you really shouldn't go opening the thing yourself, for reasons ranging from electrical safety to the warranty—which doesn't cover any damage you could cause by doing so, they say. So they're showing you exactly how to open it up in hopes that you'll leave doing so to a professional. Their new video today shows what will be inside your Steam Deck and how to remove a few of its parts.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FWUPD 1.7 Released With Supporting More Hardware For Firmware Updates On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FWUPD-1.7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FWUPD-1.7"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T19:17:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FWUPD and the Linux Vendor Firmware Service (LVFS) continue to serve as a resounding open-source success for allowing an increasing amount of hardware to support firmware updates on Linux from system/motherboard UEFI to disk drives and various peripherals. LVFS is now serving up more than two million firmware downloads a month while FWUPD 1.7 is out today with supporting firmware updates on even more hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: #ThankYouSakurai For Smash Ultimate, Now He Should Choose His Own Path]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121848</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-thankyousakurai-for-smash-ultimate-now-he-should-choose-his-own-path"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sakurai-san's creative spark can go even further than Smash Bros.

This week Masahiro Sakurai gave his last character presentation for Super Smash Bros. Ultimate, with interest and anticipation for the final broadcast reaching a fever pitch. With over 24 million sales at last count and substantial DLC uptake thanks to the many and varied guest fighters, it's a game that has contributed a great deal to the success of Switch. More than that, though, few games can have a near three-year run of big headlines in the modern industry, and the unique cultural impact of Smash Bros. — and its outrageously diverse roster — can't really be overstated. It's a behemoth.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 96 To Feature Improved WebRTC Code, Better Wayland Screensharing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-96-Better-WebRTC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-96-Better-WebRTC"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T18:41:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next month's release of Chrome 96 is a bit more exciting now thanks to the work of Jan Grulich at Red Hat...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8.5 Now Available As Beta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RHEL-8.5-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RHEL-8.5-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T18:22:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat today made available the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8.5 (RHEL 8.5) beta, incorporating a half-year of improvements to this flagship enterprise Linux distribution...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Dark Episode 4 is out now with its prison break survival story]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-dark-episode-4-is-out-now-with-its-prison-break-survival-story</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-dark-episode-4-is-out-now-with-its-prison-break-survival-story"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T18:20:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Snowbound survival sandbox The Long Dark has just launched its fourth free story episode update after two years in development. The new episode "Fury, Then Silence" follows crashed bush pilot Mackenzie on his continued search for his companion Astrid in the snowy apocalypse. This time, he's found himself captured by a gang attempting a prison break. Episode Four is out now with all that new story mode to chew on before Hinterland talk about what's next for modding tools and survival mode.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a super-fast 2TB Samsung NVMe SSD for £164 - that's £62 off]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-super-fast-2tb-samsung-nvme-ssd-for-164-thats-62-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-super-fast-2tb-samsung-nvme-ssd-for-164-thats-62-off"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T18:04:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The roomy 2TB version of the Samsung 970 Evo Plus SSD is going extremely cheap today over at Amazon, where it costs just £164 - a solid £62 off its normal price of £226. That's an insanely good price for one of the fastest PCIe 3.0 SSDs, especially on a high capacity drive like this one. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Database Helps Players Find Games With Accessibility Features]]></title>
        <id>1847811106</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-database-helps-players-find-games-with-accessibilit-1847811106"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T17:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the conversation around video game accessibility becomes more prominent, it’s clear that some games just don’t take the necessary steps to open up the experiences they offer to players with disabilities. Recently Steven Spohn, the senior director of AbleGamers, criticized Deathloop on Twitter for its lack of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take home a well-equipped RTX 3060 Ti gaming PC for £1200]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/take-home-a-well-equipped-rtx-3060-ti-gaming-pc-for-1200</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/take-home-a-well-equipped-rtx-3060-ti-gaming-pc-for-1200"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T17:42:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ebuyer are offering a good price on one of their prebuilt gaming PCs, featuring an RTX 3060 Ti, Ryzen 7 3700X processor, 16GB RAM and 1TB NVMe SSD. Right now, you can pick up this build for £1199, a cool £100 off its usual price. Given the state of the graphics card market, where even weak graphics cards are selling for hundreds of pounds above RRP, this is actually a great value.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Announces Ubuntu Frame As A Full-Screen Shell Built On Mir]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-Frame-Shell</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-Frame-Shell"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T17:36:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical today announced the launch of Ubuntu Frame, its full-screen shell built atop the Wayland-embracing Mir server for embedded displays, IoT, and related use-cases...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coffee Talk Episode 2 Is Headed For Switch Next Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121919</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/coffee-talk-episode-2-is-headed-for-switch-next-year"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starbucks, but the bucks are deer.
Coffee Talk Episode 2: Hibiscus & Butterflies was announced during the Indie Houses Direct in August, but we've now got official confirmation that it's coming to the Nintendo Switch (as well as other consoles) in 2022!
Following on from the first episode, which combined barista-core gameplay with a lightly supernatural clientele in an alternate-dimension Seattle, Coffee Talk Episode 2 is more of the same: latte art, conversations, and the chance to change your customers' lives with a simple, well-made hot drink.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Halo Infinite Calculates Your Kill-Death-Assist Ratios]]></title>
        <id>1847810384</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/how-halo-infinite-calculates-your-kill-death-assist-rat-1847810384"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you played any of Halo Infinite’s recent not-a-betas, you probably saw a fairly high number in your postmortem kill-death-assist ratio (KDA). And if you, like me, are flummoxed by math like long division, you likely thought, Cool! ...So what’s it mean?

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arcade Paradise makes everything a game, including your boring chores]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arcade-paradise-makes-everything-a-game-including-your-boring-chores</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arcade-paradise-makes-everything-a-game-including-your-boring-chores"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:31:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When your dad runs off on vacation and leaves you in charge of his junker old laundromat, what else would you do aside from flipping the thing into a booming arcade? Of course, Ashley's dad just expects her to clean and manage the laundry, but she has "half a business degree" so she has ideas. Arcade Paradise has just dropped a demo for you to try so you can pick up trash and plunge toilets or whittle away at the work day playing on the arcade cabinets in the back room.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classic Shooter Gleylancer Arrives On Switch Soon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121924</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/classic-shooter-gleylancer-arrives-on-switch-soon"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With translated cutscenes and improved modes.
Gleylancer is a name that immediately catches the eye of those in our team with a love for retro shooters, so the rather pleasing news is that publisher Ratalaika Games is bringing an improved version to the Switch eShop; it launches on 15th October priced at £5.99/ €5,99/ $6.99USD.
When originally released on SEGA Mega Drive (or Genesis for those of you in North America) in 1992 it was Japan-only, though it did appear globally on the Wii Virtual Console 16 years later. It's worth noting that original physical copies are rare and very expensive, though a reprint did help more collectors get a copy a few years back.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Round Up: Here's What The Critics Think Of Nintendo Switch OLED]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121914</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/round-up-heres-what-the-critics-think-of-nintendo-switch-oled"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it worth it?
This Friday, Nintendo will launch its latest gaming system into the wild – the Nintendo Switch OLED model. You probably already know about the new model's more obvious tweaks like its gorgeous OLED screen (all the info you could ever need on these changes can be found here) but how does it feel? What is it like to actually play? And is it worth your money?
We've been checking out the new OLED model over the past week or so and shared our full review on the site earlier today. We described it as a worthy upgrade to the standard Switch, praising the new screen, improved audio, better dock and improved kickstand, but warned that those who only play their console in docked mode really won't see much benefit here.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to reset your Twitch password and enable 2FA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-reset-your-twitch-password-and-enable-2fa</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-reset-your-twitch-password-and-enable-2fa"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:56:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to reset your Twitch password and enable Two-Factor Authentication on your account? It's a very good time and a very good idea to do so, given the recent leak on Twitch which has reportedly exposed encrypted user passwords online. If you want to secure your account and make sure no one can access it except you, then follow the steps below to learn how to reset your password and enable Two-Factor Authentication to further secure your Twitch account.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Square Enix Action RPG Is No Longer Too Blurry To Play]]></title>
        <id>1847809883</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/upcoming-square-enix-action-rpg-is-no-longer-too-blurry-1847809883"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We haven’t seen any news of Square Enix’s co-op multiplayer game, Babylon’s Fall, since its E3 showcase, and now we know why: Its developers have been busy rehauling its stylized graphics to appear more legible. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noir Cyberpunk Point-And-Click 'The Sundew' Comes To Nintendo Switch Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121864</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/noir-cyberpunk-point-and-click-the-sundew-comes-to-nintendo-switch-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunky Island.
If the tagline of this article didn't give it away, The Sundew — a game made by a one-woman developer team — combines the old-school point-and-click stylings of The Curse of Monkey Island with the cyberpunk noir of Blade Runner.
Instead of playing as Rickbrush Threepdeckard, or whatever unholy monster protagonist those two games would create, you'll play as Anna Isobe, a cyborg police officer in Japanese city Shibukawa, who's trying to solve a global conspiracy, which will potentially answer the question of why Japan lies in ruins...
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spooky card game Inscryption is stacking up to be a surprise GOTY contender]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spooky-card-game-inscryption-is-stacking-up-to-be-a-surprise-goty-contender</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/spooky-card-game-inscryption-is-stacking-up-to-be-a-surprise-goty-contender"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inscryption is the next game from Pony Island and The Hex creator Daniel Mullins, and having spent two hours playing its new demo this week, this creepy deckbuilding game has immediately shot up the list of my current game of the year contenders. It's dark, it's spooky, it's compelling, and in typical Mullins style, there's a heck of a lot more going on here than meets the eye. For starters, why the heck are my cards talking to me, and why is there one with my own name and face on it?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4 DLC adds lush outfits inspired by Indian and Korean fashion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-dlc-adds-lush-outfits-inspired-by-indian-and-korean-fashion</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-dlc-adds-lush-outfits-inspired-by-indian-and-korean-fashion"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fashion Street and Incheon Arrivals are two new paid kits for The Sims 4 offering up some excellent looks based on Indian and South Korean fashion scenes. The former is inspired by Mumbai's very own Fashion Street, adding henna tattoos, wrap skirts and more. While the latter comes from Seoul's "airport style", offering the sorts of outfits celebs would be snapped in coming off an airplane. But also, they're the sorts of outfits I kinda wanna wear! Everything looks comfy and long, and I have a sudden need for a jacket that sweeps below my knees.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Patch Adds Important Message: Don't Be A Dick]]></title>
        <id>1847809499</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/new-world-patch-adds-important-message-dont-be-a-dick-1847809499"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the main features of Amazon’s New World is an ongoing struggle between three massive player-run factions for control of Aeternum Island. This is causing some players to behave badly, from harassing members of other factions to loudly shouting obscenities in local voice chat. Today’s update adds a helpful login…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME 42 a systémový tmavý režim]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42878</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gnome-42-a-systemovy-tmavy-rezim/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:09:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S GNOME 42 se objeví možnost používání plně tmavého režimu prostředí. Tedy nikoli (například) tmavého vzhledu Adwaita, ale na úrovni samotného GNOME řešeného vzhledu. Alexander Mikhaylenko z projektu GNOME nyní na svém blogu shrnuje, jak to vypadá, co vše to obnáší a co musejí udělat tvůrci aplikací, aby nový způsob respektovali.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This hybrid RTS citybuilder has big ideas, big hordes, and an even bigger sky laser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diplomacy-is-not-an-option-steam-next-fest-demo-impressions</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diplomacy-is-not-an-option-steam-next-fest-demo-impressions"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:07:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a long time since I've found an RTS that recaptures the many hours I spent playing Warcraft 2 growing up, but Diplomacy Is Not An Option gets pretty darn close. I've been playing the hybrid citybuilder/tower defence game's demo this week, and those long forgotten memories of building row upon row of archer towers to nuke incoming orcs, defending my town hall and sending my little workers out to fish, mine and chop wood all came flooding back. Only here, those enemy armies come in waves of increasing size. Fortunately, in addition to the standard sword and bow folk at your disposal, you've also got a bit of magic - including a big fat giant sky laser. Count me in.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Share Value Continues Downward Trend As Major Investor Reportedly 'Dumps' Stock]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121906</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/nintendo-share-value-continues-downward-trend-as-major-investor-reportedly-dumps-stock"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A 28% slide since February.

While it's not necessarily at the top of everyone's list for fascinating gaming news, this has been a year with a fair amount of activity around Nintendo's share value. Unsurprisingly the value of the company rose along with its profits in 2020 as the demand for gaming entertainment rocketed; the reverse has been happening in 2021 as that demand has fallen back.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forget Halo Infinite's Big Team Battle, it's little Halo that excites me]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forget-halo-infinites-big-team-battle-its-little-halo-that-excites-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forget-halo-infinites-big-team-battle-its-little-halo-that-excites-me"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loads of us were called up by Master Chief to test out Halo Infinite and its Big Team Battle mode last weekend. Going in, I thought there would be no competition between its smaller 4 vs 4 Arena modes and this bombastic 12 vs 12 playground. Surely I'd prefer the latter. In my mind, this would be Halo at its messy best.
But no, I have proven myself wrong. In a strange turn of events, I've decided I actually much prefer Halo Infinite's smaller modes. And I think this comes down to laziness.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlmaLinux vysvětluje, co znamená členství v nadaci této distribuce]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42877</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/almalinux-vysvetluje-co-znamena-clenstvi-v-nadaci-teto-distribuce/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V rámci projektu AlmaLinux, který je nástupcem kdysi zcela svobodného CentOS, vzniká AlmaLinux Foundation. Členem této nadace se může stát kdokoli z komunity a členství je 100% svobodné/otevřené/bezplatné. Tvůrci to mimo jiné vysvětlují takto: z CentOS se postupem doby vytratilo ono C.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sad Times, The Amazing Flip Grip Accessory Doesn't Work On Switch OLED]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121895</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/sad-times-the-amazing-flip-grip-accessory-doesnt-work-on-switch-oled"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flipping' heck.
Fans of old-school shmups have long been aware that the Switch is one of the best systems to own right now, not just because it's home to many fine blasters, but because it can be played in 'TATE' mode using the fantastic Flip Grip accessory.
This seemingly simple piece of plastic allows you to set your Switch in TATE mode and bolt your Joy-Con to its sides, and really does allow you to enjoy and appreciate vertically-oriented shmups to their fullest.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exhausted Man demo's physics fun satisfied me, an exhausted person]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/exhausted-man-demos-physics-fun-satisfied-me-an-exhausted-person</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/exhausted-man-demos-physics-fun-satisfied-me-an-exhausted-person"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:12:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Isn't everything exhausting? Sorry, I didn't mean to tax you with having to think about an answer; I know you're exhausted too. And yet even I, a perpetually exhausted person, was glad to make the effort for the Exhausted Man demo in the Steam Next Fest. It is, like many modern comedy games, about completing tasks by controlling a weird figure with wonky physics—in this case, a man so tired he slithers along like a human slug. I smile every time this horrible slugman crawls up a wall.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Animal Crossing: New Horizons Direct Will Air On 15th October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121917</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/the-animal-crossing-new-horizons-direct-will-air-on-15th-october"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are the times you need!
Remember the Animal Crossing: New Horizons Direct that was teased during the other, proper Direct last month? Well, Nintendo's now spilt the beans on when we can tune in.
The show will air on 15th October at 7am PT / 10am ET / 3pm BST / 4pm CEST. It'll be "roughly 20 minutes" long, and naturally contains info on upcoming content for the game.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Round Up: The Metroid Dread Reviews Are In]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121905</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/round-up-the-metroid-dread-reviews-are-in"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it any good?
Metroid Dread will finally be in our hands in just two days' time, and it looks set to be a pretty incredible return for the franchise.
Reviews for the game have started flooding in today, including our very own, so we've gone ahead and rounded up a selection of quotes and review scores from a number of different outlets. Below, you'll see just how well the title's gone down with the media ahead of its launch, and hopefully get a clearer idea on whether or not it might be for you.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tmavý režim v GNOME 42]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/tmavy-rezim-v-gnome-42</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/tmavy-rezim-v-gnome-42"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T13:47:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MojeFedora.cz informuje o možnosti nastavení tmavého režimu v GNOME 42, jehož vydání je plánováno na březen příštího roku. Tmavý režim bude systém propagovat i do aplikací (včetně těch běžících v kontejnerech).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bug-splatting in the Starship Troopers RTS demo is harder than you'd think]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bug-splatting-in-the-starship-troopers-rts-demo-is-harder-than-youd-think</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bug-splatting-in-the-starship-troopers-rts-demo-is-harder-than-youd-think"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T13:42:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People get well into Starship Troopers, don't they? Back in the before times when I was a teen, a friend of mine went to uni and formed a terrible metal band, and one of their songs was about Starship Troopers (I believe it included shouting "Roughnecks! Ho!" a lot). And don't get me wrong: the 90s action-schlock film adaptation is very good. Replaceable cannon-fodder marines pumping bullets into giant skittering aliens, bombastic Join The Army And Die!! propaganda - It's good stuff. And perfect grist for the RTS game mill! Hence you can play the demo for Starship Troopers - Terran Command right now, in the Steam Next Fest.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon Software 21.30 PRO vs. Mesa 21.3-devel + Linux 5.15 Gaming Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30576</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30576"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T13:16:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those wondering how AMD's latest-generation Radeon RX 6000 series is competing now between the Linux driver options of AMD's official Radeon Software for Linux 21.30 "PRO" driver stack and the latest upstream, fully open-source driver components from Mesa and the mainline Linux kernel, here is a fresh comparison.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardware Review: Nintendo Switch OLED - The Screen's The Star]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121711</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/hardware-review-nintendo-switch-oled-the-screens-the-star"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T13:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But is it worth the upgrade?
Nintendo has a long and proud history of relentlessly iterating and upgrading its portable systems on a regular basis, but, outside of the smaller, cheaper Switch Lite, the original model has been the company's workhorse for the past four-and-a-bit years, contributing massively to the 89 million Switch units sold so far.
Sure, an updated version with superior battery life arrived in 2019, but on the whole, the Japanese giant has stuck with the existing 2017 design, which is an uncharacteristically loyal approach (the Game Boy Advance was updated after less than two years on sale, while the Nintendo DS Lite came around 15 months after the original 'Phat' DS was released). With the launch of the Switch OLED, that all changes; Nintendo has finally given its hybrid system a true upgrade.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Metroid Dread - Quite Possibly The Best Metroid Game Ever Made]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121641</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/metroid-dread"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And the E.M.M.I. goes to...
After absolutely nailing its first shot at a Metroid adventure with 2017's Metroid II 3DS remake Samus Returns, Nintendo has given MercurySteam another bite at the cherry in which they've chosen to retain many of the unique gameplay elements of their last outing whilst adding a bunch of stealth. It's a risky manoeuvre, adding a completely new mechanic like this to such a well-loved and heavily scrutinised franchise but, we're pleased to report, the Spanish developer has handed in a phenomenal new entry in the series that we just cannot stop playing. Metroid Dread is fantastic.
Of course, one of the most exciting things in the build up to this brand new outing for Samus Aran has been that it's the first game we're getting a chance to play on Nintendo's fancy new OLED Switch, and we really can't think of a better title with which to introduce that amazing screen. This is a properly gorgeous adventure, with each of the various biomes of the planet ZDR that you puzzle and blast your way through coming with its own with unique and wonderfully detailed enemy types, flora and fauna, some truly stunning lighting effects and other fancy graphical bells and whistles.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Twitch Is Hacked And Its Source Code Is In The Wild [Update]]]></title>
        <id>1847808252</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/report-twitch-is-hacked-and-its-source-code-is-in-the-1847808252"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T12:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to a report by VGC, an anonymous hacker has posted a 125GB torrent link containing, well, all of Twitch, including its source code and commit history going back to the start. The leak also contains streamers’ incomes since 2019, and information that suggests the Amazon-owned streaming platform’s Steam rival…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Fighter II On The NES Looks Better Than You Might Expect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121902</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/street-fighter-ii-on-the-nes-looks-better-than-you-might-expect"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Say hello to the fan-made "Street Fighter 2 Deluxe".
Street Fighter II was one of the games that really stoked the fires of the 16-bit console war, with the SNES version selling millions and making Genesis / Mega Drive owners green with envy – until, of course, they got their own version of Capcom's famous one-on-one brawler.
Street Fighter II was duly ported to pretty much every platform of the period – including the Game Boy – but one machine that didn't get the game was the NES. Sure, there was an unlicensed Famicom port by Hummer Team in 1992, but it was so terrible most people have scrubbed it from their memory banks.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi "V3D" Driver Landing Support For Multiple Sync Objects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3D-Linux-5.16-Multi-Syncobjs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3D-Linux-5.16-Multi-Syncobjs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T12:23:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new batch of drm-misc-next updates were sent out today for staging in DRM-Next ahead of the Linux 5.16 merge window. With this week's changes there is a notable addition for the Broadcom V3D DRM kernel driver, which most notably is for the Raspberry Pi 4 and newer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch source code and data reportedly leaked in hack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-source-code-and-data-reportedly-leaked-in-hack</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-source-code-and-data-reportedly-leaked-in-hack"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T12:17:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update 4.35pm: Twitch have confirmed that a breach has taken place, more below.
Original story 1.20pm: Twitch has reportedly been attacked by an anonymous hacker who has allegedly leaked a large amount of data, from source code to streamer earnings. A 4chan user has posted a 128GB torrent supposedly containing the leaked info, and more could be leaked down the line. There's also a suggestion that user passwords might be compromised, so now is probably a good time to change yours.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buy Smash Bros. Ultimate Or Any Of Its DLC And Earn Double My Nintendo Gold Points]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121892</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/buy-smash-bros-ultimate-or-any-of-its-dlc-and-earn-double-my-nintendo-gold-points"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a limited time.
The Super Smash Bros. Ultimate roster is finally complete thanks to yesterday's grand reveal, and now could be the perfect time to buy the game or any DLC you might be missing.
No doubt in celebration of yesterday's presentation, Nintendo is currently offering double My Nintendo Gold Points on any digital purchase relating to the game. The deal applies to the main game itself, both Fighters Pass collections, and individual Challenger Packs.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squid Game Features A Real Person's Phone Number, So Netflix Is Editing It Out]]></title>
        <id>1847807884</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/squid-game-features-a-real-persons-phone-number-so-net-1847807884"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Squid Game, participants are given a business card. On one side are PlayStation-like icons, and on the other is a phone number to call. The number, however, is real. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB Corp. Will Make You A Big Shot If You Have Multiple Game Boys]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121889</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/gb-corp-will-make-you-a-big-shot-if-you-have-multiple-game-boys"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Speculate to accumulate, and all that.

It seems that the development scene around retro Nintendo hardware continues to draw a loyal group of enthusiasts, with the Game Boy in particular seeing a number of new and revamped games recently. An intriguing project that's come onto our radar is GB Corp., which has a rather fun mechanic for those that have a collection of Game Boy models.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 review: familiar, messy fun, if a bit overwhelming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-6-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 6 is a vast first-person shooter that's been constructed from the same mould as its predecessors. You are to liberate a land and leave plentiful bullet casings in your wake, only this time it's the heart of the Caribbean that needs clearing, not the US or the Himalayas. Still, it remains undeniably fun running between map markers and earning rewards, if a bit one-note. A good time is guaranteed, but a memorable one? That depends on whether your brain shelve what feels like 2,000 hours of guerrilla warfare without it being reduced to paste.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl Is Out Now On Switch, Here's The Full Character Roster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121887</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-is-out-now-on-switch-heres-the-full-character-roster"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And the launch trailer!
Super Smash Bros. Ultimate may have stolen all of the headlines yesterday, but Switch fans were also treated to the release of the Smash-like Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl. Competing with Smash Bros. is already proving to be quite the challenge, it seems.
Available as we speak, the game offers single-player, online, and local multiplayer battling across levels inspired by some of Nickelodeon’s most popular franchises. 20 characters are available to choose from at launch, with more on the way.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nový web raspberrypi.com]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/novy-web-raspberrypi.com</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/novy-web-raspberrypi.com"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:24:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nadace Raspberry Pi představila nový web raspberrypi.com. Přesunuly se na něj technické informace k počítačům Raspberry Pi a souvisejícím technologiím. Web raspberrypi.org zůstane věnován nadaci a vzdělávání.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World's first patch does more to stop AFK players hogging servers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-first-patch-does-more-to-stop-afk-players-hogging-servers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-first-patch-does-more-to-stop-afk-players-hogging-servers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:04:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A week after launch New World continues to see hundreds of thousands of players logging on to get a piece of that sweet new MMORPG action. Just this weekend, the game nearly hit a million concurrent players on Steam. But with that popularity has come long queues, and some players are going AFK once they get in so they don't lose their spots if they can't play immediately. It should be harder for them to hog server space now though, because Amazon Games released New Worlds' first post-launch patch last night, changing some AFK rules.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did You Know Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania Has A Secret Code To Enter?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121891</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/did-you-know-super-monkey-ball-banana-mania-has-a-secret-code-to-enter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how to do it.
Yesterday saw the launch of Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania on Switch, and if you decided to grab a copy for yourself, we've got a little trick for you that you might want to try out.
In a neat little touch, Banana Mania lets you input a secret, hidden code on the main menu. By doing so, you can change the track playing in the background from the usual instrumental menu music to its full vocal version.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony Has Begun Accelerating Their Contributions To Open-Source / Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Sony-More-Open-Source-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Sony-More-Open-Source-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T09:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At last week's Linux Foundation Open-Source Summit / Embedded Linux Conference there was a Sony presentation about their history with open-source/Linux and how since last year they have been "accelerating" their open-source contributions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The original Ghost Recon is free for keepsies right now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-original-ghost-recon-is-free-for-keepsies-right-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-original-ghost-recon-is-free-for-keepsies-right-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T09:53:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To celebrate the Ghost Recon games turning 20 years old next month, Ubisoft last night announced Ghost Recon frontline, a free-to-play battle royale shooter. But they haven't entirely forgotten the roots of the tactical shooter series, because they're giving the first game away free for keepsies right now. You've got a few days to grab 2001's Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon and remember the good ol' days. Ubi are giving away some DLC for the latest games too.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asahi Linux na Apple M1 již použitelný pro základní linuxový desktop]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42875</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/asahi-linux-na-apple-m1-jiz-pouzitelny-pro-zakladni-linuxovy-desktop/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T09:35:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pokud člověku nechybí GPU akcelerace, lze již Asahi Linux na strojích s ARM SoC Apple M1 používat. Projekt Asahi v posledních týdnech vyřešil většinu podstatných věcí, hlásá zářijový report na jejich webu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Is Joining Forces With Universal Studios Japan]]></title>
        <id>1847807700</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-is-joining-forces-with-universal-studios-japan-1847807700"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today in Osaka, Universal Studios Japan announced it’s entering into a creative partnership with The Pokémon Company. 
“Universal Studios Japan and The Pokémon Company will enter a long-term partnership to jointly explore groundbreaking entertainment that will immerse guests into the world of Pokémon with innovative…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Kingdom Hearts Integrum Masterpiece' Collection Brings The Entire Saga To Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121883</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/kingdom-hearts-integrum-masterpiece-collection-brings-the-entire-saga-to-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[10 Kingdom Hearts experiences in one.
Yesterday, it was revealed that lots of Kingdom Hearts goodness is headed to Nintendo Switch in celebration of Sora's arrival in Super Smash Bros. Ultimate. We now have more details on the games headed our way, and there's an awful lot to unpack.
The three titles announced yesterday – Kingdom Hearts - HD 1.5 + 2.5 ReMix, Kingdom Hearts HD 2.8 Final Chapter Prologue and Kingdom Hearts III – technically contain ten 'games' altogether, which Square Enix notes is "the full saga of Sora’s exploits so far." Wrapping up all of this content will be the 'Kingdom Hearts Integrum Masterpiece' collection, an all-in-one digital package.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise Has Now Shipped Over 7.5 Million Units]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121880</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/monster-hunter-rise-has-now-shipped-over-7-5-million-units"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plenty more to come, too.
Monster Hunter Rise is now comfortably the best-selling of the IP's Nintendo system entries, a reward no doubt for the quality of its changes and of course the growth of the franchise led by the multiplatform Monster Hunter: World.
This past weekend it picked up a lucrative award, too, the Grand Award in the Games of the Year Division of the Japan Game Awards: 2021. This was unveiled during Tokyo Game Show, and in an investor's press release Capcom also confirmed that the game has now shipped over 7.5 million copies as of 24th September; that's a rise of about half a million since late May. Though momentum has understandably levelled off, it's a game that still has plenty to come that could drive even more sales.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Invasions: how to take part in Invasions in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-invasions</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-invasions"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T08:13:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you take part in New World Invasions? Invasions, also known as Corrupted Invasions, are PvE battles in New World primarily aimed at high-level players looking for late-game content. In this guide, we go through the requirements to take part in Invasions, as well as some tips on how to prevail in them.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Výpadek Facebooku způsobila chyba v interním nástroji při rutinním zásahu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15695</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/vypadek-facebooku-zpusobila-chyba-v-internim-nastroji-pri-rutinnim-zasahu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T07:37:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook provozuje jednu z nejrozsáhlejších sítí datacenter na světě. Přes všechnu snahu o robustnost se ani jemu nevyhýbají velké výpadky, které přijdou maximálně jednou za deset let. Už víme, co způsobilo ten pondělní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ELK Stack: naučte se Elasticsearch, Logstash a Kibana (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40262</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/elk-stack-naucte-se-elasticsearch-logstach-a-kibana-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T07:10:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Většina počítačových programů generuje logy – tedy zprávy a záznamy o své činnosti. ELK Stack – ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana – je populární nástroj, který umí logy efektivně zpracovávat, ukládat a zpřístupňovat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The storms in Battlefield 2042 are actually game changing, trust me]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-storms-are-game-changing-trust-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-storms-are-game-changing-trust-me"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm pleased to announce that Battlefield 2042 is indeed a Battlefield game. I went hands-on with the upcoming beta for a couple of hours earlier this week, and yes: there was a very big fight on a very big battlefield. At its core, Battlefield 2042 doesn't surprise at all. But on the surface it's a totally different story.
EA and Dice made a big deal of the game's weather and I was like, "Yeah, it rains all the time here too, heh", but you know what? The way these battlefields chop and change when storms roll in really do make a huge difference when you're there with your boots on the ground.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ampere Computing Steps Up With Monthly Open-Source Firmware Releases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ampere-Monthly-OSS-Firmware</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ampere-Monthly-OSS-Firmware"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have covered previously how Ampere Computing has been working on open-source firmware for their Ampere Altra processors and their reference server designs while now they are stepping up to the plate and committing to a monthly release cycle for their open-source firmware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Studios Japan Announces A Partnership With ﻿The Pokémon Company]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121879</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/universal-studios-japan-announces-a-partnership-with-the-pokemon-company"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T05:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first project is scheduled for 2022.

Super Mario and Donkey Kong aren't the only ones doing deals with Universal Studios Japan - it seems Pokémon will also be joining in on the fun.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Is What Kirby's New Kingdom Hearts Form Looks Like In Smash Bros. Ultimate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121877</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/this-is-what-kirbys-new-kingdom-hearts-form-looks-like-in-smash-bros-ultimate"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T04:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He's ready to join Mickey and the gang.

During the latest presentation for the new Smash Bros. Ultimate DLC fighter Sora, game director Masahiro Sakurai revealed what his own creation Kirby looks like when he uses his copy ability on the famous Kingdom Hearts character.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ET: Legacy 2.78 Released With Better OpenAL Sound, Android Support Materializing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ET-Legacy-2.78</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ET-Legacy-2.78"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T04:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of our favorite open-source game projects, ET: Legacy for letting the legendary game Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory live on as a community project, is out with a new release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Air Travel Packing List]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2525/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2525/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sylveon Has Joined The Battle In The Switch And Mobile MOBA Pokémon Unite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121876</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/sylveon-has-joined-the-battle-in-the-switch-and-mobile-moba-pokemon-unite"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Start out as Eevee and evolve.
Another pocket monster has joined the free-to-play mobile and Nintendo Switch game, Pokémon Unite. This time around it's the Eevee evolution, Sylveon.
Sylveon will start off as an Eevee and evolves into Sylveon at Lvl. 4. Here's the full rundown about this new fighter, courtesy of the official game website - including its 'Unite' move:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phrack 70]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/phrack-70</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/phrack-70"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T02:08:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po pěti letech bylo vydáno nové číslo magazínu Phrack: Phrack 70.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poll: So, Will You Be Getting The "Cloud Versions" Of Kingdom Hearts On Switch?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121875</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/10/poll-so-will-you-be-getting-the-cloud-versions-of-kingdom-hearts-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T01:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The only way to play Sora's mainline games on the hybrid system.

During the latest Mr. Sakurai Presents broadcast for Super Smash Bros. Ultimate, the director shared a surprise announcement many fans weren't expecting - the mainline Kingdom Hearts series is coming to the Nintendo Switch.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFT Buyers Scammed As 'Creator' Bails, Who Could Possibly Have Seen This Coming?]]></title>
        <id>1847806528</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nft-buyers-scammed-as-creator-bails-who-could-possibly-1847806528"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While NFTs are themselves one giant scam, there is room for lesser scams within the whole, and this week has provided us with one of the funniest examples to date.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play This Fantastic Resident Evil x Castlevania Game]]></title>
        <id>1847806377</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/play-this-fantastic-resident-evil-x-castlevania-game-1847806377"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Resident Evil: Village has a spooky old castle full of vampires. Castlevania has a spooky old castle full of vampires. You can see where this is going.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC R&D experimentuje se správou uživatelských dat pomocí Solid]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bbc-r-d-experimentuje-se-spravou-uzivatelskych-dat-pomoci-solid</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bbc-r-d-experimentuje-se-spravou-uzivatelskych-dat-pomoci-solid"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BBC R&D experimentuje v aplikaci pro nejen rozhlasové pořady s technologií Solid (představenou před třemi lety), která uživatelům poskytuje větší kontrolu nad svými metadaty v rámci modelu Human Data Interaction. Koncept shrnuje také Rupert Goodwins v komentáři pro The Register.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novinky z vývoje Asahi Linuxu - září 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/novinky-z-vyvoje-asahi-linuxu-zari-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/novinky-z-vyvoje-asahi-linuxu-zari-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:12:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na blogu Asahi Linuxu, tj. Linuxu pro Apple Silicon aneb počítače Apple s novým ARM procesorem M1, byl po dvou měsících od předchozího přehledu publikován aktuální přehled dění a novinek z vývoje Asahi Linuxu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asahi Linux On The Apple M1: "Usable As A Basic Linux Desktop" Sans GPU Acceleration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Asahi-Linux-September-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Asahi-Linux-September-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T23:22:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Asahi Linux project that has been working nearly the past year on bringing up Apple M1 support under Linux has issued their September 2021 porting and reverse engineering report...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Car Thieves Arrested After Using $27,000 'Game Boy']]></title>
        <id>1847806007</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/car-thieves-arrested-using-27-000-game-boy-1847806007"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A gang of British car thieves have been arrested after being caught using a device disguised as a Nintendo Game Boy, which was designed to bypass the security systems on modern cars.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Platform fighter Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl launches on PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/platform-fighter-nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-launches-on-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/platform-fighter-nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-launches-on-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T22:11:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone is aflutter from the Disney boy joining Smash Bros, but I've never played a Kingdom Hearts. I did, however, spend many hours as an early teen watching Hey Arnold! and CatDog. I am therefore more excited about today's release of Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl, a Smash-like platform brawler starring Nickelodeon characters including Spongebob and Invader Zim.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logování v PHP: logovací systém integrovaný do známých frameworků]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15672</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/logovani-v-php-logovaci-system-integrovany-do-znamych-frameworku/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V prvním článku se dozvíme, jaká logovací knihovna bude popisována, jak ji zprovoznit v systému PhpStorm, jaké má základní principy a jak jednoduše vyzkoušet její funkčnost. Ukážeme si také, že jsou možné různé kombinace loggerů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Herout)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (6. 10. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15694</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-6-10-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes si představíme poznámkový blok pro vývojáře, budeme sledovat vývoj hodnoty kryptoměn, vyzkoušíme několik síťových nástrojů a nakonec si poslechneme zvuky na odreagování.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jiří Sluka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Panzer Dragoon Producer Falsely Reported Dead By Game's Twitter Account]]></title>
        <id>1847805476</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/panzer-dragoon-producer-falsely-reported-dead-by-games-1847805476"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tweet sent earlier today by the official Panzer Dragoon Voyage Record account said that not only had the game been cancelled by Sega, but that one of the reasons for this cancellation was the death of producer Haruto Watanabe.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zstd bude v Linuxu 5.16 rychlejší až o 35 %]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42874</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/zstd-bude-v-linuxu-5-16-rychlejsi-az-o-35/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojář Nick Terrell z Facebooku se poslední dobou pokouší vytvořit novou implementaci kompresního algoritmu Zstd v linuxovém jádru. Nejnovější patche, které do jádra zaslal, ukazují slušný nárůst výkonu, plus samozřejmě přináší řadu dílčích oprav chyb.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally, A Genshin Impact Event That’s Not A Huge Grind]]></title>
        <id>1847805440</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/finally-a-genshin-impact-event-that-s-not-a-huge-grind-1847805440"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T21:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve celebrated my fair share of Chinese Mid-Autumn festivals, but if you’re expecting a heartwarming real life story about my experiences therein, prepare to be disappointed: I don’t usually plan anything. Mostly I just get to eat a lot of Chinese food and pretend that America gave me a public holiday (it didn’t). So …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smash Players Think Patrick Kinda Sucks In The Nickelodeon Fighting Game]]></title>
        <id>1847805189</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/smash-players-think-patrick-kinda-sucks-in-the-nickelod-1847805189"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T21:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl just came out yesterday, but that hasn’t stopped Super Smash Bros. players from tearing the game apart for any juicy morsel that may give them an edge in the platform fighter.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wasteland 3's final DLC is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wasteland-3s-final-dlc-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wasteland-3s-final-dlc-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T21:08:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wasteland 3's final DLC is out now. Cult Of The Holy Detonation features two mutant cults who worship a nuclear explosion in stasis, and as usual it's your job to chat with them and probably choose between them, in between turn-based battles. You can find the launch trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Preps More Display Code For Alder Lake P & DG2/Alchemist]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-ADL-P-DG2-Display</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-ADL-P-DG2-Display"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T20:44:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Linux 5.14 Intel introduced initial Alder Lake P enablement driver support including around the new "XeLPD" display block. With Linux 5.15 there was the initial enablement around DG2/Alchemist graphics. Now for Linux 5.16 is a significant amount of new driver code for actually getting the display support into shape for both DG2 and ADL-P...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TABS and Back 4 Blood are headed to Game Pass this month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tabs-and-back-4-blood-are-headed-to-game-pass-this-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tabs-and-back-4-blood-are-headed-to-game-pass-this-month"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T20:35:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back 4 Blood may be the successor to Left 4 Dead we've long waited for, and as a launch day arrival, logic dictates that I should be excited about its inclusion in Xbox Game Pass. But among October's haul of new additions, it's today's arrival of Totally Accurate Battle Simulator that interests me more.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tales Of Arise, As Told By Steam Reviews]]></title>
        <id>1847804247</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/tales-of-arise-as-told-by-steam-reviews-1847804247"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tales of Arise, the 17th mainline entry in Bandai Namco’s series of JRPGs that’s basically as old as human history by now, was one of September’s biggest games. For one, it smashed in terms of sales, selling more than a million copies in less than a week. For another, the action-RPG really clicked with players,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon Frontline is a new free-to-play battle royale]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tom-clancys-ghost-recon-frontline-is-a-new-free-to-play-battle-royale</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tom-clancys-ghost-recon-frontline-is-a-new-free-to-play-battle-royale"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T20:15:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft have announced Tom Clancy's Ghost Recon Frontline, a new free-to-play first-person shooter about 100 players dropping into an open world in teams of three. Yes, yes, Ubisoft are once again asking you to please give them a live service success. You can find the announcement trailer and details about its modes and first beta test below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two of Acer's best monitors are heavily discounted in the US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/two-of-acers-best-monitors-are-heavily-discounted-in-the-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/two-of-acers-best-monitors-are-heavily-discounted-in-the-us"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T19:48:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two of Acer's best monitors are heavily discounted in the US today, courtesy of discounts at Amazon and Ebay. The Nitro XV272U hits the current price/performance sweetspot with a 1440p 144Hz spec and $248 price, thanks to a $52 discount at Amazon US. Meanwhile, you can pick up a manufacturer-refurbished Acer Predator XB273K for just $484, a great price for a 4K 144Hz monitor that originally retailed for over $1000. 
Check out the links below to get the deals, or read on for our detailed explanation! 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smash Bros. Devs, You Did It, It's Finished, Go Take A Break]]></title>
        <id>1847804088</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/smash-bros-devs-you-did-it-its-finished-go-take-a-b-1847804088"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s confirmed: The big-shoed hero himself, Kingdom Hearts’ Sora, is the 82nd and final combatant to round out Super Smash Bros. Ultimate’s overflowing roster. Whew, that’s that. Now only one thing remains: It’s time for creator and game director Masahiro Sakurai to take a damn break.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Step up to a 1440p 240Hz display with Alienware's AW2721D, £150 off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/step-up-to-a-1440p-240hz-display-with-alienwares-aw2721d-150-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/step-up-to-a-1440p-240hz-display-with-alienwares-aw2721d-150-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T19:22:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Alienware AW2721D is part of a new breed of 27-in 1440p 240Hz gaming monitors, based around Fast IPS panels that provide great all-around performance. Normally it retails for £699, but today this G-Sync screen costs just £549 after a 21% price cut over at Amazon UK. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania Is Out Now And It Is Pure Joy]]></title>
        <id>1847803890</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/super-monkey-ball-banana-mania-is-out-now-and-it-is-pur-1847803890"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T19:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything about Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania is fun. The bright yellow menus with their bright and bouncy music? Fun. The rolling around collecting nanners? Fun. Gathering and customizing characters? Fun. Even the launch trailer Sega cooked up with Powerhouse Animation is fun.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sora’s Smash Reveal Forgot To Bring The Disney]]></title>
        <id>1847803373</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sora-s-smash-reveal-forgot-to-bring-the-disney-1847803373"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T18:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While he may not be everyone’s cup of tea, Kingdom Hearts’ Sora is officially coming to Super Smash Bros. Ultimate. But there’s a catch: He won’t be accompanied by Disney buddies like Donald, Goofy, and Mickey. In fact, it seems as if Nintendo scrubbed Sora’s appearance in the platform fighting game of Disney…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 KVM To Land RISC-V Hypervisor Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-KVM-RISC-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-KVM-RISC-V"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T18:36:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coming with the Linux 5.16 kernel cycle will be support for RISC-V virtualization with the Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 93.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/firefox-93.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/firefox-93.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T18:22:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byl vydán Mozilla Firefox 93.0. Přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání, poznámkách k vydání pro firmy a na stránce věnované vývojářům. Zdůraznit lze podporu AVIF, vylepšenou podporu vyplňování formulářů ve vestavěném PDF prohlížeči a SmartBlock 3.0. Řešeny jsou také bezpečnostní chyby. Nejnovější Firefox je již k dispozici také na Flathubu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CentOS Kmods SIG Working On exFAT, WireGuard Additions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CentOS-Kmods-exFAT-WG</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CentOS-Kmods-exFAT-WG"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T18:17:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Created this year has been the CentOS Kmods special interest group for dealing with deprecated device support and out-of-tree modules. This Kmods SIG has begun crafting their initial set of extra kernel modules for use on CentOS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I have a lot of respect for the Storyteller dev for finishing something after a decade]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-have-a-lot-of-respect-for-the-storyteller-dev-for-finishing-something-after-a-decade</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-have-a-lot-of-respect-for-the-storyteller-dev-for-finishing-something-after-a-decade"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:16:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Storyteller has been in development for an age - over a decade, at the longest estimate. That's a very long time. That's about a third of my entire life. Invaders Must Die came out the same year developer Daniel Benmergui first started work on his fairytale puzzle game. To be fair, Invaders Must Die is a pretty bangin' album, so logic would therefore dictate that Storyteller is going to be a pretty bangin' game, too. Alice0 is certainly enamoured with the current demo you can play as part of the Steam Next Fest this week, and I'd strongly recommend you give it a go as well while you can.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weekspot podcast #056: The Spotty Awards 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-056-game-of-the-year-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-056-game-of-the-year-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After countless Xbox Game Pass plugs, a lot of Dooming, and the arrival and subsequent disappearance of Greta Surname, The PC Gaming Weekspot is coming to an end. But, before we go, there's time to highlight some of our favourite games of 2021.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More major multiplayer games moving to Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/more-major-multiplayer-games-moving-to-steam-deck</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/more-major-multiplayer-games-moving-to-steam-deck"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T15:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that the Steam Deck has gained Easy Anti-Cheat (EAC) and BattlEye compatibility, the way is clear for more of Steam’s most-played multiplayer games to achieve full it-just-works-ability with Valve’s handheld. In theory, anyway. Developers still need to enable their respective anti-cheat tech to work with Proton, the compatibility layer that permits Windows games to run on SteamOS. That raises the question: who will?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 93 přináší podporu AVIF, dalších PDF formulářů i SmartBlock 3.0]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42873</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-93-prinasi-podporu-avif-dalsich-pdf-formularu-i-smartblock-3-0/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T14:54:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Třiadevadesátka webového prohlížeče Firefox smazává dluh oproti WebKitovým/Blinkovým prohlížečům, které ve výchozím nastavení podporují grafický formát AVIF již delší dobu. Ve Firefoxu byla podpora zatím dostupná skrze ruční nastavení, nyní je aktivována pro všechny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Far Cry 2's villain is Far Cry 1's hero, creative director confirms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-2-antagonist-is-far-cry-1-hero-creative-director-confirms</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/far-cry-2-antagonist-is-far-cry-1-hero-creative-director-confirms"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T14:37:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Far Cry 6 launching later this week, what a great time to dredge up old arguments and declare once more that Far Cry 2 was the best one. Also dredging up old thoughts, Far Cry 2 creative director Clint Hocking has confirmed an old fan theory: the man we hunt in FC2, the Jackal, is indeed meant to be the fella we played in the first Far Cry. So despite the wildly different tone and seemingly unconnected plot, it really was a sequel after all.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevConf.cz 2022 hledá prednášející]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42871</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/devconf-cz-2022-hleda-prednasejici/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T14:12:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevConf.cz hledá přednášející pro čtrnáctý ročník konference, která se uskuteční 28.-29. ledna 2022. Vítáme začínající (nabízíme koučování a další pomoc těm, kteří nemají žádné, nebo jen malé zkušenosti s prezentováním na veřejnosti) i pokročilé řečníky, kteří se nebojí podělit o své znalosti a technické výsledky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Zstd Planned For Linux 5.16 With Better Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Zstd-Linux-5.16-Plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Zstd-Linux-5.16-Plans"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T13:10:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As reported on last week, an updated Zstd implementation for the Linux kernel is being re-attempted by Zstd developer Nick Terrell at Facebook. Today he sent out the latest Zstd kernel patches to provide a much newer version of the code compared to what is currently mainlined and will provide much better performance and numerous fixes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxenfree II: Lost Signals is more of the good stuff you liked in the first game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oxenfree-2-lost-signals-is-more-of-the-good-stuff-you-liked-in-the-first-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oxenfree-2-lost-signals-is-more-of-the-good-stuff-you-liked-in-the-first-game"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oxenfree II: Oxen Free Or Die Hard (known to squares as Oxenfree II: Lost Signals) was announced earlier this year, a sequel to the much-loved spooky coming-of-age adventure Oxenfree. Did you like the naturalistic conversations and dialogue options you got in the first game? The story of self discovery? The spine-tingling creepiness that is inherent to half-tuned radios? Then I have some good news for you about Oxenfree II.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haiku The Robot is one to watch for hungry Hollow Knight fans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haiku-the-robot-is-one-to-watch-for-hungry-hollow-knight-fans</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haiku-the-robot-is-one-to-watch-for-hungry-hollow-knight-fans"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T12:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We still don't know when Hollow Knight's long-awaited sequel Silksong is coming out, but the demo for upcoming Metroid-like Haiku The Robot has been scratching that Hollow Knight itch for me like nobody's business this week. Available now as part of the Steam Next Fest, this challenging, side-scrolling action-adventure game sees your little bot pal Haiku explore a vast, apocalyptic scrap heap that's been corrupted by possessed machinery and other nasty robots - all without a single squishy bug in sight. Lovely stuff. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumina Desktop 1.6.1 vylepšuje téma vzhledu, chystá velké věci]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42872</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/lumina-desktop-1-6-1-vylepsuje-tema-vzhledu-chysta-velke-veci/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T12:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Lumina Desktop Environment, projekt desktopového prostředí původně zrozeného jako součást PC-BSD, vydává novou dílčí aktualizaci. Lumina 1.6 přitom vyšla už v lednu 2020, nyní se tedy posouváme na verzi Lumina Desktop 1.6.1 s minimem změn. Přináší práce na tématu vzhledu, které vzešly z Projektu Trident, linuxového distra postaveného na Voi Linuxu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mir 2.5 Released With Wayland Extension Updates For Better Handling On-Screen Keyboards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mir-2.5-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mir-2.5-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T12:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical continues advancing their Wayland-based Mir stack for embedded and IoT use-cases. Out today is Mir 2.5 with the latest features as they work to provide better support for on-screen keyboards...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.2.195 Introduced With Three New Extensions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-1.2.195</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-1.2.195"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T12:19:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.2.195 is out today as the latest weekly update to this high performance, industry standard API for graphics and compute...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating comic strips to solve puzzles in Storyteller's demo is a joy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/creating-comic-strips-to-solve-puzzles-in-storytellers-demo-is-a-joy</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/creating-comic-strips-to-solve-puzzles-in-storytellers-demo-is-a-joy"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T11:40:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I thought Storyteller seemed promising when I first heard about the puzzle game way back in 2012, after it won the Nuovo award at the IGFs. Now that it's finally almost finished, I am delighted to play a demo in the Steam Next Fest and report back that yes, it's clever and quite delightful. Each puzzle presents you with a cast of characters, a few verbs and nouns, and an outcome which you must achieve by arranging everything in comic strip panels. Simple, clever, satisfying, and surprisingly funny.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11 is rolling out, but don’t update your Shadow cloud PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/windows-11-is-rolling-out-but-dont-update-your-shadow-cloud-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/windows-11-is-rolling-out-but-dont-update-your-shadow-cloud-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T11:31:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11 is now out and about, gradually making its way to Windows 10 users as an optional free update. Sadly, Microsoft’s latest operating system isn’t have the most auspicious of starts: besides headline gaming features like DirectStorage not technically being usable yet, cloud gaming platform Shadow is actively discouraging users from updating their systems.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World starting zones: which is the best starting zone?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-starting-zones</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-starting-zones"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T10:28:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Which is the best starting zone to get in New World? Unfortunately, at the time of writing, you can't choose or change your New World starting zone. Once you've joined a server and created your character you play through a brief prologue, and then the game randomly spawns you into one of its four starting locations.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Releases September Update To CBL-Mariner Linux Distribution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CBL-Mariner-September-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CBL-Mariner-September-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T10:16:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not only did Microsoft release Windows 11 on Monday but they also released the latest monthly update to CBL-Mariner as the company's in-house Linux distribution...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache HTTP Server (httpd) 2.4.50]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/apache-http-server-httpd-2.4.50</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/apache-http-server-httpd-2.4.50"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T10:15:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 2.4.50 svobodného multiplatformního webového serveru Apache (httpd). Řešeny jsou mimo jiné  2 bezpečnostní chyby CVE-2021-41773 a CVE-2021-41524 zavlečeny do předchozí verze 2.4.49.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM 13.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/llvm-13.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/llvm-13.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po půl roce vývoje od vydání verze 12.0.0 byla vydána verze 13.0.0 překladačové infrastruktury LLVM (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání: 
LLVM, 
Clang, 
Extra Clang Tools,
LLD, 
Libc++, 
Polly 
a
Flang.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can preload Battlefield 2042's open beta client now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-preload-battlefield-2042s-open-beta-client-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-preload-battlefield-2042s-open-beta-client-now"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T09:53:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the multiplayer open beta test starting this week, you can now preload the Battlefield 2042 client to be ready as soon as war breaks out. The BF2042 open beta starts Friday, though pre-orderers and EA Play members will get early access from Wednesday. It's been three years since Battlefield was last in the near-future, so how do you fancy its return?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asus and Noctua have teamed up on a quieter, browner GeForce RTX 3070]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/asus-and-noctua-have-teamed-up-on-a-quieter-browner-geforce-rtx-3070</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/asus-and-noctua-have-teamed-up-on-a-quieter-browner-geforce-rtx-3070"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T09:48:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rumours were true: Asus and cooling specialists Noctua have co-created a new GeForce RTX 3070 design. The underlying GPU already makes for one of the best graphics cards, and Noctua claims their gargantuan custom radiator design and dual 120mm fans make the Asus GeForce RTX 3070 Noctua Edition - to use its full name - “the quietest air-cooled graphics card in its class”.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevConf.CZ 2022 hledá prednášející]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/devconf.cz-2022-hleda-prednasejici</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/devconf.cz-2022-hleda-prednasejici"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T09:07:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevConf.CZ hledá přednášející pro čtrnáctý ročník konference, která se uskuteční 28.-29. ledna 2022. Vítáme začínající (nabízíme koučování a další pomoc těm, kteří nemají žádné, nebo jen malé zkušenosti s prezentováním na veřejnosti) i pokročilé řečníky, kteří se nebojí podělit o své znalosti a technické výsledky. V roce 2022 bude totiž konference poprvé v hybridním formátu: tedy fyzicky na FIT VUT a zároveň v online prostředí. Díky tomu si mohou přednášející sami zvolit formát své přednášky a prezentovat prakticky odkudkoliv. Kromě nového formátu nabídne DevConf také novou podobu tématických okruhů, které se více zaměří na aktuální trendy v IT průmyslu. Pokud chcete přispět do programu svou vlastní přednáškou nebo workshopem, čas na přihlášení máte do 24. října prostřednictvím online formuláře. Nevíte s čím se přihlásit? Nechte se inspirovat loňským programem a nahrávkami.
O konferenci
DevConf.CZ začal jako interní konference společnosti Red Hat za účelem sdílení zkušeností a osvědčených postupů mezi kolegy, avšak po několika interních ročnících si Red Haťáci uvědomili, že všechny tyto diskuse mohou být otevřené veřejnosti a prospěšné pro open source komunitu. DevConf.CZ se tedy stal každoroční bezplatnou komunitní konferenci pro vývojáře, administrátory, inženýry DevOps, testery, autory dokumentace a další přispěvatele do open source technologií. Konference probíhá v angličtině a v roce 2022 bude poprvé v hybridním formátu: tedy fyzicky na univerzitě, ale i v online prostředí.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dorka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Come and hear about the creation of Sable and Inkle's Overboard at EGX 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-and-hear-about-the-creation-of-sable-and-inkles-overboard-at-egx-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-and-hear-about-the-creation-of-sable-and-inkles-overboard-at-egx-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T08:50:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[EGX 2021 kicks off this Thursday at London's ExCel, and RPS will be there doing what we do best: interviewing developers and uncovering lots of brand-new indie games for you to enjoy. In particular, we're going to be talking to the creators of Sable about the game's art and inspirations, as well as Inkle's narrative director Jon Ingold about the making of their nautical murder mystery game, Overboard. It's going to be a fun time, so if you're making the trip down, be sure to stop by the EGX Theatre stage while you're there. Read on for the full rundown of all things RPS at EGX. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micron's HSE Storage Engine 2.0 Debuts - No Longer Relies On Linux Kernel Modifications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Micron-HSE-2.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Micron-HSE-2.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April 2020 there was the somewhat surprising announcement of Micron announcing their own open-source storage engine designed for SSDs and persistent memory. The Heterogeneous-Memory Storage Engine (HSE) has been redesigned and on Monday debuted in v2.0 form with some fundamental changes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 93 Primed For Release With AVIF Image Support, Canonical Managing Official Snap]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-93</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-93"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the formal announcement has yet to hit the wire, releasing today is Firefox 93.0 as the newest monthly feature update to Mozilla's web browser...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Lands Another Big Overhead Optimization - "Substantially" Helps In Some Cases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-Display-List-Interface</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-Display-List-Interface"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T23:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged to Mesa 21.3-devel this weekend was a rework to the display list interface for the Gallium3D code and Mesa state tracker and wired up for the RadeonSI Gallium3D driver. This latest driver overhead reduction is another sizable win for AMD's open-source OpenGL driver on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elden Ring interview dishes tiny details on map fragments and difficulty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-interview-dishes-tiny-details-on-map-fragments-and-difficulty</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-interview-dishes-tiny-details-on-map-fragments-and-difficulty"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T22:42:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As it goes with Elden Ring, information is sparse between infoblasts by FromSoftware. We're at an in-between phase right now as that January 2022 launch date is still a few months away yet. In the meantime, one of Elden Ring's producers Yasuhiro Kitao did a quick interview during the Tokyo Games Show over the weekend to reiterate that yes, the game is difficult and also that it's nearly finished. You'd imagine so, at three months out. Kitao also talks just a bit about Elden Ring's map, too, and how the game doesn't use quests to drag you around its open world.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python 3.10 Released With Many Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Python-3.10-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Python-3.10-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T22:26:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Python 3.10 is out as the latest major update for this widely-used programming language's official implementation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME 41 přichází s profily napájení: ušetřete baterie nebo získejte výkon]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15691</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/gnome-41-prichazi-s-profily-napajeni-usetrete-baterie-nebo-ziskejte-vykon/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podzimní vydání GNOME přináší přepínání mezi profily napájení, takže vám umožní prodloužit výdrž na baterii, nebo naopak dodat výkon. Kromě toho obsahuje také výrazně modernizované rozhraní GNOME Software nebo řadu novinek pro vývojáře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jiří Eischmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Představení projektu SciLua]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15693</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/predstaveni-projektu-scilua/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes se začneme věnovat projektu SciLua. Ten lze s určitou dávkou zobecnění považovat za obdobu knihoven Numpy a SciPy, ovšem pro Luu. SciLua je postavena nad interpretrem LuaJIT a numerické algoritmy využívají knihovnu OpenBLAS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšel Android 12, přináší podporu AVIF či rychlejší strojové učení]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42870</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vysel-android-12-prinasi-podporu-avif-ci-rychlejsi-strojove-uceni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová hlavní verze operačního systému Android, a to jak ve variantě protkané Googlem, tak ve své otevřené variantě Android Open Source Project (AOSP). Mezi novinkami je opět přepracované uživatelské rozhraní, včetně nových widgetů a dalších vylepšení v oblasti grafické. Systém je také svižnější, notifikace responzivnější, zvýšil se i výkon strojového učení systému a došlo i na nová vylepšení v oblasti soukromí či podporu grafického formátu AVIF.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessible Games Database helps find games with the features you need]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-accessible-games-database-helps-find-games-with-the-features-you-need</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-accessible-games-database-helps-find-games-with-the-features-you-need"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T20:55:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility options for games, big and small, have become a more frequent topic of conversation in the last few years. Even just recently, Destiny 2 is adding a full-auto mode while EA are sharing their accesibility feature patents. Depending on what features you need access to though, it can still be a chore to find out exactly what options a game will support. The recently launched Accessible Games Database aims to help catalog games by a list of different accessibility features. It's launched with over 140 games logged so far, and the creators say they're planning to add more every day.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Save $230 on a titanic 4TB PCIe 4.0 SSD - until midnight tonight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/save-230-on-a-titanic-4tb-pcie-40-ssd-until-midnight-tonight</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/save-230-on-a-titanic-4tb-pcie-40-ssd-until-midnight-tonight"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T20:18:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's rare to see big discounts on high capacity SSDs, especially when the SSDs in question are also super-fast PCIe 4.0 models - but that's exactly what's happening for today only over at Amazon. PNY's XLR CS3040, a model compatible with both PC and PS5, has been discounted $230 for a massive 4TB size. That cuts the price of the drive down from a whopping $750 to a still significant (but much more reasonable) $520, a 31% discount. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get a wicked-fast PCIe 4.0 SSD for £126, a historic low price]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wicked-fast-pcie-40-ssd-for-126-a-historic-low-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/get-a-wicked-fast-pcie-40-ssd-for-126-a-historic-low-price"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T19:41:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Crucial P5 Plus is one of the fastest SSDs on the planet with a peak read speed of 6600MB/s, thanks to its combination of a PCIe 4.0 interface, 1TB of TLC NAND flash and Crucial owner Micron's advanced controller. Today, the P5 Plus is also the cheapest second-gen PCIe 4.0 SSD in the UK, as the drive has been marked down from £157 to £126 on Amazon. That's an incredible price for an SSD that works equally well in a PC or a PS5. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haunted PS1's indie horror game showcase EEK3 returns on Friday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-ps1s-indie-horror-game-showcase-eek3-returns-on-friday</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-ps1s-indie-horror-game-showcase-eek3-returns-on-friday"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T19:23:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you think you're tired of game showcases, this one might just resurrect your enthusiasm from its post-E3 grave. We're being tricked and treated to another "EEK3" showcase of indie horror games hosted by Haunted PS1. Last year's showcase dug up a whole bunch of trailers for new and upcoming spooky games with a lo-fi or retro flair. This year is sure to unearth more of the same when it premieres this Friday.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android 12 Now Available From The Android Open-Source Project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Android-12-AOSP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Android-12-AOSP"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google announced today that Android 12 is now officially available from the Android Open Source Project (AOSP)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Publishes Open-Source "GPUFORT" As Newest Effort To Help Transition Away From CUDA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Radeon-GPUFORT</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Radeon-GPUFORT"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've just been informed by AMD that they have now made their code public to a new project called GPUFORT. This new GPUFORT project will live under the Radeon Open eCosystem (ROCm) umbrella and is their latest endeavor in helping developers with large CUDA code-bases transition away from NVIDIA's closed ecosystem...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World player counts keep climbing, nearly a million concurrents on Sunday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-player-counts-keep-climbing-nearly-a-million-concurrents-on-sunday</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-player-counts-keep-climbing-nearly-a-million-concurrents-on-sunday"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T17:47:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As MMOs often do at launch, New World had busy servers and long queues to get in game last week. That's certainly not stopping folks from attempting to play though, as New World hit another concurrent player record for itself. It was already the most popular game on Steam last week with over 700,000 concurrent players. As of yesterday, New World's peak player count was nearly a million players. We don't know how many of those folks are hanging around in those server queues, of course, but they're all at least trying to play.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Prepares Linux Driver Support For USB4 DP Tunneling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-USB4-DP-Tunneling</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-USB4-DP-Tunneling"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T17:45:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The newest patch series by AMD open-source Linux graphics driver engineers worth mentioning is around USB4 DisplayPort tunneling support for next-generation AMD hardware supporting USB4 connectivity...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook, WhatsApp a Instagram mají celosvětově problém kvůli výpadku DNS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42869</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/facebook-whatsapp-a-instagram-maji-celosvetove-problem-kvuli-vypadku-dns/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T17:15:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook, WhatsApp a Instagram mají celosvětově od šesté hodiny večer našeho času problém zřejmě kvůli výpadku svých DNS serverů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Epic Games Store is launching its achievements system next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-epic-games-store-is-launching-its-achievements-system-next-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-epic-games-store-is-launching-its-achievements-system-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T16:08:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games are still in the process of getting their store and launcher hooked up with features you're used to from that other big digital games store. Next week they're adding one you might have been waiting for. Naw, it isn't the shopping cart. Not quite yet, anyway. In the nearest term, it's their achievements system that's getting its initial launch. As of next week, Epic will be rolling out Epic Achievements and XP for a handful of games including Hades, Rocket League, and Kena: Bridge Of Spirits.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Saltpeter locations: how to gather Saltpeter Ore in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-saltpeter</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-saltpeter"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T16:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where can you find Saltpeter in New World? In New World, Saltpeter is used to craft gunpowder, which in turn is a key component in crafting musket cartridges. Depending on your chosen character build and the weapons you favour, this could be an absolutely essential resource for you. But exploring Aeternum in search of a specific resource can be an intimidating prospect due to the sheer size of the island, so we've put together this guide to help you find the best Saltpeter spawn locations.
Fortunately, it's easy to predict where Saltpeter is going to spawn in New World. Unlike some other resources, Saltpeter isn't native to any particular region of the map. Instead, Saltpeter Ore nodes spawn in caves across Aeternum. Caves in New World tend to cluster around the coast, as you might expect, but you can find them inland as well, particularly at higher elevations.
The only real drawback to finding Saltpeter once you're inside the caves is that it looks quite a bit like any other rock. Saltpeter Ore is often slightly darker in color than its surroundings, and protrudes from the floor a bit more, but it's not hugely obvious. However, the good news is that within the confines of a cave, you should see the interaction text identifying Saltpeter appear on-screen if there's any nearby.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I used Planet Zoo’s new North America Animal Pack to make a grim facsimile of HBO's Deadwood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-used-planet-zoos-new-north-america-animal-pack-to-make-a-grim-facsimile-of-hbos-deadwood</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-used-planet-zoos-new-north-america-animal-pack-to-make-a-grim-facsimile-of-hbos-deadwood"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you keep even half an eye on delightful construction game Planet Zoo, you’ll know that developers Frontier tend to release a DLC pack for it every quarter, bringing a bunch of fresh animals into the game from a particular region of the globe. Whenever that happens, I tend to make what could charitably be called a concept zoo, in order to show off the new arrivals in the best possible light. 
Since this week’s DLC introduces an octet of animals from North America, there was only one conceivable way to exhibit them: an awkward combination of zoo, performance art and poundshop Westworld, displaying the majesty of nature alongside recreations of sets from the legendary TV show Deadwood. Let’s have a little walk around town, shall we?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nate Crowley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Wake Remastered: how it compares to the original]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-remastered-comparison</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-remastered-comparison"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T15:23:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Would you pay an extra 14-ish quid  for a purely visual touch-up on a game you can already buy with ease? That’s, as Katharine found in her Alan Wake Remastered review, the biggest problem facing Remedy and D3T’s restoration project. It makes a lot of sense for current-gen consoles, which for various reasons might not have always had access to the torch-and-shoot original, but of course us PC lot could well have been playing it yesterday.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This RPG in the Steam Next Fest looks like Morrowind in hell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-rpg-in-the-steam-next-fest-looks-like-morrowind-in-hell</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-rpg-in-the-steam-next-fest-looks-like-morrowind-in-hell"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T15:11:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming open-world RPG Dread Delusion is, if nothing else, a hell of a mood. Soon after starting the demo that's now available in the Steam Next Fest, I found myself just chilling with the soundtrack and watching the hot pink sun crawl across the sky, fed by tendrils swirling into it and briefly occluded by blood-red clouds. A great vibe. Like a small Morrowind, but in the sort of Hellsville where the local tavern is adorned with the giant skull of a slain god who collapsed upon it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Petalcap locations: how to get Fronded Petalcaps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-petalcaps</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-petalcaps"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T14:33:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where can you find Petalcaps in New World? Petalcaps are a useful resource in New World, since they're a key component to crafting many of the game's potions. It can be overwhelming looking for resources on Aeternum, simply because there's just so much flora and fauna knocking about (and so many other players looking for the same things). Read on for everything you need to know about where Fronded Petalcaps spawn so that you can narrow your search.
Fronded Petalcaps have a few things going for them in the noticeability department. They are quite large, are a more luminous shade of green than most of the other plants around them, and overall look quite pleasingly like giant artichokes.
The Petalcap is native to the Windsward region of Aeternum, which is a conveniently central location from the very early stages of the game, since it's right in the middle of all four starting zones. Within Windsward, Fronded Petalcaps are fairly common, sprouting up in any area that could be described as remotely verdant, whether it's an open field or a more enclosed forested area. Basically, unless you're in a dry or coastal part of the region, there's likely to be some Fronded Petalcaps relatively close by.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lemnis Gate review: a time-twisting shooter full of more frustration than creativity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lemnis-gate-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lemnis-gate-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right. Let’s think about this. If I start the round by protecting my engineer with Karl’s shield, then he won’t be blown to pieces by Deathblow’s rocket at the six second mark. That means this loop he’ll survive to place the turrets I prepared in the first round, which should be enough to deal with the flanking zippy boy from round two. Then I can wrap around, finish off the Deathblow before he turns his rocket spam on the second objective, place a second shield on MY flanking zippy boy just in case he runs into trouble next loop, then finally fire some lasers at the first objective to counterbalance any extra enemy damage it might take in either the future or the past. Easy!


It’s not, but then again, it sort of is? Lemnis Gate clearly wants me to compare it to 4D Chess, but in (this) reality it feels much closer to timey-wimey Tic-Tac-Toe.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sign up to the RPS supporter program and get a free ticket to EGX 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sign-up-to-the-rps-supporter-program-and-get-a-free-ticket-to-egx-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sign-up-to-the-rps-supporter-program-and-get-a-free-ticket-to-egx-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:20:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK's best gaming show EGX returns to the physical plane at London's ExCel later this week, and you could be there in person for zero pounds by signing up to the RPS supporter program today. New UK subscribers who sign up for a yearly premium subscription will be able to redeem a code for a free day ticket to EGX on Saturday, October 9th, which would normally set you back £26. Read on for more details.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Tiger Lake Performance Looking Even Better With Ubuntu 21.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30574</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30574"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been one year now since Intel launched Tiger Lake mobile processors and since then we've been running routine benchmarks of the Core i7 1165G7 on Linux. Tiger Lake at launch was performing well under Linux but its performance has continued evolving nicely since on Linux, especially as it pertains to the Xe Graphics with the open-source OpenGL/Vulkan drivers. With Ubuntu 21.10 due out later this month, there is another performance boost to enjoy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jett: The Far Shore review: wonderful fiction undermined by woeful friction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jett-the-far-shore-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jett-the-far-shore-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out on the Far Shore, the Wyld calls to outsiders. Sounds wishy-washy, I know, but this is a world where the spiritual meets the rational. Tor, the conical peak that sits among the waves of a rambunctious ocean, broadcasts a clear signal across the stars, like the DJ of a mystical pirate radio station. Miraculously - or inevitably, depending on your attitude to prophecy - somebody answers. A species not entirely unlike humanity leaves behind a failing orb not entirely unlike Earth, and makes an impossible journey out of faith and desperation to the source of the Hymnwave. Jett: The Far Shore’s protagonist, Mei, is one of the first scouts to step onto the shore: “A mystic among them,” as predicted by a soothsayer long ago.
Once there, the newcomers find confirmation of their wyldest dreams, but the planet soon turns against them. Equipment is damaged or taken by local fauna, and the weather pins the would-be explorers in place. Tor seems to at once welcome its guests and push them away, as if at odds with itself. Though the Hymnwave has hummed through the ether for many years, it’s clear the planet is not yet of one mind.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Peel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Wake Remastered review: a handsome lick of paint on a decade-old classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-remastered-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-remastered-review"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long before Jesse Faden and the denizens of Control were losing their minds over sentient fridges and rubber ducks, Alan Wake was doing unholy battle with possessed logging tractors and combine harvesters. In hindsight, it seems obvious that these two worlds would eventually collide in Remedy's newly established Wake-iverse - such is their shared love of shadowy, flying objects - but back in the dark days of 2010, little did we know that Remedy's tortured horror writer would be making such a big comeback eleven years later. 
Well, at least he is over on consoles. While the original Alan Wake had a brief, year-long holiday from Steam in 2017 due to the expiration of its music licences, PC folks have been able to play Remedy's cult classic shooter more or less uninterrupted since its release in 2012. Alan Wake Remastered, however, marks the first time it's ever come to PlayStation (it having been an Xbox console exclusive all these years), and its spruced up character models, higher frame rates and 4K texture packs feel very much intended to get PS4 and PS5 players up to speed on this old-but-new figure in Jesse's life than us on PC. Indeed, when there's still a perfectly good version of Alan Wake sitting right there on Steam for less than half the cost of this new remaster, you're probably better off playing the original than stumping up the cash for this latest nip and polygon tuck.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3 RADV Vulkan Driver Lands Ray-Tracing Support For Older AMD Radeon GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Mesa-21.3-Older-RT</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Mesa-21.3-Older-RT"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T12:28:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3 recently landed RADV ray-tracing support for this open-source Radeon Vulkan driver with RDNA2 graphics processors. Now the software-based/emulated Vulkan ray-tracing support has been merged for handling pre-RDNA2 GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Předělávky GTA III a Vice City opět odstraněny z GitHubu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42868</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/predelavky-gta-iii-a-vice-city-opet-odstraneny-z-githubu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T12:25:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Re3 byla open source předělávka starých her GTA III a GTA: Vice City. Objevila se v únoru a záhy poté byl jejich repozitář na GitHubu blokován kvůli oznámení firmy Take-Two, která vlastní firmu Rockstar vyvíjející GTA. Vývojáři Re3 se odvolali poté byly repozitáře znovu na čas dostupné.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Catch - Lost civilization 2021]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42867</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/the-catch-lost-civilization-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T12:15:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S říjnem, který je měsíc bezpečného internetu přichází i další ročník soutěže The Catch tentokrát s podtitulem Lost civilization.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: proteo)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Diluc build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-diluc-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-diluc-build"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T11:18:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best Diluc build in Genshin Impact? Maybe you’re here because you wished for Diluc with all your heart and finally got to add him to your party. Or maybe you’re here because he stole your pity. Whatever the reason may be, we’re here to help. As the owner of Dawn Winery (despite his hatred for wine), Diluc holds a hefty position in Mondstadt, and he’s strikingly powerful in battle as a main DPS.
This guide will show you how to create the best Diluc build in Genshin Impact. Below we'll cover everything you need to know about Diluc, including wishing, weapons, artifacts, ascension materials, talents, abilities, and constellations.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Koei Tecmo announce Atelier Sophie 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/koei-tecmo-announce-atelier-sophie-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/koei-tecmo-announce-atelier-sophie-2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're keen on alchemy, JRPGs and fighting magical monsters, you might be pleased to know that Koei Tecmo announced a sequel to Atelier Sophie at the Tokyo Game Show this weekend. In Atelier Sophie 2: The Alchemist Of The Mysterious Dream, main lass Sophie is a fully fledged alchemist, but she's gotten herself lost in a dream world where her friends don't remember her. Disaster! You can help that little fiasco when the game releases next year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumina Desktop 1.6.1 Released With Theme Improvements While Bigger Improvements Planned]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lumina-Desktop-1.6.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lumina-Desktop-1.6.1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:35:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Lumina Desktop Environment as the BSD-3 licensed desktop originally spearheaded for TrueOS/PC-BSD but found supported as well by other BSDs and Linux distributions is out with a rare new release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12 Compiler Squaring Away Its AVX-512 FP16 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-AVX-512-FP16-Landing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-AVX-512-FP16-Landing"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T10:13:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent weeks the AVX-512 FP16 support has been landing within the GNU Compiler Collection codebase for next year's GCC 12 release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's Dota 2 tournament scraps live audience due to the pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valves-dota-2-tournament-scraps-live-audience-cos-of-the-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valves-dota-2-tournament-scraps-live-audience-cos-of-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T09:58:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four days before the start of their huge Dota 2 tournament, Valve have called off having a live audience at The International. This year's event in Romania was meant to be a glorious return after 2020's International was cancelled by the pandemic, but that pandemic is not yet over. With Covid-19 infection rates in Romania rising again, Valve will still hold the tournament but now without the audience. They're automatically refunding event tickets, obvs, but oof that'll be a lot of people out travel costs.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD SEV-SNP Development Continues Towards The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-SEV-SNP-Autumn-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-SEV-SNP-Autumn-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T09:45:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since the launch of AMD EPYC 7003 "Milan" processors earlier this year there has been support for SEV-SNP as the latest evolution of Secure Encrypted Virtualization. The mainline Linux kernel still isn't yet supporting SEV Secure Nested Paging from the upstream kernel, but the out-of-tree patches continue to be available for those interested and development work continues in getting that code ready for mainline as well as ironing out other features...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Please welcome our new hardware editor, James Archer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-welcome-our-new-hardware-editor-james-archer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/please-welcome-our-new-hardware-editor-james-archer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I stepped up to become the new editor-in-chief of RPS after Graham ascended to the big corporate ship in the sky, I did so by leaving behind my throne of hardware boxes. Luckily, a new heir to the RPS tech chair has arisen, and his name is James Archer. Please come and say hello. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jádro bude mít pkill_on_warn]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42866</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/jadro-bude-mit-pkill-on-warn/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T07:42:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bezpečnostní expert Alexander Popov navrhl nový parametr linuxového jádra pkill_on_warn . V současnosti jsou dvě možnosti, pokud proces způsobí varování jádra. Ve výchozím případě se nestane nic. Nebo je nastaveno panic_on_warn a jádro se zastaví. Pokud máte nastaveno třeba kernel.panic=10, tak se počítač po deseti sekundách restartuje. Zde je výchozí 0, tedy nerestartovat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FSF oznámila doplněk do prohlížeče JShelter proti škodlivému JS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42865</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/fsf-oznamila-doplnek-do-prohlizece-jshelter-proti-skodlivemu-js/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T05:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nadace Free Software Foundation (FSF) ve čtvrtek oznámila rozšíření pro webové prohlížeče JShelter, který má blokovat škodlivý JavaScript. Umí blokovat otisk prohlížeče, sledování, snižuje přesnost geolokace přibližně na část města a zabraňuje odesílaní dat z formuláře při vyplňování před jeho odesláním. JShelter vyvíjí Libor Polčák a Matrin Bednář (VUT Brno), Giorgio Maone (NoScript) a Ana Isabel Carvalho a Ricardo Lafuente (Manufactura Independente).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comet Visitor]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2524/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2524/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Vztah mezi bezpečností, IT a vývojem se musí zlepšit]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-vztah-mezi-bezpecnosti-it-a-vyvojem-se-musi-zlepsit</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-vztah-mezi-bezpecnosti-it-a-vyvojem-se-musi-zlepsit"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM Cloud a jeho umělá inteligence i ve vlastním datacentru. HPE představilo nové cloudové služby pro platformu HPE GreenLake. Pure nabízí Database-as-a-Service pro Kubernetes. Internet věcí nás obklopuje na každém kroku, účastníci Atos Hackathonu se naučí s ním zacházet. Vztah mezi bezpečností, IT a vývojem se musí zlepšit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: pomsta ztraceného telefonu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15688</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-pomsta-ztraceneho-telefonu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V pravidelném pondělním přehledu bezpečnostních hrozeb se podíváme na dvě zranitelnosti ze světa Apple, dvě z Microsoftu, dva útoky na uživatele a dvě zprávy z Číny vám přináší zcela symetrické vydání Postřehů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CSIRT.CZ)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux s jádrem 5.14, vyšla Fedora 35 beta]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15687</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/arch-linux-s-jadrem-5-14-vysla-fedora-35-beta/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Komunita kolem Arch Linuxu vydala nový obraz s jádrem 5.14. Instalační obrazy pro beta verzi Fedora Linuxu 35 jsou k dispozici k veřejnému testování. Na Kickstarteru probíhá crowdfunding pro chytré hodinky Bangle.js 2.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc4 Released - The Kernel Is Looking "Pretty Normal"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc4"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T21:56:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds has declared Linux 5.15-rc4 as the latest weekly release candidate of the maturing Linux 5.15 codebase...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 Aims For Better USB Low-Latency Audio Playback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-USB-Audio-LL</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-USB-Audio-LL"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T12:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel is trying again to enhance the low-latency playback mode of its USB audio driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-613</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-613"/>
        <updated>2021-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for sinking into a scorching hot bath. Before you run the tap, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Madness: Project Nexus revives a Newgrounds classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/madness-project-nexus-revives-a-newgrounds-classic</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/madness-project-nexus-revives-a-newgrounds-classic"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T22:44:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Madness: Project Nexus will stir nostalgia for people who used to play browser games via Newgrounds. It's a fully 3D entry in the Madness Combat series of Flash animations which began in 2002, and named after the Flash game released in 2012.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Choo-Choo Charles is survival horror with a hungry spider-legged train]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/choo-choo-charles-is-survival-horror-with-a-hungry-spider-legged-train</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/choo-choo-charles-is-survival-horror-with-a-hungry-spider-legged-train"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T22:01:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People have been adding a seemingly-possessed Thomas The Tank Engine to games via mods for years, from Skyrim back in 2013 to the Resident Evil 2 remake more recently.

Choo-Choo Charles turns a pursuing locomotive into an entire open-world horror game. Also the train has spider legs. Find the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Elektronika s elektrony se zápornou hmotností]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-elektronika-s-elektrony-se-zapornou-hmotnosti</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-elektronika-s-elektrony-se-zapornou-hmotnosti"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Podivný model chování elektronů, kupodivu v nijak zvlášť exotických polovodičích. Zrcadlo lape vlhkost i ve vedru. Jak vůbec funguje zhroucení hvězdy? Kromě temné hmoty chybí ve vesmíru i ta běžná.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vylepšení podpory videa v PipeWire, nový ovladač pro ATI Radeony 9000]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15690</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/vylepseni-podpory-videa-v-pipewire-novy-ovladac-pro-ati-radeony-9000/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM 13.0 přináší binární balíček Flang a vylepšený OpenCL Clang, ARMv9 a GNU GCC, Intel zkoumá možnosti synchronizovaného plánovače CPU+GPU na Linuxu, I/O rozhraní Linuxu umí dokonce 5,1M IOPS/jádro.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World will disable character creation on full servers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-will-disable-character-creation-on-full-servers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-will-disable-character-creation-on-full-servers"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T21:39:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New World has implemented a system to stop players from creating characters on "full" servers. Announced today via Twitter, the system is part of Amazon's ongoing efforts to deal with overwhelming demand from folks wanting to play the new MMO.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox have cancelled several unannounced games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-have-cancelled-several-unannounced-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-have-cancelled-several-unannounced-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T21:02:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like a king cutting down lesser heirs, Paradox Interactive have cancelled "several unannounced games". The company say they want to focus on "proven game niches and projects that better meet the company's requirements on return and risk." By which they mean they'll be focusing on strategy and management games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Konami will revive Metal Gear Solid and Silent Hill, rumours say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konami-will-revive-metal-gear-solid-and-silent-hill-rumours-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konami-will-revive-metal-gear-solid-and-silent-hill-rumours-say"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T20:17:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New reports citing anonymous sources say that Konami are going to return to development of major games, with both new instalments and remakes planned for Metal Gear Solid, Castlevania, and Silent Hill. As first reported by VGC, many of these games would be developed by external studios.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 10 pouze za 12 €, super slevy až 91%!]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91-2</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91-2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stále máte šanci koupit na GoodOffer24.com doživotní licenci na Windows 10 pouze za 12  €. Buď si můžete vybrat z nabízených bundlů, nebo projet celý web GoodOffer24.com. Hlavně nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód AX30.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-164</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-164"/>
        <updated>2021-10-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Bandcamp Friday, a thing I didn't know existed until two weeks ago when Alice0 mentioned it. But it sounds good! Celebrate by buying music from small artists, even if that music isn't anything to do with video games. Am I allowed to promote non-game things? Hmm. Not sure. We'll see if a gaming sniper (no-scope, natch) has taken me out by the end of this post or not. In the meantime, here are the games we're playing this weekend!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom want PC to be their main platform and make up 50% of sales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/capcom-want-pc-to-be-their-main-platform-and-make-up-50-of-sales</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/capcom-want-pc-to-be-their-main-platform-and-make-up-50-of-sales"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T23:15:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There's no shortage of developers reafirming a love for PC as a platform lately. Sega want to do more PC ports. Atari have restructured and shifted focus to consoles and PC. Capcom too, are now saying that they want PC to be their main platform with an equal share of their game sales within the next two years. Hey, maybe the next Monster Hunter game could get a simultaneous launch. That'd be a dream.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 39/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-39-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-39-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ridiculously bloody Gungrave G.O.R.E. has called in Ikumi Nakamura]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ridiculously-bloody-gungrave-gore-has-called-in-ikumi-nakamura</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ridiculously-bloody-gungrave-gore-has-called-in-ikumi-nakamura"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T21:41:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bloody new Gungrave game is on the way, including a launch on PC, and that's not all that developers Studio Iggymob are adding to the series with Gungrave G.O.R.E. Yasuhiro Nightow, creator of Gungrave's antihero Grave and the Trigun manga, is joined by former Ghostwire: Tokyo game director Ikumi Nakamura. Along with a new cinematic and gameplay trailer, Studio Iggymob are touting Nakamura's involvement in the game, saying that she's been heavily involved in bringing "her own unique style" to the next Gungrave game. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bloober Team are teasing a return to the Layers Of Fear series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloober-team-are-teasing-a-return-to-the-layers-of-fear-series</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloober-team-are-teasing-a-return-to-the-layers-of-fear-series"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T20:12:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October's here, so it's time to start putting on a few extra layers. Of clothes, sure, but maybe some extra layers of spooks too. Layers Of Fear developers Bloober Team have just released a new trailer teasing a return to their series about creatives types in frightening locales. The next of the series, from the looks of it, might be headed back to the drawing board—or the canvas perhaps—with another story about a painter.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam's Digital Tabletop Fest is focusing on RPGs this month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-digital-tabletop-fest-is-focusing-on-rpgs-this-month</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steams-digital-tabletop-fest-is-focusing-on-rpgs-this-month"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T18:48:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October is shaping up to be a busy month on Steam. Earlier today the latest game demos event kicked off (here are the 13 best Steam Festival Demos) and later this month they'll be running another Digital Tabletop Festival. Like last year, it's a sale and livestream celebration of games inspired by and adapted from board games. This year the event will lean into RPGs, including a chat with the folks behind both Disco Elysium and Baldur's Gate 3 when it kicks off later this month.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 13 best Steam Next Fest demos you should play this October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-next-fest-october-2021-best-demos</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-next-fest-october-2021-best-demos"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Indie extravaganza Steam Next Fest is back for another edition today, showering us with hundreds of upcoming game demos to try over the next week. Running from today, October 1st, until Thursday October 7th, the latest Steam Next Fest is positively packed to the rafters with things to play, and we've picked out some personal highlights to help you get started. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Game Awards will be back in person this year on December 9th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-will-be-back-in-person-this-year-on-december-9th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-game-awards-will-be-back-in-person-this-year-on-december-9th"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T16:40:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summer's in the bin, which means it's time to stop looking back at those E3 showcases and start thinking about the end of year shows. The Game Awards, the December-ly bonanza of world premieres interspersed with the occasional trophy, is back on again. After going online in December 2020 due to the Covid-19 pandemic, show host Geoff Keighley is getting the band back together on stage this year for an in person show that's been scheduled for December 9th.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World Briar Branches locations: how to get Briars in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-briar-branches</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-briar-branches"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T15:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where can you find Briar Branches in New World? Harvesting from Briar bushes in New World can yield a number of different resources including Briar Branches, which are needed to complete the Windsward quest A Prickly Request. But with so much greenery around the isle of Aeternum, sticking your face into every shrub to see if it's the one you're looking for is a time-consuming prospect. On this page, we save you (at least some of) the trouble by explaining where you can find Briars in New World.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bonfire Peaks' puzzle man would be a great (and terrible) presence in a house move]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bonfire-peaks-impressions</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bonfire-peaks-impressions"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T15:31:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Puzzle game Bonfire Peaks is probably a metaphor about emotional baggage and closure. But I know writers who use subtext and they're all cowards. Published by Draknek (wot did the equally puzzly A Monster's Expedition), Corey Martin's new voxel Sokoban-style game features a man slowly making his way up a mountain and totemically burning all of his stuff. Secretly, though, it is a story about a man who has the only superpower people in their 30s actually want: being able to pick up and move any number of boxes at any time.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our video game music recommendations for Bandcamp Friday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-video-game-music-recommendations-for-bandcamp-friday</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/our-video-game-music-recommendations-for-bandcamp-friday"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T15:27:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today is another Bandcamp Friday, when the splendid DRM-free music shop waive their cut of sales to give artists more money. It's a good time to buy music from a good place but a bit overwhelming when the store is so big. Last month, I had some slightly esoteric game music recommendations of my own. This month, I've had everyone in the RPS treehouse recommend a huge spread of video game soundtracks and music on Bandcamp, from Paradise Killer to Skyrim covers. Come, see what we're hearing!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This free Unreal Engine 5 tech demo has me salivating over the future of next-gen food]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-free-unreal-engine-5-tech-demo-has-me-salivating-over-the-future-of-next-gen-food</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-free-unreal-engine-5-tech-demo-has-me-salivating-over-the-future-of-next-gen-food"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T15:15:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Epic unveiled their first Unreal Engine 5 tech demo last year, its ultra-realistic geometry systems and dynamic lighting effects looked impressive and all, but the resulting Tomb Raider-esque sequence left me feeling a little cold. To my eyes, Epic's tech demo didn't really look that much different to what games look like now. 
After playing a new UE5 tech demo from Japanese studio Historia, however, I am fully converted to the merits of Epic's new game engine. At 20GB-odd, The Market Of Light is a hefty download for its 15-20 run-time, but this freeform exploration game is absolutely worth a look if your PC meets its surprisingly reasonable tech requirements - especially if you're a fan of games that feature cooking. Seriously, Epic's Tomb Raider lady can get stuffed. For me, Unreal Engine 5 is all about delicious-looking next-gen food.  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UItimate Audio Bang #15: 1v1 me on shooter trivia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-15-1-v-1-me-on-trivia</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ultimate-audio-bang-15-1-v-1-me-on-trivia"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week's episode of the Ultimate Audio Bang is marked by competition. Imogen and I quiz each other on all things shooter trivia, and someone knows more than the other. Anyway, before that, there's plenty of news to catch up on. Call Of Duty: Vanguard has fixed a weird dognado glitch, time-loopy shooter Lemnis Gate is out, Halo: Infinite tech preview number two arrives very soon, and Overwatch 2 announces some reworks. Spoiler alert: Bastion now has a hat.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Forza Horizon 5 PC specs are pretty steep, huh]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-pc-specs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5-pc-specs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T14:12:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Forza Horizon 5 PC system requirements are out in full, and hoo boy, are you gonna need the best graphics cards to max it out. Revealed in a blog post, the new specs both update the previously listed Minimum requirements on Steam, and include an “Ideal” tier on top of the Recommended requirements. This doesn’t specify a particular resolution, but does ask for either an Nvidia GeForce RTX 3080 or AMD Radeon Radeon RX 6800 XT as the GPU – two of the most powerful, expensive, difficult to buy graphics cards on the market.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svoboda 1945: Liberation is all the better for its absence of drama]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/svoboda-1945-liberation-is-all-the-better-for-its-absence-of-drama</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/svoboda-1945-liberation-is-all-the-better-for-its-absence-of-drama"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I accepted long ago that If the yoof ever do the right thing, I'll probably be dragged out into the street and shot along with all the other old bastards, despite hating them just as much.


That's sort of what Svoboda 1945 Colon Liberation is about. Dynamics like that happen, especially as fascists and collaborators lie and deny everything, so there'll always be collateral in the wake of revenge on a large enough scale.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nová loga pro USB-C kabely]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42864</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nova-loga-pro-usb-c-kabely/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T13:31:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[USB Implementers Forum se snaží novými obrázky zjednodušit označení USB-C kabelů, které je v současnosti dosti složité. Nově bude logo označovat kabely a nabíječky, které umí přenést 240 W, což umožňuje nově Power Delivery od května letošního roku. Do té doby bylo možné přenášet 65 či 100 W.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running an eldritch plant shop in Strange Horticulture is everything I want in life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/strange-horticulture-preview-running-an-eldritch-plant-shop-is-everything-i-want-in-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/strange-horticulture-preview-running-an-eldritch-plant-shop-is-everything-i-want-in-life"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I immediately fell in love with Strange Horticulture when I played the demo, and now I've had a few hours with a longer, more polished preview build I am even more in loverer. I do not understand why this is not everyone's most anticipated game ever. Imagine if all the horrible shouting griefers playing war games put down their weapons and picked up a strange plant and a taxonomic tome. What a world that would be! Certainly a world with more plant shops, anyway, though probably not (m)any as strange as Strange Horticulture.
You inherit this shop, along with its secrets, a folding map of the area to go exploring, and shelves of odd plant specimins. Sometimes it is raining. It is a real October vibe. There is a strange mystery, involving cultist and murder - a stranger in a beautiful jade mask comes to the shop, sometimes, as well as the detective struggling to solve a number of troubling murders in the area. But what care I for that? I am deep role-playing as a horticulturist. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel pracuje na prioritách pro integrované GPU]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42863</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-pracuje-na-prioritach-pro-integrovane-gpu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T13:12:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Integrované grafické karty Intel umožňují stejně jako CPU řadit úlohy podle priority. Ale v současnosti ovladač i915 neumožňuje uživateli do priorit zasahovat. Vývojář ovladače Intelu Tvrtko Ursulin poslal velmi ranou verzi, která nastavení priorit pro GPU s ovladačem i915 umožňuje.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get unstuck in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-unstuck</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-unstuck"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Desperate to find out how to get unstuck in New World? It's always a good thing when developers add an "unstuck" feature into their game - particularly a sprawling MMORPG like New World where getting your character stuck in bits of landscape is more common than you might think. Fortunately, it is possible to get unstuck in New World, and this quick walkthrough will explain how to do it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This week's Mystery Steam Reviews is a sidequel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mystery-steam-reviews-055-video-games-spinoffs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mystery-steam-reviews-055-video-games-spinoffs"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-offs are dead handy. You take an established character that's already known, stick them in a new environment full of fresh characters, and you've got yourself a Frasier. Bingo bango, job's a goodun. It's a format that's done the business in television, so no wonder video games have followed suit.
  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to transfer your character in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-transfer-character</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-transfer-character"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:05:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to transfer your character to a different server in New World? Amazon's titanic MMORPG New World is full to bursting with players across its various servers and realms, but as with all such games, some servers are going to be more preferable to certain players than others. Whether it's about dodging long wait times and lag, or just joining the same realm as your friends, most players want to know sooner or later about character transfers and how they work.
Read on to find out how and when you can transfer your character over to another server in New World.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix announce Dungeon Encounters, led by FF6 director]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-announce-dungeon-encounters-led-by-ff6-director</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-announce-dungeon-encounters-led-by-ff6-director"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix today announced new game Dungeon Encounters, and surprise, it's launching in only a fortnight.
The dungeon crawler is directed by Hiroyuki Ito, who directed Final Fantasy VI, IX, and XII, as well as creating the Active Time Battle system. Some other FF veterans are onboard too. But more important than all that is: along with all manner of warriors, possible party members include a giant cat named Sir Cat, a dog holding a sword in its mouth, and a hamster. Yes, thanks.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dream Cycle is a strange blend of Skyrim and Dishonored with big potential]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dream-cycle-is-a-strange-blend-of-skyrim-and-dishonored-with-big-potential</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dream-cycle-is-a-strange-blend-of-skyrim-and-dishonored-with-big-potential"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Action adventure Dream Cycle certainly feels like an early access game. Animations are stiff, the audio mix is a bit funky, and it doesn't really have a save system yet. But look past the jank and I reckon there's a bright future ahead of Cathuria Games' latest. The studio was set up by Toby Gard, one of the folks who helped create Lara Croft, the tomb-raiding OG, so there's adventure pedigree at the helm, even if Dream Cycle bears no real resemblance to Tomb Raider. However, if you're into Skyrim and Dishonored, I'd definitely urge you to keep an eye on its progress.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can you change your name in New World?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-name-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-name-change"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T11:41:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know if you can change your name in New World? It's a common tale of woe among MMO players: your ideal name is already taken, so you have to settle for an inferior moniker. Then later you realise that it just doesn't sit right and you need a name name to strike fear into the hearts of your enemies. But can it be done? Find out whether you can rename your character in New World below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World AFK timer: how long can you remain inactive before getting kicked?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-afk-timer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-afk-timer"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T11:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How long is New World's AFK timer? Amazon's gigantic new MMO New World has had quite a launch week — with players reporting hours-long queue times before they can even set foot on the island of Aeternum — and we've not even had the first weekend yet. Amazon have promised more and bigger servers to handle the demand, which they say will begin rolling out within the next two weeks.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stranger Of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin is coming March 18th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-is-coming-march-18th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stranger-of-paradise-final-fantasy-origin-is-coming-march-18th"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T11:20:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Square Enix today announced a release date of March 18th, 2022 for Stranger Of Paradise Final Fantasy Origin, the curious action-RPG spin-off made by the studio behind Nioh, Team Ninja. A new trailer is here too and I have to say it looks more Final Fantasy-y and less less ha-ha-hilariously edgy than June's announcement trailer. It still looks plenty edgy, mind: watch out for the poor wee cactrot which gets... turned into a blood crystal and exploded?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Destiny 2 will add full-auto as an accessibility option]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-2-will-add-full-auto-as-an-accessibility-option</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-2-will-add-full-auto-as-an-accessibility-option"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T10:43:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To fire some of Destiny 2's guns at their fastest possible rate, you need to click six times per second. This sucks. This especially sucks if you have physical issues which impede rapid clicking. Honestly, with these semi-auto weapon archetypes I've often looked for rolls with the Full Auto Trigger System perk to spare my hands. So it's grand to hear from Bungie's new accessibility initiative that yep, they're planning to add some sort of accessibility option enabling automatic fire. In some way.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get a house in Genshin Impact: Serenitea Pot system explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-house-serenitea-pot</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-house-serenitea-pot"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T09:57:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to get a house in Genshin Impact? Genshin Impact’s Serenitea Pot system grants you the ability to decorate your own realm with characters, furniture, plants, rocks, and even pets. Some players have carefully crafted gardens with elegantly decorated houses. Other players have simply used their teapots to trap Venti in an empty room filled with animals — whatever you want to do with your house, we can’t judge.
Whether you haven’t unlocked the housing system yet or you’re looking for ways to improve your Serenitea Pot, this guide will show you everything you need, including unlocking housing, placing characters, choosing a layout, getting furniture, and increasing your Trust Rank and Adeptal Energy. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 best songs in PC games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-10-best-songs-in-pc-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-10-best-songs-in-pc-games"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not just the best songs. These are the best songs performed by characters in-game. In other words, if it's not sung by a fictional band, hollered by a karaoke-obsessed protagonist, or purred by a honey-tongued vocalist who also shoots at you with a ridiculous firearm, then it doesn't count. For this reason, in-game radios are also out. It's too easy, video games. Sorry. That means no rock station classics from Grand Theft Auto and no 80s bangers from Metal Gear Solid V. Learn to accept it. The best music is diegetic, baby. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vytvořte si bezpečnou VPN pomocí OpenVPN (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-41285</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vytvorte-si-bezpecnou-vpn-pomoci-openvpn-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T08:27:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VPN umožňuje bezpečně propojit různá zařízení pomocí šifrovaných tunelů. Umožňuje také zapojit uživatele do vnitřní sítě přes zabezpečený přístupový bod. Na našem školení VPN a bezpečné připojení k síti s OpenVPN si prakticky ukážeme, jak to celé nastavit a zprovoznit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI pro krátkodobou předpověď počasí]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42862</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ai-pro-kratkodobou-predpoved-pocasi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T08:23:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Výzkumníci z univerzit ve Velké Brtitánii a z DeepMind, který je vlastněný Google, vytvořili umělou inteligenci schopnou přesně krátkodobě předpovídat srážky. Předpověď má platnost do dvou hodin, používá se pro ni anglický termín nowcast na rozdíl od běžné předpovědi na den až tři dopředu forecast. Tyto krátkodobé předpovědi používají jen data ze srážkového radaru.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Endangered]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2523/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2523/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vypršel kořenový certifikát DST Root CA používaný autoritou Let's Encrypt]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42861</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyprsel-korenovy-certifikat-dst-root-ca-pouzivany-autoritou-let-s-encrypt/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T21:09:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jak už bylo certifikační autoritou Let's Encrypt předem avizováno, 30. září 2021 ve 14:00 UTC došlo k expiraci kořenového certifikátu DST Root CA, který byl používán jako dočasný po několik let. V zásadě by nemělo dojít k potížím, protože Let's Encrypt CA používá ISRG Root X1 pro RSA nebo ISRG Root X2 pro ECDSA již mnoho měsíců.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Software Defined Silicon (SDSi), softwarové upgrady CPU se vrací na scénu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42860</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-software-defined-silicon-sdsi-softwarove-upgrady-cpu-se-vraci-na-scenu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T14:54:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhruba před 11 lety přišel Intel s velmi kontroverzním a negativně vnímaným programem Upgrade Service. V rámci něj bylo možné u vybraných CPU za úplatek odemknout do té doby neaktivní části CPU a zvýšit tak jeho parametry (tu odemknout HyperThreading, tu zvýšit frekvence, tu zvětšit cache). Program by přijat s odporem IT komunity a víceméně během roku 2011 vyšuměl do ztracena.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD chce 30× efektivnější AI na CPU i GPU do roku 2025]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42859</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-chce-30-efektivnejsi-ai-na-cpu-i-gpu-do-roku-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T14:23:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD představila svoji vizi pro příští čtyři roky. Firma věří, že do roku 2025 dosáhnou její procesory 30× vyšší efektivity při běhu AI a HPC úloh. Slovem procesory jsou zde myšleny jak modely řady EPYC, tak GPU typu (Radeon) Instinct.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Linux 35 Beta, vyzkoušejte si GNOME 41]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42858</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/fedora-linux-35-beta-vyzkousejte-si-gnome-41/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T09:49:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vydání pětatřicáté Fedory se blíží, máme tu beta verzi a s ní i přijatelně fungující možnost vyzkoušet si nejen čerstvé GNOME 41, ale také další novinky, kterými Fedora posouvá linuxový desktop zase více do budoucnosti (v čele třeba s projektem PipeWire). Ostrá verze bude vydána na konci října, beta je k dispozici mimo jiné v podobě Workstation, Server i IoT, samozřejmě pak též v podobě Spinů (s jinými desktopovými prostředími) a Lab(s)ů (předpřipravená pro specifické potřeby) a také pro platformu ARM.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTTPS pro správce serverů (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-39289</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/https-pro-spravce-serveru-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T08:26:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HTTPS se stává běžným, většina webů už ho nasadila. Jak to ale udělat správně, opravdu bezpečně a hlavně bezbolestně? Na školení HTTPS pro správce serverů si ukážeme si nejnovější trendy, prakticky si vyzkoušíme vygenerování certifikátu a nasazení na web server.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-Factor Security Key]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2522/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2522/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 36-37/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-36-37-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-36-37-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na sklonku léta vyšel nový Whonix, podíváme se na systém pro klientské stanice ThinStation a aktualizovány byly také distribuce Finnix, Lakka, GhostBSD, Tails, Kali, Ubuntu LTS, Sailfish OS nebo Sparky Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD dosáhla 16% podílu v serverech, Xeony Ice Lake stále nedostatkové]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42857</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-dosahla-16-podilu-v-serverech-xeony-ice-lake-stale-nedostatkove/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T10:53:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Před lety varoval tehdejší šéf Intelu Brian Krzanich před tím, aby AMD získalo 15–20% podíl v serverech (resp. že jej získá), na úkor firemních výdělečných Xeonů. Intel ale stále není schopen dodat novou generaci Xeonů v množství dostatečném pro saturování zákazníků, takže ti častěji pokukují po EPYCech od AMD, které ostatně nabízí lepší parametry.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření HTTPS Everywhere míří do důchodu, už není potřeba]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42856</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rozsireni-https-everywhere-miri-do-duchodu-uz-neni-potreba/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Frontier Foundation se připravuje na postupné ukončení podpory pro rozšíření HTTPS Everywhere, které na webech automaticky přepíná z HTTP na HTTPS. To už podle organizace začíná být zbytečné, protože rozšíření HTTPS zažilo v posledních letech výrazný nárůst a prohlížeče navíc přišly s vlastním řešením automatického přechodu na HTTPS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chcete vědět kolik byste mohli vydělávat u konkurence na stejné pozici?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/chcete-vedet-kolik-byste-mohli-vydelavat-u-konkurence-na-stejne-pozici</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/chcete-vedet-kolik-byste-mohli-vydelavat-u-konkurence-na-stejne-pozici"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peníze jsou ožehavé téma, obzvlášť jedná-li se o výplaty v zaměstnání. Člověk přemýšlí, zda kolegové nevydělávají víc nebo jestli by si u jiného zaměstnavatele nepolepšil. Jak to ale zjistit? Teď naštěstí jednoduše, protože IT pracovní portál No Fluff Jobs u všech nabídek zveřejňuje nabízené platové ohodnocení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Umělá inteligence uprostřed jihoamerických lesů pomáhá zachránit psího samotáře]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-umela-inteligence-uprostred-jihoamerickych-lesu-pomaha-zachranit-psiho-samotare</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-umela-inteligence-uprostred-jihoamerickych-lesu-pomaha-zachranit-psiho-samotare"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Video, se kterým konečně pochopíte rozdíl mezi běžným a moderním úložištěm. Digitalizace zákaznické péče: jak vybrat nejlepší řešení kontaktního centra. Jaké novinky přináší Arcserve UDP 8.1? On-line konference VMworld 2021: stovky přednášek a tutoriálů zdarma. Gartner na křivce seřadil klíčové nastupující technologie. Studie Dell Technologies: hrozba ztráty dat po kyberútoku je větší, než kdy jindy. Umělá inteligence uprostřed jihoamerických lesů pomáhá zachránit psího samotáře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 38/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-38-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-38-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Planety v centru Mléčné dráhy]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-planety-v-centru-mlecne-drahy</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-planety-v-centru-mlecne-drahy"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moudrost davu. Dokážeme úspěšně předpovědět, kdy k nám dorazí světlo supernovy? Kvasary jako standardní svíčky. Neutron má na povrchu záporný náboj. Proč se zlato vyskytuje vedle arsenu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Komunikace má zvyšovat produktivitu vývojářů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-komunikace-ma-zvysovat-produktivitu-vyvojaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-komunikace-ma-zvysovat-produktivitu-vyvojaru"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hlavní trendy umělé inteligence: Malá a rozprostřená data. Nový typ kybernetických útoků – zneužívání proxyware platforem. Roboti, kteří udělají přesnou díru do hlavy, zachraňují životy. O vstupu do nebe rozhoduje sv. Petr, pro síť je tu ClearPass. Kouzla zbavené? Nepravděpodobné řešení hrozící personální krize ve finančních službách. Honeywell u nás investuje do R&D. Komunikace má zvyšovat produktivitu vývojářů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Přepínané zrcadlo z roztaveného kovu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-prepinane-zrcadlo-z-roztaveneho-kovu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-prepinane-zrcadlo-z-roztaveneho-kovu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Černá díra vyžrala hvězdu. Nanotechnologie s černým oxidem titaničitým. Život v atmosféře subneptunů. Maličké hory na neutronových hvězdách.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>