<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-15T14:13:37.540Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-15T14:13:37.540Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: SkateBIRD - A Chirpy, Charming Tony Hawk-Alike That Fails To Stick The Landing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120790</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/skatebird"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flip the bird.
The skateboarding game, as a genre, has been under-explored. Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater defined it with such finesse in 1999 that there has barely been any room for improvement – as borne out by the continuing appeal of that first game two decades later. But considering how much it has in common with a 3D platformer – open environments with an emphasis on acrobatic exploration and discovery – there is surely an opportunity for others to try some new ideas.
Enter SkateBIRD, the game that answers the question, “What if Tony Hawk was a tiny hawk?” Whoever flippantly asked that question probably wasn’t expecting an answer in the form of a video game released several years of work later, but here it is.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This new Doom mod will let you send Thatcher back to Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-new-doom-mod-will-let-you-send-thatcher-back-to-hell</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-new-doom-mod-will-let-you-send-thatcher-back-to-hell"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next week, reviled former British prime minister Margaret Thatcher will rise from her grave to bring Hell back to Earth, and only one space marine can stop her. Announced today, Thatcher's Techbase is an upcoming mod for classic Doom which ventures in the tenth circle of Hell (aka the United Kingdom) to battle the demonic forces of the Iron Lady. Modding politicians into games is a vintage jape but Thatcher's Techbase makes a real effort with custom art, its own campaign, music from Paradise Killer's composer, and apparently even the voice behind Demeter and Persephone in Hades. Watch this trailer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Publishes Initial Firmware For Yellow Carp APUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Yellow-Carp-FW</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Yellow-Carp-FW"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:25:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A small but important step forward is seeing AMD recently publishing their binary firmware files in advance of new GPU/APU launches for rounding out their Linux driver support stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: These Gaming Shoe Concepts Are So Good We Wish They Were Real]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120965</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/random_these_gaming_shoe_concepts_are_so_good_we_wish_they_were_real"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We'll take the Nintendo 64 pair, thanks.
Companies like Puma may well be launching all sorts of official Nintendo shoes these days – have you seen their Animal Crossing and Mario designs? – but that won't stop us from dreaming of having an entire wardrobe of the things. You know, for different days of the week or something...
Exacerbating our issues feelings tremendously, The Sole Supplier has been busy crafting mock-up designs for a variety of gaming systems. To be clear, these aren't real things you can go out and buy, but you can definitely imagine what would it be like to buy them, and that's close enough.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Fish review: a physics platformer with sole]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-am-fish-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-am-fish-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like a splash of cold water to the face, I Am Fish is a wonderfully refreshing physics platformer. This isn't a grim tale wrapped in layers of metaphor, or a walking simulator that guides you slowly through a field of feelings. Here, you are simply a fish. The bowl is your prison. The ocean is your freedom. Now imagine Ian Mckellen with the same gravitas as he had playing Gandalf in Lord Of The Rings, except with a farmer's cap on. He is peering into your googly, goldfish eyes. In a west country accent, he bellows, "Swim, you fool!"
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: How To Use Bluetooth Headphones On Switch - Connect AirPods To Nintendo Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120954</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/how-to-use-bluetooth-headphones-on-switch-connect-airpods-to-nintendo-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Connect wireless headphones to Switch via Bluetooth.
A firmware update to the Nintendo Switch has enabled the use of wireless headphones directly with the console (without the need for an external third-party dongle or workaround to use Apple AirPods, Powerbeats, and other popular Bluetooth headphones with the system.
In this Nintendo Switch wireless headphones connection guide, we'll take you through the steps to connect your AirPods to Switch and look at how to adjust the Switch's maximum headphone volume to your liking. It will also look at some common Bluetooth audio issues and offer potential solutions.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kontroverzní firma Kape Technologies kupuje ExpressVPN]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/kontroverzni-firma-kape-technologies-kupuje-expressvpn</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/kontroverzni-firma-kape-technologies-kupuje-expressvpn"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T12:07:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Register informuje o koupi populární služby ExpressVPN firmou Kape Technologies, jejíž historii rekapituluje včetně tvorby adware pod jménem Crossrider. Před dvěma lety Kape Technologies převzala také Private Internet Access, rovněž provozovatele VPN a také sponzora řady open-source projektů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi V3DV Driver Still Working On Vulkan 1.1 Conformance, More Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-2021-Status</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-2021-Status"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T12:07:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iago Toral of Igalia kicked off the first day of the virtual XDC2021 developer conference today by sharing a status update on V3DV as the open-source Mesa Vulkan driver most notably used for Raspberry Pi 4 and newer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon ﻿Illustration Contest Could See Your Artwork Made Into An Official Trading Card]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120946</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pokemon_illustration_contest_could_see_your_artwork_made_into_an_official_trading_card"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with a $5,000 prize!
The Pokémon Company is kicking off its latest Trading Card Illustration Contest, giving fans the chance to share their artwork in a bid to have it transformed into a real card.
Usually restricted to just Japan, the 2022 Contest will also be thrown open to fans across the US (unfortunately, those of us in Europe will still miss out this year). The contest is centred around the theme of "drawing a moment in a Pokémon’s daily life", with applications set to open next month on 13th October.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Deathloop weapons: every weapon in Deathloop explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-weapons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-weapons"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T11:27:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many weapons are there in Deathloop and how do you get the best ones? Deathloop is about two assassins locked in a time-looping duel to the death, so naturally, there are weapons aplenty in this game. Thanks to the titular loop, you aren't always going to be able to hang on to every weapon you pick up, so knowing where and how to get your favourite weapons back is going to be important.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Switch Case Lets You Store Eight Cartridges, Available Now From My Nintendo (Europe)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120960</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/this_switch_case_lets_you_store_eight_cartridges_available_now_from_my_nintendo_europe"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just pay shipping.
The latest My Nintendo freebie has arrived, and this one really reminds us of the good old Club Nintendo days.
For 500 Platinum Points, you can now claim a special Nintendo Switch Card Case which stores up to eight cartridges at once – similar cases were often released for the 3DS when Club Nintendo was around, and we're so fond of them that we've held onto them ever since.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death Trash and others want to know how the sausage is made]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/death-trash-and-others-want-to-know-how-the-sausage-is-made</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/death-trash-and-others-want-to-know-how-the-sausage-is-made"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“What’s with all the meat everywhere, anyway?” my Death Trash alter ego Mildred asks. “It’s just there. Grows.” the meat merchant replies. “Maybe we’re living on a planet full of flesh and right now we’re standing on a crust of stone and dirt. So, do you want a piece of meat now?” I really don’t. But Mildred does. After all, this mystery meat is the main healing item in the game. It’s what keeps you and the world around you alive. It’s harvested from the ground like precious stones, the literal blood flowing in this grotesque world’s barebones economy, eaten raw and served in meat bars.
But where does the meat come from? Whence the amorphous flesh blobs and pools of blood? From another planet, another dimension? There are no animals in this strange ecosystem apart from Fleshworms. The strange meat seems to be linked to another mystery, the advent of the flesh titans (which are exactly what the name suggests). Soon we discover that we are able to commune with the meat and, through it, speak to a enigmatic being called The Oracle. The meat is a kind of universal consciousness, a flesh and blood information highway, into which those who are attuned to it can plug in. Whether the meat and the flesh titans are good or bad for humanity is up for debate, and there are factions that deify and others that hate them, vying for power. The clot thickens.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Inderwildi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix's Kate Did Do Right By Japanese Tattooing]]></title>
        <id>1847678326</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/netflixs-kate-did-do-right-by-japanese-tattooing-1847678326"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For all the things that Kate gets wrong, it did get one important thing right: properly crediting tattoo artists. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orange Publishes An In-Kernel eBPF-Powered Cache - Can Speed Up Memcached By ~18x]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Orange-BPF-Memory-Cache-BMC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Orange-BPF-Memory-Cache-BMC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French telecommunications giant Orange has published "BMC" as the (e)BPF Memory Cache providing a cache focused on memcached usage within the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HP OMEN Laptops To Be Better Supported With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=HP-OMEN-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=HP-OMEN-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:08:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HP's higher-end "OMEN" laptop series is set to see better support with the next kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boyfriend Dungeon broke my heart, and I'm glad it did]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/boyfriend-dungeon-broke-my-heart-and-im-glad-it-did</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/boyfriend-dungeon-broke-my-heart-and-im-glad-it-did"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:03:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitfox’s recently released dating sim Boyfriend Dungeon has a novel premise. In Boyfriend Dungeon you date sword people: humans who transform into weapons that you can take dungeon crawling. And no, not sex dungeons. Classic video game dungeons with loot and monsters. On paper, Boyfriend Dungeon sounds like the best six-ish hours you could have in a game, combining the endorphin rush of monster-slaying with a cast of hotties that’ll make your heart flutter. Sounds like a great time… except one of these hotties slid a sword right through my heart.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vivaldi 4.2]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/vivaldi-4.2</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/vivaldi-4.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová stabilní verze 4.2 (4.2.2406.42) webového prohlížeče Vivaldi (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek v příspěvku na blogu. Zdůrazněna je například možnost překladu vybraného textu pomocí překladače Lingvanex hostovaného na serverech Vivaldi. Nejnovější Vivaldi je postaven na Chromiu 93.0.4577.83.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Reimagined GameCube Controller Offers Wireless Play, Pre-Orders Open Now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120951</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/this_reimagined_gamecube_controller_offers_wireless_play_pre-orders_open_now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Compatible with GameCube, Switch and PC.
Thanks to its 20th anniversary yesterday, there's an awful lot of love going around for the GameCube at the moment. The console might not have performed spectacularly sales-wise, but it's often remembered very fondly indeed by those who did go ahead and pick one up two decades ago.
If you just so happen to be one of the 21 million people who bought one, you might be interested in the BladeGC, a new controller designed to be used with the original hardware. Just like Nintendo's official WaveBird controller, the BladeGC offers wireless play, also reimagining the controller's design to fall more in line with the standardised shape seen on modern-day pads.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Intel Tremont Optimizations Heading To The GCC Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Tremont-Faster-GCC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Tremont-Faster-GCC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T09:45:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GNU Compiler Collection has already supported Intel's Tremont cores as used by the low-power Jasper Lake platform. Now though coming to GCC are some optimizations to further enhance the performance when targeting the Tremont micro-architecture...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve posts Steam Deck dev kits, on blog and in mail]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-posts-steam-deck-dev-kits-on-blog-and-in-mail</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-posts-steam-deck-dev-kits-on-blog-and-in-mail"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T09:34:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck, Valve’s attempt at a fully portable handheld PC, has taken another step towards being an actual product. In a Steam blog post, Valve have shown off the Steam Deck dev kits that are leaving the roost to provide game developers with some hands-on time, ahead of the planned launch this December. They grow up so fast, eh?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone's invited to play Age Of Empires 4 this weekend in a stress test]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everyones-invited-to-play-age-of-empires-4-this-weekend-in-a-stress-test</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/everyones-invited-to-play-age-of-empires-4-this-weekend-in-a-stress-test"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T09:15:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After running an Age Of Empires 4 closed beta test for lucky ticketholders, the makers now want absolutely everyone to pile in and click men as hard as you can to see if the game explodes. The historical RTS is holding an open "technical stress test" this weekend, from Friday to Monday, to give the multiplayer backend a sound kicking and see if it stays stands. In short, hey, you can play AO4's multiplayer for free this weekend.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Walking Dead's Negan and Maggie Join Brawlhalla As Playable Fighters Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120944</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/the_walking_deads_negan_and_maggie_join_brawlhalla_as_playable_fighters_next_week"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joining Rick, Daryl and Michonne.
New fighters just keep on coming in Brawlhalla, with two new characters from The Walking Dead set to appear next week.
Both Negan and Maggie will be added to the game on 22nd September as 'Epic Crossovers'; their arrival kicks off new in-game celebrations that will also see the Walker Attack Game Mode featured as the Brawl of the Week.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Finally Adds Bluetooth Audio To The Switch]]></title>
        <id>1847678157</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-finally-adds-bluetooth-audio-to-the-switch-1847678157"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the Nintendo Switch went on sale in March 2017, it did mysteriously not have Bluetooth audio support. Nor was it added despite years of complaining by owners. Now, thanks to Nintendo’s latest update, it finally does. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Seamless Update: aktualizace UEFI bez restartu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42819</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/intel-seamless-update-aktualizace-uefi-bez-restartu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Intel připravuje do Linuxu zajímavou inovaci pro své platformy. První patche už do jádra zamířily a až se vše podaří dotáhnout do konce, bude možné na strojích Intel aktualizovat firmwary (zejména UEFI) bez nutnosti restartu stroje. Vše proběhne v rámci aktuálního běhu operačního systému.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gitlab CI: automatizujte přímo v Gitlabu (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-38836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gitlab-ci-automatizujte-primo-v-gitlabu-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T06:39:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automatizace pomocí continuous integration přímo v Gitlabu. CI vám pomůže automatizovat rutinní procesy a ušetří vám hromadu času. Pomůže vám od automatického testování, buildy po nasazování. Chcete vědět víc? Přijďte na naše školení, které se uskuteční 29. září a proběhne plně online. Školí Ondřej Sika.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Java 17 a OpenJDK 17 s hotovým Maturing Vector API a plánovaným koncem Applet API]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42818</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/java-17-a-openjdk-17-s-hotovym-maturing-vector-api-a-planovanym-koncem-applet-api/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová hlavní verze Javy, resp. číselně stejná verze balíku OpenJDK. Sedmnáctka přináší několik novinek, například novou renderovací pipeline pro macOS (používá API Metal, OpenGL končí), podporu portu pro Apple M1, vylepšené pseudo-náhodné generátory čísel, označení Java Applet API za zastralé (naplánováno je odstranění), podpory sealed classes, odstranění experimentální kompilace ahead-of-time (AOT) a just-in-time (JIT), o další krok posunutých prací na Java Vector API či práce na context-specific deserializačních filtrech.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daemon X Machina Is Probably Getting A Sequel, But It's Going To "Take Time"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120942</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/daemon_x_machina_is_probably_getting_a_sequel_but_its_going_to_take_time"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T03:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The development team is motivated to make it happen.
Daemon X Machina is currently celebrating its second anniversary. As part of this, Nintendo has also released a Switch Online trial. That's not all, though...
During a special anniversary live stream, the game's producer, Kenichiro Tsukuda, stated how his team would eventually make a second entry. The only catch is it might take a while before it's actually released. Here's a translation, courtesy of Nintendo Everything:
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Desktopové prostředí Budgie bude přepsáno z GTK do EFL]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/desktopove-prostredi-budgie-bude-prepsano-z-gtk-do-efl</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/desktopove-prostredi-budgie-bude-prepsano-z-gtk-do-efl"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T02:52:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Desktopové prostředí Budgie vyvíjené v rámci linuxové distribuce Solus bude přepsáno z GTK do EFL. Joshua Strobl rozepsal důvody v příspěvku na svém blogu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zynga's New Free-To-Play Star Wars Game Has Been Delayed To 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120941</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/zyngas_new_free-to-play_star_wars_game_has_been_delayed_to_2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T02:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Confirmed alongside a new cinematic trailer.

Following on from the delay of LEGO Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga, Zynga's new "free-to-download" title Star Wars: Hunters has now also been delayed until 2022.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bespoke Synth 1.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bespoke-synth-1.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/bespoke-synth-1.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T02:11:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Challinor vydal po deseti letech vývoje verzi 1.0.0 svého open source modulárního syntezátoru Bespoke. Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitHubu pod licenci GPLv3 [Hacker News].]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Has "No Plans" For A Switch Price Drop In America]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120940</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/nintendo_has_no_plans_for_a_switch_price_drop_in_america"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T01:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The trade price adjustment is for Europe only.
Earlier this week, Nintendo announced it would be reducing the price of the base model Switch to £259/€269 across Europe, ahead of the OLED model launch on October 8th.
If you happen to be located in the US and were hoping for something similar, it seems this won't be happening. Axios Gaming newsletter co-author, Stephen Totilo, has been in contact with Nintendo of America, and has been informed there'll be no price changes happening in this market.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch System Update 13.0.0 Is Live, Adds Bluetooth Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120939</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/nintendo_switch_system_update_13_0_0_is_live_adds_bluetooth_audio"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T00:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And a Switch OLED dock update.

The new Switch OLED model arrives next month and ahead of its release Nintendo has rolled out a sizable update - bumping the system firmware all the way up to version 13.0.0.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sega Releases Its First Patch For Sonic Colors Ultimate On Nintendo Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120937</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/sega_releases_its_first_patch_for_sonic_colors_ultimate_on_nintendo_switch"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T23:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And more are on the way.
When Sonic Colors Ultimate arrived on the Nintendo Switch a few weeks ago some players began encountering all sorts of issues. We had a look ourselves and were also able to replicate these issues by following certain steps.
Although there were problems present in other versions of the game, the Switch release was evidently in the worst state. Digital Foundry even recommended waiting for an update if you picked up this version. The good news is Sega and Blind Squirrel Games appear to have listened to fan feedback and have now rolled out a patch.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how to remove Deathloop's intro logos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-to-remove-deathloops-intro-logos</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-to-remove-deathloops-intro-logos"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:46:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If there's one thing I hate in this life, it's having to lift my hand onto the Esc key so I can press it to skip logos. Ideally I only lift my arms to deliver food to my maw, or to express my lack of care. So it's nice that someone has already identified which files to delete to remove the logos at the start of Arkane's new shooter Deathloop.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bonfire Peaks Has A New Demo And A Release Date]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120936</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/bonfire_peaks_has_a_new_demo_and_a_release_date"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yeaaaah, this box is on fire.
Good news for fans of fiendish puzzlers: Bonfire Peaks, made by Corey Martin and Alan Hazelden's boutique company, Draknek & Friends, is almost here!
With a brand-new release date of the 30th of September, you'll be able to play this box-burning brain-twister before the leaves start to turn. Which is perfect, actually, because Bonfire Peaks is big Autumn vibes, with its warm colour palette, cosy fires, and voxels chunkier than your favourite sweater.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellaris 3.1 is out and adds new content to old DLC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellaris-31-is-out-and-adds-new-content-to-old-dlc-alongside-many-balance-tweaks</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/stellaris-31-is-out-and-adds-new-content-to-old-dlc-alongside-many-balance-tweaks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scifi grand strategy Stellaris's free 3.1 update, titled "Lem", is out now. This is the first update created by "The Custodians", a new team formed within developers PDS Green focused on free, quarterly updates which tweak game balance, add new content to old DLC and fix bugs.

The "Lem" update does all three, changing how tradition trees work, adding new features to old species packs such as 2016's Planetoids, and rebalancing some Civics and Origins.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Faire Prague 2021 obrazem: setkání bastlířů, vynálezců a inovátorů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15664</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/maker-faire-prague-2021-obrazem-setkani-bastliru-vynalezcu-a-inovatoru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Největší setkání bastlířů, vynálezců a inovátorů v Česku se konalo v Průmyslovém paláci pražského Výstaviště. Představilo 150 makerských expozic, workshopů a přednášek, včetně zahraničních hostů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (15. 9. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15663</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-15-9-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sonda do světa otevřeného softwaru. Dnes si řekneme o svobodné alternativě k Discordu, vyzkoušíme si aplikaci pro ovládání ITUSB1 USB Test Switch, dáme si dohromady knihovnu obrázků a stáhneme si do počítače instalační balíčky pro Android.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 už nezkompilujete s GCC 4.9 a starším]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42817</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-5-15-uz-nezkompilujete-s-gcc-4-9-a-starsim/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jedna z posledních změn v rámci vývoje příští verze jádra Linux 5.15 povyšuje minimální verzi GCC pro kompilaci. Až dosud stačilo GCC 4.9, nyní bude pro sestavení jádra potřeba minimálně GCC 5.1. Jde současně o verzi, která je už delší dobu potřebná pro build na architektuře Aarch64 (64bit ARM).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Even Beefy Rigs Aren't Saving Deathloop From PC Issues]]></title>
        <id>1847676264</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/even-beefy-rigs-arent-saving-deathloop-from-pc-issues-1847676264"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop is, by all accounts, a damn good game. That said, its reception on Steam is sitting shakily in “Mixed” territory due to the various performance-related issues currently plaguing PC players.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WD's SN850 1TB SSD is down to £145 with a free heatsink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-sn850-1tb-ssd-is-down-to-145-with-a-free-heatsink</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wds-sn850-1tb-ssd-is-down-to-145-with-a-free-heatsink"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WD Black SN850 is a tremendously fast PCIe 4.0 SSD, capable of hitting some outrageous speeds - up to 7000MB/s reads and 5300MB/s writes. That makes it a great choice for any PC that can handle it (as well as the PS5, which gets external SSD support tomorrow). It's been discounted on Scan to £145 today, where you'll also get a free Akasa NVMe heatsink in the bargain. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The World Seems Ready For A Nintendo Switch Price Cut]]></title>
        <id>1847676245</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-world-seems-ready-for-a-nintendo-switch-price-cut-1847676245"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nintendo Switch has received its first price cut in certain parts of the world, dropping from £330 in Europe and £280 in the UK down to £270 and £260, respectively. But while fans hoped the same could happen in the U.S., especially with sites like VGC insisting a cut is coming, Nintendo says such a thing is…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Rock Galactic now has official mod support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-now-has-official-mod-support-and-a-mod-that-gives-spiders-beards</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deep-rock-galactic-now-has-official-mod-support-and-a-mod-that-gives-spiders-beards"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:14:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mods are amazing and can never get enough love, so I'm glad to see that co-operative cave-diving FPS Deep Rock Galactic now has official mod support. It includes mod.io integration for browsing and installing mods, an in-game mod manager, and clearer communication for players joining modded servers, among a lot of other changes.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The top-rated Dell S2721DGFA Fast IPS monitor is 20% off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-top-rated-dell-s2721dgfa-fast-ips-monitor-is-20-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-top-rated-dell-s2721dgfa-fast-ips-monitor-is-20-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dell's S2721DGFA has had a storied history, starting out as a critically acclaimed 27-in gaming monitor that no one could actually buy, to slowly becoming available over the months and finally now to being a great value option in the wake of several big price cuts. 
Today, the S2721DGFA has hit a historic low thanks to a code at the Dell UK site: using the phrase DAE40S at the checkout will knock the price from its usual £329 to just £265.94, a £63 savings and more than £100 cheaper than the same monitor at Amazon. That's an incredible price for one of the best gaming monitors on the planet. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Go Gets 'Form Changes' For Fashion Week]]></title>
        <id>1847675986</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-go-gets-form-changes-for-fashion-week-1847675986"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You probably know that fashion week happens eight times per year, twice annually in Paris, Milan, London, and New York. But soon, the so-called “Big Four” will face some serious competition for the limelight when Pokémon Go kicks off its own fashion week event next Tuesday.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy's Humble Burger Farm Is A First-Person Horror That Would Make Gordon Ramsay Barf]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120935</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/happys_humble_burger_farm_is_a_first-person_horror_that_would_make_gordon_ramsay_barf"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is this a stealth campaign for veganism?
Hey, remember that Make-A-Wish nightmare burger restaurant that a kid made in Minecraft? If not, that sentence probably seems pretty wild, but the point is that Happy's Humble Burger Farm is that nightmare burger restaurant made reality. Or virtual reality, at least, because it's a video game.

Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funcom acquires the Conan and Mutant Year Zero IP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/funcom-acquires-the-conan-and-mutant-year-zero-ip</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/funcom-acquires-the-conan-and-mutant-year-zero-ip"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:46:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Funcom have acquired the Cabinet Group, the company which owns the intellectual properties Conan The Barbarian and Mutant Year Zero. Funcom have already developed several Conan games by licensing the IP, including the MMO Age Of Conan and more recently the survival game Conan Exiles. 

The announcement also mentioned that a new game is currently in development which will star Conan and "many of the characters in the Robert E. Howard universe."

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workers Accuse Activision Blizzard Of Union Busting]]></title>
        <id>1847675870</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/workers-accuse-activision-blizzard-of-union-busting-1847675870"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard employees represented by the ABetterABK worker group filed a lawsuit against the Call of Duty publisher with the National Labor Review Board yesterday accusing it of union busting. It comes in the wake of a bombshell California lawsuit alleging widespread sexual harassment and discrimination at the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Lands Big Batch Of Improvements To Lower CPU Overhead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-RadeonSI-Lower-CPU</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-RadeonSI-Lower-CPU"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following portions of the merge request landing, the rest of the RadeonSI CPU-overhead-lowering work was just merged to Mesa 21.3...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nobody Wants A Driver TV Show, Ubisoft]]></title>
        <id>1847675656</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nobody-wants-a-driver-tv-show-ubisoft-1847675656"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubisoft plans to revive the Driver franchise, the company announced today...with a live-action streaming series. Those sounds you just heard were millions of excited fans collectively scooting forward in their seats and then immediately slumping back in disappointment.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Just Read 1,025 Chapters Of One Piece, And It's A Damn Masterpiece]]></title>
        <id>1847671952</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/i-just-read-1-025-chapters-of-one-piece-and-its-a-damn-1847671952"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only three things in life are certain for a shonen otaku: tournament arcs, Studio Trigger series finales ending in space, and One Piece continuing until the heat death of the universe. I’d made prior attempts to read One Piece, but each time I got too intimidated by its length, which has now surpassed 1,000 chapters.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077's 1.31 update is small but has substantial fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-131-update-is-small-but-has-substantial-fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cyberpunk-2077s-131-update-is-small-but-has-substantial-fixes"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Cyberpunk 2077 patch is small, but the bugs it fixes aren't. 1.31 addresses issues that only affected some users, but they include issues that would halt progress on critical quests if they happened. The patch is live now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory Pak: If Crashing In Burnout Is Wrong, Then I Don’t Want To Be Right]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120914</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/memory_pak_if_crashing_in_burnout_is_wrong_then_i_donrt_want_to_be_right"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Car carnage.
Happy birthday, GameCube! It's been twenty years since your gorgeous, chunky indigo shape graced our TV stands, and we were all introduced to that beedle-deedle-deedle-deedle-beedle-deedle-beedly-beep, BLUMP. You know the one I mean.
The GameCube's catalogue is so stellar that I've already written several features about its games, from my favourite game, Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door, to the grim realities of Harvest Moon: A Wonderful Life. But there are still so many other games to talk about! Luigi's Mansion! Super Mario Sunshine! The Legend of Zelda: Wind Waker!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kali Linux 2021.3. NetHunter pro chytré hodinky TicWatch Pro]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/kali-linux-2021.3.-nethunter-pro-chytre-hodinky-ticwatch-pro</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/kali-linux-2021.3.-nethunter-pro-chytre-hodinky-ticwatch-pro"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T19:52:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 2021.3 průběžně aktualizované linuxové distribuce navržené pro digitální forenzní analýzu a penetrační testování Kali Linux (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek i s náhledy a seznamem nových nástrojů v oficiálním oznámení. Kali NetHunter běží nově také na chytrých hodinkách TicWatch Pro.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Java 17 / JDK 17 LTS]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/java-17-jdk-17-lts</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/java-17-jdk-17-lts"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T19:17:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána Java 17 / JDK 17. Nových vlastností (JEP - JDK Enhancement Proposal) je 14. Nová Java / JDK vychází každých 6 měsíců. Java 17 / JDK 17 je LTS verze. Předchozí LTS verze je verze 11. Porovnání verze 17 s verzí 11.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[oneAPI Level Zero Loader v1.5 Released With VPU Driver Recognition, Multi-Driver Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=oneAPI-Level-Zero-Loader-1.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=oneAPI-Level-Zero-Loader-1.5"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T18:22:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel has released a new version of their loader for oneAPI Level Zero for loading the Level Zero software driver components...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Games Are You Looking Forward To Playing On Switch OLED?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120841</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/talking_point_what_games_are_you_looking_forward_to_playing_on_switch_oled"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[14 games we're dying to (re)play.
It's an odd phenomenon when new hardware comes along which makes you delve into your back catalogue for gems you might have missed, or perhaps just revisit classic titles to see how they look and perform on your shiny new system. It's something that PS5 and Xbox Series X gamers have encountered over the last year, with a slim selection of brand new, bespoke titles prompting players to revisit their existing library on the new consoles and see how the classics look on the new machine.

Nintendo Switch OLED Model - Price, Release Date, Specs, Battery Life And Where It Leaves 'Switch Pro'

While Switch OLED might not have any performance benefits over its normal LCD-screened siblings, we're still itching to replay our favourite games on the new console and see how they look on that gorgeous new screen — to enjoy the richer, deeper blacks and popping colours the new screen will offer. Some of us are, in fact, putting off collecting Korok seeds or starting something new from our back catalogue just so we get to play on the new Switch when it finally arrives.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Java 17 / OpenJDK 17 Hits GA With Maturing Vector API, Removal Planned For Applet API]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenJDK-17-Java-17</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenJDK-17-Java-17"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:48:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Java 17 has made it to general availability status today with a number of improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Boy’s Here, So Let’s Get Real]]></title>
        <id>1847673845</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/your-boy-s-here-so-let-s-get-real-1847673845"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What’s up, Kotaku? I’m Jeremy Winslow, your second Black staff writer, and while I hustled for this spot and know that I earned it through years of hard work and dedication, part of me still can’t believe I actually made it here.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random: Xbox's Phil Spencer Reveals His Favourite GameCube Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120930</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/random_xboxs_phil_spencer_reveals_his_favourite_gamecube_game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an insane world, it was the sanest choice.
As you may have noticed, today marks 20 years since the Nintendo GameCube launched in Japan and we (along with the rest of the internet) have been getting all nostalgic for Nintendo's purple box.
As is customary on these significant anniversaries (or any anniversary when it comes to social media — gotta mark those 17th and 36th birthdays, too), the Twitterverse and Facebookverse and other variously dystopian ‘verses have been quite rightly celebrating, with Gamecube trending in gamers' thoughts in a way Nintendo wishes it might have two decades back.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hopes for God Of War on PC stoked by leaked Nvidia list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hopes-for-god-of-war-on-pc-stoked-by-leaked-nvidia-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hopes-for-god-of-war-on-pc-stoked-by-leaked-nvidia-list"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:25:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since Sony began releasing PlayStation-exclusive games on PC too, many have been clamouring for more of the big'uns: God Of War, Spider-Man, chuffing Bloodborne for god's sake please Bloodborne. While Sony are still being coy about which games are coming our way, hopes were raised by a recent leaked list of games pulled from the digital guts of GeForce Now, which included a mention of God Of War for Steam. I wouldn't get too excited just yet. While Nvidia have confirmed the list itself was real, they say some games on the list were "speculative".
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Splitgate’s Getting Bigger And Better, Thanks To A Cool $100M]]></title>
        <id>1847673704</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/splitgate-s-getting-bigger-and-better-thanks-to-a-cool-1847673704"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developer 1047 Games has raised $100 million from a bunch of venture capital investors, the studio announced via press release today. The eye-popping fundraising haul will allow the outfit to remain independent and beef up work on its enormously popular free-to-play arena shooter, Splitgate.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SpiderHeck Is A Chaotic Brawler With Lightsabers And Guns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120863</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/spiderheck_is_a_chaotic_brawler_with_lightsabers_and_guns"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have the high ground, Arachnid.
The Switch eShop isn't short of chaotic multiplayer games, but there's always room for one more. Especially when it features nimble spiders fighting with lightsabers - or 'laser swords' as the developer is legally obliged to call them - and guns.
SpiderHeck is from solo developer Neverjam (Uvis Zviedris), and it's been picked up for publishing by TinyBuild and confirmed for an assortment of systems - including the Switch. It's heading into a Steam playtest today, so hopefully it's not too far away, though naturally there'll be time taken to work on player feedback, develop ports and so on.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ren And Stimpy Are Coming To The Nick Fighting Game As A Duo]]></title>
        <id>1847673337</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/ren-and-stimpy-are-coming-to-the-nick-fighting-game-as-1847673337"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hailing from the darkly humorous animated show, Ren and Stimpy are the newest additions to the Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl roster, developer Ludosity announced on Tuesday.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Patch Makes Its Roads Wet Again]]></title>
        <id>1847673046</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-patch-makes-its-roads-wet-again-1847673046"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T16:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a minute there, Cyberpunk 2077 wasn’t wet enough. Today, it is, thanks to an update that restores missing water effects in the troubled open-world shooter.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Where To Pre-Order Pokémon Legends: Arceus On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-111995</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/where-to-pre-order-pokemon-legends-arceus-on-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: My Nintendo Store UK pre-orders are live, with bonuses.
Update (Tue 14th Sep, 2021 17:15 BST): The UK My Nintendo Store now has Pokémon Legends: Arceus pre-orders up for grabs. Purchasing from Nintendo's official store will net you a free SteelBook and an Arceus figurine, too:

Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Cruis'n Blast - An Arcade Racing Icon Returns In Spectacular Fashion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120828</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/cruisn_blast"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Blast from the past.
Long-time Nintendo fans will know that the Cruis’n series has an interesting history with the company. The original arcade version of the first game, Cruis’n USA, was said to be the first title running on Nintendo's upcoming Ultra 64 hardware, a claim which ultimately turned out to be a bit of a porky pie.
Its subsequent Nintendo 64 port was generally criticised (a bit unfairly) for not really being up to scratch, but that wasn’t enough to stop sequels Cruis’n World and Cruis’n Exotica making their way to the N64, followed by a GBA spin-off, before the series was quietly mothballed (we don’t talk about Cruis’n on the Wii). Cruis’n Blast is an attempt to resurrect the series, and we’re absolutely delighted that attempt has been made because it's successful in a way we could never have dreamt would be possible.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weekspot podcast #053: in the loop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-053-deathloop</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-053-deathloop"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, we all know the game has a very cool look, and all of us enjoy playing a good time loop game, but what actually is Deathloop? Thankfully, Matthew's played the first few hours and is here to enlighten both you and I.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to install an SSD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-an-ssd</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-an-ssd"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:52:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the RPS guide on how to install an SSD, which you’ll note is not titled “How to install an SSD or hard drive”. Yes yes, old-timey mechanical drives are cheaper, and better if you need terrabytes upon terabytes of space, but when you can buy a good-quality NVMe SSD like the WD Blue SN550 at £70 for 1TB…I mean, you should probably do that instead.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl Adds Ren & Stimpy To Roster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120876</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/nickelodeon_all-star_brawl_adds_ren_and_stimpy_to_roster"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy happy! Joy joy!
Update:
As promised new characters for the Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl roster have been confirmed, and it's Ren & Stimpy! You can check out some footage and screens below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon 25: The Album Gets A Release Date, Includes 14 Tracks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120919</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pokemon_25_the_album_gets_a_release_date_includes_14_tracks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-order and get 6 tracks now.
The Pokémon Company has been rather busy promoting the franchises' 25th Anniversary, and one of the biggest projects has definitely been Pokémon 25: The Album. With multiple videos featuring major artists (including Katy Perry with 'Electric', above) and EP releases, there's been a steady flow of new music. Now the full release - Pokémon 25: The Album - has a release date; it arrives on 15th October.
The digital version is definitely being pushed, with that version getting four exclusive tracks to take the total to 14. You can see the full list below.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Met Gala 2021 outfits remind me of video game heroes and villains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/met-gala-2021-outfits-remind-me-of-video-game-heroes-and-villains</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/met-gala-2021-outfits-remind-me-of-video-game-heroes-and-villains"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:21:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual Met Gala event took place last night as some of the world's most famous people gathered to celebrate fashion. This year's theme was "In America: A Lexicon of Fashion", which is wildly inaccurate since most of the attendees decided to dress as video game heroes and villains. Fashion brands like Balenciaga and Versace designed outfits that wouldn't be out of place on a JRPG antagonist or in a Platinum game. Let's look at which celebrities decided to take the Paragon route and dress as a hero and who decided to go full Renegade, dressing as a video game boss.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Pass Is Really Blowing Up In September]]></title>
        <id>1847672280</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/game-pass-is-really-blowing-up-in-september-1847672280"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a cynical, bitter, battle-worn games critic, I would like nothing better than to declare what a disastrous mess Microsoft is making of Game Pass. But damn them, they’re not, and the line-up of new additions coming in the second half of September is pleasingly strong. Another 13 games are getting added by October…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last Soul Is An Upcoming Action Platformer With A Heroic Robot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120902</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/last_soul_is_an_upcoming_action_platformer_with_a_heroic_robot"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out in Q2 2022, will have a Kickstarter for "pre-orders and early fan bonuses".
For every game that sets out its stall as an action platformer with pixel-based visuals there's the challenge of trying to stand out from the crowd. Another that'll aim to do that next year (Q2) is Last Soul, the work of Canadian studio WULUM with publishing by Bonus Stage.
It actually has an imminent Kickstarter campaign (which the video above is also teasing) but the latest press release highlights the publishing deal, confirms the game for Switch and various platforms while pitching the crowdfunding as primarily being for 'pre-orders and early fan bonuses'.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opus: Echo Of Starsong: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847672103</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/opus-echo-of-starsong-the-kotaku-review-1847672103"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While most science fiction games ask me what it means to be human, Opus: Echo of Starsong asked me: “Is it enough to be human?” This philosophical space opera is a staggeringly emotional game that deserves a spot among indie narrative greats such as Transistor and What Remains of Edith Finch. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Otevřený telefon Librem 5 zdraží na 1199 USD]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42816</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/otevreny-telefon-librem-5-zdrazi-na-1199-usd/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:48:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nová cenovka telefonu Librem 5 bude od listopadu tohoto roku 1199 dolarů. Telefon přitom v rámci kampaně šlo v roce 2017 předplatit za 599 dolarů, tedy poloviční částku. Dnes ještě stojí 899 dolarů, plus existuje verze vyráběná v USA s cenovkou 1999 dolarů. Hlavním důvodem dalšího výrazného růstu ceny je samozřejmě situace na trhu s komponentami a materiály.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The PS5 Is Getting A Major Update]]></title>
        <id>1847671904</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-ps5-is-getting-a-major-update-1847671904"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PS5 is getting a slew of new features in a massive software update set to go live around the world on September 15, Sony announced in a PlayStation blog post today.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic Colours Ultimate Physical Editions Delayed In Europe, Look Set For October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-119929</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/sonic_colours_ultimate_physical_editions_delayed_in_europe_look_set_for_october"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Amazon Spain sets a new target.
Update (14th September):
A member of the Nintendo Life team received an order update from Amazon in Spain, stating that it will be delivered on 11th October or later, so there's still quite a wait in that case.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dying Light 2 Delayed To 2022]]></title>
        <id>1847671839</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/dying-light-2-delayed-to-2022-1847671839"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dying Light 2: Stay Human, the first-person zombie parkour game slated for a December 7 release, has been delayed, developer Techland announced in a tweet today. It’ll now come out on February 4, 2022, for Xbox, PlayStation, and PC, contributing to what’s shaping up to be the most stacked release month of all time,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 reveals Grand Cathay's army, created for the game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-reveals-grand-cathays-army-created-for-the-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-reveals-grand-cathays-army-created-for-the-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The mysterious army of Grand Cathay have finally been revealed for Total War: Warhammer 3, wearing their Chinese influences plainly. Grand Cathay have existed in the world of Warhammer (Warlore? Lorehammer?) for almost 30 years but not fielded a full plastic army, so one had to be created for Creative Assembly's fantasy strategy game. Led by dragons in human form, they field forces including Jade Warriors, towering Terracotta Sentinels, and the Celestial Dragon Guard. Come meet 'em in the new trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardware Classics: Nintendo GameCube]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-90886</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/hardware_classics_nintendo_gamecube"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Indigo, Spice and all things nice.
In celebration of the GameCube's 20th birthday, we're republishing this look back at Nintendo’s little box of tricks...
In many ways, the GameCube was a console out of time, arguably arriving too late (or perhaps too early) to realise its true potential. We can look back now and appreciate its quirks, admire its design and excellent software library, and lust after the variants that never made it to western shores, but in the early 2000s it was a big, defiantly colourful block with a chunky handle at a time when sleek multimedia units were all the rage. It was a square peg in the round hole, an embarrassingly sore thumb that stood out against the laser-targeted ‘cool’ of the competition. It’s not by accident that the decade-long period straddling the millennium is looked back on as the ‘PlayStation generation’.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dying Light 2 delayed again, shambling into February 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-2-delayed-again-shambling-into-february-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dying-light-2-delayed-again-shambling-into-february-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:17:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parkour enthusiasts will need to wait two months longer to prance around an open-world city full of zombies (and zombies-to-be), because Dying Light 2 has been delayed again. Previously due December 7th, and spring 2020 before that, Dying Light 2 is now scheduled to launch on February 4th, 2022. The developers, Techland say they need extra time to make it good, yeah?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Come and gawp at Clash: Artifacts Of Chaos' gorgeous, sketchy planet in this new dev diary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-and-gawp-at-clash-artifacts-of-chaos-gorgeous-sketchy-planet-in-this-new-dev-diary</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/come-and-gawp-at-clash-artifacts-of-chaos-gorgeous-sketchy-planet-in-this-new-dev-diary"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first-person brawler Zeno Clash games have been long-time favourites here at RPS, and when Chilean developers ACE Team announced they were making a new game set in their weird and wonderful Clash universe back in July, we were over the moon. Admittedly, Clash: Artifact Of Chaos' reveal trailer left a lot of unanswered questions at the time, but the good news is that we've got an early sneak peak at a new developer diary that tells us all about the game's story and what to expect when it eventually releases next year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop slabs and abilities: how to obtain and fully upgrade all paranormal powers in Deathloop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-slabs-abilities</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-slabs-abilities"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:14:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to collect and fully upgrade all the slabs in Deathloop? Slab abilities are the paranormal powers in Deathloop, the game's take on Dishonored's Void Powers and Prey's Neuromods. When playing as Colt or Julianna there are five of these slabs to pick up, as well as several levels of upgrades for each.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA RTX 30 Series Resizable BAR Support Continues Helping Performance On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30523</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30523"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:09:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While NVIDIA has been supporting Resizable BAR for a while now with their GeForce RTX 30 series graphics cards, for those exclusively using Linux it remains more of a challenge due to AIB partners generally not releasing any vBIOS updates for ReBAR support that can be easily applied under Linux. But if you do carry out an update -- such as under Windows -- the performance uplift can be worthwhile if using a game that can benefit from the support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastward review: a stunning, but slow burning post-apocalypse adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/eastward-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/eastward-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling flying pigs, saving a nerdy kid from the school bullies, cooking up exquisite dishes to appease a local casino boss whose slot machines you accidentally rinsed with your trusted lucky coin... These are the stories most adventure RPGs would stuff into their ever-growing sidequest menus - distractions meant to provide extra flavour to the world you're meant to be saving, or which hold bountiful supplies of EXP to level up your skills and weapons. Not so in Eastward.
In this impressive debut from Shanghai developers Pixpil, these humdrum slices of life are placed front and centre, forming much of the narrative backbone that drives the game forward. This is still a game that's ultimately about saving the world from a mysterious and all-consuming miasma, but it's also one that makes damn sure you know what you're doing it all for - and that's its striking cast of NPCs. As you busy yourself with the minutiae of their everyday lives, Eastward makes every person (and robot) count in this deadly post-apocalypse, and the result is an affecting, detail-rich tale that owes as much to the action of top-down Zelda games as it does to the role-playing intimacy of Earthbound. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attack On Titan Gets Freaky-Looking Trash And Recycling Bins]]></title>
        <id>1847671052</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/attack-on-titan-gets-freaky-looking-trash-and-recycling-1847671052"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T11:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Attack on Titan, the human-eating Titans are horrifying and freaky. So naturally, when official Titan trash and recycling bins were introduced in Japan, they also look unsettling—even more so when placed next to Coca-Cola vending machines. 
As part of an effort to promote recycling and good urban sanitation,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2 remaster cutscenes look like how I remember the originals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-remaster-cutscenes-look-like-how-i-remember-the-originals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-remaster-cutscenes-look-like-how-i-remember-the-originals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T11:19:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I appreciate when a remaster of an old game looks like my memories of the original, a rose-tinted vision which would crumble if I looked at even one screenshot. Blizzard and Vicarious Visions have managed that with Diablo 2: Resurrected, from what I've seen, and a new trailer focuses on the redone cutscenes. And yeah, this is how I remember D2 cutscenes looking? They were dead fancy and high-tech, yeah? Must have looked like this?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World's open beta hasn't convinced me to drop Final Fantasy XIV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-open-beta-hasnt-convinced-me-to-drop-final-fantasy-xiv</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-worlds-open-beta-hasnt-convinced-me-to-drop-final-fantasy-xiv"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The last time I got some brief hands-on time with Amazon's upcoming MMO New World, I emerged from Aeternum feeling pretty positive about this new kid on the massively multiplayer block. Crafting, in particular, had me pretty excited. But having spent a big chunk of time in its open beta, I've come away feeling a bit, I don't know, bleh? If anything, I just wanted to go back to my beloved Final Fantasy XIV.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Organizace IETF schválila nový internetový standard, spoluautorem je Ladislav Lhotka z CZ.NIC]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42815</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/organizace-ietf-schvalila-novy-internetovy-standard-spoluautorem-je-ladislav-lhotka-z-cz-nic/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:43:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ladislav Lhotka, vedoucí Laboratoří CZ.NIC, je spoluautorem nového internetového standardu (RFC 9108), který v září vydala organizace IETF. Toto RFC převádí dva IANA registry do podoby vhodné pro datové modelování v jazyku YANG. Jde o dva důležité parametry služby DNS – třídy a typy zdrojových záznamů (resource records).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links 2.24]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/links-2.24</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/links-2.24"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:42:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze 2.24 svobodného webového prohlížeče pracujícího v grafickém i textovém módu Links (Wikipedie). Přehled novinek v seznamu změn. Řešeny jsou chyby v X, na OS/2 i Minix 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keisuke Honda Played Himself In Pro Evo And Wasn't Happy]]></title>
        <id>1847670873</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/keisuke-honda-played-himself-in-pro-evo-and-wasnt-happy-1847670873"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a tale as old as time—or at least as old as sports games. Athlete plays the in-game version of themselves and is sorely disappointed by what they see. Keisuke Honda, you are not alone!
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Používáme OpenCV na Fedoře]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/pouzivame-opencv-na-fedore</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/pouzivame-opencv-na-fedore"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:22:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na MojeFedora.cz vyšel zatím dvoudílný článek Používáme OpenCV na Fedoře (část 2) věnovaný použití knihovny OpenCV (Open Source Computer Vision Library) pro počítačové vidění na Linuxu, konkrétně na Fedoře a v Pythonu. Jedná se o lehce upravený překlad anglického originálu z Fedora Magazine.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends will keep tap-strafing, at least for now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-will-keep-tap-strafing-at-least-for-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-will-keep-tap-strafing-at-least-for-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:11:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago, Respawn Entertainment said they were going to get rid of tap-strafing in Apex Legends, but now it seems they've changed their minds. Tap-strafing is a movement exploit that allows players to keep their momentum after slide-jumping, letting them make speedier turns than they should. Unfortunately for Respawn, they say getting rid of this tech has some "unexpected side effects", so tap-strafing gets to stay in the game, for now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Radeon Software update simplifies overclocking, brings Smart Access Memory to older GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-software-update-simplifies-overclocking-brings-smart-access-memory-to-older-gpus</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/amd-radeon-software-update-simplifies-overclocking-brings-smart-access-memory-to-older-gpus"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:05:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD have launched a big update for their Radeon Software app and Adrenalin drivers, unlocking a clutch of potentially frame rate-boosting features for those with recent AMD graphics cards and CPUs. The new version, 21.9.1, also includes a Windows 11 driver that gets Radeon Boost, Radeon Anti-Lag and Radeon Image Sharpening ready for Microsoft’s next big OS launch.



In the meantime, those with both a Ryzen 5000 series CPU and a Radeon RX 6000 series graphics card – those lucky enough to have found one in stock, I should say –  can take advantage of Radeon Software 21.9.1’s updated overclocking feature. In previous versions, it was possible to instantly overclock your graphics card with a single click; now you can do the same with both the GPU and CPU at once. Provided they’re from these specific product lines, mind.
 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Seamless Update: Intel Preparing For System Firmware Updates Without The Reboot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Seamless-Update</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Seamless-Update"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T10:05:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Intel Seamless Update" is a forthcoming feature for Intel platforms seemingly first being exposed by their new Linux kernel patches working on the functionality... Intel is working on being able to carry out system firmware upates such as UEFI updates but doing so at run-time and being able to avoid the reboot in the process...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neočekávané vydání Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS řeší revokaci klíčů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42814</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/neocekavane-vydani-ubuntu-18-04-6-lts-resi-revokaci-klicu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:59:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S dalším vydáním v rámci LTS řady 18.04 se už po loňské verzi 18.04.5 nepočítalo, nicméně revokace klíčů si vyžaduje vydání aktualizovaných instalačních obrazů této stále podporované LTS verze Ubuntu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Debugger aneb GDB 11.1]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/gnu-debugger-aneb-gdb-11.1</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/gnu-debugger-aneb-gdb-11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:56:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Debugger aneb GDB byl vydán ve verzi 11.1. Podrobný přehled novinek v souboru NEWS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop is out now, but some PC players report stuttering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-is-out-now-but-some-pc-players-report-stuttering</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-is-out-now-but-some-pc-players-report-stuttering"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dishonored and Prey devs Arkane have released their latest superpowered sneak-o-shooter, the time-looping Deathloop. It's good, everyone tells me. However, one word of warning: a fair number of PC players are complaining about stuttering framerates, enough to bring it down to a 'Mixed' review rating on Steam. That's the sort of wonky time you don't want. If you want your initial loop o' death to be as slick as blood, maybe wait a bit in the hope of a fix?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Libinput 1.19 Released With Hold Gestures & High Resolution Wheel Scrolling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=libinput-1.19</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=libinput-1.19"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:42:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Libinput 1.19 is now available as the newest version of this Linux input handling library commonly used these days by both X.Org and Wayland desktops...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nintendo GameCube Turns Twenty Today]]></title>
        <id>1847670755</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-nintendo-gamecube-is-now-twenty-years-old-1847670755"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On September 14, 2001, the GameCube went on sale for the first time in Japan. Two months later, on November 18, the console was released in North America. Can you believe it’s been twenty years? 
Facing off against the PlayStation 2 and the Xbox, the GameCube was the first Nintendo console to use optical discs—though,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Raises Its GCC Compiler Version Requirement]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Raising-GCC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Raising-GCC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Linux 5.15-rc1 was released on Sunday with its many changes, landing on Monday was a late change to raise the baseline GCC version requirement for building the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web PrivacyTools pod novým jménem Privacy Guides]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/web-privacytools-pod-novym-jmenem-privacy-guides</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/web-privacytools-pod-novym-jmenem-privacy-guides"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T03:34:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Webové stránky privacytools.io, populární kompilace doporučení softwaru a poskytovatelů online služeb s ohledem na ochranu soukromí, jsou dostupné na doméně privacyguides.org pod novým jménem Privacy Guides. Příčinou změny (diskuse na Redditu) je, že původní zakladatel projektu věnoval jen málo času a na podněty rostoucí komunity reagoval pouze příležitostně, a to včetně aktualizací doporučení na webu, ale původní doménu si chtěl ponechat. Další služby jako Matrix či Mastodon budou přesunuty postupně.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fluttershy, yay!</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone Who Worked On A Game Should Be In The Credits]]></title>
        <id>1847669211</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/everyone-who-worked-on-a-game-should-be-in-the-credits-1847669211"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T01:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop is out, and by all accounts it’s pretty good! It’s a shame, then, that it’s also the reason we’re revisiting the topic of, “Video games people being weirdly shitty about who makes it into the credits and who doesn’t.”

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa Lands Option That Can Help XWayland-Based Gaming On The Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-Vulkan-WSI-No-Wait-XWay</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-Vulkan-WSI-No-Wait-XWay"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T00:48:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3 today landed a debug option that can help with the XWayland-based gaming performance around latency and for power management as well...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nike's Gundam Sneakers Look Badass]]></title>
        <id>1847669373</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nikes-gundam-sneakers-look-badass-1847669373"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These have been teased by sneaker types for months now, but over the last few days Nike has finally come out and made them official: over the next few weeks we’re getting not one but two pairs of Dunk Highs paying homage to Gundam.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Plunkett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 34-35/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Závěr letních prázdnin a začátek školního roku přinesly několik významných vydání, LibreELEC s novým Kodi, příručky Linux From Scratch nebo novou stabilní větev OpenWrt, a také aktualizace Clonezilly, Ubuntu LTS, EndeavourOS či EasyOS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Craftopia, the everything game, is on Xbox Game Pass now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/craftopia-the-everything-game-is-on-xbox-game-pass-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/craftopia-the-everything-game-is-on-xbox-game-pass-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:38:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The description under the latest trailer for Craftopia explains that its developers "combined many features we find enjoyable, such as hunting, farming, hack-and-slash, building, [and] automation" in making the game. It does not explain whether catching giraffes in Pokéball-like traps counts as "hunting", or whether blasting cows into space with a baseball bat is "hack-and-slash."

Craftopia remains every game that has ever existed, from Zelda to Factorio, just as it was last year - only now it's available via Xbox Game Pass.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wow, This Quake Clone Is Smaller Than A Word Doc]]></title>
        <id>1847668782</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/wow-this-quake-clone-is-smaller-than-a-word-doc-1847668782"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Games today are massive, taking up dozens of gigabytes. Some recent bigger games, like Call of Duty Black Ops Cold War, cracked 250GB in total. That’s too big. But a new free mini-shooter out today, Q1K3, is a blast and only needs 13KB of JavaScript. It’s also part of a contest dedicated to devs making smaller games…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl’s True Power Is In Its Fanservice]]></title>
        <id>1847668755</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/nickelodeon-all-star-brawl-s-true-power-is-in-its-fanse-1847668755"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s easy to understand why Nickelodeon All-Star Brawl made waves when it was first announced in July.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrobrighting: vraťte starému počítači původní vzhled]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15641</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/projekt-retrobrighting/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Některé z mnou napsaných článků o legendárních počítačích končily zmínkou o nutnosti vrácení jejich původního vzhledu pomocí metody zvané retrobrighting. Výsledky svého letošního snažení bych rád krátce představil.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Tauchman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Křivky v přírodě i v počítačové grafice – svět spirál]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15659</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/krivky-v-prirode-i-v-pocitacove-grafice-svet-spiral/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spirály se v různé podobě objevují na mnoha místech v přírodě, a to jak v malých škálách (ulity, popínavé rostliny), tak i na škálách odpovídajících planetám (víry v atmosféře) či dokonce celým galaxiím (spirální galaxie).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 2.6.1 přináší vylepšení ořezu a opravy chyb]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42813</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/openshot-2-6-1-prinasi-vylepseni-orezu-a-opravy-chyb/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Thomas informuje o nové verzi střižny OpenShot. Ta slouží primárně jako vydání opravující nahlášené chyby předchozí verze 2.6.0 z doby před pár týdny. Najdeme zde ale také automatickou migraci klíčových snímků u ořezu z projektů verze 2.5.1. Zpětná kompatibilita je zde 100%. Opraveny jsou také chyby v některých překladech (včetně slovenštiny) a mnoho překladů bylo vylepšeno.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 will launch in early access on October 26th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-26th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/darkest-dungeon-2-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-26th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T21:39:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2 will launch in early access via the Epic Games Store on October 26th. Developers Red Hook announced the date via Twitter earlier today, after first announcing a 2021 release date in October of last year.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch are suing two users for leading "hate raids"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-suing-two-users-for-leading-hate-raids</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/twitch-are-suing-two-users-for-leading-hate-raids"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T21:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch, the livestreaming platform, are suing two users for allegedly organising "hate raids" against streamers. According to the complaint, these users began in August 2021 to "attack these streamers by flooding their chats with bot-powered Twitch accounts that spew racist, sexist, and homophobic language and content" in violation of the Twitch terms of service.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Posts Initial Code For x86 User Interrupts On Linux  - Shows Great Performance Potential]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-RFC-x86-User-Interrupts</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-RFC-x86-User-Interrupts"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T20:38:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to the big Advanced Matrix Extensions support still being in flux and the kernel-side AMX code not yet being merged, another feature of next year's Xeon "Sapphire Rapids" that we are only now seeing in early published form for the Linux kernel is handling of x86 user interrupts...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The winner of the US Open did the best FIFA celebration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-winner-of-the-us-open-did-the-best-fifa-celebration</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-winner-of-the-us-open-did-the-best-fifa-celebration"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T20:16:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The winner of the men's US Open tennis final called me a legend yesterday during post-match interviews. Daniil Medvedev was explaining the strange celebration he did immediately after his victory. "Only legends will understand what I did after the match is 'L2 + Left'."

And I did understand. L2 + Left is the best celebration from the FIFA series.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone Made An Among Us Fighting Game Because Why Not]]></title>
        <id>1847667386</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/someone-made-an-among-us-fighting-game-because-why-not-1847667386"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T19:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve often said that anything with a cast of unique characters can be turned into a fighting game. Case in point: Among Us Arena, which takes the multi-colored crewmates of the popular Mafia-like and places them in a surprisingly fun one-on-one combat system.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FUTEX2 System Call Updated To Work On ARM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FUTEX2-v3-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FUTEX2-v3-Patches"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T18:45:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Linux 5.15 has many new features and improvements, one of the patch series we have been eager to see land is the work introducing the new FUTEX2 system call. FUTEX2 can help improve the performance of newer Windows games running on Linux via Wine / Steam Play's Proton by better matching the Windows kernel behavior, but while it didn't land for Linux 5.15, at least a new version of the patches were posted...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Samsung 980 Pro PCIe 4.0 1TB SSD is £36 off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-samsung-980-pro-pcie-40-1tb-ssd-is-36-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-samsung-980-pro-pcie-40-1tb-ssd-is-36-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T18:40:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Samsung 980 Pro SSD is one of the very fastest drives on the market, thanks to its PCIe 4.0 connection and 7000MB/s flash memory, and today it's been heavily discounted... on Amazon Germany. I know what you're thinking, but with a bare minimum of effort you can get the 1TB drive for £136, way below the current UK price of £172. Here's how it works. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classic LittleBigPlanet Servers Shut Down Permanently Following Hacks]]></title>
        <id>1847666558</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/classic-littlebigplanet-servers-shut-down-permanently-f-1847666558"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LittleBigPlanet fans have a bit of a good news/bad news situation this morning. After months of downtime, the PS4 servers for LittleBigPlanet 3 are back online, with all the community content restored and working as before. However, servers for all prior PS3 and Vita versions will remain offline indefinitely, having…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nvidia RTX 3080 Ti graphics card is shockingly available to purchase in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-nvidia-rtx-3080-ti-graphics-card-is-shockingly-available-to-purchase-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-nvidia-rtx-3080-ti-graphics-card-is-shockingly-available-to-purchase-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T18:06:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nvidia RTX 3080 Ti is currently available for purchase at its recommended retail price, a headline that would have ludicrous to write a few years ago but now constitutes major news. Scan in the UK have stock of the high-end card at its £1049 RRP, stock that has seemingly persisted for a few hours - one of only a handful of times that an Nvidia RTX graphics card at RRP hasn't sold out immediately. If you're building a high-end rig, I'd say this is a great option - as long as you can't find an RTX 3080, at least. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zink OpenGL-On-Vulkan Tackling Support For More Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Zink-September-Games</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Zink-September-Games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T17:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After last month landing the Zink sub-allocator code for improved performance and also enabling OpenGL ES 3.2 support for Zink, lead developer Mike Blumenkrantz at Valve has been spending time this month working to get more games running on this OpenGL-over-Vulkan Mesa driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Debugger 11.1 Released With MTE Support, Core File Debugging For 64-bit Cygwin Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GDB-11.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GDB-11.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T17:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GDB 11.1 is now available as the latest feature update to the GNU Debugger...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paradox CEO admits "inappropriate behaviour" towards employee in 2018]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-ceo-admits-inappropriate-behaviour-towards-employee-in-2018</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-ceo-admits-inappropriate-behaviour-towards-employee-in-2018"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T17:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fredrik Wester, the CEO of Paradox Interactive, has publicly expressed regret for "inappropriate behaviour" towards an employee at a company event in 2018. This comes shortly after someone leaked the results of a union survey which revealed many employees felt they'd been mistreated at the company behind games including Crusader Kings and Hearts Of Iron. "Accountability starts from the top," said Wester.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Střídání času ještě minimálně pět let, na zrušení není shoda]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42812</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/stridani-casu-jeste-minimalne-pet-let-na-zruseni-neni-shoda/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T16:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Střídání času se mělo podle Evropského parlamentu zastavit již letos. Jenže plány překřížila pandemie COVID-19. Dnes naše vláda schválila nařízení, že střídání času bude probíhat dalších pět let.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop: PC performance guide and the best settings to use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-pc-performance-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-pc-performance-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:51:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve read Brendan’s Deathloop review, you’ll know Arkane Lyon’s latest is a frequently hilarious time-loop shooter that’s worth getting trapped in. And if you’ve seen its official PC system requirements, you’ll also know it makes some big asks of your hardware. At least, in theory. After a few hours of testing it appears the minimum requirements aren’t quite so minimum, and it’s possible to get slick frame rates in Deathloop even on older graphics hardware – especially if you make a few choice settings adjustments. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total War: Warhammer 3 delayed into 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-delayed-into-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-delayed-into-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, someone has to apologise to the neighbours and round up the dogs of war, because Total War: Warhammer 3 has been delayed. Previously expected late this year, the trilogy-concluding strategy game based on Games Workshop's fantasy plastic world is now due in 2022. The developers, Creative Assembly say they want to make sure it's good, yeah?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games appealing the Apple app store battle ruling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-appealing-the-apple-app-store-battle-ruling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-games-appealing-the-apple-app-store-battle-ruling"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:03:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though a judge largely ruled against Epic Games on Friday in their App Store legal battle with Apple sparked by Fortnite in-app purchases on iOS, clearly that wouldn't be the end. It isn't. On Sunday, Epic filed a notice that yes, they're appealing the ruling. At this point they haven't said precisely what they object to and why but, y'know, they want it to go their way.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things left on my office desk after 18 months of working from home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/things-left-on-my-office-desk-after-18-months-of-working-from-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/things-left-on-my-office-desk-after-18-months-of-working-from-home"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T15:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently I am one of about six people in the entire world who hates working from home. I can't do it. At home I am lazy, unproductive, and I accidentally do hours of overtime despite this, because I have no place where work ends and home begins. In March 2020, we were all officially sent home for a temporary office closure, the definition of "temporary" soon being stretched as far as I allow my credulity to when I watch The Prestige. It's magical! David Bowie makes thousands of hats!
Anyway, at the tail end of last week I returned to the office, which it turns out is still almost entirely empty. It's like working from home except I have to wear trousers (also Graham is here too so I can kick his chair and throw stuff at him). I spent a few hours on the first day creeping about looking at everything that had been left here for 18 months, and concluded that if our office were a level in a post-apocalyptic game, or a scene in 28 Days later, it would be pretty embarrassing.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Among Us mods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-among-us-mods</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-among-us-mods"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among Us made a hit out of some very basic minigames and complex social interaction. Surviving against the Imposters as they stab and lie their way through a game might rely more on the players than on the game, but you can craft a more complex base game with a few mod additions - the best of which we've rounded up right here. While you can’t mod your friends, you can mod the game, building on the anxiety-ridden camaraderie crusher by adding new roles and new modes to the basic format. Below, you’ll find out how to fall in love or enact the rule of law (by killing) with our guide to the best Among Us mods. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Craig Pearson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple musí otevřít platby v AppStore]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42811</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/apple-musi-otevrit-platby-v-appstore/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T13:54:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V již rok trvajícím sporu Epic vs. Apple kvůli hře Fortnite byl v pátek vynesen 185 stránkový rozsudek kalifornským soudem. Ten dává většinou za pravdu Apple a Epic tak bude muset platit náhradu za platby Fortnite, které šly mimo AppStore. To dělá přes 3,6 milionů dolarů. A k tomu další náhrady.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Delivers Many Features With New NTFS Driver, In-Kernel SMB3 Server, New Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30519</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30519"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T13:16:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feature development is over on the Linux 5.15 kernel with Linux 5.15-rc1 being issued. It's now on to testing and bug fixing over the next two months before the kernel is christened as stable. Here is our original Linux 5.15 feature overview about all of the big changes in this next kernel version.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toem review: a modern, yet nostalgic photography adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/toem-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/toem-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Remember that brief period in the 00s where everyone had a mobile phone, but none of them could take decent photos, so at least one girl per friendship group also had to have a small digital camera? Laboriously uploading and tagging. These are the photos that come up on your Facebook Memories, reminding you that for a brief period during your final year of school you started wearing 50s-ish neck scarves, for some reason. 
The little black-and-white puzzle adventure game Toem, in which all problems are solved with a camera, reminds me of that. Not because you are able to make disasterous or whimisical fashion choices - you very much are, mostly in the hat department - but because you just take photos of everything, for the fun of it, to remember this thing you saw. Wonky-focused snaps of a flower, or a ladybird, or a nice building (poorly framed because you can't get all of it in shot). This isn't really photography for the camera nerds interested in lenses or different exposures. This is photography as a joyful insta-record of your life. I was here, I did this thing, it was good.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 18.04.6 LTS Special Being Prepared To Deal With Unbootable Media]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-18.04.6-LTS-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-18.04.6-LTS-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T12:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Ubuntu 18.04.5 LTS shipped one year ago as the last planned point release to the "Bionic Beaver", an emergency issue is leading to Ubuntu 18.04.6 now being prepared...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still-Pending AMD PSF Control Patch To Be Retailored For KVM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PSF-Control-September</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PSF-Control-September"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T12:40:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Of all the great stuff for AMD in Linux 5.15, one of the patches still not having yet been mainlined is the control support around Predictive Store Forwarding (PSF) with Zen 3 processors. It's been six months since AMD published their security whitepaper around PSF while the Linux patch has yet to be mainlined while now it seems will be updated for a reduced focus on KVM usage...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšel GNU Wget2, rychlejší Wget]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42810</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vysel-gnu-wget2-rychlejsi-wget/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T12:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Všichni jistě znáte GNU Wget, jednoduchý stahovač pro HTTPS, HTTP a FTP do příkazové řádky. Včera vyšel GNU Wget2 ve verzi 2.0.0 Jde o nové přepsání nástroje okolo knihovny libwget. Wget2 by měl být rychlejší než Wget, protože podporuje více vláken, HTTP/2, HTTP kompresi, TCP fast open a hlavičky If-Modified-Since.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop review: this is not your daddy's Dishonored]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T12:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[William Blake once wrote: "Hold Infinity in the palm of your hand, and Eternity in an hour." Shut up, Blake. This is Deathloop. It is a full-blown action-comedy with a double jump. You get a sideways dash and a gun that splits to become two, smaller guns. If I see anyone trying to be too smart about this game, in which a time-looping assassin tries to break free of hilarious eternity by murdering many people who deserve it, I will look at them with hollow eyes and say: "In Deathloop you regularly snap necks by 270 degrees." Turn away, poets and stealth likers. This is not your daddy's Dishonored.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Destiny 2's revamped Trials Of Osiris is great, and hugely popular]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-2s-revamped-trials-of-osiris-is-great-and-hugely-popular</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/destiny-2s-revamped-trials-of-osiris-is-great-and-hugely-popular"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T11:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Bungie announced last year that they were reviving Destiny 2's serious PvP weekend event mode, Trials, they said "It's important that this doesn't go out half-baked." Reader dear, it went out half-baked. But! Seventeen months and one revamp later, Trials Of Osiris is good now. Really good. With generous new reward systems, the option to queue solo, and a few anti-cheater measures, the return of Trials this weekend has seen a huge surge in player numbers and been, like, actually fun.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxenfree 2's villains are sending spooky signals to the original game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oxenfree-2s-villains-are-sending-spooky-signals-to-the-original-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oxenfree-2s-villains-are-sending-spooky-signals-to-the-original-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T11:31:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The makers of Oxenfree have started teasing the upcoming sequel via audio transmissions in the original game. Oxenfree 2: Lost Signals is set to arrive sometime next year, and it'll feature villains who're causing mysterious radio signals that mess with electronics. But it seems they're already up to no good, because an update to the original Oxenfree has introduced these spooky transmissions, which you can hear in several different areas in the supernatural thriller. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to fish in Genshin Impact]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-fish-in-genshin-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-fish-in-genshin-impact"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T11:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to learn how to fish in Genshin Impact? Genshin Impact’s 2.1 update is finally here, and it introduces an entirely new mechanic that will gives you something else to procrastinate searching for your missing sibling with: fishing! Before you can become Teyvat’s most accomplished angler, though, you’ll need to complete a short quest and become familiar with the fishing mechanic. Here’s everything you’ll need to know about fishing in Genshin Impact.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Zollner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Developers Talk Again About An Accelerator Subsystem - Or Moving Them Into The GPU/DRM Area]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Accel-Drivers-2021-Discussion</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Accel-Drivers-2021-Discussion"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T09:57:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On and off for years has been talk of an accelerator subsystem for the Linux kernel considering that for now most AI training/inference accelerator drivers end up lodged within the "char/misc" area of the kernel. That accelerator subsystem discussion has been restarted with talks of having such a subsystem or moving those drivers within the GPU/DRM subsystem space...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyhledávač Google má tmavý vzhled, zatím ale ne pro všechny]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42809</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vyhledavac-google-ma-tmavy-vzhled-zatim-ale-ne-pro-vsechny/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T08:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vyhledávací stránku Google.com je možné nyní přepnout do tmavého vzhledu. Je potřeba být přihlášen a na stránce s výsledky zmáčknout ozubené kolečko vpravo nahoře. V nastavení vyhledávání se vám možná objeví nová položka vzhled. Tam je možné přepnout na tmavý, světlý a výchozí podle zařízení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux mírně rozvolní opatření proti Spectre]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42808</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-mirne-rozvolni-opatreni-proti-spectre/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T08:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxové jádro mírně „rozvolní“ opatření proti Spectre V2 a  V4 (Speculative Store Bypass) pro uživatelské úlohy. Od jádra 4.20 je výchozím chováním spec_store_bypass_disable=seccomp a spectre_v2_user=seccomp  , tedy jen pro úlohy používající SECCOMP (secure computing mode). Nově by mělo být nastaveno prctl, tedy jen pro procesy, které to mají nastaveno.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naučte se používat Linux správně a bezpečně (online školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40574</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/naucte-se-pouzivat-linux-spravne-a-bezpecne-online-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T06:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxových systémů přibývá, každý den se spouštějí nové servery a někdo se o ně musí starat. To znamená spoustu různých dovedností specifických právě pro linuxové prostředí. Jak to zprovoznit, kudy bezpečně dovnitř, co tam najdeme, jak se o to postaráme a jak to nastavíme nebo rozšíříme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine Research]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2515/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2515/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc1 Brings New NTFS Driver, In-Kernel SMB3 Server, AMD Changes, Intel DG2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T00:22:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As expected this evening the Linux 5.15-rc1 kernel was released to top off the two week merge window that saw many changes to the kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo představuje hybridní tablety budoucnosti. Canon rozšiřuje nabídku A3 multifunkcí pro hybridní pracovní prostředí. Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: FortiGate pod palbou]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15661</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-fortigate-pod-palbou/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes postřehneme zranitelnou VPN od Fortinetu, návrat starých a příchod nových známých, vykradené OSN i nového člena advisory boardu ProtonMailu. V rychlosti pak nové zranitelnosti Microsoft nástrojů či zamyšlení nad biometrickými údaji.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CESNET CERTS)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin oživuje PalmOS, Linux Mint pracuje na vzhledu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15658</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/pumpkin-ozivuje-palmos-linux-mint-pracuje-na-vzhledu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt Pumpkin má za cíl oživit ukončený systém PalmOS na moderních strojích. Linux Mint se hodlá zaměřit na přepracování témat vzhledu. Na serveru OSNews vyšla obsáhlá recenze KDE Slimbooku. Program unzip na openSUSE poškozuje soubory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Is A Very Exciting Kernel For AMD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-AMD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-AMD"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While working on my usual Linux kernel feature overview that summarizes the many articles over the past two weeks outlining all of the new features and changes merged, one area that particularly stands out for Linux 5.15 are all of AMD's upstream contributions that happened to make it in this kernel. There is a lot of new enablement on the AMD side -- both for CPUs and Radeon graphics -- but also improving existing hardware support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Software Foundation Saw $3M In Revenue, ~134M Changed Lines Of Code Last Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apache-FY2021-Report</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apache-FY2021-Report"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T11:11:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Apache Software Foundation recently published their FY2021 report for their year-ended 30 April. Even with the ongoing pandemic, the Apache Software Foundation managed to raise more than $3M USD and enjoyed a host of software successes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Looking Like Folios / Pagesets Might Miss Making It Into Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Folios-Pagesets-MIA-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Folios-Pagesets-MIA-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T10:20:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are now down to the last day of the Linux 5.15 merge window and one of the patch series we have been waiting to see if it would land during this two week period was the "folios" code -- or that also was recently renamed to "pagesets" to address some concerns over the name...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RISC-V Gets Expanded Stack Randomization With Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RISC-V-Better-Stack-Rand</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RISC-V-Better-Stack-Rand"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T10:04:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to the RISC-V changes merged last week for the Linux 5.15 kernel, a second batch of patches was merged this weekend...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-610</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-610"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for staring at Mr Muscle, debating for a second whether you could take him, then coming to the conclusion that you absolutely couldn't. Before you consider things, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Preparing To Slightly Loosen Its Spectre Defaults]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Spectre-V2-V4-Going-Prctl-Def</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Spectre-V2-V4-Going-Prctl-Def"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A change first proposed last year to the Linux kernel's Spectre mitigation defaults looks like it will soon be sent in for the mainline kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Dokázali přepnout vodivost z 2D na 1D]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-dokazali-prepnout-vodivost-z-2d-na-1d</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-dokazali-prepnout-vodivost-z-2d-na-1d"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Topologické izolátory. Janusovský grafen a baterie. Zachycen nový typ gravitačních vln. Dvojvrstvý borofen. Hledání mimozemských civilizací. Dysonovy sféry u černých děr. Planeta Devět. Oblečení z umělých svalových vláken.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple nabírá experty na RISC-V, IBM uvedla první servery s POWER10]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15660</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/apple-nabira-experty-na-risc-v-ibm-uvedla-prvni-servery-s-power10/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LG představila River OS, nový operační systém pro TV protkaný reklamou, VESA přidává certifikaci DisplayHDR True Black 600, vychází Wine 6.17 a také GNOME 41 Release Candidate s řadou vylepšení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Dynasties aka 'Crusader Kings in space' is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-dynasties-aka-crusader-kings-in-space-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-dynasties-aka-crusader-kings-in-space-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T20:47:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's always been a surprise that more games haven't followed in the footsteps of Crusader Kings, but Star Dynasties looks to give it a go. It's a space strategy game about growing your space empire, getting space married, and having space affairs. It left early access at the beginning of the month.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Eternal Cylinder will roll onto hard drives on September 30th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-eternal-cylinder-will-roll-onto-hard-drives-on-september-30th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-eternal-cylinder-will-roll-onto-hard-drives-on-september-30th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T19:02:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Eternal Cylinder was first shown as a prototype six years ago. Back then, Adam described it as "Billy Hatcher and the Giant Egg by way of Philip José Farmer, Icepick Lodge and Hieronymus Bosch, all set in the shadow of a hungry horizon." The prototype was a personal project of ACE Team co-founder Carlos Bordeu, who said that he wasn't yet sure what you would do in the game moment to moment.

Now the game is reaching the end of its journey. ACE Team have announced you'll be able to flee the planetary rolling pin on September 30th.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Epic vs. Apple court has a great definition of video games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-epic-vs-apple-court-has-a-great-definition-of-video-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-epic-vs-apple-court-has-a-great-definition-of-video-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T18:34:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Epic's court case against Apple reached a conclusion yesterday, at least temporarily, but the judge's ruling didn't only address the big issues of app stores and payment systems. Judge Yvonne Gonzalez also offered an answer to a question raised during the trial: what is a game? Most surprisingly, Gonzalez's definition is pretty great.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Latest Progress On Rust For The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Rust-Linux-Kernel-Linaro-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Rust-Linux-Kernel-Linaro-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T18:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Rust programming language support for usage within the kernel isn't landing for the Linux 5.15 merge window ending this weekend, that effort remains ongoing. A status update on the effort was shared this week about Rust usage for the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic vs. Apple: US court rules Apple must allow third-party payment systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-vs-apple-us-court-rules-apple-must-allow-third-party-payment-systems</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/epic-vs-apple-us-court-rules-apple-must-allow-third-party-payment-systems"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T17:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[iOS app developers must be allowed to direct users towards payment options other than those provided by Apple, a US judge has ruled in the Epic v. Apple case. Apple have 90 days, until December 9th, to comply. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Batch Of RadeonSI Optimizations Land In Mesa 21.3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-More-For-Mesa-21.3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-More-For-Mesa-21.3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T17:15:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another batch of minor optimizations were merged to Mesa 21.3 for the RadeonSI Gallium3D driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Lake Support Added To Intel's TCC Driver In Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Alder-Lake-TCC-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Alder-Lake-TCC-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T13:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While much of Intel's next-gen Alder Lake processor support appears to be in good shape for Linux 5.14, some remaining items are landing for the current Linux 5.15 cycle. The latest Alder Lake support hitting the kernel is for Intel's TCC cooling driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CoreCtrl 1.2 Brings Support For More Sensors, Voltage Offsets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CoreCtl-1.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CoreCtl-1.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T11:45:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CoreCtrl 1.2 was released this week as the open-source, independently-developed application for exposing more sensor support on Linux and offering various controls aroudnd over/under-clocking and other tuning. At the moment CoreCtrl is primarily focused on making the most use of AMD Radeon GPUs under Linux with some options not otherwise readily available on the platform...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 2.6.1 Released For This Open-Source Video Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenShot-2.6.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenShot-2.6.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T10:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Released in August was the big OpenShot 2.6 video editor update while this weekend has been succeeded by its first point release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-161</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-161"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I thought the air would be cleared by the tremendous thunderstorm that rattled my windows this week, but no. We are still all muggy. This is the worst of between times, where it is not quite warm enough to go without a hoody or a light cardigan, but definitely not cool enough that your t-shirt doesn't get stuck to both your back and your rucksack because of the sweat. Even though the rucksack said it had a special 'moisture wicking' bit of material on it to avoid this situation. WELL! I shall just cast my rucksack down this weekend and play games instead.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 36/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-36-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-36-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Originální doživotní aktivační klíč Windows 10 Pro za pouhých 12,52 EUR od Goodoffer24.com]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/originalni-dozivotni-aktivacni-klic-windows-10-pro-za-pouhych-12-52-eur-odgoodoffer24.com</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/originalni-dozivotni-aktivacni-klic-windows-10-pro-za-pouhych-12-52-eur-odgoodoffer24.com"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Získejte doživotní aktivační klíč k Windows 10 za 12,52 EUR na prodejním portálu GoodOffer24.com. Kromě toho zde můžete získat mnohem více, od dalších nástrojů produktivity od Microsoftu, až po hry. Nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód  AX30.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Extraction's latest trailer shows more gadgets and operators]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rainbow-six-extractions-latest-trailer-shows-more-gadgets-and-operators</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rainbow-six-extractions-latest-trailer-shows-more-gadgets-and-operators"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T20:22:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I loved the wall-busting, door-blocking, remote-camera-ing gadgets that Rainbow Six Siege gave players, but the community quickly outpaced my ability to compete with them. That's why I'm looking forward to Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Extraction. It broadly gives you the same toys, but you're using them against AI-controlled alien mutants. I'm traditionally alright at competing with those.

There was a new trailer showing the gadgets and operators in action during last night's PlayStation event, and you'll find it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What videogame would you like to look at outside your window?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-videogame-would-you-like-to-look-at-outside-your-window</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-videogame-would-you-like-to-look-at-outside-your-window"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T19:27:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA['Frasier looking at video games' is the latest single-purpose Twitter account spreading across the games industry. Each tweet features the same still from the sitcom Frasier featuring Frasier Crane looking out his apartment windows, but in each the Seattle skyline has been replaced by a different videogame landscape.

So I ask you, if you were Frasier Crane, what videogame would you like to gaze upon from your fabulously expensive apartment?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Konami have released some lofi remixes to chill/study to]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konami-have-released-some-lofi-remixes-to-chillstudy-to</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/konami-have-released-some-lofi-remixes-to-chillstudy-to"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T18:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's the 35th anniversary of the Konami code, the string of button presses that first activated cheats in Gradius on the NES in 1986, but which would feature in many later Konami games as well. To celebrate the birthday of up up down down left right left right BA, Konami have produced some lofi hip hop to chill, study and/or relax to.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forza Horizon 5 sure has a lot of cars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5s-confirmed-car-list-is-enormous</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forza-horizon-5s-confirmed-car-list-is-enormous"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T18:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don't know my carburetor from my timing belt drive pulley, so much so that I had to Google "car engine parts" in order to find a second reference for this sentence. The Forza Horizon series mostly operates on my wavelength, letting me be excited by cars because they're shiny and have smooth lines and go fast, without me needing to know their innards.

The list of cars so far confirmed for Forza Horizon 5 might mean different things to you than it does to me, then. To me it means that the Jaguar XJ220 I had as a toy when I was 8 is in there, but maybe you have opinions about different kinds of Land Rover.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Of all the retro Final Fantasy games, you should definitely make time for FF4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/of-all-the-retro-final-fantasy-games-you-should-definitely-make-time-for-ff4</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/of-all-the-retro-final-fantasy-games-you-should-definitely-make-time-for-ff4"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T18:04:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I came to Final Fantasy IV (or II, if you're American) pretty late in the day. At the time, back in the mists of 1991, it was never actually released in the UK. I was also just three-years-old then, but that's besides the point. Instead, we had to wait another decade until it got a proper UK release, where it landed on the original PlayStation in 2002. However, because I was young and naive and far too wrapped up playing Final Fantasies VII-IX at that point, it never even occurred to me to look back down the Roman numeral line and pick it up. Heck, I even missed its appearance on the GBA in 2006 - arguably the last 'best' version of this early 90s classic. It wasn't until the 3D Remake arrived on the Nintendo DS in 2008 that I finally sat up and took notice - a whole 17 years after it first came out. 
But cor, I'm glad I did, because Final Fantasy IV is still arguably one of the best Final Fantasy games ever made, and is easily the best (or second best, depending on who you ask) of the older retro ones. If there's one Final Fantasy game you make time for over the next few months, make it FFIV. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TFI Friday: 3 new indie games for back-to-school season]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-3-new-indie-games-for-back-to-school-season</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-3-new-indie-games-for-back-to-school-season"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T15:11:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past week or so has been Back To School time in the UK, also known as the season of adverts on TV about protractors and pencil cases, and posts on Facebook showing a six-year-old standing by a front door and wearing their new school uniform. A dance as old as time. I remember getting a blue jumper that was two sizes too big for me so I could grow into it. Remember it like it was yesterday.
But enough about school itself, a time in my life that I hated to an extraordinary extent and shudder to think of even now. We move to happier things, i.e. games, and in particular the assumption I'm making that now your kids are out of the house for most of the day, you'll have more time to play games. Here are three new indie games that came out in the last month or so, that I feel are apposite for a back-to-school theme.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The baddies in Ghostwire Tokyo's new trailer look like Buffy's The Gentlemen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-baddies-in-ghostwire-tokyos-new-trailer-look-like-buffys-the-gentlemen</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-baddies-in-ghostwire-tokyos-new-trailer-look-like-buffys-the-gentlemen"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T14:43:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It must be a typical human fear to not like things with deathly pale faces, shadowy eyes, and suits. I know I'm certainly not a fan, but this specific type of villain has a habit of showing up in spooky games, films and TV series. Last night, paranormal action-RPG Ghostwire: Tokyo got a new trailer as part of the PlayStation showcase stream, and it's chock-full of these baddies that look an awful lot like the Gentlemen from Buffy The Vampire Slayer.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a PS5 DualSense controller on PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-use-a-ps5-dualsense-controller-on-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-use-a-ps5-dualsense-controller-on-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T14:40:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sony’s DualSense pad is a lovely bit of peripheral design; it’s a shame, then, that figuring out how to use the PS5 controller on PC is a right old pain in the thumbstick. Without the Microsoft-masterminded, plug-and-play sensibilities of Xbox controllers, the PS5 controller often needs some help to get working on a Windows machine. It’s all doable, though, and this here guide will walk you through the setup process as well as how to get the most out of different games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You should play Axis Football 2021 in coach mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-should-play-axis-football-2021-in-coach-mode</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-should-play-axis-football-2021-in-coach-mode"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sport of Americaball was about the last thing I was expecting to enjoy in 2019. Since then, I've skipped an entry but come back for Axis Football 2021 and found myself impressed despite having higher standards now.
It may have taken a long iterative route, but this is becoming a strong sport series even if you're not a fan of pooting the old dogskin.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tchia had the best trailer in the PlayStation Showcase]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tchia-had-the-best-trailer-in-the-playstation-showcase</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tchia-had-the-best-trailer-in-the-playstation-showcase"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T14:28:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previously announced at The Game Awards 2020, cute adventure game Tchia received a brand-new trailer at last night’s PlayStation livestream and it looked gorgeous.
Tchia is an open world game set in a fictional series of islands, inspired by New Caledonia - a collection of islands that are in the Pacific but remain a French-administered territory. Our latest glimpse at Tchia was light on new details about the game but it still gave us updated looks at the vibrant environments, modes of traversal and cast of characters. Take a look at the trailer below. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop looks as vibrant and murderous as ever in its new story trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-looks-as-vibrant-and-murderous-as-ever-in-its-new-story-trailer</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-looks-as-vibrant-and-murderous-as-ever-in-its-new-story-trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T12:46:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In just four days Arkane's new time-looping stealth 'em up Deathloop will be part of our lives, and last night the devs treated us to a new trailer telling us a few titbits about the game's story. Of course, like most of the other trailers, it's also full of sneaking, cool powers, lotsa guns, and excellent fashion. It's almost like we're stuck in a timeloop ourselves, watching main character Colt slay his way through semi-familiar areas in new ways. I can't get enough of it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oprava uspávání notebooků s AMD bude v jádře 5.15]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42807</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/oprava-uspavani-notebooku-s-amd-bude-v-jadre-5-15/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T12:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Některé notebooky s novými procesory AMD mají problémy s probuzením ze spánku s2idle. Mezi nimi například HP Envy x360. Po probuzení například nesvítí dioda napájení, nefunguje ovládání jasnosti displeje či dokonce nefunguje ventilátor.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wartales is a tactical RPG that won't bog you down with quests you never wanted to do in the first place]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wartales-is-a-tactical-rpg-that-wont-bog-you-down-with-quests-you-never-wanted-to-do-in-the-first-place</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wartales-is-a-tactical-rpg-that-wont-bog-you-down-with-quests-you-never-wanted-to-do-in-the-first-place"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I didn't realise how annoying I found main quests in RPGs until I played a game that didn't force one on me. That game is Wartales, an upcoming tactical open world game from the developers of Northgard, Shiro Games. It plonks you into a fairly mundane medieval world - in the sense that there' are no wizards's no magic, elves, or grand drama for you to fix - where you can just exist as mercenary doing as you please. It's coming out in early access at some point in the near future, and after having a go of the demo, I spoke to game director Nicolas Cannasse about why they chose to make a game that sets you free, rather than railroading you into some giant mission.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say hello to Felisha and Paolo, our first official comments moderators]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/say-hello-to-felisha-and-paolo-our-first-official-comments-moderators</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/say-hello-to-felisha-and-paolo-our-first-official-comments-moderators"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T11:49:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reader comments have always been an incredibly important part of RPS, but sifting through them all often fell to the RPS staff. Since we were only looking at them during work hours, we'd often be slow to respond, and sometimes miss out on discussions entirely. The good news is that we've now got proper official comments moderators to help keep the conversation going, both between yourselves and between you and the wider RPS team. So please give a warm welcome to Felisha Dela Cruz and Paolo Balmes.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD bude mít ovladač frekvencí procesoru amd_pstate, o 11 % lepší výkon na Watt]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42806</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/amd-bude-mit-ovladac-frekvenci-procesoru-amd-pstate-o-11-lepsi-vykon-na-watt/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T11:33:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Procesory AMD Zen 2 a 3 budou mít lepší ovladač frekvencí amd_pstate místo doposud používaného acpi_cpufreq. Nový ovladač bude lépe využívat možností procesoru podobně jako u Intelu intel_pstate. Používat bude rozhraní ACPI CPPC (Collaborative Processor Performance Controls), které umožňuje jemnější řízení než staré ACPI. Z počátku bude podpora pouze pro Zen 3, později bude přidána podpora Zen 2.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radiohead team up with Epic Games for a virtual exhibition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/radiohead-team-up-with-epic-games-for-a-virtual-exhibition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/radiohead-team-up-with-epic-games-for-a-virtual-exhibition"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T11:11:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radiohead are releasing a digital exhibition to celebrate the 21-year anniversary of their Kid A and Amnesiac albums, and it'll be available on the Epic Games Store this November. It's called the Kid A Mnesia Exhibition, and from the sounds of things we'll be able to explore some sort of interactive environment while we listen to the band's old iconic tunes. This certainly wasn't an Epic exclusive I was expecting, but it sounds pretty cool nonetheless.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite's next multiplayer preview is targeting Sep 24th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-next-multiplayer-preview-is-targeting-sep-24th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-next-multiplayer-preview-is-targeting-sep-24th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T10:57:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developer 343 have announced that Halo Infinite’s next multiplayer technical preview is “targeted” to arrive on September 24th. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lost In Random review: a grand adventure with few surprises]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lost-in-random-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lost-in-random-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given it's called Lost In Random, you'd expect Zoink Games' new game to be filled with all sorts of oddities and twists and turns and things. Well, it sort of is. And it sort of isn't. I had hoped it would surprise me more, actually. This is a strategy-combat-meets-adventure game that's solid fun and has some great personality, but it gets a little too comfortable to knock you for six.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ProtonMail předal IP adresu francouzských aktivistů policii, doporučuje používat tor]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42805</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/protonmail-predal-ip-adresu-francouzskych-aktivistu-policii/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T08:27:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Švýcarská šifrovaná e-mailová služba ProtonMail dříve prohlašovala, že ve výchozím stavu neloguje IP adresy ani další detaily uživatelů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manjaro Linux Cinnamon mění výchozí prohlížeč, namísto Firefoxu nasadí Vivaldi]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42804</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/manjaro-linux-cinnamon-meni-vychozi-prohlizec-namisto-firefoxu-nasadi-vivaldi/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T07:41:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuce Manjaro Linux Cinnamon změní výchozí prohlížeč. Původní Firefox bude nahrazen prohlížečem Vivaldi. Vývojáři distribuce vysvětlují, proč ke změně přikročili: Aby měl Vivaldi větší pozornost, kterou si zaslouží, rozhodli jsme se jej zahrnout jako výchozí prohlížeč do naší oblíbené Cinnamon Community Edition. Díky pozoruhodné rychlosti, výjimečné přizpůsobitelnosti a zejména způsobu, jakým hodnotí soukromí uživatelů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Botnet Mēris vytvořil rekordní útok s 21,8 miliony požadavků za sekundu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42803</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/botnet-m-ris-vytvoril-rekordni-utok-s-21-8-miliony-pozadavku-za-sekundu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T07:28:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový botnet nazvaný Mēris, který během léta získával na síle, vytrvale útočí na ruskou společnost Yandex. Ta nyní ohlásila rekordní útok, který ve špičce představoval 21,8 milionů požadavků za sekundu (RPS). V srpnu přitom CloudFlare ohlásil předchozí rekord ve výši 17,2 milionů RPS – za ním stojí úplně stejný botnet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rocky Linux nabízí oficiální placenou podporu pro firmy]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42802</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rocky-linux-nabizi-oficialni-placenou-podporu-pro-firmy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T07:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rocky Linux umožňuje získat oficiální placenou podporu pro firemní zákazníky, kteří chtějí operační systém používat ve své infrastruktuře. Službu oznámila společnost Ctrl IQ (zkráceně CIQ), kterou nedávno založil Gregory Kurtzer, zakladatel Rocky Linuxu a také původního projektu CentOS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linuxová distribuce Microsoftu CBL-Mariner má ISO]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42801</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linuxova-distribuce-microsoftu-cbl-mariner-ma-iso/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T06:23:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft nedávno vytvořil vlastní distribuci CBL-Mariner. Distribuci založenou na balíčcích RPM používá například ve WSL a Azure. Včera vyšla srpnová aktualizace 1.0. Největší novinkou je možnost stažení ISO souboru.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lab Equipment]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2514/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2514/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forspoken's story has a sassy cuff, big writers, and oddly stiff faces]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forspokens-story-has-a-sassy-cuff-big-writers-and-oddly-stiff-faces</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/forspokens-story-has-a-sassy-cuff-big-writers-and-oddly-stiff-faces"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T22:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During tonight's PlayStation livestream, we got a longer look at Square Enix's Forspoken. It's a third-person, open world action game in which you can go free running across a fantasy world, but the new trailer focuses on combat and on protagonist 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Co se chystá pro Linux 5.15, část druhá: nové platformy i rychlejší řešení OOM]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15657</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/co-se-chysta-pro-linux-5-15-cast-druha-nove-platformy-i-rychlejsi-reseni-oom/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nové ARM platformy, syscall pro rychlejší uvolnění paměti, AMD RDNA2 a Van Gogh, kernelový SMB3 File Server, Suspend/Resume u AMD, nová GPU, mountování FUSE pro CERN, lepší podpora platformy RISC-V.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Wake Remastered will launch on October 5th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-remastered-will-launch-on-october-5th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alan-wake-remastered-will-launch-on-october-5th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T21:41:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a sleepy guy, Alan Wake is moving at high speed. From leaked news of a remaster last week to an official announcement this week to tonight, when we got a first trailer and an imminent release date: October 5th. Watch the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncharted: Legacy Of Thieves Collection confirmed for PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-confirmed-for-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/uncharted-legacy-of-thieves-collection-confirmed-for-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T21:23:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We already knew that Uncharted 4 was headed to PC thanks to its inclusion in an investor report earlier this year. Now it's official. Uncharted: Legacy Of Thieves Collection is headed to PC, and it contains not only Uncharted 4: A Thief's End, but Uncharted The Lost Legacy, too. There's a new trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star Wars: Knights Of The Old Republic Remake announced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-announced</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-wars-knights-of-the-old-republic-remake-announced"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T21:06:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Star Wars: Knights Of The Old Republic Remake was announced during tonight's PlayStation livestream. This is confirmation of what had been long rumoured, including the detail that the remake would be developed by Aspyr. There's a teaser trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nioh is free to keep from the Epic Games Store right now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nioh-is-free-to-keep-from-the-epic-games-store-right-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nioh-is-free-to-keep-from-the-epic-games-store-right-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T20:05:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samurai yokai battler Nioh is free to download and keep from now until September 16th via the Epic Games Store. It's the latest in Epic's endless line of freebies, but if you're desperate to pay some money for a game, there's also a big September Savings sale underway.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football Manager 2022 will be available on day one from Xbox Game Pass]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022-will-be-available-on-day-one-from-xbox-game-pass</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/football-manager-2022-will-be-available-on-day-one-from-xbox-game-pass"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T19:38:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every year, I ask: is this the one? Is this the year where I get back into Football Manager? Throw all my books and films and other games away and boil my cultural consumption down to the media equivalent of Huel. Everything I need in one entertaining paste. 

I'm asking it again right now. Football Manager 2022 will release on November 9th, and Sports Interactive have announced that this year it'll also be available on day one via Xbox Game Pass.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to clean your mechanical keyboard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-clean-your-keyboard</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-clean-your-keyboard"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T16:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the RPS guide on how to clean a mechanical keyboard, something Graham specifically told us to do a while back, complete with a look at the revolting crud medley that had accumulated within his own mechanical board. His cleaning technique was pretty good too, though having recently Kim and Aggie’d my way through a guide on how to clean a PC, I reckon we can do better – no wet wipes required. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dice Legacy review: a plate-spinning nightmare in disguise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dice-legacy-review-a-plate-spinning-nightmare-in-disguise</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dice-legacy-review-a-plate-spinning-nightmare-in-disguise"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I used to hate dice in games. If I wanted to play Dingoes & Daggers I'd play it, you know? Even with those choose your own adventure books as kids, we'd just sort of assume that things went a particular way, because who has the time to start again for no reason? And now every game in the world (all of them) has cards in. Ach. I've even played several building games with cards, and I still can't decide if it really works.
Dice Legacy is, on the surface, a building game based entirely on rolling dice. Dice and cards obviously aren't the same, but they share a big chunk of territory. And after living there for most of this week, I am prepared to lie down and let Death take me from here. Dice Legacy drove me goddamn insane.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Splitgate review: a raucous FPS that's much more than Halo meets Portal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/splitgate-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have heard Splitgate described as "Halo meets Portal", a useful shorthand for those of us with brains too tired to describe it more colourfully as "a gun learns physics" or "Benny Hill gets a battle rifle". However you describe it, Splitgate is a belter of a multiplayer arena shooter, born of gimmickry, yet graduating with honours, it's a grin-delivering game of tight, gun gymnastics and wacky Loony Tunes doorways, and just the right amount of frustrating to make you sweat and launch into another scramble for the bazooka in the middle of the map. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 155: the best puzzles special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-155-the-best-puzzles-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-podcast-episode-155-the-best-puzzles-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We here at the Electronic Wireless Show podcast have done an episode about puzzles before, but Matthew and I just love puzzles a whole lot. We're talking about our favourite puzzle, as well, not puzzle game. This means that nate can bring up games about orcs, or whatever, that also happen to have a puzzle in them somewhere. Also yes, I got the number of the podcast wrong again, I know I keep doing this, let's just all move on together.
What is a surprise is that we don't really need to spend ages arguing over what the definition of a puzzle is, which I think shows personal growth. Well done us! Asides this week include what role Matthew you fill on the team in a heist movie, Nate vs. Rufus Hound, and what the hell is the Riddler's whole deal about, anyway? Also: please give us creative control of all major IPs in cinema and games, so we can remake them to be about the drink Rio Tropical.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Type 63 loadout in Warzone Season 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-warzone-type-63-loadout</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-warzone-type-63-loadout"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T14:47:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best Type 63 loadout to bring into Warzone? This Tactical Rifle has excellent damage that allows it to quickly kill with several well-placed shots. Thanks to its available attachments, it can easily outmatch some of the best SMGs in Warzone. This loadout capitalizes on that potential so that you can bring the Type 63 into any close-quarters Warzone engagement with the confidence that you'll come out on top.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Foley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best R1 Shadowhunter loadout for Warzone Season 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-r1-shadowhunter-loadout-warzone</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-r1-shadowhunter-loadout-warzone"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T14:42:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best R1 Shadowhunter Crossbow loadout to bring into Warzone? Then you must be looking to score some flashy kills and to troll some enemies. In truth, this crossbow has great damage potential, but its slow firerate and limited range are far too impractical to be useful in Warzone. If you're trying to figure out how to get better at this battle royale, you should skip this weapon and check out our guide on the best guns in Warzone. For those determined to become elite archers, we've still got you covered.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Foley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New World tips and tricks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-tips-and-tricks-beginners-guide</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-tips-and-tricks-beginners-guide"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T14:36:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for tips and tricks on surviving in New World? Amazon's behemoth of an MMORPG took Steam by storm during its closed beta period back in July. Now it's out again in open beta, and with it has arrived a great surge in questions asked by new players on what they should be doing, how to gather, how to craft, how to fight, and so much more.
We get it. It's an MMO. It can be overwhelming. But follow the below tips and tricks on getting started in New World and you'll find firm footing from which you can begin your character's journey across the mystical, dangerous, and fascinating land of Aeturnum.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud Gardens review: zen gardening in the middle of the wasteland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cloud-gardens-review-zen-gardening-in-the-middle-of-the-wasteland</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cloud-gardens-review-zen-gardening-in-the-middle-of-the-wasteland"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The post-apocalypse is often accompanied by violence, grit and gore when it comes to video games. So many titles use the inevitable wasteland to emotionally torture their characters or as a playground to squash some monsters – or both. Cloud Gardens abandons all the blood and tears. Refreshingly, the game doesn’t rely on any drama or conflict. Instead, Cloud Gardens is solely focused on the idea of revitalisation and nature taking back spaces… after we’re gone.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pathfinder: Wrath Of The Righteous is a CRPG belter, if you can handle your fantasy admin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pathfinder-wrath-of-the-righteous-is-a-crpg-belter-if-you-can-handle-your-fantasy-admin</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pathfinder-wrath-of-the-righteous-is-a-crpg-belter-if-you-can-handle-your-fantasy-admin"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T13:22:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had high hopes of reviewing Pathfinder: Wrath Of The Righteous this week. However, somewhere around six hours into the game, when I realised I was still honking great tracts of story away from even unlocking most of the game's core mechanics, reality set in. Without properly no-lifing it for at least the rest of the week, I knew there was no way I was going to see enough of it to give any kind of overall verdict. It's months' worth of game, before even starting on replay potential. And honestly? If you're a certain kind of CRPG player, that should be all the recommendation you need. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nate Crowley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to level up quickly in New World]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-leveling</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-world-leveling"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T12:46:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to level up fast in New World? With the game's launch into open beta, Amazon's ambitious foray into the world of MMORPGs has taken its next step towards engulfing the lives of many a player who wishes to level up their character as quickly as possible. But it's a long, slow process for most players to reach the highest levels - that is, unless you follow the tips below and learn all the fastest leveling methods available in New World.
Below we'll walk you through the best sources of XP in New World, from Main Quests to Town Missions; and we'll also go through small things that you can do to boost the XP you gain over time. We'll also explain how to improve your Trade Skill levels and your weapon masteries as efficiently as possible.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valorant's new defender-centred map Fracture has arrived]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-new-defender-centred-map-fracture-has-arrived</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-new-defender-centred-map-fracture-has-arrived"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T11:23:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valorant has a new map now, its name is Fracture, and it scares me. Unlike any of the other Valo maps in Riot's tactical FPS, Fracture is designed so the defending team starts in the middle, and attackers can come at you from either side - and they can slide under the map on cool ropes too! On top of that, there are a few tweaks to character's abilities and more in the game's latest act.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's when New World's open beta kicks off today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-when-new-worlds-open-beta-kicks-off-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-when-new-worlds-open-beta-kicks-off-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T10:29:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in July, thousands upon thousands of players descended upon New World's last beta, suggesting that Amazon might actually have a winner with their upcoming MMO. Unfortunately, they delayed it just a week later, making players wait an extra month to get their hands on it again. You'll be able to get a little bit of a fix this weekend though, because New World is getting an open beta that starts later this very day. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop system requirements confirmed, along with AMD FidelityFX Super Resolution support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-system-requirements-confirmed-along-with-amd-fidelityfx-super-resolution-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-system-requirements-confirmed-along-with-amd-fidelityfx-super-resolution-support"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T10:14:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop, or Deeaaaaaaathlooooooooooop as it’s called in the absolute banger of a theme song, has some official PC system requirements out ahead of release on September 14th. In a blog post, publishers Bethesda have also detailed some of the PC-only graphics settings you’ll be able to tinker with, while confirming support for AMD’s FidelityFX Super Resolution upscaling tech.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fallout 76's customisable Worlds update is now live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-76s-customisable-worlds-update-is-now-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-76s-customisable-worlds-update-is-now-live"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T22:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After launching public tests back in July, Fallout 76's 'Fallout Worlds' update is now available to all. 

Fallout Worlds offers players the ability to edit the settings of the game, removing build restrictions and upending game balance, then inviting friends along to play.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Psaní aplikací pro terminál: ošetření vstupů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15625</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/psani-aplikaci-pro-terminal-osetreni-vstupu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V předchozím článku jsem se snažil obecně někam zařadit knihovnu ncurses. V tomto článku se snažím o vysvětlení nebo popis zpracování vstupů a snažím se komentovat (a zdokumentovat) problémy, se kterými jsem se setkal při psaní pspg.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Stěhule)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projekt SpaceVim – moderní distribuce Vimu inspirovaná Spacemacsem]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15656</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/projekt-spacevim-moderni-distribuce-vimu-inspirovana-spacemacsem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na několik článků o Spacemacsu a taktéž o Doom Emacsu dnes navážeme pohledem na druhou stranu pomyslné barikády. Popíšeme si totiž projekt SpaceVim, který byl sice inspirován Spacemacsem, ovšem je kompletně postaven na Vimu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy IV's pixel remaster is out now on Steam]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-ivs-pixel-remaster-is-out-now-on-steam</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/final-fantasy-ivs-pixel-remaster-is-out-now-on-steam"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T21:38:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Final Fantasy IV's pixel remaster is now available on Steam. It follows the release of the pixel remasters of I-III in July, with V and VI both due in the near future. It's also arguably the first Final Fantasy to resemble what the series would become, in terms of characters and its battle system.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kitaria Fables, action RPG Stardew with cats, is out now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kitaria-fables-action-rpg-stardew-with-cats-is-out-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kitaria-fables-action-rpg-stardew-with-cats-is-out-now"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T21:03:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, Kitaria Fables might better be described as "Rune Factory with cats", but let's make the useful comparison to the game most folks have heard of. Kitaria Fables is a game in which you, a cat, biff monsters in classless combat to gather resources, and then spend time planting crops and chatting to NPCs at home. It's out now.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spuštěna registrace na jOpenSpace 2021]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42800</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/spustena-registrace-na-jopenspace-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T20:19:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ne-konference jOpenSpace 2021 se koná 8. – 10. října 2021 v Hotelu Antoň v Telči. jOpenSpace je česká ne-konference. Konference typu OpenSpace jsou specifické tím, že se jejich program dopředu příliš neplánuje. Mluví se zkrátka o tom, co účastníky zajímá. Nikdo není jen pasivním divákem, každý přispěje svou desetiminutovou prezentací.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Zdenek Henek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima is a luxury brand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hideo-kojima-is-a-luxury-brand</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hideo-kojima-is-a-luxury-brand"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T20:16:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hideo Kojima has been tweeting about the final trailer for Death Stranding: Director's Cut for weeks now. He wants you to know that it was "self-edited", "handmade", that he obsessed over it. He sounds more like someone selling artisinally roasted coffee beans than a Sony-funded blockbuster that contains Monster Energy product placement. 

The trailer is out now and you can watch it below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Is Strange: True Colors review: a more mature LIS, but one still beset by narrative growing pains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/life-is-strange-true-colors-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/life-is-strange-true-colors-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whenever a new Life Is Strange game comes out I sometimes wonder how my life would manifest as an ironic and metaphorical super power. I usually stop quite quickly, because I have a feeling the answer would be somewhat disappointing. In the first game, Max Caulfield discovered she could rewind time or travel back to the past via photographs. In Life Is Strange 2, we shaped the outlook of young Daniel Diaz and how he used his somewhat fraught telekinetic powers. Now, in Life Is Strange: True Colors, we step into the shoes of Alex Chen, who can step into the hearts and minds of others.
Alex is a 21-year-old product of the foster system who can feel, manipulate or even absorb the intense emotions of those around her. We join Alex just as she steps off the bus into a remote Colorado mining town called Haven Springs to start a new life with her brother Gabe. Things - as they typically do during weddings in soap operas, the opening ten minutes of a hospital drama, or the end of the first chapter of a Life Is Strange game - go terribly wrong. What follows is simultaneously my most and least favourite Life Is Strange game.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Artful Escape review: musical odyssey is a one hit wonder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-artful-escape-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-artful-escape-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They call me the Slippery Matthew Castle. Or at least they do aboard the Cosmic Lung, an intergalactic concert hall overseen by a brainstem in a cloak voiced by Jason Schwartzman. Impressively, this is one of the more rote happenings in The Artful Escape, a quest that also takes in astral highways, rock-powered butterflies and - steel yourself - a passive aggressive skiffle group. Its creator, the fabulously named Johnny Galvatron, describes it as what would happen if David Bowie had gone on a literal space trip to become Ziggy Stardust, and that seems about right.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Midnight Suns new gameplay video reveals how this deckbuilding XCOM-like will actually play]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-midnight-suns-new-gameplay-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-midnight-suns-new-gameplay-video"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T15:56:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After announcing their new tactical RPG at Gamescom the other week, Firaxis held a 20 minute livestream for Marvel’s Midnight Suns yesterday, giving us a brand-new look at the game’s card-based combat system, its RPG elements and a deep-dive on how Wolverine, Sabretooth and big bad Lilith will play in-game. And from the looks of things, it's all shaping up very nicely indeed.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaan Serin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whatever you do, don't listen to DokeV's trailer song before bed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whatever-you-do-dont-listen-to-dokevs-trailer-song-before-bed</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whatever-you-do-dont-listen-to-dokevs-trailer-song-before-bed"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T15:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I reckon I'm not too bad at winding down in the evenings. Often I'll chill in Discord with some friends and treat myself to a Müller Corner, maybe even a banana as a special treat. Afterwards (or before, depending on how young the night is), if I'm feeling particularly decadent, I'll run myself a bath and use the special "Muscle Therapy" bubble bath mixture that looks suspiciously like blood.
I'd say most of the time this ritual leads to a solid night's sleep. But for some reason, I got cocky last night. Just before beddy-byes I listened to that music from the DokeV Geoffscom reveal trailer, purely because I thought "why not, huh?". And I've not been the same since.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop concept art shows its characters being absolute fashion icons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-concept-art-shows-its-characters-being-absolute-fashion-icons</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-concept-art-shows-its-characters-being-absolute-fashion-icons"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T15:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, who is the stylist that designs the Deathloop characters' outfits and will you come to my house and design me some too, please? We're less than a week away from playing Arkane's 60s-themed stealth 'em up, and I'm utterly enamoured with the excellent clothes main characters Colt and Juliana get to wear. 


In a recent blog post, assistant art director and lead character artist Jean-Baptiste Ferder shared a little bit of background on how Colt and Juliana were designed, along with some concept art showing various outfits for the stylish duo. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bloodhunt Blood Resonance types explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloodhunt-blood-resonance-types</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bloodhunt-blood-resonance-types"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T15:17:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn what the different Blood Resonance types in Bloodhunt do? It's possibly the most complex and novel system in Sharkmob's new vampiric Battle Royale, but it's important to understand, because the choice of mortals upon whom you feed will determine how your character grows in strength throughout a match.
Below we'll walk you through the four different types of Blood Resonance in Bloodhunt, the effects that each one bestows upon you, and which are the best types of blood for each vampire type. We'll also explain how to increase the number of Blood Resonance points you can obtain over the course of a match.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Razer Basilisk V3 review: A faster, smarter gaming mouse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-basilisk-v3-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/razer-basilisk-v3-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T15:02:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Razer have launched a new version of its customisation-focused wired mouse, the Basilisk V3. Outwardly it looks much like a retread of last year’s Basilisk V2 – the pointy click buttons married to smooth curves, the grippy thumb rest, the stark black-and-RGB colour scheme – but there are enough tweaks to the V3 model that it feels and acts like a very different rodent. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tales Of Arise review: a tale worth telling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tales-of-arise-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tales-of-arise-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many Japanese role-playing games boast unprecedented realism thanks to modern development tools that are capable of building dragons scale-by-scale. But not everyone thrives on a strict diet of grit and grime. I, for one, occasionally break away and indulge the urge to jump into bright, busy JRPGs that check off every anime cliche ever devised. 
These are the JRPGs that actively make me seek battles because it just feels good to leap a metre off the ground and punch an eagle in the face. These are the JRPGs that make me wonder why the protagonist wears a heavy, half-broken mask that probably screws with his peripheral vision. (Then I tell myself that my dumb anime son can do whatever he wants.) These are among my favourite kinds of JRPGs, and Bandai Namco's Tales of Arise keeps good company with them.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Oxford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected is limiting ultrawide support because it breaks the game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-is-limiting-ultrawide-support-because-it-breaks-the-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-is-limiting-ultrawide-support-because-it-breaks-the-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T11:54:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Diablo 2: Resurrected beta opened its fiery gates to everyone last month, and by Alice B’s account it was quite the enjoyable nostalgia trip. Some players, however, may have been having a little too much fun – specifically though the use of ultrawide monitors, which Blizzard say will no longer receive full 21:9 aspect ratio support in the remaster.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlefield 2042 shows off new specialists, who all seem very familiar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-shows-off-new-specialists-who-all-seem-very-familiar</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battlefield-2042-shows-off-new-specialists-who-all-seem-very-familiar"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T11:38:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[EA have dropped new gameplay showing off five of Battlefield 2042's specialists doing things like pulling the trigger, laying down turrets, pulling the trigger, and healing friends with a needle gun. They look good, if very, very predictable.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 92 vylepšuje podporu HTTPS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42798</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/firefox-92-vylepsuje-podporu-https/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T10:07:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na světě je nová verze webového prohlížeče Firefox. Dvaadevadesátka už automaticky přejde na HTTPS spojení s použitím HTTPS RR jako Alt-Svc hlaviček, dále nově podporuje plné spektrum barevných úrovní na mnoha systémech (blíže neupřesněno), na macOS pak v souborovém menu nabízí systémové volby pro sdílení a na témže OS jsou podporovány obrázky obsahující barevné profily ICC v4.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GhostBSD 21.09.06 nahrazuje OpenRC za původní rc.d z FreeBSD]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42797</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ghostbsd-21-09-06-nahrazuje-openrc-za-puvodni-rc-d-z-freebsd/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T09:59:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nové vydání operačního systému GhostBSD, uživatelsky přívětivě variace na FreeBSD, přechází od init systému OpenRC zpět do lůna rc.d z projektu FreeBSD. Sice vlastnosti jako service status v OpenRC jsou fajn, ale udržování jeho podpory v systému je nad síly projektu GhostBSD, a tak bude init řízen pomocí v tomto smyslu bezúdržbového rc.d. OpenRC bude nadále ve zdrojovém stromu GhostBSD minimálně do příštího roku.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tails 4.22 opravuje chyby v asistentu Tor Connection]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42796</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/tails-4-22-opravuje-chyby-v-asistentu-tor-connection/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sešlo se několik problémů s novým asistentem pro připojení, tedy Tor Connection, a na ně se právě soustředí nová verze operačního systému Tails. Řeší chyby týkající se nastavení vlastního bridge, umožněno je ukládat jeden takový do persistentního úložiště, uživatel dále může ručně upravit hodiny, když připojení k Toru selže (zejména to prý pomůže lidem na východ od Londýna, kteří se připoují přes obfs4 bridge a obecně je nyní způsob připojení k Toru robustnější).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saturn Hexagon]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2513/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2513/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jaderné noviny – přehled za srpen 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-srpen-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/jaderne-noviny-prehled-za-srpen-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Přehled srpnových vydání Jaderných novin: stav vydání jádra, citáty týdne a seznam článků týkajících se jádra.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revelation]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2512/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2512/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-06T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Co prozradí myš]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-co-prozradi-mys</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-co-prozradi-mys"/>
        <updated>2021-09-05T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grafen vrací do hry pevné disky, hustota dat může vzrůst až 10krát. Hlavní chyby digitální transformace. Kontejnery jsou klíčová technologie při vývoji podnikových aplikací. Co prozradí myš.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Zachytili rozpad elektronu na chargon a spinon]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-zachytili-rozpad-elektronu-na-chargon-a-spinon</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-zachytili-rozpad-elektronu-na-chargon-a-spinon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kvantové spinové kapaliny. Delší dolet dronů díky palivovým článkům. Po 12 letech ukončuje provoz český tokamak COMPASS. Odhady hmotností černých děr. Pozornost si zaslouží i měsíce Uranu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 35/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-35-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-35-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CDKDeals: Back to School se softwarem produktivity za cenu oběda]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/cdkdeals-back-to-school-se-softwarem-produktivity-za-cenu-obeda</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/cdkdeals-back-to-school-se-softwarem-produktivity-za-cenu-obeda"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nový školní rok je tady, tak neváhejte a pořiďte softwarové nástroje produktivity z nabídky CDKDeals za ceny, které byste mohli přirovnat k platbě za oběd nebo večeři v restauraci! Kdybyste pak chtěli více, třeba hry, vyberete si také. Když před dokončením nákupu zadáte slevový kód AX30, máte dalších 30 % z ceny dolů!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 31-33/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-31-33-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-31-33-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V srpnu byl vydán nejen stabilní Debian 11 „Bullseye“, ale i nový OSMC, elementary OS, Zorin OS, IPFire nebo Sparky Linux. Aktualizací se dočkaly také Tails, Manjaro či KaOS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>