<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-27T22:14:35.739Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-27T22:14:35.739Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTubers Show Old Switch And New OLED Model Running Side By Side]]></title>
        <id>1847755781</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/youtubers-show-old-switch-and-new-oled-model-running-si-1847755781"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T22:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nintendo Switch — OLED Model is coming out soon, and Nintendo recently held events at which the press could try it out alongside Metroid Dread. YouTube channel Nintendo Prime, a gaming enthusiast channel with a preference for Nintendo games, obtained footage of a Switch OLED sent to them by an anonymous viewer.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaiah Colbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam may be planning to restrict player access to old game builds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-may-be-planning-to-restrict-player-access-to-old-game-builds</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-may-be-planning-to-restrict-player-access-to-old-game-builds"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T21:55:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As they always do, things in Steam are likely to change again. Unlike Valve's Steam Labs experiments for storefront discoverability or downstream effects of the upcoming Steam Deck, this one is a little more under the hood. As spotted by the unaffiliated Steam tracking site SteamDB, the beta version of Steam's client now has a new method that is capable of preventing users from accessing former builds of games they own. The majority of players likely aren't pulling up old game builds often, if ever, but this change could make life a lot tougher for modders, speedrunners, and anyone trying to roll back a buggy game update while they wait for a hotfix.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 To Bring Initial DisplayPort 2.0 Support For AMD Radeon Driver (AMDGPU)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-DP-2.0-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-DP-2.0-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T21:46:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A batch of feature updates was submitted today for DRM-Next of early feature work slated to come to the next version of the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Unite Survey Suggests Huge Changes Could Be Coming]]></title>
        <id>1847754725</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-unite-survey-suggests-huge-changes-could-be-com-1847754725"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that Pokémon Unite has made its Android and iOS debut, developer TiMi Studio Group has pushed out an in-game survey for players to complete. The questionnaire suggests that some new features, like additional game modes and more ways to interact with your monsters, might come to the popular MOBA in the future.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oculus announces Resident Evil 4 VR release date for October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oculus-announces-resident-evil-4-vr-release-date-for-october</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/oculus-announces-resident-evil-4-vr-release-date-for-october"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:14:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[October is creeping up on us all and, like a proper jump scare just before I'd expected it, so has Resident Evil 4 VR. Leon Kennedy's spooky cult adventure begins again in the first-person and hands-on version that's arriving on the Oculus Quest 2 next month. Now that you'll be getting all up close and personal with Salazar and Saddler and El Gigante and all, they've gotten some fresh pixels as well, which you can catch a look at once again in a new trailer.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rune Factory 5 Will Finally Let The Gays Marry]]></title>
        <id>1847754456</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/rune-factory-5-will-finally-let-the-gays-marry-1847754456"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a lengthy blog post, Rune Factory 5’s publishers confirmed that the English localization will allow same-gender marriages. This decision marks the first time that Rune Factory players can get gay married without a workaround.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastward: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
        <id>1847753920</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/eastward-the-kotaku-review-1847753920"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eastward is a phenomenally constructed video game. All of its music hits. The characters are relentlessly charming. Its art and level design are nothing short of extraordinary. Disregarding a few pacing missteps, the game fires on all cylinders for its entire duration. Hell, they even put a second video game in the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Renata Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonic The Hedgehog Returns To The Macy's Parade, Almost 30 Years After Injuring Two People]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121488</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/sonic_the_hedgehog_returns_to_the_macys_parade_almost_30_years_after_injuring_two_people"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He's hungry for blood again.
The Sonic the Hedgehog Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade balloon has a chaotic, yet thrilling history: He was the first-ever video game character to be represented as a Macy's Parade balloon, but he's also the most removed balloon in the parade's history. And now, he's back.
He first appeared in the Thanksgiving parade in 1993, as a 64-feet-tall balloon filled with helium and hope, but strong winds turned his debut into a disaster. In a twist that seemed orchestrated by Eggman himself, Sonic was stabbed in the eye by a lamp post, and the falling debris injured an off-duty police officer and a ten-year-old girl (who were both fine, don't worry).
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bethesda Gives Deathloop Actor A PS5 So He Can Play His Own Game]]></title>
        <id>1847754110</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/bethesda-gives-deathloop-actor-a-ps5-so-he-can-play-his-1847754110"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actor Jason Kelley, who voices Colt in the recently released Deathloop, is among the many still unable to get their hands on a PlayStation 5. After admitting his problem, Bethesda helped out and got him one, IGN reported. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death Stranding Director’s Cut Makes Its Private Rooms Even Creepier]]></title>
        <id>1847753637</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/death-stranding-director-s-cut-makes-its-private-rooms-1847753637"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new Director’s Cut edition of Death Stranding has only been out for a few days, but folks are already finding a slew of new Easter eggs, some of which add to the nightmare fuel that occasionally haunted unsuspecting players in the original game’s private rooms.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Switch OLED Comparison Video Has Surfaced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121490</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/the_first_switch_oled_comparison_video_has_surfaced"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's BIG.
YouTubers have been getting their hands on the Nintendo Switch OLED ahead of release, and after last week's Switch OLED unboxing from Japanese YouTuber HikakinTV, another video has arrived: an unboxing from Nintendo Prime which also features a comparison to the original Nintendo Switch.
As you can see, the OLED's screen is quite a lot bigger and a little bit brighter than the original, and although we knew that the screen would be 0.8 inches larger, it was pretty hard to envision what that meant.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Intel Software Defined Silicon" Coming To Linux For Activating Extra Licensed Hardware Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Software-Defined-Silicon</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Software-Defined-Silicon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:45:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has been talk of Intel moving to offer more license-able/opt-in features for hardware capabilities found within a given processor as an upgrade. We are now seeing the Linux signs of that support coming with a driver for "Intel Software Defined Silicon" to allow for the secure activation of such features baked into the processor's silicon but only available as an up-charge option...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix's lady assassin movie Kate is getting an action roguelike tie-in game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-lady-assassin-movie-kate-is-getting-an-action-roguelike-tie-in-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflixs-lady-assassin-movie-kate-is-getting-an-action-roguelike-tie-in-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been positively held hostage by the lady assassin action movie trend—having been in the same room as my partner relentlessly devouring the likes of The Old Guard, Ava, Terminal, and Gunpowder Milkshake. No surprise then that I also got sucked into watching Kate, Netflix's new action movie starring assassin Mary Elizabeth Winstead and her teen hostage slash sidekick Miku Martineau. What is surprising—even though Netflix have shown an increasing interest in games—is that Kate is getting a tie-in action game called Kate: Collateral Damage. It's a fast-paced and arcade-y roguelike with some twin-stick style shooting coming out in October.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Real Guy From The Big Short Gets Subpoenaed About GameStop]]></title>
        <id>1847753415</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-real-guy-from-the-big-short-gets-subpoenaed-about-g-1847753415"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The frenzy around GameStop and other meme stocks from earlier this year may have quieted down a bit, but the SEC is still diligently on the case, trying to get to the bottom of what happened. That apparently includes subpoenaing big time investor Michael Burry, famous for betting against the 2000s housing bubble, and…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: Let's Take A Closer Look At Kirby And The Forgotten Land's Debut Trailer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121463</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/video_lets_take_a_closer_look_at_kirby_and_the_forgotten_lands_debut_trailer"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every scene analysed.
One of the highlights from last week's Nintendo Direct was without question the reveal of Kirby and the Forgotten Land, a new 3D Kirby game headed to Switch next year.
We were treated to just over two minutes of footage in total consisting of large 3D spaces, combat and copy abilities, and lots of Kirby waddling around on his lonesome. In fact, having gotten so used to the Kirby Star Allies-style formula, where Kirby and friends find themselves bouncing around more compact 2D levels, seeing our favourite puffball roaming around such a vast area was quite the sight to behold.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This 27-in 240Hz Samsung monitor is £229 right now (£70 off)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-27-in-240hz-samsung-monitor-is-229-right-now-70-off</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-27-in-240hz-samsung-monitor-is-229-right-now-70-off"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T17:55:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a while, I was super into Counter-Strike: Global Offensive, and I took getting better at the game very seriously. I swapped out my mouse and headset, practiced grenade line-ups for hours and even learned a few Russian phrases to try and get the respect of my match-making teammates. All these steps worked, but the real results came when I swapped my old 144Hz monitor for a 240Hz model, the Samsung CRG5. Hitting such a high frame-rate in Counter-Strike isn't difficult even on old hardware, and the increase in clarity meant hitting shots a lot easier. 
If you want to follow in my footsteps, then it's good news: this 240Hz screen is going cheap on Amazon today. They're asking £229 for it, £70 off its regular price of £299, and I think that's a great deal. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rare Mew Pokémon Oreos Are Selling For Thousands]]></title>
        <id>1847752974</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/rare-mew-pokemon-oreos-are-selling-for-thousands-1847752974"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T17:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best quick-buck scheme of the year isn’t GameStop stock, cryptocurrency, or reselling next-gen consoles. It’s...Pokémon Oreos? Oreos emblazoned with designs of Mew, the psychic-type feline Pokémon, are currently selling for hundreds if not thousands of dollars on eBay.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite Is Filled With Memes, Dataminers Unfortunately Reveal]]></title>
        <id>1847752115</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-is-filled-with-memes-dataminers-unfortun-1847752115"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite’s latest multiplayer technical preview (or, in actual terms, beta) is live, and has been for a few days now. And while the beta offers only a small taste of what will be available in the online shooter once it releases later this year, dataminers and curious fans have been digging into the game’s files…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Actraiser Renaissance - A Noble Attempt At Resurrecting The Godly 16-Bit Classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121371</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/actraiser_renaissance"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the lap of the gods.
The original Actraiser was a truly seminal release. Launched alongside the Super Famicom at the close of 1990, Quintet's skilful blend of platforming action and Populous-style world-building was immediately lauded as a stone-cold classic, and it's striking that in the 30 years that have passed since, it has never been bettered. Direct sequel Actraiser 2 unwisely ditched the 'God Sim' sections, and the recent 'spiritual successor' SolSeraph tried and failed to capture the same magic. Then, out of the blue in September 2021, Square Enix shadow-dropped Actraiser Renaissance, a full remake of the original game developed not by Quintet (that studio has long since been disbanded), but by Sonic Powered, a Japanese outfit best known for its Boku wa Koukuu Kanseikan: Airport Hero series.
Actraiser Renaissance retains the unique two-genre setup of the 1990 version, with the player assuming the role of a benevolent deity who seeks to liberate the world from the evil clutches of the Dark Lord Tanzra, who has cruelly subjugated several regions via his dutiful sub-lieutenants. Each area offers two distinct gameplay styles; first, you must take the form of a warrior character – your physical embodiment on earth, essentially – and tackle a side-scrolling action section that culminates in a boss fight. When you've done this, the game switches to a top-down view of the region, where you directly control your talkative angel helper. Here, you can guide the direction in which your settlement grows while using your angel to take down respawning aerial monsters with holy arrows. The aim is to locate and tackle a second side-scrolling section and defeat Tanzra's champion for that region, bringing lasting peace and prosperity before you move onto the next location to repeat the process.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung's 2TB 870 Evo SSD is down to £197.50 at Amazon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/samsungs-2tb-870-evo-ssd-is-down-to-19750-at-amazon</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/samsungs-2tb-870-evo-ssd-is-down-to-19750-at-amazon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:55:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We reckon that Samsung's 870 Evo is the best SATA SSD for gaming, and today the mammoth 2TB model has been reduced on Amazon. It's now retailing for £197.50, the best price we've seen on this drive since the Chia mining craze began and some £45 below RRP. It's even cheaper than the (older and slower) 860 Evo. Here's a link to the deal and a few more words on why we like this particular drive so very much. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Judd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arknights Low Rarity Characters Are Better Than High Rarity Ones]]></title>
        <id>1847752102</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/arknights-low-rarity-characters-are-better-than-high-ra-1847752102"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arknights, the enormously successful tower defense game, does something special in the crowded field of gacha games: Some of the most common characters in the game can help clear difficult levels that their rarer counterparts can’t. By giving the consolation prize characters unique niches, Arknights builds up a more…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breathedge Is So, So Good, But Also So, So Bad]]></title>
        <id>1847752037</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/breathedge-is-so-so-good-but-also-so-so-bad-1847752037"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have longed for a space survival game that makes me feel the same way Subnautica does. That sense of methodical management, combined with serene isolation, is my gaming happy place, and I was so delighted to see Breathedge popping up on Game Pass this month, a game that looked like it would deliver it. Except, oh…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Infographic Shows Every Game Featured In September's Direct]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121480</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/nintendo_infographic_shows_every_game_featured_in_septembers_direct"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time to circle those favourites!
As has become something of a tradition at this point, Nintendo has shared its usual infographic showcasing all the games that were featured in last week's Nintendo Direct presentation.
If you're keen on getting these downloaded and circling all of your favourites to share on social media, get the image saved and have some fun. Lots of exciting games were included in the show, including the likes of Kirby and the Forgotten Land and Bayonetta 3, as well as all of the Nintendo Switch Online additions, of course!
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix shows off more The Witcher season 2 clips and announces season 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-shows-off-more-the-witcher-season-2-clips-and-announces-season-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/netflix-shows-off-more-the-witcher-season-2-clips-and-announces-season-3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you thought there was any risk of Netflix dumping Geralt and company in the near future, you can rest your head easy after this weekend. They've now shown off several more clips for the upcoming second season of their main, Cavill-powered Witcher TV series and also announced that they're definitely going to be going for a third season. Not just that, but there are even more Witcher projects on the way: another animated movie, that Blood Origin series, and—for some unfathomable reason—a children's show. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Debuts At Tourney, Seemingly Missing Jeff Kaplan Nod]]></title>
        <id>1847751895</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-debuts-at-tourney-seemingly-missing-jeff-k-1847751895"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some of the best players in the world took the reins to Overwatch 2 over the weekend during the recent Overwatch League 2021 championship. During the tourney broadcast, these pros showed off a couple of big character reworks and strategic overhauls coming to the sequel, while also highlighting an apparent missing…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Gach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commuting home from work turns mighty spooky in this indie game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/commuting-home-from-work-turns-mighty-spooky-in-this-indie-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/commuting-home-from-work-turns-mighty-spooky-in-this-indie-game"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:56:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Plane Effect is a moody isometric adventure game about a guy trying to get home. Pretty normal stuff, except there is a cosmic anomaly looming over the city that seems to be causing some weirdness, so good luck with that. Out now, the game will have you puzzling through levels full of high-contrast moody lighting. It reminds me a bit of Inside, if Inside had rooms full of scary-looking red lasers.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo II: Resurrected Keeps Barring Players From Using Their Own Characters]]></title>
        <id>1847751590</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/diablo-ii-resurrected-keeps-barring-players-from-using-1847751590"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo II: Resurrected launched last week with a host of annoying bugs and glitches, as is Blizzard tradition. While many of the crash-causing, progression-halting issues have been patched, other players continue to be plagued by a bug that’s keeping their characters from being able to join games.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK Charts: Mario Kart 8 Deluxe Takes Pole In A Switch-Exclusive Top Three]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121481</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/uk_charts_mario_kart_8_deluxe_takes_pole_in_a_switch-exclusive_top_three"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Super Lucky's Tale enters top 40.
UK physical chart data is now in for the week ending 25th September, revealing that Mario Kart 8 Deluxe has once again screeched into first place.
The game leads a top three made up exclusively of Switch games, with Minecraft and Animal Crossing: New Horizons following close behind. Last week's number one Deathloop falls to fifth spot, while Sega's latest release, Lost Judgment, debuts in fourth.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch Streamers' Lives Are About To Get Much Better, Thanks To This Chat Change]]></title>
        <id>1847751548</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/twitch-streamers-lives-are-about-to-get-much-better-th-1847751548"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch streamers may soon be able to restrict who can or cannot hop into the chat. According to Twitch observer Zach Bussey, the streaming giant is planning on adding expanded features that would allow streamers to require phone or email verification from the commentariat.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ari Notis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Hot Wheels Unleashed - Probably The Best Hot Wheels Game Ever]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121066</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/hot_wheels_unleashed"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More die-cast fun than a game of D&D.
There are few licences out there that are better suited to a video game than Hot Wheels. After all, when the whole brand revolves around collecting a wide variety of tiny cars then creating over-the-top tracks for them to race on, it’s fair to say that any game that manages to capture that essence of pure fun is well on its way to becoming a success.
Hot Wheels Unleashed is the latest attempt to digitise the toy series and it's probably the best Hot Wheels game to date. That said, there’s just something about it (at launch, at least) that leaves us wanting a little bit more.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing ingredients in Potion Craft is better than meditation or yoga]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/smashing-ingredients-in-potion-craft-is-better-than-mediation-or-yoga</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/smashing-ingredients-in-potion-craft-is-better-than-mediation-or-yoga"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T14:39:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Potion Craft came out in early access last week, and while I still think the economy and haggling bits need a little tweaking, I am really enjoying the methodical nature of being an alchemist. It's part art, part science, because you have to sort of feel your way around the potion map and fudge recipes with the ingredients you have. Your recipe book is limited, so I've started writing down extra recipes in real life, crossing things out and updating them as I find better combinations. It's just like being a real backwoods alchemist throwing twigs in a bucket!
But my favourite thing is the pestle and mortar. Smashing ingredients up (and grinding them into sludge) awakens their properties so they move further on your potion map, like how crushing mint will make for a livelier mojito. And I love it intensely.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 will make murderbot Bastion more mobile]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-will-make-murderbot-bastion-more-mobile</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overwatch-2-will-make-murderbot-bastion-more-mobile"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rejoice! The absolute pain in the arse that is Bastion is getting a rework for Overwatch 2, and he'll no longer be able to heal himself or turn into a murderous tank. He will be a lot more mobile and have a sticky grenade however, so watch out for that. Over the weekend, Blizzard revealed the changes coming to both Bastion and Sombra in the sequel. While Sombra's tweaks are a little more minimal, it looks like Bastion's will make him play a whole lot differently. Importantly, he'll also wear one of Torbjorn's caps. Fashion.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rune Factory 5 Will Feature Same-Sex Marriage In The West]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121354</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/rune_factory_5_will_feature_same-sex_marriage_in_the_west"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Players can marry all 12 candidates.
Rune Factory 5 was one of the many games shown off in the September 2021 Nintendo Direct, and it was revealed that for the first time in the series, we're going to get the ability to marry people of the same gender — despite rumours to the contrary.

Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Party Superstars Includes 100 Minigames - Here's The Full List]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121471</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/mario_party_superstars_includes_100_minigames_-_heres_the_full_list"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All minigames from N64 to Wii U.
Mario Party is always a good bit of fun when you have family or friends over, and while the boards themselves are often thought of as the main attraction, we all know that the minigames are really where it's at. Right?
Well, the good news is that Mario Party Superstars, set to launch on Switch on 29th October, will include a whopping 100 minigames to play that have been cherry-picked from games gone by. You might want to head to safety if you'd rather not be spoiled because we're about to share the full list for you right here.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghostscript 9.55.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ghostscript-9.55.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ghostscript-9.55.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:57:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze 9.55.0 interpretu PostScriptu (PS) a Portable Document Formatu (PDF) Ghostscript. Mimo jiné byla opravena bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2021-3781, na kterou byl nedávno zveřejněn exploit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything that we know about the Warden in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-warden-deep-dark</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-warden-deep-dark"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:07:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know more about the Warden in Minecraft? The Warden is a new mob that will arrive in Minecraft 1.18, otherwise known as the Caves and Cliffs update. It is set to be a terrifying addition, making every adventure underground a trip that could result in a particularly scary death.
This guide will cover everything that we currently know about the Warden in Minecraft, including its behaviour and where it will spawn.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands On: Metroid Dread's First Hour Is Legit Kinda Terrifying]]></title>
        <id>1847742944</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/hands-on-metroid-dreads-first-hour-is-legit-kinda-terr-1847742944"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If there’s one thing I want from Metroid games above all else, it’s a feeling of dread.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carolyn Petit</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: We've Actually Played Metroid Dread, Does It Meet Our Expectations?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121464</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/video_weve_actually_played_metroid_dread_does_it_meet_our_expectations"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[The same 'dread' pun everyone else has made].
That's right, we've finally managed to get our mitts on Metroid Dread (temporarily); Nintendo UK were kind enough to invite us down for a good old fashioned preview in their showroom so we could have a go on it using one of those swanky new Switch OLED Model consoles to boot.
Our expectations were high, but hoo lordy we were still majorly impressed. We got around 90-100 minutes of playtime before having the console metaphorically slapped from our hands as we'd done all we were allowed to do, and we loved every bleeding second of it.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Image Of The Last Of Us Live-Action Series From HBO]]></title>
        <id>1847750359</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/first-image-of-the-last-of-us-live-action-series-from-h-1847750359"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Naughty Dog’s post-apocalyptic survival yarn is getting a live-action series from HBO. Here’s a first look at the upcoming show.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wonderbox Is Like Zelda Meets Captain Toad's Treasure Tracker]]></title>
        <id>1847743299</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/wonderbox-is-like-zelda-meets-captain-toads-treasure-tr-1847743299"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I really enjoyed the Captain Toad mini-games in this year’s expanded Switch version of Super Mario 3D World; they gave my mind a welcome reprieve from the frustration of navigating the main adventure’s floaty, 3D platforming. I know Captain Toad: Treasure Tracker has long been a thing, and while I have yet to get…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Horizon Chase Turbo Honours F1's Ayrton Senna In New 'Senna Forever' Expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121468</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/horizon_chase_turbo_honours_f1s_ayrton_senna_in_new_senna_forever_expansion"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Including new single-player career.
Brazilian developer AQUIRIS has announced Senna Forever, a brand new expansion for Horizon Chase Turbo that'll honour legendary Brazilian racing driver, Ayrton Senna.
Launching on 20th October, the new expansion introduces an entirely new set of cars, tracks, and features inspired by Senna's career, and will even offer a new single-player career mode that lets you follow Senna's own motorsport journey.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing The New ASUS Platform Profile Support In Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30554</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30554"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:15:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the in-development Linux 5.15 kernel there is now support for ACPI Platform Profiles on supported ASUS laptops. This ASUS laptop platform profile support joins the likes of HP, Dell, and Lenovo laptops already having this support exposed under Linux that allows users to control their power/performance preference. Here are some tests with the ASUS ROG Strix G15 AMD Advantage laptop with the platform profile options under Linux 5.15.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření HTTPS Everywhere míří do důchodu, už není potřeba]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42856</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rozsireni-https-everywhere-miri-do-duchodu-uz-neni-potreba/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Frontier Foundation se připravuje na postupné ukončení podpory pro rozšíření HTTPS Everywhere, které na webech automaticky přepíná z HTTP na HTTPS. To už podle organizace začíná být zbytečné, protože rozšíření HTTPS zažilo v posledních letech výrazný nárůst a prohlížeče navíc přišly s vlastním řešením automatického přechodu na HTTPS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSSH 8.8 vypíná podporu protokolu ssh-rsa]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42855</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/openssh-8-8-vypina-podporu-protokolu-ssh-rsa/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:03:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili novou verzi balíku OpenSSH s označením 8.8. Hlavní novinkou je vypnutí podpory protokolu ssh-rsa, který staví na slabém hašovacím algoritmu SHA-1. Na změnu upozorňovalo několik předchozích verzí, většina uživatelů si navíc ničeho nevšimne, protože OpenSSH podporuje algoritmy RSA/SHA-256/512 (RFC8332) od verze 7.2 a automaticky je použije.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astria Ascending Is The Prettiest Turn-Based Game I’ve Ever Played]]></title>
        <id>1847741591</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/astria-ascending-is-the-prettiest-turn-based-game-i-ve-1847741591"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Astria Ascending is a turn-based JRPG with gameplay that pays homage to Bravely Default and Octopath Traveler. I enjoyed the combat in both of those titles, but the colorful art style of Astria Ascending felt like an upgrade from the somber color palette of those games. It also puts an interesting twist on the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sisi Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zarude Arrives In Pokémon GO This Week, Here's How To Get One]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121461</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/zarude_arrives_in_pokemon_go_this_week_heres_how_to_get_one"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jot down these dates and times.
Another rare and elusive Mythical Pokémon is set to appear for the very first time in Pokémon GO this week, and you'll want to get your hands on one while you can.
In celebration of the upcoming global release of Pokémon the Movie: Secrets of the Jungle, which is set to launch worldwide on Netflix on 8th October, the Rogue Monkey Pokémon Zarude will be appearing in-game. Other content inspired by the movie will also be present, including the return of Team Rocket's Jessie and James.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astria Ascending review: peak tedium]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/astria-ascending-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/astria-ascending-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the face of it, Astria Ascending should be right up my street. With its lush visuals, intriguing character designs and often engaging turn-based battle system, this handsome hand drawn adventure could have been a surprise dark horse to rival recent JRPG greats such as Tales Of Arise and Bravely Default II. Colombian RPG Cris Tales managed it, so why not Astria Ascending?
French Canadian developers Artisan Studios have certainly tried hard to fulfill J part of this Japanese-inspired RPG, acquiring the talents of Final Fantasy XII composer Hitoshi Sakimoto and Final Fantasy X writer Kazushige Nojima to bolster their small team, but even these big name veterans can't salvage this game from the depths of its own tedium. Between its bewildering, colour-swap dungeons, cringeworthy voice acting and uneven focus on its large cast, Astria Ascending stumbles before it ever has the chance to soar. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim food and cooking: all recipes, what buffs they provide, and where to cook them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-food-cooking</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-food-cooking"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:25:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you cook in Valheim? Valheim has never been short on food and recipes, but with the recent Hearth & Home update, the game's cooking system has been significantly expanded and overhauled. Gone are the days when nearly every animal dropped the same generic type of meat, or when you could cook sausages without the right spices (ugh, so bland, you monster). The buffs offered by some of the original foods have also been rebalanced, so read on for an up-to-date culinary guide to Valheim.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected players still can't access some of their characters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-players-still-cant-access-some-of-their-characters</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-players-still-cant-access-some-of-their-characters"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:23:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected launched last week, letting players dive into a remaster of Blizzard's hellish action-RPG. Alas, "hellish" seems appropriate in more ways than one, because players are still struggling with launch bugs. While the developers issued a number of fixes over the weekend, some players are still experiencing "lockout", meaning they can't play with certain characters because the game thinks they're already in use.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kampaň na programovatelnou kameru OAK-D-Lite na Kickstarteru]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42853</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/kampan-na-programovatelnou-kameru-oak-d-lite-na-kickstarteru/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:22:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na Kickstarteru před několika dny začala kampaň na novou verzi kamery OAK-D-Lite. Umožní snadno a rychle vytvořit aplikaci, která bude pracovat s obsahem videa. Může například rozpoznávat SPZ, překládat znakový jazyk, rozpoznávat gesta rukou a podobně.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: spider-x)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[23. stretnutie komunity ohľadne technológií Cloud Native – Kubernetes - ONLINE]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42854</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/23-stretnutie-komunity-ohladne-technologii-cloud-native-kubernetes-online/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dňa 29. 9. 2021 od 18:00 do 20:00, 23. stretnutie komunity ohľadne technológií Cloud Native – Kubernetes – ONLINE]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallery: Feast Your Eyes On 21 Screenshots Of Bayonetta 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121459</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/gallery_feast_your_eyes_on_21_screenshots_of_bayonetta_3"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our closest look yet.
Footage of Bayonetta 3 is finally out in the wild, and we've got the screenshots to prove it.
Yes, as you'll probably already know, the first trailer for Bayonetta 3 was finally unveiled during last week's Nintendo Direct. Featuring just about as many terrifying monsters and sassy witches as you'd expect, the clip showed off what promises to be an ambitious new title for the series, and one that fans will no doubt be looking forward to all the more having finally seen their first glimpse.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elder Scrolls Online video shows Nvidia’s new DLAA tech in action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elder-scrolls-online-video-shows-nvidias-new-dlaa-tech-in-action</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elder-scrolls-online-video-shows-nvidias-new-dlaa-tech-in-action"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T10:37:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls Online is the first game to implement Nvidia DLAA (Deep Learning Anti-Aliasing), and thanks to YouTuber MxBenchmarkPC you can now see how the AI-powered edge-smoothing system looks in the fantasy MMO. DLAA is a new spin on Nvidia’s existing DLSS (Deep Learning Super-Sampling): whereas DLSS involves rendering a game at a lower resolution then upscaling, reducing the performance hit of the AA it applies, DLAA skips the upscaling part and keeps the resolution native.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If You Want Bayonetta 3 On PlayStation Or Xbox, Hideki Kamiya Says To Tell Nintendo]]></title>
        <id>1847750165</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/if-you-want-bayonetta-3-on-playstation-or-xbox-tell-ni-1847750165"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first Bayonetta was multiplatform. But the game’s sequel was a Nintendo exclusive, as is the upcoming Bayonetta 3. Other than getting a Switch, what should PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S owners do if they want to play the game? Tell Nintendo, says the game’s executive director, Hideki Kamiya. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Ashcraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSSH 8.8]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/openssh-8.8</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/openssh-8.8"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T10:09:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána nová verze 8.8 sady aplikací pro SSH komunikaci OpenSSH. Dle plánu je ve výchozím nastavení zakázán algoritmus ssh-rsa kvůli možnému útoku na SHA-1. V blízké budoucnosti bude scp pro přenosy používat SFTP místo SCP/RCP. Řešena je bezpečnostní chyba CVE-2021-41617.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capcom Will Share More On Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak In TGS Spotlight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121455</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/capcom_will_share_more_on_monster_hunter_rise_sunbreak_in_tgs_spotlight"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airing this week at a rather convenient time.
For those of us that rather enjoy riding Palamutes named after dearly-departed canine friends and fighting awesome monsters, last week's Nintendo Direct started particularly well. It brought the reveal of Monster Hunter Rise: Sunbreak, which promises to be a significant expansion for the game next Summer.
Its timing - a few months after the game also arrives on PC - hopefully points to an Iceborne-style expansion in terms of scope (which gave fresh life to Monster Hunter: World). The good news is that we'll learn more soon, with Capcom hosting a spotlight presentation at Tokyo Game Show focused on Sunbreak.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ELK Stack: naučte se Elasticsearch, Logstash a Kibana (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40262</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/elk-stack-naucte-se-elasticsearch-logstach-a-kibana-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:53:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Většina počítačových programů generuje logy – tedy zprávy a záznamy o své činnosti. ELK Stack – ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana – je populární nástroj, který umí logy efektivně zpracovávat, ukládat a zpřístupňovat.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs Merges Support For Btrfs-Like Snapshots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bcachefs-Lands-Snapshots</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bcachefs-Lands-Snapshots"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:34:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a while since having any news to report on Bcachefs as the promising open-source file-system born out of the Linux kernel's block cache code. However, Kent Overstreet continues working tirelessly on it and has now merged Bcachefs' snapshot support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania "Would Never Have Come To Be" Without The Fans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121458</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/super_monkey_ball_banana_mania_would_never_have_come_to_be_without_the_fans"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New camera and minigames explained.
Super Monkey Ball Banana Mania will be rolling onto Nintendo Switch in just over a week and from our time with the game so far, it's shaping up to be a very enjoyable experience indeed.
We'll share our full thoughts on how the game stands up to the original Super Monkey Ball and its sequel (what with Banana Mania being a remake of these two titles) in our review a little closer to release, but in the meantime, the game's director Masao Shirosaki has been busy discussing some of the improvements and tweaks the team has been working on.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Crypto Driver Being Worked On For Linux, Yields Much Better AES Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Nintendo-AES-Crypto-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Nintendo-AES-Crypto-Driver"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:22:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel support around the Nintendo Wii and Wii U game console hardware continues to improve and now a new Nintendo crypto driver is being tackled based on reverse-engineered documentation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lavapipe Mesa Software Driver Enables Vulkan 1.2 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lavapipe-Vulkan-1.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lavapipe-Vulkan-1.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:10:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adding to the growing list of Mesa 21.3 features for next quarter's feature release is Lavapipe now supporting Vulkan 1.2...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pokémon Unite's Latest Update Fixes Crustle And Lucario Bugs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121451</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/pokemon_unites_latest_update_fixes_crustle_and_lucario_bugs"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of this week's new character arrival.
Yet another minor update has been released for Pokémon Unite, this time fixing bugs relating to two of the game's battle stars.
The two Pokémon in question are Crustle and Lucario; issues which saw Crustle's strength being unintentionally boosted and Lucario's Extreme Speed doing more damage than intended under certain conditions have now been fixed.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MediaTek Hoping To Bring nanoMIPS Support Upstream Into GCC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MediaTek-2021-nanoMIPS-GCC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MediaTek-2021-nanoMIPS-GCC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The nanoMIPS architecture that was announced by MIPS in 2018 for embedded devices to lower power consumption and yield smaller code footprints was announced for the MIPS I7200 but since then there hasn't been much of nanoMIPS. However, MediaTek is now looking to contribute upstream the compiler support for this processor ISA into GCC...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TeXstudio 4.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/texstudio-4.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/texstudio-4.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T23:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TeXstudio (Wikipedie), tj. integrované prostředí pro vytváření dokumentů v LaTeXu, bylo vydáno ve verzi 4.0.0. Přehled novinek v changelogu. Díky podpoře Qt6 byla vylepšena podpora HiDPI.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Week In Games: A Whole New World, A Dazzling Place]]></title>
        <id>1847749113</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-week-in-games-a-whole-new-world-a-dazzling-place-1847749113"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After what feels like years of beta and alpha testing, Amazon’s first (successful) game is out later this week. New World is a new MMORPG hitting PC this Tuesday, September 28.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chcete vědět kolik byste mohli vydělávat u konkurence na stejné pozici?]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/chcete-vedet-kolik-byste-mohli-vydelavat-u-konkurence-na-stejne-pozici</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/chcete-vedet-kolik-byste-mohli-vydelavat-u-konkurence-na-stejne-pozici"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peníze jsou ožehavé téma, obzvlášť jedná-li se o výplaty v zaměstnání. Člověk přemýšlí, zda kolegové nevydělávají víc nebo jestli by si u jiného zaměstnavatele nepolepšil. Jak to ale zjistit? Teď naštěstí jednoduše, protože IT pracovní portál No Fluff Jobs u všech nabídek zveřejňuje nabízené platové ohodnocení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postřehy z bezpečnosti: velká úroda malwaru i zranitelností]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15681</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/postrehy-z-bezpecnosti-velka-uroda-malwaru-i-zranitelnosti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tentokrát se podíváme na zranitelnosti WordPressu, Drupalu, Apache OpenOffice a Nagiosu, na malware Capoae a OpenSUpdater. Naopak potěší, že provozovatel DDoSových serverů i mafiáni dojdou zasloužené odplaty.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: CESNET CERTS)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční věstník: Ubuntu 21.10 v betě, LineageOS podporuje nová zařízení]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15677</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/distribucni-vestnik-ubuntu-21-10-v-bete-lineageos-podporuje-nova-zarizeni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical vydal veřejnou betu Ubuntu 21.10 „Impish Indri“. Tým kolem operačního systému FreeBSD plánuje změnit výchozí root shell. Operační systém LineageOS 18.1 rozšířil seznam podporovaných zařízení.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Filip Zatloukal)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc3 Released - Looking "Pretty Normal" Plus Performance Fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T21:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds has now issued the third weekly release candidate of the forthcoming Linux 5.15 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Hate Myself, But I Love Taco Bell's New Chicken Sandwich Taco]]></title>
        <id>1847748830</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/i-hate-myself-but-i-love-taco-bells-new-chicken-sandwi-1847748830"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T20:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taco Bell has a new chicken sandwich that’s also a taco, but is also not a taco or even really a sandwich. It’s weird. Yet, even weirder than all that is that I.. like it?  
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Every Nintendo Switch Online N64 Game Ranked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-100445</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/every-nintendo-switch-online-n64-game-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All the N64 games, ranked by you.
The library of N64 games announced as part of the upcoming 'Expansion Pack' for the Nintendo Switch Online subscription service boasts some of the system's heaviest hitters and a good first pass at getting a varied catalogue of quality 64-bit games in the hands of Switch owners.
But which of the N64 games coming the Nintendo Switch Online are the very best? Well, we can answer that question with the help of Nintendo Life readers who have rated the titles on our Games Database.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Step Aside Lady Dimitrescu, There's A New Evil And Tall Video Game Queen]]></title>
        <id>1847748564</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/step-aside-lady-dimitrescu-theres-a-new-evil-and-tall-1847748564"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lady Dimitrescu aka the tall vampire woman from Resident Evil Village is great. She quickly became super popular online and around these parts, many Kotaku staffers adored her too. But when the game came out she fizzled out and was barely involved in the overall story or action of Village. That’s why I’m here to say,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rumour: Game Boy And Game Boy Color Games Still Expected For Switch Online]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121448</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/rumour_game_boy_and_game_boy_color_games_still_expected_for_switch_online"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T17:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And could be part of the "current" service.
Nintendo lifted the lid on a new tier of Switch Online retro offerings this week. The new 'Expansion Pack' will be comprised of a "collection" of Nintendo 64 and Sega Mega Drive (Genesis) titles.
So, what about those rumoured handheld systems for Nintendo's online service? While there's no sign of them, Eurogamer's news editor, Tom Phillips, has now shared a bit of an update on Twitter - suggesting Game Boy and Game Boy Color titles are still on the way.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 92 vs. Chrome 94 Browser Benchmarks On Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-92-Chrome-94-Benchmarks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-92-Chrome-94-Benchmarks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T17:29:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given last week's release of Chrome 94, here are some fresh browser benchmarks looking at Firefox 92 stable against Chrome 94 running on Ubuntu Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide: Best Castlevania Games On Nintendo Consoles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-96840</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-castlevania-games-on-nintendo-consoles"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far from a miserable pile.
In honour of the series' 35th anniversary — yes, it's 35 years since Castlevania first launched in Japan on the Famicom Disk System on 26th September 1986 — we're republishing our ranked list of every Castlevania game on Nintendo consoles. Enjoy!

The Castlevania series has a rich history on Nintendo consoles ever since the original game came first to the Japanese Famicom Disk System way back in 1986, and then to the NES a year later. There may be a significant release or two from Konami's vampire-killing catalogue still missing from Nintendo platforms (we're looking at you, Symphony of the Night), but the vast majority of the series can be found on Nintendo consoles.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wild Halo Infinite Bug Creates An Endless Wave Of Wet Floor Signs]]></title>
        <id>1847746928</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/wild-halo-infinite-bug-creates-an-endless-wave-of-wet-f-1847746928"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been said many, many times, but video games are very hard to make and stupid complex. So there will always be bugs. Some bugs are annoying and ruin a game. Other bugs, like some that are popping up in the Halo Infinite beta, are funny and just a hoot to look at it. Let’s look at some! 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayonetta 3 Might Have Borrowed A Mechanic From Platinum's Cancelled Xbox Exclusive Scalebound]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121446</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/bayonetta_3_might_have_borrowed_a_mechanic_from_platinums_cancelled_xbox_exclusive_scalebound"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And the links don't end there...
The Bayonetta 3 Nintendo Direct trailer began like a scene out of Astral Chain and ended up looking more like something from PlatinumGames' cancelled action-RPG Xbox project, Scalebound.
Why, though? As highlighted by former Scalebound creative producer, JP Kellams on Twitter - it's quite possibly because Bayonetta 3's director, Yusuke Miyata, was the lead designer of the axed Xbox exclusive.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feature: What Is The Zelda 'Formula'? We Break Down The Secret Recipe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121263</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/feature_what_is_the_zelda_formula_we_break_down_the_secret_recipe"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[12 ingredients that make a game feel like Zelda.

Have you ever played a game and thought, “This feels a bit like Zelda?” Only the other week, we described the excellent Eastward as “quite a bit like a 2D Zelda game”, and the PC/Xbox game Death’s Door — a title that our sister site Pure Xbox called "a 2021 GOTY contender" when awarding it a 10/10 score back in July — evoked a similar response in reviewers. It's an influence that goes across all platforms, which is unsurprising due to the extraordinary history and prestige of Nintendo's series.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunday Comics: THEY KNOW!]]></title>
        <id>1847747019</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/sunday-comics-they-know-1847747019"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! It’s time for Kotaku’s Sunday Comics, your weekly roundup of the best webcomics. The images enlarge if you click on the magnifying glass icon.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Wget2 2.0 Released With HTTP2 & SSL Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Wget2-2.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Wget2-2.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T14:06:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Wget2 2.0 has been released for this successor to GNU Wget. There are many improvements to this GPLv3+ licensed program. Over the original GNU Wget, Wget2 is faster, supports more protocols especially around HTTP/2 and compression, supports multi-threading / parallel connections, and other improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sunday Papers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-612</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-612"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sundays are for watching Antiques Roadshow with all your might. Before you tune in, let's read this week's best writing about games.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mini Review: Project Winter - Social Deduction That Survives But Doesn't Thrive On Switch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-120787</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/project_winter"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Snow close, yet snow far.
Project Winter is an interesting combination of survival and social deduction — think Among Us mixed with The Long Dark — that's brilliant in its best moments, but sadly kneecapped by the compromises you'll have to make to play it on Switch.
The pitch may sound familiar: a team of between five and eight people, a few of whom are "traitors", are tasked with either completing or sabotaging tasks. Traitors have extra crates to open and hatches to fast-travel across the map; survivors have to band together to stay alive, and figure out who to trust. Everything can kill you, traitors and survivors alike — roaming wolves, moose, bears, traps, hunger, the weather, and the biting cold are all your enemies; if you overcome all of that, you still might get hacked to death by another person.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Record Of Lodoss War: Deedlit In Wonder Labyrinth Is Coming To Switch This Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121443</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/record_of_lodoss_war_deedlit_in_wonder_labyrinth_is_coming_to_switch_this_year"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physical version confirmed with English language support.
Playism and Team Ladybug have announced that that the critically-acclaimed 'Metroidvania' Record of Lodoss War: Deedlit in Wonder Labyrinth is coming to Nintendo Switch later this year.
The game – which is based on the popular anime series – will also be released on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S and Xbox One on December 16. It was previously available on Steam, where it currently holds a 'Very Positive' rating.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated AMD P-State Driver Published For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-amd-pstate-v2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-amd-pstate-v2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T10:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month AMD published their "amd-pstate" Linux driver that leverages ACPI CPPC data to make more informed CPU frequency scaling decisions with an aim to boost the performance-per-Watt for Zen 3 (and eventually Zen 2) processors on Linux. The second spin of that "amd-pstate" Linux kernel driver is now available for testing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fly-Pie 7]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fly-pie-7</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/fly-pie-7"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T10:41:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rozšíření GNOME Shellu Fly-Pie přidávající do GNOME koláčové menu (marking menu, varianta pie menu) bylo vydáno ve verzi 7. Podporován je GNOME Shell 40 a novější. Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitHubu. Ukázka na YouTube.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux IO_uring Can Now Achieve Up To ~3.8M IOPS Per-Core]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-IO-3.8M-IOPS-Per-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-IO-3.8M-IOPS-Per-Core"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T10:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just last month when ~3.5M IOPS per-core was impressive with the code for Linux 5.15 to further push Linux's I/O limits. Now for code likely to be included in Linux 5.16 it's currently at 3.8M IOPS with a single tread...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hideki Kamiya Reminds Fans Bayonetta 3 Is A Nintendo Switch Exclusive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121438</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/hideki_kamiya_reminds_fans_bayonetta_3_is_a_nintendo_switch_exclusive"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["simply buy a Switch" if you want to play it.
Nintendo's latest Direct presentation went out with a bang - with the reveal of actual gameplay footage of Bayonetta 3.
It's been dated to arrive on the Switch at some point in 2022, but there still seems to be some fans out there wondering if it'll be released on other platforms. The game's executive producer, Hideki Kamiya, has now commented on the title's exclusivity.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Namco Classics Join Hamster's Arcade Archives This Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.nintendolife.com/#article-121436</id>
        <link href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2021/09/two_namco_classics_join_hamsters_arcade_archives_this_week"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T04:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A double serve of retro games.

Hamster Corporation joined in on the Nintendo Direct celebrations earlier this week, with not one but two Namco game releases on the Switch eShop.
Read the full article on nintendolife.com]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nintendo Life | Latest Updates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm going to use the new N64 controller on PC and you can't stop me]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-going-to-use-the-new-n64-controller-on-pc-and-you-cant-stop-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/im-going-to-use-the-new-n64-controller-on-pc-and-you-cant-stop-me"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:57:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During this week's Nintendo Direct, we found out that N64 games would soon be playable on Switch via Nintendo's online subscription. More importantly, we found out that Nintendo are making a new wireless N64 controller for use with the Switch.

You can connect the Switch Pro controller to PC with or without a wire, so it stands to reason I'll be able to use this new N64 controller on PC too, right? Because if so, I'm gonna.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Umělá inteligence uprostřed jihoamerických lesů pomáhá zachránit psího samotáře]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-umela-inteligence-uprostred-jihoamerickych-lesu-pomaha-zachranit-psiho-samotare</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-umela-inteligence-uprostred-jihoamerickych-lesu-pomaha-zachranit-psiho-samotare"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Video, se kterým konečně pochopíte rozdíl mezi běžným a moderním úložištěm. Digitalizace zákaznické péče: jak vybrat nejlepší řešení kontaktního centra. Jaké novinky přináší Arcserve UDP 8.1? On-line konference VMworld 2021: stovky přednášek a tutoriálů zdarma. Gartner na křivce seřadil klíčové nastupující technologie. Studie Dell Technologies: hrozba ztráty dat po kyberútoku je větší, než kdy jindy. Umělá inteligence uprostřed jihoamerických lesů pomáhá zachránit psího samotáře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nový textový editor pro GNOME, 100% evropské RISC-V procesory EPI EPAC1.0]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15680</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/novy-textovy-editor-pro-gnome-100procentne-evropske-risc-v-procesory-epi-epac10/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beta verze Ubuntu 21.10, MidnightBSD 2.1 přechází na LLVM 10, Apple vydal iPhony 13, nabídne i ProRes video, vývojová verze Wine 6.18, Joe Biden jmenoval šéfku AMD do svého poradního týmu, AMD a Mediatek dohromady.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foxhole's Entrenched update makes the massive multiplayer shooter even bigger]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foxholes-entrenched-update-makes-the-massive-multiplayer-shooter-even-bigger</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/foxholes-entrenched-update-makes-the-massive-multiplayer-shooter-even-bigger"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T21:44:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Foxhole has made foxholes better. The Entrenched update for the massive, multiplayer sandbox war game adds a lot, but top of the pile is new building tools for crafting better bunkers, trenches, and frontline defenses. The update is live now, and there's a video introducing its many features below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Signal State is a Zachlike about rewiring synthesizers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-signal-state-is-a-zachlike-about-rewiring-synthesizers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-signal-state-is-a-zachlike-about-rewiring-synthesizers"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T21:10:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it still a Zachlike if it's not made by Zachtronics? Because The Signal State sure looks like a Zachlike. It's about solving logic puzzles inspired by modular synthesizers, which means you'll tinker with ornate machinery by twisting knobs and changing wiring. It's also wrapped in a post-apocalyptic story in which your actions will "change the fate of agriculture."

It's out now. Check out the trailer below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitman is now on GOG, but getting slammed for its lack of offline features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-is-now-on-gog-but-getting-slammed-for-its-lack-of-offline-features</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hitman-is-now-on-gog-but-getting-slammed-for-its-lack-of-offline-features"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T20:22:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news! Hitman: Game Of The Year Edition is now on GOG and 70% off. Bad news! The game requires an internet connection for so many singleplayer features that customers on the DRM-free digital store are real mad about it.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BattlEye Anti-Cheat will support Steam Deck and Proton, too]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battleye-anti-cheat-will-support-steam-deck-and-proton-too</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/battleye-anti-cheat-will-support-steam-deck-and-proton-too"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T19:45:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's claim that the Steam Deck would run every game in your Steam library is looking more and more like fact. Yesterday Easy Anti-Cheat announced support for Linux and the Proton compatibility laters the Deck relies upon. 

Today, BattlEye Anti-Cheat followed suit, announcing they'd support the Steam Deck and Proton in a tweet.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Witcher Renewed For Season 3 On Netflix Alongside A Spin-Off For Kids]]></title>
        <id>1847746369</id>
        <link href="https://kotaku.com/the-witcher-renewed-for-season-3-on-netflix-alongside-a-1847746369"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T19:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix is continuing to expand The Witcher into a giant franchise, announcing today that the main show starring Henry Cavill is getting a third season, while also announcing a second anime film and oddly, a spin-off aimed at kids and families too. The streaming giant also released some new footage from Witcher’s…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zack Zwiezen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.24 On Wayland To Support DRM Leasing For VR Headsets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Plasma-5.24-DRM-Leasing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Plasma-5.24-DRM-Leasing"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T17:34:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the KDE Plasma 5.23 release quickly approaching, feature development is already heating up for Plasma 5.24 while concurrently driving many fixes into the v5.23 codebase...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron 15.0.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/electron-15.0.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/electron-15.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T15:33:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána verze 15.0.0 frameworku pro vývoj multiplatformních desktopových aplikací pomocí JavaScriptu, HTML a CSS Electron (Wikipedie, GitHub). Chromium bylo aktualizováno na verzi 94, V8 na verzi 9.4 a Node.js na verzi 16.5.0. Electron byl původně vyvíjen pro editor Atom pod názvem Atom Shell. Dnes je na Electronu postavena celá řada dalších aplikací.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Has Been Working On BOLT'ing The Linux Kernel For Greater Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Facebook-BOLTing-The-Kernel</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Facebook-BOLTing-The-Kernel"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T13:20:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For several years now Facebook engineers have been working on BOLT as a way to speed-up Linux/ELF binaries. This "Binary Optimization and Layout Tool" is able to re-arrange executables once profiled to generate even faster performance than what can be achieved by a compiler's LTO and PGO optimizations. One of the latest BOLT efforts has been on optimizing the Linux kernel image...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's User Interrupts With Sapphire Rapids Looking Quite Great For Faster IPC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-x86-User-Interrupts-LPC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-x86-User-Interrupts-LPC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T12:32:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month Intel engineers posted their initial Linux kernel enablement around x86 User Interrupts with this feature premiering with Xeon "Sapphire Rapids" CPUs. As implied by the name, the User Interrupt functionality allows for interrupts to bypass the kernel for more efficient, low-latency, low-utilization interrupts being received by other user-space tasks. Intel talked more about User Interrupts this week at LPC2021...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Úvahy o Borrow Checkeru pro C++]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42851</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/uvahy-o-borrow-checkeru-pro-c/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T10:43:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Server This Week in Rust přinesl odkaz na zajímavý článek z pera tří vývojářů projektu Chromium. Autoři v něm rozvíjejí myšlenku implementovat v C++ stejná, nebo alespoň podobná pravidla paměťové bezpečnosti na úrovni typového systému, jako má Rust (tzv. Borrow Checking).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: klokan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenZFS 2.0.6 Released With Support For Newer Kernels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-2.0.6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenZFS-2.0.6-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T10:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the OpenZFS 2.1 feature release has been available since July, for those still using the OpenZFS 2.0.x series and not yet prepared to make the jump to that big new release with dRAID and other changes, OpenZFS 2.0.6 was released this week...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine-Staging 6.18 Released With 616 Patches Atop Upstream]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-6.18</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-6.18"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T09:52:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off yesterday's Wine 6.18 development release is now the next Wine-Staging installment that has more than six hundred extra patches on top...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are we all playing this weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-163</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-we-all-playing-this-weekend-163"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, here we are: it is now autumn. I'm ready. I've folded my summer bedding away, pulled out the big duvet, and bought a bigger Thermos. And this is the nice part of autumn, when things are cosy and transitionary, before the feeling of death sets in. I was cheered by reading about your favourite autumn games this week. But anyway, what are you playing this weekend? Here's what we're clicking on.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XWayland GLX Path Enables sRGB Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-sRGB-Support</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-sRGB-Support"/>
        <updated>2021-09-25T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another item is now crossed off the XWayland TODO list with OpenGL sRGB support wired up...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Handcop is a hilariously horrifying "fist person shooter" in development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/handcop-is-a-hilariously-horrifying-fist-person-shooter-in-development</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/handcop-is-a-hilariously-horrifying-fist-person-shooter-in-development"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:39:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handcop is a work in progress "fist person shooter" that's just as neat as it is horrifying. This wacky prodecurally-animated cop hand has three legs and chest hair for goodness sake. I can't decide if three "legs" is better or worse than three finger "arms". Oh, and of course officier Michael McWrist is running about carrying a giant gun. It's relatively early days for Handcop right now, it sounds like, but its wacky animations are already catching the internet's attention.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.18 Released With HID Joystick Enabled By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.18-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.18-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.18 has been popped as the newest bi-weekly development release of this software that allows Windows applications and games to run under Linux and in turn what also powers Steam Play's Proton...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 38/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-38-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-38-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coreutils 9.0]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/coreutils-9.0</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/coreutils-9.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T21:53:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Po roce a půl od vydání poslední stabilní verze 8.32 byla vydána nová stabilní major verze 9.0 balíku základních nástrojů Coreutils (GNU Core Utilities). Nová verze přináší celou řadu novinek: příkaz cp má ve výchozím stavu povoleno copy-on-write (CoW), příkaz wc používá AVX2 instrukce k počítání řádků, příkaz cksum má volbu -a pro výběr hašovací funkce, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frankenstein and Dracula are roomies in this moody narrative adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frankenstein-and-dracula-are-roomies-in-this-moody-narrative-adventure</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/frankenstein-and-dracula-are-roomies-in-this-moody-narrative-adventure"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T21:36:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Dracula and Frankenstein are modern day 20-something flatmates who never see one another and only exchange sticky notes. Also they are both very sad. Also Dracula wears puple shades," is the kind of message I'd expect to see from one of my writing acquaintances with the timestamp [2:15am]. It's also the kind of thing I'd respond to with a "yes, do it," eager to find out exactly how the hell they would. That's the energy that I downloaded Frank And Drake's demo with, and it sure is a moody, somber narrative adventure about two unlikely housemates.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Castlevania Advance Collection whips out four classics now on PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/castlevania-advance-collection-whips-out-four-classics-now-on-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/castlevania-advance-collection-whips-out-four-classics-now-on-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T20:11:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dracula's back from the dead again and so are four Castlevania games from the aughts. Three different vampire stomping adventures originally hailing from the Game Boy Advance—and one SNES—have made their way into a new collection on PC via Steam. Two Belmonts, a Graves, and a Cruz all get their time to shine against those undead baddies in Castlevania: Circle Of The Moon, Harmony Of Dissonance, Aria Of Sorrow, and Dracula X. Konami launched the Castlevania Advance Collection yesterday, complete with some modern conveniences for us PC players in the year 2021.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BattlEye To Support Valve's Steam Deck / Proton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BattlEye-Proton-Steam-Deck</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BattlEye-Proton-Steam-Deck"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T19:52:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday it was Epic Games confirming Easy Anti-Cheat for Linux and Wine/Proton ahead of the Steam Deck launch and today it's BattlEye confirming Proton / Steam Deck support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IBM Engineer Has Been Exploring Possible Rust Modules For GRUB]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IBM-Possible-Rust-GRUB</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IBM-Possible-Rust-GRUB"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T18:50:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM engineer Daniel Axtens presented at this week's Linux Plumbers Conference on the prospects of using the Rust programming language for creating modules for the GRUB2 boot-loader...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This mod adds a universal photo mode to over 300 Unreal Engine games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mod-adds-a-universal-photo-mode-to-over-300-unreal-engine-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-mod-adds-a-universal-photo-mode-to-over-300-unreal-engine-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T18:46:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo modes are undeniably in fashion now, so much so that I've just started assuming most major RPGs and third-person action games will have one built in at launch. I've never put in the time to get particularly skilled at lining up the best shots, but I'm always well impressed by those who do. It's a bummer though when a looker of a game doesn't have a way to really get up close and personal with its pretty cast and environments. Tales Of Arise, which just launched this month, doesn't have one yet, for instance. That's where the extremely nifty and very handy Universal Unreal Engine 4 Unlocker comes in. It's a mod that lets you toggle a free camera to take amazing screenshots in over 300 Unreal Engine games.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Coreutils 9.0: cp Now Enables CoW By Default + Copy Offload, wc Now Uses AVX2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Coreutils-9.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Coreutils-9.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T17:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coreutils 9.0 is now available and it's a significant update to this collection of common open-source utilities found on effectively all Linux systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["TMORPG" Book Of Travels will launch in early access on October 11th]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tmorpg-book-of-travels-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-11th</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tmorpg-book-of-travels-will-launch-in-early-access-on-october-11th"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T16:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Might And Delight's "tiny Multiplayer Online RPG" Book Of Travels has scheduled itself a new early access launch date after its most recent delay. As M&D previously reassured fans, it is indeed a shorter wait than I'd feared. Their cozy online RPG is now setting out into early access on October 11th, with plans to work towards a full launch in two years.  

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[8 Minecraft castle ideas to build in 1.17]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-castle-ideas</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-castle-ideas"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T15:41:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to build an epic Castle in Minecraft? How about 8 castles? That’s how many we’ve got for you in this list, so you’d best get building! These castles look truly stunning, but we're sure they'll be even better atop the new mountains that are coming when the Minecraft 1.18 update launches later this year.
Check out all of these builds to get some inspiration for your own world in Minecraft, or just follow along with the Youtube tutorials if you like what you see!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squid Game is the perfect Netflix show for Zero Escape & Danganronpa likers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/squid-game-is-the-perfect-netflix-show-for-zero-escape-danganronpa-likers</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/squid-game-is-the-perfect-netflix-show-for-zero-escape-danganronpa-likers"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Listen up, escape room fans. There's a new Korean drama you need to watch. It's called Squid Game, it's on Netflix, and it's real good. It's a show about 456 down and outers - folks with no life, family or who are in huge piles of debt - who enter a deadly competition to win a truck ton of money to help them turn their life around. All they need to do is compete in six games. Easy peasy, everyone thinks. How hard can that be? Only the first of those games, a riff on the classic children's game Statues / Grandma's Footsteps / Red Light Green Light - involves running toward a giant automaton with motion sensors in her eyes, as well as a team of snipers waiting in the rafters to take down anyone who does stay perfectly at the right time. 
It's grim, but it's also the perfect blend of some of my favourite things ever: Zero Escape, Danganronpa and Battle Royale (the Japanese thriller, not the game genre) - and I implore you to give it a go.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TFI Friday: 3 new indie games about soaking things in water]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-3-new-indie-games-about-soaking-things-in-water</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tfi-friday-3-new-indie-games-about-soaking-things-in-water"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T15:07:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love doing this column because it means a) it is the end of a working week (working hard or hardly working, amiright?) and b) I get to play something nice and (often) small, and usually a bit weird. I am also, as it turns out, really smug about the theme I discovered for this week. Last night I had a bath, so am ideally positioned to extoll the benefits of dunking things in water. May I present to you three brand new indie games: a frog's tea party, a potion workshop and a rainy walk.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Text Editor, nový editor pro GNOME na Flathubu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/text-editor-novy-editor-pro-gnome-na-flathubu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/text-editor-novy-editor-pro-gnome-na-flathubu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:53:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MojeFedora.cz představuje nový editor pro GNOME s názvem Text Editor. Text Editor je postavený na GtkSourceView (komponenta pro zobrazování zdrojového kódu v GNOME Builderu). Instalovat jej lze z Flathubu. Zdrojové kódy jsou k dispozici na GitLabu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge Of Spirits Warrior Path walkthrough]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-warrior-path-walkthrough-toshis-love</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-warrior-path-walkthrough-toshis-love"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:19:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck on the Warrior Path in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? You're not alone. The sheer number of portals and zipping between locations throughout the Warrior Path has led many a player to distraction and frustration. At least, until they found this handy walkthrough, which guides you carefully through every part of the Toshi's Love quest, through every combat area and puzzle, until you reach the end and defeat the Warrior himself.
Keep scrolling to read our written and our video walkthrough of the Warrior Path in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomb Raider reboot studio now working on Perfect Dark reboot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tomb-raider-reboot-studio-now-working-on-perfect-dark-reboot</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tomb-raider-reboot-studio-now-working-on-perfect-dark-reboot"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:18:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After rebooting Lara Croft with 2013's Tomb Raider, Square Enix's Crystal Dynamics studio are now helping reboot another vintage hero: Joanna Dark. They'll be chipping in on Microsoft's mysterious new Perfect Dark, helping out the mysterious Santa Monica studio named The Initiative. Secrecy might be thematically appropriate for a game about a futuristic superspy but we don't know much of anything about it so all you can really say is "Yup, I guess they're doing that."
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embrace the machine gun, Metal Dogs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embrace-the-machine-gun-metal-dogs</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/embrace-the-machine-gun-metal-dogs"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's all very silly. Having survived the grey, po-faced gruntman domination of the 2000s, I love that games can still be very silly.
Metal Dogs is a twin stick (sort of) shooter about sending heavy weapons platforms into irradiated future deserts to fight giant insects, ghost tanks, and robot hippos. Naturally, those heavy weapons platforms are strapped onto dogs.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave vydal Brave Talk: službu pro bezpečné videohovory]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42850</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/brave-vydal-brave-talk-sluzbu-pro-bezpecne-videohovory/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:35:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Společnost Brave, známá především svým internetovým prohlížečem zaměřeným na soukromí představila novou službu na bezpečné videohovory. Jmenuje se Brave Talk, v základu je zdarma, běží na Jitsi as a Service a je open-source. Začít můžete na talk.brave.com.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: spajk)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to install RAM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-ram</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-install-ram"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:31:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Installing RAM is both one of the easiest steps to building a PC and one of the simplest ways to upgrade an existing gaming rig. In a physical sense, anyway. Just like installing an M.2 SSD, there are no power or data cables to worry about, and as long as your RAM sticks fit the RAM slots on your motherboard, ultimately you just need to push them in. There is room for error, though, hence why this article is going to continue beyond the introductory paragraph. See? RAM can be interesting.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robot beings rule Mystery Steam Reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mystery-steam-reviews-054-video-games-robots</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mystery-steam-reviews-054-video-games-robots"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humans are boring. All fleshy and feelings and Netflix. Like this quiz, robots don't have hidden agendas. Robots want to wish Paulie a happy birthday, and we want to entertain you for quarter of an hour. It's the perfect match.
  
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SiFive HiFive Unmatched Hands-On, Initial RISC-V Performance Benchmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30545</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30545"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:22:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I finally received the HiFive Unmatched from SiFive as their flagship RISC-V development board. As a reminder this is their mini-ITX development board that is powered by their U740 SoC and features 16GB of DDR4 system memory, one PCI Express x16 slot that can work with AMD Radeon graphics cards on Linux, and other features. It's been a delight playing with this developer platform and enclosed are some early benchmarks as well showing off the U740 performance as well as how the Linux software support/performance has been evolving.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Send Thatcher back to Hell in this new Doom 2 mod today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/send-thatcher-back-to-hell-in-this-new-doom-2-mod-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/send-thatcher-back-to-hell-in-this-new-doom-2-mod-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following a short delay caused by Tennent's Lager (actual true story), Margaret Thatcher has returned from Hell to menace us once more. Thankfully, one doomed space marine will stand up and venture into the tenth circle of Hell (aka the UK) to put the reviled British prime minister down for good. Thatcher's Techbase is its name, and Doom 2 is the game you'll need to play this free mod now it's out. It is quite the thing, and even has a custom soundtrack from Paradise Killer's composer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cult classic SNES platformer ActRaiser now on PC with a remaster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cult-classic-snes-platformer-actraiser-now-on-pc-with-a-remaster</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cult-classic-snes-platformer-actraiser-now-on-pc-with-a-remaster"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T13:02:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What's up 90s kids, how would you like to jump back into a SNES platforming city-builder that was first released 30 years ago? Last night's Nintendo Direct had a surprising amount of PC news on offer, including the announcement that a remake of ActRaiser is available to play on PC right now. Named ActRaiser Renaissance, Square Enix say they've given the game a "complete graphical overhaul", as well as added some new features for players to try.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Čínská centrální banka prohlásila transakce kryptoměnami za nezákonné]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/cinska-centralni-banka-prohlasila-transakce-kryptomenami-za-nezakonne</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/cinska-centralni-banka-prohlasila-transakce-kryptomenami-za-nezakonne"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:57:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Čínská centrální banka prohlásila transakce kryptoměnami za nezákonné.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 Minecraft tower ideas to build in 1.17]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-tower-ideas</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-tower-ideas"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:56:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for a cool tower to build in Minecraft? This list is filled with exciting tower ideas that you can try out in Minecraft, with everything from a simple base to a magical Wizard tower.
Take a look through all of these suggestions to get inspired, or follow along with one of the videos and get building right now!
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim Crystal: how to get crafting materials for the Crystal Battleaxe and Crystal Wall]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-crystal-shards</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-crystal-shards"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:39:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where do you get Crystal Shards in Valheim, and what are they used for? Crystal has existed as a resource in Valheim for a while, but like many crafting materials in this Early Access cult hit, it's only recently been given a use. The Hearth & Home update has added Crystal Battleaxe and Crystal Wall recipes, and now this previously purely decorative resource is in high demand.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge Of Spirits Incense Pots puzzle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-incense-pots-puzzle-toshis-fear</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-incense-pots-puzzle-toshis-fear"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T11:34:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering how to solve the Incense Pots puzzle in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? If you've followed the Mask Maker path as part of the Toshi's Fear quest and you're stuck on these infernal Incense Pots, you've come to exactly the right place. There's not much to say here, so let's jump right into our walkthrough of how to solve this particular puzzle in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim Obliterator: how to craft and use an Obliterator]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-obliterator-thunder-stones</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-obliterator-thunder-stones"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:37:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you craft and use the Obliterator in Valheim? The Obliterator was added to Valheim with the Hearth & Home update, and exists to address a recurring problem experienced by Valheim players in older iterations of the Early Access smash hit. Previously, there was no way to actually get rid of items you didn't need — which could include a surplus of crafting materials and even trophies made from the body parts of slain enemies. The Obliterator gives you the option to neatly dispose of all the inventory junk you don't want to display or store.
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Rise announces Sunbreak expansion before even hitting PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-announces-sunbreak-expansion-before-even-hitting-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-rise-announces-sunbreak-expansion-before-even-hitting-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though Monster Hunter Rise isn't even out on PC for months yet, Capcom have announced an expansion is coming our way. During last night's Nintendo Direct stream they revealed Monter Hunter Rise: Sunbreak, which will launch simultaneously on Switch and PC in summer 2022. Hey, at least that means while consoleers had to wait over a year for the expansion, we'll have it after only a few months. Have a peek in the announcement trailer.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vyšla konečná betaverze Ubuntu 21.10, vydání je plánováno na 14. října]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42849</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/vysla-konecna-betaverze-ubuntu-21-10-vydani-je-planovano-na-14-rijna/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:35:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili konečnou betaverzi připravovaného Ubuntu 21.10 s kódovým označením Impish Indri (rošťácký lemur). Vše jde podle připraveného časového harmonogramu, čeká nás ještě kandidát na vydání a poté přijde 14. října ostrá verze.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice Of Cards: The Isle Dragon Roars is Yoko Taro's new card-based RPG]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voice-of-cards-the-isle-dragon-roars-is-yoko-taros-new-card-based-rpg</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/voice-of-cards-the-isle-dragon-roars-is-yoko-taros-new-card-based-rpg"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T10:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nier director Yoko Taro is making a new role-playing game in which everything is depicted through cards, and somehow it's not called Yoko Tarot. Story? There are cards for that. Combat? Turn-based card battles, of course. Travelling through the world? Flip over some cards, see what you find! It's called Voice Of Cards: The Isle Dragon Roars, and it's set to release this October. On top of that, a demo will be available later today if you fancy trying it out. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ansible: úvod do automatizace, role a AWX (školení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-40036</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/ansible-uvod-do-automatizace-role-a-awx-skoleni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:51:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na internetu píšou, že začít s automatizací správy serverů můžete do půl hodiny. Dokážeme vám, že s Ansible to je pravda. Stačí navštívit naše pražské školení Ansible – úvod do automatizace a pak navazující Ansible – role a AWX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Redakce)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MidnightBSD 2.1 Released For This Desktop-Minded BSD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MidnightBSD-2.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=MidnightBSD-2.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:46:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MidnightBSD 2.1 debuted this week as the latest version of one of the few desktop-focused BSD open-source operating system projects...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine adds DLC in surprise 'Anniversary Edition']]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-adds-dlc-in-surprise-anniversary-edition</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-40000-space-marine-adds-dlc-in-surprise-anniversary-edition"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:43:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rise, brothers, to venerate Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine as it celebrates its tenth birthday this month. Relic Entertainment and Sega have a surprise for us all too, turning the third-person ork-smasher into an 'Anniversary Edition' which includes all the DLC as well as bonuses like the soundtrack. That's all for free, which is nice.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck compatibility conundrum partially solved with Easy Anti-Cheat support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-conundrum-partially-solved-with-easy-anti-cheat-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-conundrum-partially-solved-with-easy-anti-cheat-support"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:17:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Steam Deck has just broken through a major compatibility barrier: one that would have made it difficult for some of Steam’s most-played multiplayer games to properly function on the Valve handheld. Gabe and co. have Epic to thank for this one, though, as the latter’s Easy Anti-Cheat (EAC) tech is now extending support to Linux and it Wine and Proton compatibility layers. The same layers, you may recall, that the Steam Deck relies on to run games without native Linux ports. In other words, games with multiplayer components that wouldn’t have worked on the Steam Deck - because their use of EAC precluded Linux/Wine/Proton compatibility - should, in theory, be able to run in full.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Beta Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T09:16:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical has released the final beta of next month's Ubuntu 21.10 "Impish Indri" release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 (Impish Indri) Final Beta]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-21.10-impish-indri-final-beta</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/ubuntu-21.10-impish-indri-final-beta"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T08:56:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Byla vydána finální beta verze Ubuntu 21.10 s kódovým názvem Impish Indri. Přehled novinek v poznámkách k vydání. Dle plánu by Ubuntu 21.10 mělo vyjít 14. října 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to find Slimes and make a Slime Farm in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-slimes-how-to-find-slimes-make-slime-farm</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-slimes-how-to-find-slimes-make-slime-farm"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T08:49:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to find Slimes in Minecraft? Slimes can vary in size from annoying little blobs to giant monstrosities, but there’s one thing they all have in common. They all drop Slimeballs, which are extremely useful in Minecraft.
This guide will take you through everything that you need to know about Slimes, including how to find them, what you can use Slimeballs for, and how to make your own Slime farm.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sourcetrail končí, vývoj je příliš náročný]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42848</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/sourcetrail-konci-vyvoj-je-prilis-narocny/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T07:20:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sourcetrail je open-source program, který slouží k statické analýze a vizualizaci zdrojových kódů v jazycích C, C++ a Python. Dnes jeho vývojáři na svém blogu oznámili ukončení jeho vývoje.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: D.A. Tiger)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 95 Beta Completely Removes Deprecated FTP Support, Reduced User Agent Info Trial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-95-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-95-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T04:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Chrome 94 having shipped this week, Google has now promoted Chrome 95 to beta...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Lands Memcg Performance Regression Fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Regression-Fixed</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Regression-Fixed"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a follow-up to A Fix Is Pending For That Linux 5.15 Performance Regression, Linus Torvalds decided to pull the fix directly into Linux 5.15 Git today for addressing this real-world, measurable performance regression...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symbols]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2520/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2520/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testovací vzorky evropského procesoru EPI EPAC1.0 RISC-V]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/testovaci-vzorky-evropskeho-procesoru-epi-epac1.0-risc-v</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/zpravicky/testovaci-vzorky-evropskeho-procesoru-epi-epac1.0-risc-v"/>
        <updated>2021-09-24T01:04:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Evropská procesorová iniciativa (European Processor Initiative, EPI) oznámila, že obdržela 143 testovacích vzorků procesoru EPI EPAC1.0 RISC-V. Cílem EPI jsou nízkoenergetické výkonné evropské procesory.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ladislav Hagara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fuga: Melodies Of Steel is a strategy RPG with a giant child-powered tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fuga-memories-of-steel-is-a-strategy-rpg-with-a-giant-child-powered-tank</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fuga-memories-of-steel-is-a-strategy-rpg-with-a-giant-child-powered-tank"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T23:05:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fuga: Melodies Of Steel is set during an anthropomorphic animal anime World War 2 in which your parents have been taken by the dog Nazis. Still with me? You and your fellow cat children find Howl's Moving Tank in a cave and set about getting your families back, with turn-based, RPG battles.

You also discover at the end of the tutorial that your giant angry house has a "Soul Cannon", which is a gun that only fires if you feed it the soul - and permanently kill - one of the children.

Still with me?

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Planety v centru Mléčné dráhy]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-planety-v-centru-mlecne-drahy</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-planety-v-centru-mlecne-drahy"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moudrost davu. Dokážeme úspěšně předpovědět, kdy k nám dorazí světlo supernovy? Kvasary jako standardní svíčky. Neutron má na povrchu záporný náboj. Proč se zlato vyskytuje vedle arsenu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evropská komise chce jednotnou nabíječku s USB-C a Power Delivery]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15678</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/evropska-komise-chce-jednotnou-nabijecku-s-usb-c-a-power-delivery/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exekutivě Evropské unie došla trpělivost a chystá nařízení, kterým sjednotí roztříštěný svět nabíječek (nejen) smartphonů. Postihne to všechny, kdo se vymykají standardu USB-C, v čele s Apple.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite's multiplayer test will go ahead as planned]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-multiplayer-test-will-go-ahead-as-planned</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinites-multiplayer-test-will-go-ahead-as-planned"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T21:58:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking news: everything is normal and fine. Yesterday Halo Infinite developers 343 Industries mentioned during a livestream that they might need to delay this weekend's beta. Today they confirmed that's not the case, and posted an overview of what to expect.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CS:GO's Operation Riptide revives the riot shield]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/csgos-operation-riptide-revives-the-riot-shield-and-makes-a-major-change-to-dust2</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/csgos-operation-riptide-revives-the-riot-shield-and-makes-a-major-change-to-dust2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T20:52:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The riot shield was probably the most divisive item ever added to Counter-Strike - and now it's back. New update Operation Riptide, out now, introduces the defensive item to Counter-Strike: Global Offensive's casual mode, alongside major tweaks to Dust2, new missions, shorter matches, and private matchmaking queues.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BPF-Based Linux Firewall "bpfilter" Shows Impressive Performance Potential]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BPFILTER-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BPFILTER-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generating much excitement back in 2018 was bpfilter for the potential to better Linux's firewall and packet filtering by making it more robust and performance. Recently work on this BPF-based firewall solution was renewed and the performance potential over iptables and nftables is looking very good for the future...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected characters keep disappearing, among many launch issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-characters-keep-disappearing-among-many-launch-issues</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-characters-keep-disappearing-among-many-launch-issues"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T19:24:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected launched earlier today, offering players the chance to relive the classic hack-and-slasher. But why recreate the experience of one Diablo game when you could recreate the experience of two? Resurrected is also experiencing a bunch of launch issues related to its online mode, just like Diablo 3 before it.

Those issues include players being unable to see their existing characters, create new characters, or launch the game. Some might say essential features.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Games Announces Easy Anti-Cheat For Linux - Including Wine/Proton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Easy-Anti-Cheat-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Easy-Anti-Cheat-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T18:40:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not too surprising given the Steam Deck is inching closer towards release and we've known Valve has been working to improve the anti-cheat situation for games on Linux, but today EAC owner Epic Games officially announced Easy Anti-Cheat for both Linux and macOS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated "FUTEX2" futex_waitv Patches Posted To Address Latest Feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FUTEX2-futex_waitv-v2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FUTEX2-futex_waitv-v2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T18:16:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The promising FUTEX2 work focused on improving the Linux performance for running Windows games via Wine/Proton by extending futex to wait on multiple locks is still moving forward...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected's hotkeys are still a goddamn mess]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-hotkeys-are-still-a-goddamn-mess</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-hotkeys-are-still-a-goddamn-mess"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terrible news continues to pour out of Blizzard like pus from of a festering wound around a splinter you forgot about and left for way too long. You should really get that looked at. Still, they must be drawing some comfort from the fact that Diablo II: Resurrected is out today, one of Blizz's most beloved games of all time.
Naturally, a lot of people will be excited for the remastered version. But if my tone is more immediately aggro than the last time I wrote about Diablerrected, that's because I was previously playing the beta through the rose-tinted haze of this game being very important to me and a big part of my childhood, and bonding with my older brother, and so on. This time, I have been playing the final version for several hours, and am cross.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rally Point: Putting Mech Engineer on trial (and error)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-putting-mech-engineer-on-trial-and-error</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-rally-point-putting-mech-engineer-on-trial-and-error"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T16:05:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you've played a lot of games, or seen a lot of films, or probably eaten at a lot of restaurants or generally oversaturated your life with one subject, it's easy to start making rules and codes for How It Should Be. I given a lot of games a hard time for being opaque and failing to explain themselves. And yet here I am, finally writing about Mech Engineer after watching and playing it for nine months, waiting for it to hit the point where I can almost, sort of, not exactly recommend it... but share my fascination with it.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sin Vega</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard will, sadly, fix dognados]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-will-sadly-fix-dognados</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguard-will-sadly-fix-dognados"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:50:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The primary function of ragdoll physics in video games, everyone knows, is to freak out and make people laugh. Everyone knows this. The technology was created explicitly to bring a subversive touch of merry mayhem to po-faced murdergames. Everyone knows this. But developers are wary of overdoing it or openly acknowledging this fact which everyone knows. This is why, sadly, Call Of Duty: Vanguard will indeed 'fix' the 'bug' which could make attack dogs turn into a giant maelstrom of limbs, teeth, and mashing meat noises, a phenomenom known as the 'dognado'. Tragic.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to set up two monitors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-set-up-two-monitors</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-to-set-up-two-monitors"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s funny to think how different the use cases are for setting up two monitors for your gaming PC, compared to setting up three. A trio of displays lets you play in ultrawide with a wraparound effect that even most purpose-built ultrawide monitors can’t match, but while you can configure a dual-monitor setup to run games across displays, it doesn’t make nearly as much sense. With the borders of each screen running straight down the middle, most of the best ultrawide PC games would be nigh-unplayable. Still! If you can budget for it, two remains better than one. It’s an expanded but focused setup for when you’re playing a full-screen game but also want a browser tab, video, or streaming controls visible at the same time.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Diablo 2: Resurrected classes and builds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-diablo-2-resurrected-classes-and-builds</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-diablo-2-resurrected-classes-and-builds"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:20:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best classes and builds in Diablo 2: Resurrected? The shiny new remaster is finally here, but the gameplay of Diablo 2: Resurrected will be very familiar to veterans. If you’re playing for the first time, however, the game’s complex character progression can seem overwhelming. The foundations of your experience are your choice of class, and the skill(s) you build around on that class. Each of Diablo 2’s seven classes features multiple talent trees that grant you new abilities and define how you approach the game.
If you’re planning to play on Hardcore mode or push deep into Hell difficulty, you will want a quality build. Blizzard has not made balance adjustments to Diablo 2: Resurrected, so the long-established meta still holds in the remaster. Prepare for Hell with our guide to the best classes and builds in Diablo 2: Resurrected.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected Runes and Runewords]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-runes-runewords</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-runes-runewords"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:20:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trying to wrap your head around Runes in Diablo 2: Resurrected? Runes are the cornerstone of Diablo 2’s gear system. As there are no balance changes in Diablo 2: Resurrected, longtime players will be familiar. If you’re new, however, this system will look entirely unfamiliar, even if you’ve played Diablo 3 or Path of Exile. There’s nothing quite like Diablo 2’s Rune system in the ARPG genre. If you’re having trouble wrapping your head around the quirks of Runes and Runewords, we’re here to help.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diablo 2: Resurrected farming spots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-farming-level-85</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-farming-level-85"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:20:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best farming spots in Diablo 2? An ARPG would be nothing without a grind. The grind in Diablo 2 is the foundation of the genre’s last 20 years. The genre-defining classic has seen very few changes for the remastered version, Diablo 2: Resurrected, so veterans of the original will have their strategies in place. If you’re a new player looking to optimize your character after beating the game though, you’ll need to know where to farm your gear. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EWS podcast episode 157: the best animal companions special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-episode-157-the-best-animal-companions-in-games-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-electronic-wireless-show-episode-157-the-best-animal-companions-in-games-special"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week on The Electronic Wireless Show podcast I was inspired by the extremely cute little monsters the Rot, who are you besties in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits, to ask Matthew and Nate about their favourite animal companions in video games. You will probably be able to predict some of their answers. Others, not so much.
A big digression about trains and commuter rage this week, as well as a shocking update from Matthew re. the farewell fizzy drink tour. But most exciting is that the Cavern Of Lies is replaced this week by a Cavern Of Announcements! Yes, we have very special news indeed, and you have to listen to at least two thirds of the podcast to find out what it is. But it is genuinely incredible.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valheim Tar: how to find Tar Pits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-tar-pits</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-tar-pits"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:42:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where can you find Tar Pits in Valheim? Tar is a new resource introduced in Valheim's Hearth & Home update. It's a versatile crafting resource that you'll need before you can make many of the update's new items, including Darkwood furniture and building materials, Raven and Wolf Adornments, and — last but never least — the hot tub.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea Of Thieves explores the Sunken Kingdom in new season today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sea-of-thieves-explores-the-sunken-kingdom-in-new-season-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sea-of-thieves-explores-the-sunken-kingdom-in-new-season-today"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:11:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new Sea Of Thieves content update heralds the start of a new season today, encouraging pirates to plunge overboard and explore the beautiful halls and mysteries of the Sunken Kingdom. All sorts of coral-y PvE surprises await, with Shrines to quietly explore and Treasures to plunder by force. As beautiful as the game's water is from above, I'm very keen to see more from below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chorus is an exhilarating space combat shooter with a rhythm all its own]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chorus-is-an-exhilarating-space-combat-shooter-with-a-rhythm-all-its-own</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/chorus-is-an-exhilarating-space-combat-shooter-with-a-rhythm-all-its-own"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since Chorus first broke out of hyperspace during Microsoft's Xbox Series X showcase last year, Fishlabs' enigmatic space shooter has been a tricky thing to pin down. The first trailer gave us a taste of its high speed combat and third-person battles, but its deep, ominous narration, hints of a mysterious cosmic power, and that final image of a planet being sucked into a black hole almost looked like it was verging into horror territory rather than plain sci-fi. Having now played around an hour of Chorus, I can safely say it's very much a pure breed of space combat shooter, following in the same, adrenalin-fuelled vein as EVE: Valkyrie and Star Wars Squadrons. 
Forsaken, the sentient ship you control in Chorus that's piloted by the rebel cultist Nara, is probably a similarly slippery thing to nail down in the eyes of your enemies, too. Thanks to one of Nara's special Rite powers, bestowed on her by that aforementioned cosmic power you'll be hunting down over the course of the game, Forsaken is able to shift and teleport right behind enemy ships for brutal, bullet-ridden takedowns. It's immensely satisfying, and can also make for daring, last-minute escapes from incoming crosshairs. But you'll need much more than Nara's crafty Rite powers to survive Chorus' unforgiving dogfights. Forsaken went up in flames more times than I care to admit in my hour of hands on time, but I'm very much looking forward to going back for more when it finally launches on Steam and the Epic Games Store on December 3rd later this year.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discord testing YouTube integration to let you watch videos with pals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/discord-testing-youtube-integration-to-let-you-watch-videos-with-pals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/discord-testing-youtube-integration-to-let-you-watch-videos-with-pals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T13:43:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discord has started testing official YouTube integration, rolling out a new feature named Watch Together which, well, allows users watch YouTube vids together. It comes just a few weeks after Google's lawyers shut down several third-party Discord bots with a similar function. Watch Together has reportedly been enabled in a limited number of Discord servers for now, with plans to roll it out to everyone by the end of October.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Fix Is Pending For That Linux 5.15 Performance Regression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30536</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30536"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T13:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week was the article on noticing various workloads performing slower on the Linux 5.15 development kernel. There is now a patch pending that in testing so far does indeed correct the performance drop on this forthcoming kernel.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's "CLOn12" Mesa Code Adds SPIR/SPIR-V Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Microsoft-CLOn12-Mesa-SPIR-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Microsoft-CLOn12-Mesa-SPIR-V"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T13:09:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's "CLOn12" effort to allow OpenCL over DirectX 12 by leveraging Mesa now has landed a major rework to its code within Mesa...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Tales of Arise rose up for a new audience]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-tales-of-arise-rose-up-for-a-new-audience</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/how-tales-of-arise-rose-up-for-a-new-audience"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bandai Namco's first Tales Of game, Tales Of Phantasia, weighed in at a previously unheard of 48MB when it released in 1995. That's a mere wisp of data nowadays, but a veritable beast for a Super Famicom game cartridge. The cost of these high capacity carts, combined with westerners' ho-hum attitude towards RPGs at the time, likely axed any chance it had of being translated. Later Tales games have had better success in the west - 2003's Tales Of Symphonia was arguably its first breakout hit outside Japan - but the series as a whole has always seemed to exist on the fringes of the JRPG dynasty. While the Tales games certainly have a following outside Japan, western JRPG fans still tend to gravitate toward Square Enix's Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest games, or Atlus' Persona series. 
But the Tales series' low-key existence is seemingly coming to an end thanks to the recently released Tales Of Arise. With its bright, eye-catching visuals and its uniquely frantic battle system, it turns monster slaying from a chore into an addiction, and has won the hearts of many curious newcomers in the process (including yours truly). With this influx of new blood, Tales might stand a chance of grabbing a throne at the heart of the JRPG genre. I recently talked to Arise producer Yusuke Tomizawa, who worked hard to tailor the adventure for a new Tales audience as much as its established fans. He explains how Arise's development went down a long, risky road, but it paid off in excellent review scores, happy fans, and a refreshing new direction for Tales.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Oxford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to open the Storehouse Door in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-storehouse-door-puzzle</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-storehouse-door-puzzle"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:39:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Puzzled about how to open the Storehouse Door in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? The smallest area of the game, the Storehouse, is also one of the more confusing and puzzle-dense areas of the world - and the confusion isn't helped by the fact that you've just been given a new power and must quickly learn how it works in order to get through the Storehouse in one piece.
Below we'll walk you through exactly how to activate the two Power Crystals and open the Storehouse Door in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits. You'll find both a written and a video walkthrough of the Storehouse puzzle below, so what are you waiting for? Let's dive in.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Dark's story campaign continues with Episode 4 in October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-darks-story-campaign-continues-with-episode-4-in-october</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-long-darks-story-campaign-continues-with-episode-4-in-october"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T11:05:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Splendid snowy survival sandbox The Long Dark will launch the much-anticipated fourth episode of its story campaign on the 6th of October, developers Hinterland Studio have announced. Named 'Fury, Then Silence', episode 4 of the 'Wintermute' campaign sees one of our protagonists captured by murderers sheltering from the strange superfreeze in a prison complex. Have a peek at that in the new trailer below.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apex Legends still has stability issues after patch that should've fixed them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-still-has-stability-issues-after-patch-that-shouldve-fixed-them</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apex-legends-still-has-stability-issues-after-patch-that-shouldve-fixed-them"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T10:34:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've tried to play Apex Legends over the last week or so and noticed that things have been pretty slow, you're not alone. Since the game's Evolution Collection event launched last week, the battle royale and its servers have been struggling, and Respawn Entertainment have been tinkering away to try and sort it all out. Yesterday, they issued a patch to resolve a number of bugs and improve stability, but having played a few matches myself last night, it seems we're not out of the woods just yet.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck FAQ confirms you can use it as a giant PC controller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-faq-confirms-you-can-use-it-as-a-giant-pc-controller</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-faq-confirms-you-can-use-it-as-a-giant-pc-controller"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T10:10:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Valve haven't been overly secretive with the Steam Deck, there are still plenty of burning questions to ask about the upcoming handheld PC. For me, these are usually along the lines of “Will it slip into my big coat pockets as easily as the Switch does?” or “Will it survive my cat pushing it off literally any flat surface?” but the newly-launched Steam Deck FAQ covers enquiries of a generally more techy nature.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Archer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I beg you, enable multiplayer in Deathloop and embrace mortality]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-beg-you-enable-multiplayer-in-deathloop-and-embrace-mortality</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-beg-you-enable-multiplayer-in-deathloop-and-embrace-mortality"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The dastardly multiplayer invasions of Deathloop are some murderous hijinks. But not everybody wants to see a player-controlled assassin with vicious human instincts pop up as they sneak through their time loop adventure. That's fine, say developers Arkane, you can simply switch to single player mode, which will replace player incursions with periodic visits from an NPC Julianna who is (let's be diplomatic) a less feisty opponent. I am here to ask, nay, beg: do not do this. Leave it in Online mode. Welcome malice, embrace pain, receive with warmth that sudden mortal stab in the back. You are strong and capable of overcoming such things. I'm not just giving you an ego boost here. As the tenacious Colt, the fight is fixed in your favour.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Caldwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blood Bowl 3 delays early access launch following beta feedback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blood-bowl-3-delays-early-access-launch-following-beta-feedback</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/blood-bowl-3-delays-early-access-launch-following-beta-feedback"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T09:49:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fantasy sports management sim Blood Bowl 3 is delayed again, with the early access launch now pushed out of September and into the nebulous future. The official word is that after beta feedback, they realised yeah it wasn't ready. They say, "our teams are more committed than ever to make Blood Bowl 3 the most comprehensive and polished instalment in the series yet." Yeah go on, please do that.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MikroTik zažívá další vlnu DDoS útoků]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42846</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/mikrotik-zaziva-dalsi-vlnu-ddos-utoku/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T07:13:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na základě článku laboratoře QRATOR labs firma MikroTik na svých stránkách upozorňuje na další vlnu DDoS útoků.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME 41 přináší vylepšení výkonu a novinky v podpoře Waylandu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42847</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gnome-41-prinasi-vylepseni-vykonu-a-novinky-v-podpore-waylandu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-23T07:10:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vývojáři uvolnili pravidelnou půlroční aktualizaci desktopového prostředí GNOME, tentokrát s označením 41. Mezi hlavní novinky patří vylepšení správce software, nastavení multitaskingu a vylepšení power managementu. Kromě toho je tu nová aplikace Connections, aktualizovaná aplikace Music a vylepšení výkonu v celé řadě komponent.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brewing and haggling sim Potion Craft opens for business in early access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/brewing-and-haggling-sim-potion-craft-opens-for-business-in-early-access</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/brewing-and-haggling-sim-potion-craft-opens-for-business-in-early-access"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:52:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Step on in and please don't mind the badly-labelled vials I've left lying about the shop. Potion Craft is now in early access with all its myserious brewing and haggling and alchemy-ing. I've been quite taken with the demos and playtests for this one so far, not least because it brings some spirit back to the act of crafting. It's out now in early access, during which Niceplay Games will be adding even more crafting options to toy with before its full launch.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sable review: a beautiful adventure beset by troubling bugs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sable-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sable-review"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you might expect from a game set on a desert planet, Sable has a lot of sand. You traverse it on your floating motorbike as the titular character, a young woman who's part of a nomadic culture where adolescents leave home to complete their Gliding. During this gap year of sorts, the Glider does odd jobs and explores the world until they figure out what they want to be for the rest of their life. Sand is a feature. But as they say, sand is coarse and rough and irritating, and it gets everywhere. Each individual grain of sand is small, but a pinch of sand in your bed will change how you feel about your entire sleep experience.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kořen Let's Encrypt na konci měsíce vyprší, dotkne se to starších klientů]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15675</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/koren-let-s-encrypt-na-konci-mesice-vyprsi-dotkne-se-to-starsich-klientu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na konci září vyprší platnost kořenového certifikátu DST Root CA X3, na kterém od začátku stála podpora certifikační autority Let's Encrypt. Ta už sice používá nový kořen, ale staré systémy budou mít problém.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PC-BASIC: reinkarnace populárního i zatracovaného GW-BASICu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15676</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/pc-basic-reinkarnace-popularniho-i-zatracovaneho-gw-basicu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V první polovině osmdesátých let patřilo k dobrému vychování dodávat domácí i osobní počítače vybavené nějakým dialektem programovacího jazyka BASIC. Výjimkou není ani IBM PC, pro které byl dodáván mj. i GW-BASIC, později QBasic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop chose to boot its melee system in favor of that excellent kick]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-chose-to-boot-its-melee-system-in-favor-of-that-excellent-kick</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-chose-to-boot-its-melee-system-in-favor-of-that-excellent-kick"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T21:44:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time-looping murder puzzle Deathloop sure seems like it's worth putting on repeat. For all the usual action romp reasons that Arkane are good with, but also for some of its sillier bits. Kicking baddies off ledges sounds like it's the real backbone of Deathloop's comedy. Colt has one damn powerful boot and, according to a new chat with Deathloop director Dinga Bakaba, it's all thanks to Arkane's choice to scrap most of their melee combat system. Here's why Colt traded arm day for leg day. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Řada kritických chyb ve VMware vCenter]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42845</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/rada-kritickych-chyb-ve-vmware-vcenter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T20:42:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Včera večer byla vydána opravná verze VMware vCenter 6.5, 6.7 a 7.0. Tato nová sada verzí opravuje několik kritických zranitelností, od XSS, přístupu k skrytým endpointům API, neoprávněnou manipulaci s nastavením sítě virtuálních strojů, vzdálené mazání souborů na vCenteru až po asi nejzávažnější vzdálené spuštění kódu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: LD)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple won't let Fortnite back on the App Store until they run out of appeals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apple-wont-let-fortnite-back-on-the-app-store-until-they-run-out-of-appeals</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/apple-wont-let-fortnite-back-on-the-app-store-until-they-run-out-of-appeals"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T20:32:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The legal battle between Epic Games and Apple continues as it seems that both are probably willing to cut the proverbial Fortnite baby in half. Earlier this month, the court ruled that Apple must allow third-party payment systems, which was apparently not enough for Epic, who decided to submit an appeal last week. Now, Apple have informed Epic that they will not be allowing Fortnite back into the App Store clubhouse until they've exhausted all their own avenues to appeal. Which means Fortnite could remain off the store for years yet, according to Epic.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Lesbian road trip RPG" Get In The Car, Loser! has just hit the road]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lesbian-road-trip-rpg-get-in-the-car-loser-has-just-hit-the-road</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lesbian-road-trip-rpg-get-in-the-car-loser-has-just-hit-the-road"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T18:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get In The Car, Loser! begins as all RPGs about young protagonists with magical powers do—just a lot more bluntly. The world is being threatened by the evil Machine Devil and the Machine Devil cultists, and apparently no one is going to save it if not your plucky party of heroes. So hop on in the back seat, you dork. Get In The Car, Loser!, a free game written by Christine Love of Ladykiller In A Bind fame, is now fueled up and headed out on its self-proclaimed "lesbian road trip RPG".

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jett: The Far Shore's fictional language started life as gibberish choral music]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jett-the-far-shores-fictional-language-started-life-as-gibberish-choral-music</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jett-the-far-shores-fictional-language-started-life-as-gibberish-choral-music"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lots of good sci-fi has made up languages, but I don't think many could claim their fictional languages were developed through song. Enter Jett: The Far Shore. It's an upcoming interstellar adventure made by Sword & Sworcery developers Superbrothers with Pine Scented Software, in which a team of scouts take off in their jetts to explore an uncharted planet. Better yet, it features its very own language that sound designer Priscilla Snow developed after finding meaning in the gibberish words she used to form the game's music. 


While the initial plan was never to have their own in-game language, the Jett team now have a dictionary around 2000 words strong, and I had a chance to talk to them about how it all came to be. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sims 4 just added a massive 1200 new color swatches to 149 build items]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-just-added-a-massive-1200-new-color-swatches-to-149-build-items</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sims-4-just-added-a-massive-1200-new-color-swatches-to-149-build-items"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T16:27:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oh rejoice, a Sims 4 update that's all for me. Maxis have just dropped a free update which they say their art team totally took over by whipping up around 1200 new color swatches for 149 different Buy and Build Mode objects. There are tons of new window drape colors, new countertop swatches, wood furniture choices, and even plants. That is a lot of new color choices for a lot of items and oh boy I will probably use them all. Fellow builders, this one is for us. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's better: unit designers, or handcrafted art?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whats-better-unit-designers-or-handcrafted-art</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/whats-better-unit-designers-or-handcrafted-art"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T16:16:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last time, you decided that fiddling with environmental objects (henceforth known as fiddlebits) is better than rocket jumping. A toughie there, no doubt; I thank you for your careful deliberation. Next up, we're settling an issue of whose hand shapes  game, whether you're getting hands-on with your mens or having someone else lovingly handcraft the entire world for you.
What's better: unit designers, or handcrafted art?
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 94 nasazuje sRGB u elementu canvas a přidává WebGPU]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42844</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/chrome-94-nasazuje-srgb-u-elementu-canvas-a-pridava-webgpu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T15:45:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Možná nejvýznačnější novinkou v Chrome/Chromium 94 pro uživatele je to, že element canvas je nyní implicitně kalibrován na barevný prostor sRGB, nicméně stránka může specifikovat jiný, podporován je i DCI-P3. Pete LaPage dále doporučuje na web.dev věnovat pozornost textu Eugena Zemtsova o WebCodecs s příklady využití přímého videa pomocí hardwarově akcelerovaných kodeků, které již prohlížeč má (aneb blíží se konec nutnosti dodávat v kódu vlastní neakcelerovanou WASM verzi kodeků). Podpora kodeků skrze WebCodecs se týká jak přehrávání, tak komprese.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make and activate a Beacon in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-beacon-how-to-make-activate-beacon</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-beacon-how-to-make-activate-beacon"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T14:39:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to make and activate a Beacon in Minecraft? Beacons have two very important uses in Minecraft, as they give you status effects whilst also emitting a beam of light that can act as a waypoint marker to guide you and your friends home.
This guide will walk you through everything you need to know to make and use a Beacon in Minecraft, including how to get a Nether Star, which is one of the ingredients you will need.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An ode to cutting off boss tails in Dark Souls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-cutting-off-boss-tails-in-dark-souls</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/an-ode-to-cutting-off-boss-tails-in-dark-souls"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Happy 10th anniversary Dark Souls! Here's to you, Sin the Slumbering Dragon. And to you, Crossbreed Priscilla. Chin-chin! Oi, not to you Ornstein, or to you, Smough. How did you even get in, anyway? This is an invitation only event for bosses who have cuttable tails.
There's a tinge of sadness to this celebration, though. Cuttable tails were all the rage back in the original Dark Souls but now they're lost to time, never to be seen again, just like the tails you cut off themselves. Although a part of me hopes that the cycle will renew (like the sort of tails that grow back after you cut them off). And just like skinny jeans are slowly going out of fashion in favour of the 90s wide leg, I'm hoping FromSoftware's bosses won't cling so closely to their tails in Elden Ring and maybe, just maybe, they'll let us lop them off again.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy's chaotic combat owes more to JRPGs than you think]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxys-chaotic-combat-owes-more-to-jrpgs-than-you-think</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marvels-guardians-of-the-galaxys-chaotic-combat-owes-more-to-jrpgs-than-you-think"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I went hands-on with roughly an hour's worth of Marvel's Guardians Of The Galaxy last week, and I have come away pleasantly surprised. I'll admit, I judged a book by its cover on this one, thinking it would be an action adventure game only Marvel stans with decades worth of MCU facts beamed into their brains could rally behind. But no, even I, who's watched precisely three Marvel films in the last ten years, had a lot of fun with it. Good fun, at that.
Mainly, I liked how the game's combat takes cues from JRPGs, of all things, cribbing off the likes of Final Fantasy XV and Tales Of Arise so your fellow guardians feel just as - if not more - important than yourself.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are your favourite autumn games?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-your-favourite-autumn-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/what-are-your-favourite-autumn-games"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T12:40:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today brings the autumn equinox and the start of the season where things, like, fall. It's a good season! I will always mourn the end of summer but I relish the brief window to hike through golden forests, swimming through shoals of leaves in rivers, cosy up around bonfires with cocoa, and break out the warm duvet again. But while we wait for the season to properly kick in, I'm curious: which autumns in video games do you enjoy? Yes, Halloween included.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valorant's latest patch nerfed the floating knife-fiend Jett]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-latest-patch-nerfed-the-floating-knife-fiend-jett</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valorants-latest-patch-nerfed-the-floating-knife-fiend-jett"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T11:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you play Valorant, you undoubtedly know one of those Jett players. The sort that will very un-tactfully launch all three of their smokes in a messy line so they can dash into or out of fights, bamboozling their teammates just as much as the enemy team. It should be a little harder for these speedy knife-slingers to perform such daft feats in the future, because Riot Games have taken away one of Jett's smokes, and they've nerfed her knives to boot.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to find and defeat the Wither in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-wither-how-to-spawn-defeat-wither</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-wither-how-to-spawn-defeat-wither"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T10:27:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to spawn and defeat the Wither boss in Minecraft? The Wither is one of the most formidable enemies in Minecraft, and is one of only two boss mobs that can be encountered in the game.
If you’re ready to fight the terrifying monster then gear up and read on, as this guide will walk you through everything that you need to know to find and beat the Wither in Minecraft.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Souls bosses rated by how much money they’d owe you after a night out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-souls-bosses-rated-by-how-much-money-theyd-owe-you-after-a-night-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dark-souls-bosses-rated-by-how-much-money-theyd-owe-you-after-a-night-out"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, thought you’d take all your great Lordran chums out for a drink to celebrate the 10th anniversary of Dark Souls, did you? Bad times, pal. Sure, they’ll take care of any everlasting dragons you happen to have hanging around on your lawn, but when it comes to a night on the bevvies, they might well be the sorriest bunch of cheapskates since Final Fantasy VIII’s GFs. Consider this your one and only warning before these fantasy grifters clear you out for the month. 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nic Reuben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deathloop PC patch addresses framerate stuttering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-pc-patch-addresses-framerate-stuttering</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/deathloop-pc-patch-addresses-framerate-stuttering"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T09:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Arkane Studios sneak-o-shooter Deathloop is a good'un, but the PC launch was marred by technical problems which caused the framerate to stutter for many players. One week later, they've put out a patch which should fix the stuttering for many folks playing with a mouse. However, you might not find the game hunky-dory now, as they say they're still investigating another potential stutterorama. Always tricky when multiple issues create similar-looking outcomes.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webové stránky politických stran obsahují zranitelnosti]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42843</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/webove-stranky-politickych-stran-obsahuji-zranitelnosti/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T08:12:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Test deseti webových prezentací politických stran odhalil v pěti případech kritické zranitelnosti, nejčastěji se jednalo o cross-site scripting, objevily se ale zranitelné zastaralé knihovny a v jednom případě také děravý jedenáct let starý Apache. Více ve zprávě na webu spajk.cz.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: spajk)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 přinese podporu senzorů dalších základních desek ASUS]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42841</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/linux-5-16-prinese-podporu-senzoru-dalsich-zakladnich-desek-asus/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V Linuxu 5.16 dojde ke změně v ovladači nct6775, který obstarává čtení dat ze senzorů mnohých základních desek značky ASUS. Ovladač dostane podporu přístupu k ASIC za použití funkcí ASUS WMI (desky od Asusteku nepoužívají standardní cestu přes ACPI, kterou ovladač disponuje již nyní). S úpravou pak logicky do jádra zamíří i podpora níže uvedeného seznamu základních desek:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 2.10.28 opravuje další chyby]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42840</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/gimp-2-10-28-opravuje-dalsi-chyby/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Na GIMP 3.0 si ještě chvíli počkáme, vezměmež tedy zavděk dalším, víceméně opravným vydání dva-desítkové řady. GIMP 2.10.28 totiž přináší solidní množství oprav.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sloped Border]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2519/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2519/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hero's Hour is a strategy RPG with huge automatic battles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heros-hour-is-a-strategy-rpg-with-huge-automatic-battles</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heros-hour-is-a-strategy-rpg-with-huge-automatic-battles"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:25:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I spend roughly 90% of my free time watching what the YouTube algorithm offers me. I've not been radicalised yet, although I do now refer to any shopping I buy as a "haul" and end all my conversations by thanking Skillshare. 

To my surprise, the algorithm has recently started throwing indie games my way. Hero's Hour is among the most interesting it's shown me: a strategy RPG in which you construct armies of pixelated fantasy beasts who then have automated battles.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino Mega na zbernici s PC]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15662</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/arduino-mega-na-zbernici-s-pc/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Platforma Arduino sa stala veľmi rozšírenou najmä vďaka tomu, že umožňuje veľmi jednoducho naprogramovať rôzne typy kontrolérov pre najrozmanitejšie úlohy. Zároveň využívame väčšinu výhod kontrolérov.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ferenc Lengyel)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Softwarová sklizeň (22. 9. 2021)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15671</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/softwarova-sklizen-22-9-2021/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dnes si představíme jednoduchý editor odvozený z projektu lite, budeme optimalizovat velikost obrázků, začneme si vést vlastní deník a nakonec využijeme průzkumníka slovníků EPWING, LingvoDSL a StarDict.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jiří Sluka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podpora Ubuntu 14.04 LTS a 16.04 LTS se prodlužuje na 10 let]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42839</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/podpora-ubuntu-14-04-lts-a-16-04-lts-se-prodluzuje-na-10-let/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical rozhodl o prodloužení podpory starších LTS vydání operačního systému Ubuntu na 10 let od první vydané verze. To znamená, že řada Ubuntu 14.04 LTS „Trusty Tahr“ bude podporována až do dubna 2024 a řada Ubuntu 16.04 LTS „Xenial Xerus“ až do dubna 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: David Ježek)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phoenix Point's Corrupted Horizons will open up on October 1st]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/phoenix-points-corrupted-horizons-will-open-up-on-october-1st</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/phoenix-points-corrupted-horizons-will-open-up-on-october-1st"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T21:26:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Phoenix Point's fourth DLC is due on October 1st. Corrupted Horizons adds a new corruption mechanic which can sap the will of your squad, as well as new Mutoid soldiers, pictured above. The Mutoids are immune to corruption, can learn any class's skills, but are unable to heal.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death Of The Reprobate will complete a point and click triptych]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/death-of-the-reprobate-will-complete-a-point-and-click-triptych</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/death-of-the-reprobate-will-complete-a-point-and-click-triptych"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T21:01:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I feel as if the header image successfully conveys the appeal of Joe Richardson's work. He makes point-and-click adventures which take real Renaissance paintings, animate them in cut-out style (think Monty Python), and juxtapose them with modern vernacular.

His next game was announced today. It's called Death Of The Reprobate, and there's a trailer showing both pointing and clicking below.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You can once again check whether your PC will run Windows 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-once-again-check-whether-your-pc-will-run-windows-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-once-again-check-whether-your-pc-will-run-windows-11"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T20:24:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft have put their PC Health Check app back online. The simple tool is designed to tell you whether Windows 11 is compatible with your computer, but it was pulled offline back in June when it kept telling people with modern PCs that they couldn't run the new operating system, with little information as to why not. It's more recently been available to members of the Windows Insider program, but it's back now for all.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nová mobilní Datovka nabízí další způsob platby za odesílané poštovní datové zprávy]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42842</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/nova-mobilni-datovka-nabizi-dalsi-zpusob-platby-za-odesilane-postovni-datove-zpravy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T20:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Laboratoře CZ.NIC vydaly další verzi mobilní Datovky (1.13.0). Kromě oprav nalezených chyb, jako jsou oprava chyby při načítání uložených informací o datovém trezoru nebo vypnutí upozornění na vypršení platnosti hesla, pokud je zvoleno přihlašování Mobilním klíčem, byl podobně jako v případě desktopové aplikace přidán výběr způsobu platby za odesílané poštovní datové zprávy, pokud má uživatel k dispozici více možností.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: anonymní)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neo: The World Ends With You comes to you on PC next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/neo-the-world-ends-with-you-comes-to-you-on-pc-next-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/neo-the-world-ends-with-you-comes-to-you-on-pc-next-week"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T17:07:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following its debut on PlayStation 4 and Switch in July, Square Enix plan to bring Neo: The World Ends With You over to PC on the 28th of September. That's next Tuesday, day dudes. It's the sequel to an RPG from the Nintendo DS in 2007, set inside a colourful and weird version of Tokyo where young'uns get drawn into a deadly game.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weekspot podcast #054: bridge of spies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-054-deathloop-kena</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/pc-gaming-weekspot-podcast-054-deathloop-kena"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After getting a taste last week, both myself and Matthew have spent the last few days in Blackreef. We've been enjoying doing the same things over and over. Yeah, Deathloop is pretty good.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Colm Ahern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halo Infinite will have back-to-back tech previews this weekend and next]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-have-back-to-back-tech-previews-this-weekend-and-next</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/halo-infinite-will-have-back-to-back-tech-previews-this-weekend-and-next"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:54:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're not too busy Deathlooping, Kena: Bridge Of Spiriting, or Diablo 2: Resurrecting this weekend, perhaps you'll have a spare moment to drop into Halo Infinite's next technical preview. Between Thursday and Sunday, players registered as a Halo Insider will have a chance to try out the sci-fi FPS's 4v4 Arena mode. But that's not all! 343 have announced that the following weekend, Insiders can jump into another tech test, and have a crack at the game's 12v12 Big Team Battle mode too.

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard's open beta feels like Modern Warfare with a lick of WW2 paint]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-open-beta-feels-like-modern-warfare-with-a-lick-of-ww2-paint</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-vanguards-open-beta-feels-like-modern-warfare-with-a-lick-of-ww2-paint"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Vanguard's multiplayer feels familiar, have I been here before? Yes, in the past, but also in the future. Despite its World War II setting, Vanguard's open beta has me thinking back to the days of Call Of Duty: Modern Warfare. Having played a sizable chunk of it now, I'm not kidding when I say that it's like the Modern Warfare lot LARPING on a WWII set. For some this will be good. For others this will be bad. For me? It needs Warzone.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Thorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to access the secret cow level in Diablo 2: Resurrected]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-cow-level</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/diablo-2-resurrected-cow-level"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:21:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the secret cow level in Diablo 2: Resurrected? The cow level became Diablo 2’s worst-kept secret in the decades following its release. This infamous hidden zone contains armies of halberd-wielding Hell Bovines that swarm players, plus the goofily named Cow King boss. The cow level is a fun little side area to run, and it will of course be present in Diablo 2: Resurrected. If you missed out on the original and don’t know how to find the portal, we’re here to help.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlie Biggerstaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Crossbow loadout in Warzone Season 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-crossbow-loadout-warzone</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-crossbow-loadout-warzone"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:07:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for the best Crossbow loadout to bring into Warzone? It's certainly a unique option to consider in a game all about firearms and high tech weaponry. Still there's fun to be had when wielding this modern take on a medieval weapon, and it's more than capable of one-shotting enemies if you have the skills to wield it. Just don't take the Crossbow into Warzone with the expectation of dominating. It's a novelty at best, and you should be using the best guns in Warzone if your goal is to win.  

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Foley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jackbox Party Pack 8 arriving in time to spook your Halloween party]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jackbox-party-pack-8-arriving-in-time-to-spook-your-halloween-party</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/jackbox-party-pack-8-arriving-in-time-to-spook-your-halloween-party"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:04:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You've got a checklist for Halloween: peeled grapes (eyeballs); cold spaghetti (worms); 12-foot skeleton (skeleton); 25 metre bolt of black cotton (costume). But wait, what will people play? Friendo, you're in lucko. Jackbox Games have announced that The Jackbox Party Pack 8, their latest collection of funny party games, will launch on October 14th. It'll pack five games, from murder mystery to a new version of fan-favourite Drawful, this time having players animate their drawings.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice O'Connor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rogue Lords is a devilishly fun roguelike where cheating is considered a virtue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rogue-lords-is-a-devilishly-fun-roguelike-where-cheating-is-considered-a-virtue</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rogue-lords-is-a-devilishly-fun-roguelike-where-cheating-is-considered-a-virtue"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything about Rogue Lords is very Halloween-y. It's an upcoming gothic roguelike in which you, the devil, send disciples out into the world to wage war with demon hunters and cause general mischief in the mortal world. Having played a bit myself, I already feel the need to start carving pumpkins and hanging up fake cobwebs around my house. It reminds me of all the spooky animated films you see on the telly throughout October, which makes sense because the developers at Cyanide and Leikir Studios tell me the game's art style is partially inspired by Tim Burton films.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make a Book in Minecraft]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-how-to-make-a-book</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/minecraft-how-to-make-a-book"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T14:39:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to know how to make a Book in Minecraft? Books are very important, as you will need them to enchant your armour and weapons with various effects. You can also make pretty bookshelves to spruce up your home, if you aren’t interested in becoming an all-powerful wizard.
This guide will walk you through everything that you need to know to make a Book in Minecraft, including how to get Paper and Leather, which you will need.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayden Hefford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Genshin Impact Sangonomiya Kokomi build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-sangonomiya-kokomi-build</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-genshin-impact-sangonomiya-kokomi-build"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T14:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn how to create the best build for Sangonomiya Kokomi in Genshin Impact? Kokomi has been present in Genshin Impact since August's V2.0 update as an NPC, but a playable version of the character is now available as part of the Drifting Luminescence event (running from September 21st to October 12th).
 Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kena: Bridge Of Spirits bosses and how to beat them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-bosses-boss-fights</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/kena-bridge-of-spirits-bosses-boss-fights"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T13:42:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to learn about all the boss fights in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits? There is a grand total of 16 boss fights (that is, fights with big boss health bars at the top) in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits - and like everything else in Ember Lab's marvellous action-adventure game, each one offers some true spectacle. If you're looking for a list of all the boss fights and some advice on how to beat each one, you've come to the right place.
Keep scrolling to check out all 16 bosses in Kena: Bridge Of Spirits. I've also included footage of myself beating each boss on Master Spirit Guide difficulty.
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Toms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activision Blizzard are now being investigated by the US government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-are-now-being-investigated-by-the-us-government</id>
        <link href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-blizzard-are-now-being-investigated-by-the-us-government"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T12:59:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The US government's Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) are investigating Activision Blizzard over the company's handling of sexual misconduct and harassment allegations. This comes just two months after the Call Of Duty publishers were sued by a State department for alleged workplace harassment, discrimination, and retaliation. Now, The SEC have subpoenaed a number of high-level executives, reportedly including CEO Bobby Kotick, and have requested internal documents relating to the allegations. 

 
Read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Imogen Beckhelling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V seznamáckém hackathonu zvítězil tým EasyPeasy.Net]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42838</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/v-seznamackem-hackathonu-zvitezil-tym-easypeasy-net/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T10:06:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Celodenní soutěžní hackathon pro programátory od české technologické společnosti Seznam.cz zná své vítěze. Nejlepší výkon předvedl tým s názvem EasyPeasy.Net ve složení Tomáš Jurásek, Michal Mrnuštík, Michal Motyčka a Adam Jež (zleva).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ondřej Nový)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test terabajtových SSD pro rozhraní PCIe 4.0 od WD, Samsung, Adata, Seagate, Aorus]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42837</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/test-terabajtovych-ssd-pro-rozhrani-pcie-4-0-od-wd-samsung-adata-seagate-aorus/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T06:34:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kolegové ze serveru Cnews.cz otestovali pět terabajtových SSD pro rozhraní PCIe 4.0. Konkrétně šlo o disky značek WD, Samsung, Adata, Seagate a Aorus, jejichž cena se pohybuje okolo 5500 Kč. Testován byl výkon po připojení na novou sběrnici PCIe 4.0, ale zároveň i ve zpětně kompatibilní PCIe 3.0.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Petr Krčmář)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrobrightin­g: výsledky procesu bělení plastu a jeden průšvih]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15642</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/retrobrightin-g-vysledky-procesu-beleni-plastu-a-jeden-prusvih/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T22:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V druhé části článků o retrobrightingu se podíváme na samotné výsledky mého snažení. Ve většině případů je výsledek velmi uspokojivý, ale jak uvidíte v jednom případě, ne vždy je vše dokonalé.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Michal Tauchman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Křivky v přírodě i v počítačové grafice – svět spirál (dokončení)]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-text-15668</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/clanky/krivky-v-prirode-i-v-pocitacove-grafice-svet-spiral-dokonceni/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T22:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V dnešní části seriálu o křivkách, které nalezneme v přírodě, architektuře, technice i v počítačové grafice, dokončíme popis různých typů spirál. Zabývat se budeme například klotoidou a evolventou.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Pavel Tišnovský)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot-clone: nástroj umožňující získat obraz připojeného disku]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42836</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/hot-clone-nastroj-umoznujici-ziskat-obraz-pripojeneho-disku/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chcete-li vytvořit bitovou kopii souborového systému, asi není úplně dobrý nápad používat nástroje jako dd, je-li disk zároveň připojen. Vytváření obrazu bude určitou dobu trvat a pokud se během této doby na disk zapisuje, bude výsledný obraz velmi poškozený.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Ondřej Caletka)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SMB3 server v jádře 5.15 KSMBD už má první vážnou opravu]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42835</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/smb3-server-v-jadre-5-15-ksmbd-uz-ma-prvni-vaznou-opravu/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:22:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SMB3 server implementovaný v jádře s názvem KSMBD, za kterým stojí Samsung, se dostal do jádra 5.15. To ještě ani nevyšlo a už se v KSMBD objevila závažná zranitelnost, kdy pomocí znaků .. v cestě je možné přistupovat k souborům mimo sdílené adresáře.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Co očekáváme ve Fedoře 35]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42834</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/co-ocekavame-ve-fedore-35/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T14:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 35 beta by měla vyjít každým dnem. Ostrá verze se očekává 19. října, nebo o týden později. Na serveru mojefedora.cz vyšel dnes článek shrnující novinky očekávané ve Fedoře 35 Workstation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edward Snowden nedoporučuje používat ExpressVPN]]></title>
        <id>www.root.cz-actuality-42833</id>
        <link href="https://www.root.cz/zpravicky/edward-snowden-nedporucuje-pouzivat-expressvpn/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=text&amp;utm_campaign=rss"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T09:13:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Edward Snowden se minulý týden na Twitteru vyjádřil, že nedporučuje používat ExpressVPN. Důvodem je, že bývalý CIO ExpressVPN Daniel Gericke spolu s dalšími dvěma bývalými zaměstnanci NSA pracovali jako nájemní hackeři mezi lety 2016 a 2019 pro firmu DarkMatter ve Spojených arabských emirátech. Za porušení exportních zákonů, jim soud uložil pokutu více jak 1,5 milionů dolarů. Navíc dostali doživotní zákaz bezpečnostní prověrky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>redakce@root.cz (Root.cz: Jan Fikar)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lumpers and Splitters]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2518/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2518/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Komunikace má zvyšovat produktivitu vývojářů]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-komunikace-ma-zvysovat-produktivitu-vyvojaru</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-komunikace-ma-zvysovat-produktivitu-vyvojaru"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hlavní trendy umělé inteligence: Malá a rozprostřená data. Nový typ kybernetických útoků – zneužívání proxyware platforem. Roboti, kteří udělají přesnou díru do hlavy, zachraňují životy. O vstupu do nebe rozhoduje sv. Petr, pro síť je tu ClearPass. Kouzla zbavené? Nepravděpodobné řešení hrozící personální krize ve finančních službách. Honeywell u nás investuje do R&D. Komunikace má zvyšovat produktivitu vývojářů.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Přepínané zrcadlo z roztaveného kovu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-prepinane-zrcadlo-z-roztaveneho-kovu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-prepinane-zrcadlo-z-roztaveneho-kovu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Černá díra vyžrala hvězdu. Nanotechnologie s černým oxidem titaničitým. Život v atmosféře subneptunů. Maličké hory na neutronových hvězdách.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Událo se v týdnu 37/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-37-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/udalo-se-v-tydnu-37-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ucelený přehled článků, zpráviček a diskusí za minulých 7 dní.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoodOffer24: Doživotní licence Windows 10 pouze za 12 €, super slevy až 91%!]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/goodoffer24-dozivotni-licence-windows-10-pouze-za-12-super-slevy-az-91"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pořiďte si doživotní aktivační klíč k Windows 10 za 12,52 EUR na prodejním portálu GoodOffer24.com. Kromě toho nástrojů produktivity od Microsoftu zde lze získat i hry a další software. Nezapomeňte zadat před dokončením nákupu slevový kód  AX30.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reklama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rover Replies]]></title>
        <id>https://xkcd.com/2517/</id>
        <link href="https://xkcd.com/2517/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>xkcd.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distribuční novinky 34-35/2021]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/distribucni-novinky-34-35-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Závěr letních prázdnin a začátek školního roku přinesly několik významných vydání, LibreELEC s novým Kodi, příručky Linux From Scratch nebo novou stabilní větev OpenWrt, a také aktualizace Clonezilly, Ubuntu LTS, EndeavourOS či EasyOS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ITBiz: Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-itbiz-sprava-a-analyza-dat-tlaci-podniky-do-cloudu"/>
        <updated>2021-09-12T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenovo představuje hybridní tablety budoucnosti. Canon rozšiřuje nabídku A3 multifunkcí pro hybridní pracovní prostředí. Správa a analýza dat tlačí podniky do cloudu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Týden na ScienceMag.cz: Dokázali přepnout vodivost z 2D na 1D]]></title>
        <id>http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-dokazali-prepnout-vodivost-z-2d-na-1d</id>
        <link href="http://www.abclinuxu.cz/clanky/tyden-na-sciencemag.cz-dokazali-prepnout-vodivost-z-2d-na-1d"/>
        <updated>2021-09-11T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Topologické izolátory. Janusovský grafen a baterie. Zachycen nový typ gravitačních vln. Dvojvrstvý borofen. Hledání mimozemských civilizací. Dysonovy sféry u černých děr. Planeta Devět. Oblečení z umělých svalových vláken.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Redakce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>